01 Sherlock Holmes And The Hound
Of The Baskervilles 1939 English.
Hello there?
Hello there, is something wrong?
My wife and I found him
lying dead in the yew alley,
face downward.
What did you do then?
I hurried across the moor to
fetch the doctor, Dr. Mortimer.
He was at dinner with
Miss Stapleton and her brother.
Very well, Barryman, that's all.
Yes, sir.
Dr. Mortimer,
to what do you attribute
the death of Sir Charles?
Heart failure, sir.
I might add that for some time Sir Charles
was in a highly nervous state, worried.
Something was preying
on his mind.
And did he confide to you
what was preying on his mind?
Well...
- No.
- Well then, what about those footprints, Mortimer?
As though Sir Charles had been
tiptoeing back towards the house?
I examined them myself,
and as a man of science, I...
So did I, Mr. Stapleton.
- More likely, Sir Charles was running...
- Running?
Running from what?
If you please, gentlemen,
one at a time.
Why don't you tell the truth,
all of you,
tell all you know!
Silence, Mr. Franklin.
You've already testified.
You were not there, know nothing
whatever of this matter.
Nevertheless, I insist
he was murdered!
- Murdered, I tell you!
- That will do, sir, that will do.
- There were no marks on the body of any kind, Dr. Mortimer?
- None.
Then as his physician, what would you say
was the cause of Sir Charles' death?
Most emphatically
a heart failure, sir.
Such then gentlemen, is the
verdict of this coroner's court.
Call it what you like.
Sir Charles was murdered.
There's more than one
person in this room,
knows I speak the truth.
I'm blasted if I know why on earth
you want all these clippings
about this Baskerville fellow.
I have an idea, Watson, that
young Sir Henry isn't destined
for a very long existence
in this world.
What?
My conjecture is
that he'll be murdered.
Murdered?
It would be very interesting to
see if my deductions are accurate.
Oh, Mr. Holmes,
while you were out a gentleman
called to see you and left this.
He asked you to give it to me?
- Oh, no, sir, he just left it by mistake, I imagine.
- Mm-hmm.
A Dr. Mortimer?
He didn't leave his name, sir.
- No, it's here on the stick, Mrs. Hudson.
- Oh, is it, I didn't notice.
Do you know any
Dr. Mortimer, Watson?
No? What did he want?
He didn't say, sir.
What do you make of it, Watson?
Why should I make
anything of it?
- The fellow came to see you.
- Ah, but what kind of a fellow?
Let me hear you reconstruct him
from his walking stick
by our usual method of
elementary observation.
Well, I should say that
Dr. Mortimer is a successful man,
- well esteemed.
- Good, excellent.
I should say that he does a great
deal of his visiting on foot,
- because the iron ferrule is worn down.
- Perfectly sound.
Let's have a look at
this inscription.
"From his friends
of the C.C.H ."
C.C.H.
I should say that's the
something or other hunt.
Really, Watson,
you've excelled yourself.
Does anything escape me?
- Almost everything, my dear fellow.
- What?
A present to a doctor I'd say is more
likely to come from a hospital than a hunt.
And when the letters "C.C"
are placed before the hospital,
the name Cherring Cross Hospital
rather obviously presents itself.
Oh, okay, you may be right.
Furthermore I'd say that Dr. Mortimer
had a small practice in the country
- and was the owner of a dog.
- How can you tell that?
Quite simple,
from the teeth marks.
Look, you can see for yourself.
A rather large dog, I'd say,
and unless I'm mistaken, Dr. Mortimer
will call on us again in a few moments.
Rubbish, Holmes, rubbish.
How the devil
can you deduce that?
Well, as he left his stick,
isn't it reasonable to presume
that he'll come back and get it?
Dr. Mortimer, sir.
Mr. Holmes?
Yes, come in, Dr. Mortimer.
- I took the liberty of calling upon you...
- And left your stick.
Oh, so I did. Thank you so much.
A presentation, I see.
Yes, sir,
from Cherring Cross Hospital.
This is my friend, Dr. Watson.
Of course.
How do you do, sir.
Mr. Holmes,
you're the one man in all
England who can help me.
Well, won't you sit down?
Thank you.
A friend of mine
is in grave danger.
- May I inquire his name?
- Sir Henry Baskerville.
The Heir to the Estate
of Baskerville Hall.
I'm in mortal fear Sir Henry's
life will be stuffed out.
Why, what makes you think that?
I have information which leads me
to believe that for centuries past,
every Baskerville who
has inherited the estates
has met with a violent,
and sudden death.
But as I recall it, Sir Charles died
from natural causes, heart failure.
Apparently, and that was
the verdict of the coroner,
in which I, Sir Charles'
physician, concurred,
but there was one point which
I kept back from the police,
from everybody.
Yes?
About 50 yards from where
Sir Charles fell dead
were footprints.
A man's or a woman's?
Mr. Holmes, they were the
footprints of a gigantic hound.
A hound?
Well, why didn't you report it?
Not a soul
would have believed it.
And during the night it rained.
And in the morning the marks
were completely obliterated,
but I saw them
as clearly as I see you.
And then a few days ago, as one
of the executors of the estate,
I found this.
This old document.
"Legend of the
Hound of the Baskervilles."
Let me read it to you,
Mr. Holmes,
it's quite short.
I won't bore you, I promise.
Yes, please, go on.
"In the time of the
Great Rebellion, about 1650,."
Baskerville Manor was held
by Hugo of that name,
a profane and godless man.
One Michaelmas, Mr. Hugo stalled
out of a neighbouring farm
and carried off
the daughter of the house.
He locked her
in an upper chamber,
and while Hugo and his friends
were carousing
"as was their nightly custom..."
Such a cuddle some little wench
never existed before, I swear.
Cheeks soft as velvet.
A form so wondrously rounded.
- Tell us more.
- What happened then?
- Where was I?
- The form, you were saying.
Oh, yeah.
No need to cry out, I told her.
Hugo will not hurt you.
With that, I whisked
her up on my saddle,
covered her with my cloak
and we were off like the wind.
- You brought her here?
- To the Manor?
- Where is she?
- Go fetch her, Hugo.
Easier said than done, eh, Hugo?
How can he fetch her
if she isn't here?
She isn't, eh?
Come on, I'll show you.
May we come in, my sweet?
These drunken sots
will give Hugo the...
There is no girl.
Gone!
Gone.
Get out of my way.
Tim! Danny!
- Yes, Sir Hugo.
- What's wrong, sir?
She's gone, the wench.
Well, don't stand there gaping,
go bring my mare.
What's wrong?
I've never seen him
in such a rage.
Where's he gone?
Lets follow him.
- Lets go, Roderick.
- Farewell.
Come on, Matthew.
Hold it still, you blockhead.
I'll give my soul to the devil
for that wench!
Did you hear how he pledged his
soul to the devil for that wench?
Well, may he find her and wed her.
Then the devil will have his soul.
"On and on they road,
until suddenly they came
upon the body of the girl."
Dead.
"Then, from just over a rise,
they heard sounds so hideous"
that the blood froze
in their veins,
"and looking up, they beheld..."
"Before we could get at him,
Sir Hugo was dead,"
his body literally
torn to shreds.
Such is the history of the hound
that has cursed the
Baskerville family ever since.
Many having been
unhappy in their death,
"that have been sudden,
violent, and mysterious."
Well, Mr. Holmes?
Interesting.
Very interesting.
- What do you think?
- I don't know.
But Sir Henry is arriving
from Canada tomorrow.
Please understand my dilemma,
my responsibility.
I was Sir Charles' best friend.
My duty is to protect that boy.
If I should take him down there
to Baskerville Hall,
- and anything happened to him...
- What I'd suggest, Dr. Mortimer,
is that when Sir Henry arrives,
you bring him here.
Oh, thank you,
thank you, Mr. Holmes.
You don't know what a load
you've taken off my mind.
- Good night, Dr. Watson.
- Good night, sir.
You've left your stick again.
Oh, thank you.
By the by, Dr. Mortimer,
you have a dog?
I have no dog.
Then how do you
account for these marks?
Evidently the teeth marks
of a dog.
I used to have a dog,
a small Spaniel,
but it died.
- Good night.
Well, Holmes,
what do you make of it?
Do you think there's
anything in it?
Good heavens, you're not going to start
scratching on that infernal thing, are you?
Dear old Watson.
Well, goodbye, Sir Henry.
If you ever go back to Canada,
be sure you sail with us.
Thanks,
you've all been wonderful.
Very best of luck, sir.
And the same to you, sir.
This way, Sir Henry.
Thank you, sir.
- And you.
- Thank you, Sir Henry.
- Thank you, sir.
Sir Henry?
Oh, it's too bad it's all over,
just when you and Betsy Anne were
really getting to know each other.
Oh, but we are going to
see one another in London,
aren't we, Sir Henry?
Oh, I should love to,
but I have to go down to
the country, unfortunately.
To your ancestral estate?
How exciting.
Perhaps, Betsy Anne,
if you're very good,
Sir Henry will ask us
to visit him.
Of course, yes.
- We're staying at The Savoy.
- Don't forget.
- I won't.
- Bye.
Goodbye.
Sir Henry?
Yes.
I'm Dr. Mortimer.
Your uncle was my best friend.
How do you do? Thank you
for coming to meet me.
Not at all, my dear boy.
Did you have a pleasant trip?
Splendid, thank you.
I've taken rooms for you at the
Northumberland Hotel,
where I'm stopping.
Fine.
I assume you'll be staying
in London for a few days?
Yes, I haven't seen it
since I was a boy.
- Thank you, sir.
- Northumberland Hotel.
Sir Charles' death was a
great personal loss to me.
I was more than his doctor...
What's this?
What are those words?
You mind, Sir Henry?
No, not at all.
What do you make of it,
Mr. Holmes?
Why do you think that last
word is printed in ink?
Oh, that's simple enough.
The words have been snipped
from The London Times,
that's evident
from the typography.
But the word "moor"
is an unusual word.
Your correspondent evidently
couldn't find it in the newspaper.
You'll admit, Dr. Mortimer, there's
nothing supernatural about this.
Supernatural?
Tell me, Sir Henry,
has anything else unusual
happened to you today
since your arrival in London?
I can't think of anything,
unless you'd say that losing
one of your boots is unusual.
- You lost one of your boots?
- Yes, and brand new ones too, never had them on.
I put them outside the door
to be cleaned,
and when I went to fetch them,
there was only one there.
Brand new boots and you
put them out to be cleaned?
They were tan ones, Dr. Watson.
It prevents them from scratching
to have them polished first.
Now will you please tell me
what this is all about?
Dr. Mortimer bringing me here
to see you, this letter?
It's about you, Sir Henry, your
inheritance in Baskerville Hall.
And Dr. Mortimer thinks that it might
not be safe for you to go down there.
- Safe?
- On account of a hound,
a wild, supernatural monster
that has cursed you Baskervilles
for the last two to 300 years.
Ho, ho, that sounds grand!
A family ghost, eh?
Why did you tell me about
this before, Dr. Mortimer?
Well, Mr. Holmes suggested...
He's going to tell you
about it now, Sir Henry.
Take him back to the hotel,
Dr. Mortimer.
Show him that old document tell him
everything, the whole business.
I'll join you a little later.
Come on, we'll stroll back.
You can tell me on the way.
This is not something to joke
about, Sir Henry, believe me.
See you presently.
Good night.
What's up?
Shh.
- Come on, Watson.
- What's up, now?
- Where are we going?
- You'll see soon enough.
We've not a moment to lose.
Newspaper.
Get your evening paper.
Keep your eye on that hansom.
This letter dates back
to about 1650.
Paper, get your evening paper.
Get your paper, evening paper.
Evening paper, sir,
get your evening paper.
Get your paper, evening paper.
Evening paper, sir?
Tells all the latest news
that's going on, sir.
- Tells you all about it.
- Thank you, sir.
Evening paper.
A dissident, drunken fellow...
He was a decadent...
Look out, stop!
Whip up, cabby. Whip up, I say.
Very good, sir.
- Who was it?
- I don't know, but it's just as I expected.
- Hadn't we better hurry on and warn them?
- No, no, no.
They're not in any danger now.
Here's the number
of that hansom.
Find out from Scotland Yard
who the cabbie is
and if you can,
fetch him along to the hotel.
I'll do my best.
Well, now that Dr. Mortimer
has told you everything,
what have you decided?
To go there, of course.
Good, that's what I thought
you'd say.
And if Dr. Mortimer
would only guarantee
that this supernatural hound
of his would really appear,
I'm all the ready.
Oh, don't say that, my boy.
Sounds like a bogey story they tell
kids to frighten them at night,
- isn't it, Mr. Holmes?
- Yes, rather.
It might interesting to know,
however,
that you were shadowed
from my house.
Shadowed?
Yes, and probably have been ever
since you arrived in London.
By whom?
I don't know.
A man in a hansom.
He must have seen me run after
him and have the cabbie dash off.
Oh, by the by.
- Did you ever discover your mislaid boot?
- No...
Hello.
The brown one's here,
but one of the black one's gone.
I'll ring for the chambermaid,
perhaps she can explain.
Yes, do.
Now, why should anyone
want to take an odd boot
and then exchange a
brand new one for an old one?
Can you explain it, Mr. Holmes?
No, no, I can't.
Come in?
Did you ring, sir?
Yes, about that boot of mine?
Oh, I haven't found it yet, sir. I've
made inquiries all over the hotel.
Well, it's back, the brown one, but
now one of my black one is gone.
Oh, sir, that is odd.
Who else except yourself
has access to this apartment?
Only the housekeeper, sir, and
she wouldn't do a thing like that.
- No, no, no, of course not.
- I'm terribly sorry, sir,
- I'll do my best to find your boot.
- All right, thanks.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening, Dr. Watson.
I've got him.
Come on in, Clayton.
Come this way.
- This is John Clayton, No. 2704.
- How do you do?
How do you do, Clayton?
Won't you sit down?
Won't keep you long,
it's good of you to come.
Thank you, sir.
Now, Clayton,
I wish you'd tell us
who your fare was
that watched a certain house
on Baker Street this evening
and later followed
these two gentlemen?
Well, you know
as much as I do, sir.
Not quite as much, I hope.
The gent said as though
he was a detective, sir.
- Oh, he did?
- Yes, sir.
How would you describe
this gentleman, Clayton?
He was I supposed about
35 years of age, sir,
and dressed like a toff.
Had a small black beard.
Colour of his eyes?
I can't say, sir.
I see.
When did he tell you
that he was a detective?
At the station, sir,
when he give me the two guineas
what he'd promised me.
Did he tell you his name?
Yes, sir.
- What did he say it was?
- Sherlock Holmes, sir.
- What?
- Well, that's the name what he gave me, sir.
Sherlock Holmes.
Well, whoever it is
at least has a sense of humour.
Here, Clayton, here's something
for your trouble.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you kindly, sir.
Is there anything else
I can tell you, sir?
- Nothing at all, I think.
- Al-right sir, good day, sir.
- Good day.
- Good day, gentlemen.
Well, Mr. Holmes,
have we progressed, do you think?
Perhaps.
Now, tell me, Sir Henry,
when were you planning
to go down to Dartmoor?
Immediately, tomorrow.
I'm really awfully keen
to see the old place.
You'll accompany us, Mr. Holmes?
I'd like to very much,
Dr. Mortimer,
but unfortunately I have some rather
pressing business here in London.
Of course, there's no need.
Please don't think me
ungrateful, Dr. Mortimer,
I do appreciate
your concern for me.
But this story of the hound,
it's nonsense.
As for that silly letter
and all the rest of it,
I'm sure it can all quite
easily be explained.
I quite agree with you,
Sir Henry.
All the same, if you don't mind,
I'd like to ask Dr. Watson
to go down with you.
- What's that?
- If you don't mind, Watson.
- Gladly, if you care to come?
- Of course, I'll be delighted.
- Good.
- Oh, thank you, thank you, Dr. Watson.
And thank you, sir.
Then we'll stalk
the hound together.
Don't take it too lightly,
Sir Henry.
- Well, I must be going.
- Mr. Holmes?
Yes, Dr. Mortimer.
About that per7son calling
himself "Sherlock Holmes"?
Very interesting, Dr. Mortimer.
- You would, um...
- Keep me posted, Watson, write me daily reports.
- To the smallest detail, Holmes.
- Fine.
I give him into your care,
Sir Henry. Guard him well.
Good night.
Guard me well? I like that.
Here we are, Sir Henry,
on famous Dartmoor,
and what a history it has.
You see those rocks over there.
Actually they're stone houses
built by Neolithic man,
50 or 100,000 years ago.
You don't suppose the
Baskervilles go back that far.
And over there, beyond that
hill, those dark spots.
That's the Great Grimpen Mire,
as treacherous a molass
as exists anywhere.
Thousands of lives have been sucked
down into its bottomless depths.
Cheerful little spot.
But fascinating.
Oh, it is, Sir Henry,
and mysterious.
No wonder the people about here
have such odd beliefs.
Some will tell you
that nothing really ever dies
up on the moor.
And after time
one gets to believe it.
Really?
Do you believe that?
Of course not.
If I believed all the legends
about this place,
I wouldn't live here.
I wouldn't have the courage.
And now, if you look,
Baskerville Hall,
the home of your ancestors,
Sir Henry.
- How are you, Barryman?
- Very well, thank you, sir.
Thank you.
This is Barryman, the butler,
Sir Henry, and Mrs. Barryman.
Welcome, Sir Henry,
welcome to Baskerville Hall.
Thank you.
Barryman was with your
uncle most of his life,
as was his father before him.
Well, I hope you'll be
just as happy here with me.
Thank you, Sir Henry.
Baskerville Hall.
And just as it's always been,
Sir Henry,
your uncle did some
modernizing upstairs,
but down here nothing has been added
or taken away since Sir Hugo's time.
Well, I wouldn't say it's the most
cheerful spot I've ever seen.
I beg your pardon, sir.
What time do you wish
dinner served, sir?
Early I think,
Dr. Mortimer has to drive home.
Tell the coachman to have the
carriage ready after dinner.
I'll tell him, sir. And now,
I suppose you'd like to freshen up.
There's hot water
in your room, sir.
- I'll show the way.
- Thank you.
Be careful, sir, these steps
are a bit in need of repair.
I didn't want to startle you.
I thought you might be asleep.
- What is it?
- Come quickly, someone's prowling around.
What are you doing, Barryman?
Oh, nothing, sir,
it was the window.
The window?
Yes, sir, I was just seeing
that it was fastened.
Well, does it matter
whether it's fastened or not,
the window on the second floor?
I go around every night,
seeing that they're fastened.
Sir Charles always
insisted upon it.
Well, that sounds
reasonable enough.
Well, if it's properly fastened now,
Barryman, you can get back to bed.
Yes, sir, thank you.
Do you see anything?
Nothing.
Nothing except
a pinpoint of light
a long way off,
over there by the crags.
Well, keep your eye
on that point of light,
and tell me what happens.
Do you see anything now?
It's gone now.
There it is again,
and there it goes.
Just as I thought.
Barryman was signalling someone.
Come on, get some clothes.
We'll find out.
It's still there.
Yes.
Try not to lose sight of it.
Crouch down here,
whoever it is may come back.
What about getting a little
further away from that light?
Up there.
Good idea.
Stop!
Are you mad?
Whoever it is knows his way
among these rocks, we don't.
Who the devil can it be?
You were right about Barryman.
Yes, but what connection
can there possibly be
between that horrible creature
and Barryman?
You know, I have half a mind to
fire the fellow in the morning,
then notify the police
and let them shadow him.
No, it's the last thing that
Holmes would want us to do.
Our job is to watch Barryman,
watch him like a hawk.
Come on, let's get back.
What, what do you think it is?
What does it sound like to you?
Well, if we were back in London,
this would seem ridiculous.
Let's get on.
Look here, Doctor,
you don't believe that
nonsense, do you?
Of course not,
no more than you do.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Sir Henry.
So that's our famous moor, huh?
Yes, sir.
Come in.
Where's Sir Henry?
He went out, sir.
Where?
Across the moor.
Didn't I tell you to
let me know immediately
if Sir Henry ever
ventured out there alone?
I know, but I only just
found out from my wife.
Hello there!
Oh, forgive my shouting at you,
Dr. Watson.
My name's Stapleton,
live just across the moor.
But how did you know
my name, sir?
- Oh, from Dr. Mortimer, one of our neighbours.
- Oh, yes, sir.
How is Sir Henry?
He's very well, thank you.
We were a bit worried he might
decide not to come here.
After the rumours that followed
the sad death of Sir Charles,
has Mr. Sherlock Holmes
come to any conclusion yet?
I really can't say.
Well, is he going to honour us
with a visit?
I haven't the slightest idea.
But if I can be of any help,
I do hope you'll call upon me.
I know this place pretty well.
Thank you, but I don't think
I shall be needing any help.
Wonderful place, this moor.
From a scientist point of view,
there's nothing like it.
Vast, barren, mysterious.
You see those
bright green spots over there?
Seems a little more fertile
than the rest.
"Fertile."
That's the Great Grimpen Mire.
One false step means death.
Only yesterday one of the
moor ponies wandered into it.
It turned me sick with horror
to see it struggling.
And the sound of its screams-
What's that?
Oh, that.
Well, the people around here
say it's the hound.
Surely you don't
believe such rut.
Bogs make queer noises, or
perhaps it's a bittern booming.
A bittern?
Yes, it's a very rare bird,
practically extinct,
if anything is extinct
on the moor.
Stop, stop!
Look out, stop!
That was a voice.
A woman's voice!
Thank heavens, you heard me!
Another few yards
you'd have been into that mire.
Looks innocent, doesn't it?
But only yesterday
a little moor pony got into it,
and that was the end of it.
Well, thank you
for shouting at me.
- Your Sir Henry?
- Yes.
I suppose I should say welcome,
Sir Henry,
but I'm afraid
it wouldn't be sincere.
Oh, that's understandable.
A stranger coming here and taking the
place of someone you were fond of.
Oh, it's not that, I...
No, Tell me what is it?
Sounds silly, I know, but...
Oh, it's not that
ridiculous hound legend?
I never used to believe those things
till I came to live down here.
But you do now.
You're rich.
You can go anywhere you want to.
There are so many other places
to live in the world,
interesting places.
Just now, I find this place
very interesting.
- Why hello, Beryl.
- Hello.
- Oh, Dr. Watson, my stepsister Miss Stapleton.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
Hello, Doctor.
- And this, I'm sure must be...
- Oh, Sir Henry, my brother.
- How are you?
- I was just telling Dr. Watson
how delighted we are
you decided to come here.
I'm here, and to stay.
Oh, that's splendid.
You know, it's been quite dull around
here since the Hall's been closed.
It's wide open now, especially
to friends of my uncle.
You must both come
and dine with me.
You must come to us first.
Yes, what about tomorrow night,
you and Dr. Watson?
We'll invite the neighbours
over to meet you.
Of course, you already know
Dr. Mortimer.
The only other one's
old Mr. Frankland.
Who's he?
Wait till you meet him,
Sir Henry.
He'll bring suit against you,
I warn you.
- What on earth for?
- He'll find something.
Suing people
is a passion with him.
I'll look forward
to meeting him.
- All right, tomorrow night then.
- Thank you.
And thank you again
for rescuing me.
- Good-bye.
And were it not a personal
insult to Sir Henry.
I would have never have
come here this evening.
Oh, but why, Mr. Frankland?
As a stickler for convention.
I'm not in the habit of
breaking bread with my host
on the eve of prosecuting him.
Great heavens, what crime
have I committed now?
A most gruesome one,
Mr. Stapleton,
that of body snatching.
What?
You're a body snatcher, sir,
a ghoul, a despoiler of graves!
Oh, come, come, Mr. Frankland,
that's a very serious charge.
Oh, Beryl, refill Mr. Frankland's
glass, will you.
Thank you, my dear.
And an excellent
vintage it is too.
- But if you're implying that I'm tipsy, sir!
- Oh, of course he's not.
Tell us more, Mr. Frankland.
Whose body has Mr. Stapleton
been snatching?
According to my evidence, sir,
Mr. Stapleton was seen digging among
the old stone huts in the moor,
and removed from there a skull.
Oh, that!
A most interesting relic,
Sir Henry, of Neolithic man.
I'll show it to you
after dinner.
50,000 years old if it's a day.
Nonetheless, sir,
you removed it from the grave
without the consent
of the next of kin,
and according to British law,
that constitutes body snatching.
Deny that if you can.
But what good will it do you
to prosecute Mr. Stapleton?
None sir, I have no interest
in the matter.
I act entirely from
a sense of public duty.
If you care to drop by my house someday
and take a tippler of wine with me,
I'll be glad to tell you a thing
or two about everybody here.
About him, prowling the
Grimpen Mire at night,
and why he takes her with him.
Oh, there's no secret about us.
As you know,
I dabble a bit in the occult.
Mrs. Mortimer has very strong
mediumistic qualities.
She finds the old caves
in the moor
particularly conducive
to psychic phenomena.
Very interesting.
Have you ever tried to communicate
with my uncle since his death?
Oh yes, on several occasions,
but with no success.
But if my wife would consent
to a seance tonight
while you, Sir Henry,
are present, we might...
No, no, James,
not tonight, please.
Perhaps some other time.
Shall we have coffee
in the drawing room?
If you and Dr. Watson would care
to see my little collection.
- Oh, yes, the skulls.
- Yes, they're in here.
Yes, I would like to very much.
Quite a museum.
Oh, a very modest
little collection.
But this one really is
quite a treasure.
You'll observe its
unusual cranial index.
Gentleman, gentleman,
my wife has consented!
She's agreed to a seance!
- Splendid.
- Oh, fine.
Please come at once!
Now, then, if you'll all get chairs
and arrange yourselves naturally,
comfortably here by the fire.
As Shakespeare says,
"You can call spirits
from the vastly deep,
but will they answer?"
They won't answer
scoffers are sceptics!
If that's your attitude,
Mr. Frankland,
perhaps you wouldn't
mind leaving us.
I'm sure Mr. Frankland
didn't mean to doubt.
Of course I doubt,
and I ask you to keep a civil
tongue in your head, Dr. Mortimer.
Ordering me out
from under the roof of my host
is grounds for a
very nasty little lawsuit!
Oh, come now, Mr. Frankland,
sit down by me.
Now, tonight we may communicate
with Sir Charles,
find out what he
feared so greatly,
what he was running away from.
Now, Jennifer,
you sit here, please.
Sir Henry, here.
- Would you please put out those lights?
- Certainly.
Stapleton, that light please.
Dr. Watson.
Now, would you all keep quiet,
and sit quite naturally.
Sir Henry, your hand, please?
Sir Charles,
can you speak to us?
Let us know if you're present.
There are things
that only you can explain.
Speak to us, Sir Charles,
if you're here.
There are things that
only you can tell us.
Sir Charles,
can you speak to us?
Let us know if you're present.
There are things
that only you can tell us.
Speak to us, Sir Charles,
if you're here.
There are things
that only you can explain.
That sound.
I've heard it before.
It's nothing,
nothing but the wind.
Or a bittern.
I was telling Dr. Watson
only yesterday about it.
Sir Charles,
what happened that night?
What was it you feared?
Tell us, Sir Charles, of all
the weird, terrible things
that have happened on the moor?
Listen. There it is again.
Oh, I can't stand it. Would
somebody put on the lights, please?
I tell you it's nothing,
nothing but the wind.
Mr. Frankland,
what did you think it was?
The hound, of course,
the hound of the Baskervilles.
Any fool would know that!
James, get my cape,
take me home.
Very well, my dear.
Dr. Watson, can I give you
and Sir Henry a lift?
No, thank you,
we have our own carriage.
You're trembling.
That wasn't the wind we heard.
I've heard that sound
before, often.
That's what I tried to tell you
yesterday on the moor.
That's why I wish
you hadn't come here.
But sounds can't hurt you.
It doesn't matter what they are
or where they come from.
You don't know.
Oh, you've got to get all that
nonsense out of your head, Beryl.
- I wish I could.
- You're going to.
I'm going to make it my
business to see that you do.
You've been alone too much.
There's nothing to do down here.
That's the trouble.
I'm going to change all that,
if you let me.
We'll go fishing together, riding.
Do you like riding?
Yes, I do.
Good, we'll start tomorrow,
shall we?
Yes, thanks.
Fine, I'll ride over for you
in the morning.
- Are you coming, Sir Henry?
- Right, Doctor.
- Good night.
Hello.
Hello, Beryl.
Well, where shall we go today?
- There's one place we haven't been, High Tor.
- Fine.
That's where all
the old ruins are.
You know, Jack says that
they're over 50,000 years old.
That sounds interesting.
And you can still see the
remains of their stone huts.
All right, good.
Those platter stones over there,
they're graves.
Oh, and those huge ones, monoliths,
the remains of their temples.
Doesn't anybody know who they
were or what they looked like?
Jack has a theory about them.
But anyway, they must have
been very primitive
living on roots
and dressing in skins.
But still laughing and
dreaming, just as we do.
I wonder how many times
some young savage
brought his bride
into this very hut.
Said, take your hat off,
darling, this is home!
You know, this is probably where
she cooked his first meal for him.
And what a yell he must have
let out when she burnt it up.
And now they're quite forgotten.
Just as we will be too, one day.
Do you suppose when a man
met a girl that he liked,
he had to wait
a respectably long time
before he dared tell her,
or things like that,
sudden, natural?
I'd like to think that
things were like that.
Beryl, that's the way
they are with me.
Oh, oh, but we've only known each
other for such a little while.
There, you see,
convention, custom!
We can't even be ourselves
when we want to be.
Why is that?
You know, I used to come
down here quite often
and explore these old caves when
Jack and I first came to live here.
I didn't have a fear
of the moor then.
And you've none now
that's all gone.
When I'm with you, it's gone.
I seem to forget it,
laughing and talking.
When I'm alone
it all comes back to me.
And at night
I still wake up trembling,
as if in my sleep
I can hear those awful noises.
Then it gets bad as ever, and
- oh, I think of you and I wish you weren't here.
- Oh, don't say that.
Well, I wish you were in London
or in Canada.
But even if I wanted to go back
to London or Canada, I couldn't.
Why not?
You know why. You must know why.
I can't go anywhere now,
unless you come with me.
Oh, Henry.
Oh.
Would you mind
pausing for a minute?
I'm afraid I've lost my way.
Hello, Doctor.
Sir Henry and I were just...
We were... We were...
- We were getting engaged.
- Engaged! Splendid.
- May I congratulate you both?
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Who is that?
It seems that we didn't pick
a very secluded spot.
What do you want?
Just crossing the moor, sir.
Just crossing the moor.
I... I be peddling my wares, sir.
I must have something here
what interests you, sir.
How about... how about
a nice mouth organ, sir?
No, thank you.
Here, here's something an old
squire like you could use, sir,
a fusel,
a fusel for calling
your sheep dog.
- Calling my what?
- Sheep dog, sir.
A regular charmer, sir.
Hear it for miles around, sir.
Take it away,
and yourself with it!
How, how about, how about
some scent for the lady, sir?
That'll do.
Be off about your business.
All right, all right, sir,
I ain't doing no harm.
You know, that's what
I hate about this moor.
There's always
something strange.
Look, he's limping
on the other foot now.
Barryman?
Yes, sir.
Who delivered this note?
No one, sir. I found it
slipped under the front door.
Thank you.
Oh, Barryman,
is Sir Henry at home?
No, sir.
He's gone across the moor.
Hmm, sorry I missed him.
Did Dr. Watson go with him?
No, sir.
Oh, thank you, Barryman.
- I'll tell Sir Henry you called, sir.
- Yes, do.
Was it you who sent
me that communication?
I did, sir!
Out with it, whatever it is
you want me to hear!
I only want you to hear
this zither, sir.
Zither?
They don't come no finer, sir.
What blasted impertinence!
Getting me out here to see...
Look here my man,
you're up to something!
I... I only ask you to try 'em, sir!
Be careful, the things loaded!
Who are you?
Well, I might ask
the same of you, sir,
travelling around the moor,
spying out on everybody.
That's my business, to spy.
Oh, oh, it is, is it?
Yes, and if you want to know
who I am, I'll tell you.
Who... who are ye?
I'm Sherlock Holmes.
Sherlock Holmes, the detective?
Yes, and now perhaps you realize
why I can't be hoodwinked.
Oh, sir, sir, sir,
that changes everything.
Now, who are you? Quick!
Well, in that case, sir,
my name must be Watson.
Ha, ha, ha.
- Holmes!
- How are you, my dear fellow?
A fine detective you are,
calling yourself Sherlock Holmes!
So you've been down here
on the moor all the time!
That's a fine way
to treat me, I must say!
Send me down here, let me think
you were in London,
working on that Blackman case,
make me sit up half the night
writing those blasted reports!
Superior reports my dear Watson,
and very valuable they were, too.
I made arrangements to have
them forwarded on to me.
A shabby trick
which I'll not forget.
Ah, but a very necessary trick.
If I'd come down here
with you and Sir Henry,
every movement of mine
would have been watched.
Why, in this way, only you and
Sir Henry have been watched,
and I've been free to work.
That's all very well,
but making a fool of me.
Sit down, Watson, do sit down.
Perhaps a little supper will
help you to get over your huff.
Huff, I'm in no huff!
Here,
try some of these sardines.
It's a pity
I didn't know you were coming,
I'd have provided a
braise of pheasant.
It's a pity you didn't think of
bringing that inferno violin of yours,
to regale me with some
of your enchanting music.
I did, my dear Watson.
Anything to oblige.
Well, if you've had enough to eat, Watson,
and you're feeling in better spirits,
I think we better
be getting along.
Getting along where,
if I'm not prying?
I'm returning with you
to Baskerville Hall.
There are still some gaps
to be filled in,
but all in all, things are
becoming a little clearer.
Not to me, I assure you.
It's still a hopeless jumble.
Mr. Frankland, Dr. Mortimer,
the Barrymans,
put it all together
and what have you got?
Murder, my dear Watson,
refined, cold-blooded murder.
Murder?
There's no doubt about it
in my mind.
Or, perhaps I should say
in my imagination.
But that's where crimes are
conceived and where they're solved,
in the imagination.
But there's been no murder,
unless you mean Sir Charles.
And the facts clearly indicated
that he died from heart failure.
That's why so many
murders remain unsolved.
People will stick to facts
even though they prove nothing.
Now, if we go beyond facts,
use our imagination
as to criminal does,
imagine what might have
happened and act upon it,
as I've been trying to do
in this case,
we usually find
ourselves justified.
- Then you know?
- Another day or two at the most, and I will know.
My one fear is that the murder
will strike before we're ready.
In that case...
What's that?
Where's it coming from?
- There.
- No, no, no there!
The hound.
Come on Watson, quick!
Look!
Sir Henry!
He must have run along that
bridge and fallen over the cliff.
He's dead.
His skull is crushed in.
The convict! Thank heaven!
What?
That's the man I shot at
the night we arrived,
the man Barryman
was signalling to.
Who is it?
The Notting Hill murderer.
He escaped from prison
last month
and hiding on the
moor ever since.
The Notting Hill murderer?
Do you mean that he's
responsible for all this?
That remains to be seen.
But he's wearing
Sir Henry's clothes.
Yes, yes, that accounts for it.
- Accounts for what?
- For the hound.
These clothes were the cause
of that poor devil's death.
Do you mean that the hound
was after Sir Henry?
Yes, and mistook the convict for him
because of the scent of the clothes.
Do you remember that
missing boot, Watson?
Why do you suppose
the brown one,
the one that had
never been worn,
was so mysteriously replaced
and the black one taken?
- Why?
- Because a boot that had never been worn
wouldn't have had the scent of
the owner, and the black one had.
But how does this convict come to
be wearing Sir Henry's clothes?
Oh, well, that's simple enough.
Why, Dr. Watson!
Is somebody hurt? Who's this?
The convict who
escaped from Princeton.
Oh, how terrible.
I heard a cry, that's what
brought me over here.
What's your theory about it,
Mr. Holmes?
You're quick at identification.
Oh, everybody knows you, sir.
As a matter of fact, we've
been expecting you down here.
- My name's Stapleton.
- How do you do?
You came in time
to see a tragedy.
Yes, it's a most unpleasant
remembrance for me
to take back to London tomorrow.
But must you go so soon?
I've been looking forward
to meeting you.
Yes, yes, I'm afraid I must.
We've been hoping, Mr. Holmes, that
you may be able to shed some light
on the occurrences that
have puzzled us down here.
Yes, but an investigator needs something
more than legends and rumours.
Oh, quite so.
Give me a hand, will you,
Watson.
We better put this poor fellow in
one of the huts till the morning.
Let me give you a hand.
Oh, I think we can manage
all right, thank you.
Where's Sir Henry, Barryman?
In the library, sir.
Oh, Barryman,
if your wife's still up,
will you tell her Mr. Sherlock
Holmes would like a word with her?
- Sherlock Holmes?
- Yes.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Sir Henry.
Holmes.
Oh, I'm glad to see you
so well, Sir Henry.
- Why didn't you tell me Mr. Holmes was coming?
- Well, I'm...
Oh, he didn't know. We ran across
each other in the village.
I am glad to see you.
What is it, Barryman?
Oh, I asked to see Mrs. Barryman,
if you don't mind, Sir Henry?
Of course not.
Come in, Mrs. Barryman.
I think you better sit down.
Thank you, sir,
I prefer to stand.
I'm afraid I have some
rather bad news for you.
What is it?
Well, it's going to be
a bit of a shock.
Oh, they've caught him.
Your, your brother...
They'll hang him for sure.
No, Mrs. Barryman,
he's beyond the law now.
He's in more merciful hands.
We came across the poor fellow
as we were crossing the moor.
He must have missed his footing
and fallen over the cliff.
No further need, Barryman, to
signal to him from the window
or take food out to him or
give him Sir Henry's
discarded clothes.
I'm sorry, Sir Henry.
It is all my doing?
Barryman here
wanted to tell you all along
so as you could notify
the police.
It was he was my kin,
my own kin,
even though he wasn't
never any good.
We understand.
You won't hold it against
Barryman will you, sir?
Of course not.
Now, take her along,
see that she's all right.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, Sir Henry.
Well, it's nice to get that end
cleared up,
for their sake as well as mine.
It clears up everything,
I think, Sir Henry.
That poor devil must have been
completely demented.
And that accounts for those
dreadful noises
- that we've been hearing from time to time.
- Exactly.
Your troubles are over,
Sir Henry.
I really am most grateful,
Mr. Holmes.
Oh, not at all,
I've done little enough.
But you can sleep peacefully
in your bed now
and commence to lead the life
of a happy country squire.
Well, not for a little bit,
I'm afraid.
- I'm off to Canada again.
- Canada?
Beryl, Miss Stapleton and I,
are going to be married.
Miss Stapleton?
A very charming young lady.
Congratulations.
Everything's arranged.
Her brother's giving us a
farewell party tomorrow night.
We'll be married in London
the following day,
and then off for a honeymoon
to Canada.
- My congratulations, too, Sir Henry.
- Thanks.
What luck you're here.
You and Dr. Watson
will be with us tomorrow night!
No, I'm sorry, I...
I'm afraid I can't.
I must hurry back to London,
and so should you too, Watson.
We'll have to report to the police here
about that convict in the morning,
but there's a train leaving
early in the afternoon.
Oh, what a pity! Beryl will be
dreadfully disappointed.
Now, we'll remedy that
when you come up to London.
You must...
You must dine with us
before you sail.
Well, there's the old boy
himself, Sir Hugo.
Hugo,
the Beast of the Baskervilles.
Not a bad bit of brushwork, by
Ransom, one of the minor painters.
Oh, I don't imagine
it's very valuable.
I can't quite agree with you,
Sir Henry.
One day it might prove
to be of the greatest value.
Well, we must be going.
There's still one or two
little points, Holmes,
and I can't for the life of me
reconcile with your theory,
about that poor demented convict.
One or two little points?
Surely you can't mean that he
was in London three weeks ago,
sent that letter,
stole that boot?
- Of course not.
- Then who the devil did?
The same person that was responsible for
the death of that convict last night
- and will try again to murder Sir Henry tonight.
- Tonight?
Unless my imagination has run away with
itself, and I don't think that it has.
Then why are we
rushing up to London,
leaving Sir Henry
entirely unprotected?
We're not, my dear Watson,
we're just giving the impression
of rushing up to London.
In a minute and a half
we'll be in Oak Hampton,
there we'll catch a train
back to Dartmouth,
and if my surmise is correct,
we'll nab our man in the act.
But if you know who it is, why
all this roundabout rigmarole?
- Why don't you have him arrested?
- Because I have no case,
not a shred of evidence
that would hold in any court.
The only way is to
catch him red-handed,
to catch him in such a way that
there's no escape, no alibi.
- And that means gambling with Sir Henry's life.
- But you can't...
Gambling to save his life.
But we've got to take
that chance.
Otherwise, the shadow of sudden death
will be forever hanging over his head
and sooner or later...
Here we are, Oak Hampton.
And may you both spend the
rest of your years together
- in happy contentment.
- Here, here.
- Thank you.
And now, I want to thank you all for the
kindness that you've shown a stranger.
And when Beryl and I return,
I want you to know that you'll always
be welcome at Baskerville Hall.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, Sir Henry.
It's going to be lonely for you,
Mr. Stapleton, with Beryl gone.
Yes, indeed it will,
Mrs. Mortimer.
I shall be more dependent than
ever upon you, my neighbours.
Don't count upon me, sir.
In my opinion
you're a body snatcher.
And until the courts
have decreed otherwise,
I want nothing whatsoever
to do with you!
Oh, Mr. Frankland.
I say, driver,
can't you go a little faster?
I'm doing the best I can, sir.
You idiot!
We said go faster,
not break our necks.
How fast is it
to Baskerville Hall?
It's five miles by road, sir,
but if you want to
cut over the moor,
- it's only about three.
- Here you are.
- Come on Watson, quick!
- Thank you, sir.
It's been a wonderful evening,
Stapleton.
- Oh, glad you could be with us, Mortimer.
- Thank you.
Take this brooch, my dear, and
wear it on your wedding dress.
It belonged to my
great grandmother.
Something old, something new.
You know.
Oh, that's so sweet of you,
Mrs. Mortimer.
Thank you so much.
And come back to us soon,
both of you.
We will.
May I offer you a lift, my lad?
It's such a beautiful night, Mr. Frankland,
I think I'll walk, thank you.
Merely a gesture of hospitality.
Reject it if you like.
Get up, there!
You're not going to cross
the moor alone, Sir Henry?
Why not? There's nothing
to fear any more?
We can't be sure.
Oh, but I have Mr. Sherlock Holmes'
own word for it.
Come along, James.
- Good night, Sir Henry.
- Good night, Mrs. Mortimer.
- And the best of luck to you both.
- Thank you.
- Good night.
I wish you'd let Mr. Frankland
drive you home.
I wanted to stay
and say goodnight to you.
This is our last goodnight.
From tomorrow on
there won't be any more, ever.
Tomorrow we'll be away
from this place.
I wish it were now.
So do I.
Oh now, don't be silly.
- Good night, Beryl.
- Good night, dear.
Well, was it a nice party?
Wonderful, everything,
and most of all you.
Jack, I hadn't said very much
about going away,
- but you know how I feel.
- Yes, of course, it had to be.
You won't be too
dreadfully lonely, will you?
No, I shall have my work...
Henry and I will be back
before you even know it.
Yes, of course you will.
Well, you better go to bed now.
You've got a big day
ahead of you tomorrow.
- Good night, Jack.
- Good night, dear.
Over there!
We'll head him off!
Jack!
Where are you?
He's coming to.
You'll be all right, old man.
- Watson.
- Yes, old chap.
- Mr. Holmes?
- Yes.
What, what, what was it?
We've got to get him home,
quickly!
- Can you manage him alone?
- Yes.
Because I've got things to do.
Help get his arm
around my shoulder.
I'm all right.
It's pretty painful, I know,
but it won't take much longer.
Go on, it doesn't hurt.
Now, Mrs. Barryman,
some gauze, please.
I just heard the dreadful news.
Thank heavens, you're safe.
Is he all right?
Well, now we know for certain
that this is no legend, no myth.
There really is a hound.
- Was a hound.
- Yes, Mr. Holmes told me.
I ran into him across the moor.
He asked me to
send you to him at once.
It's a matter of
great importance.
He said he'd wait for you at the spot
where the... the beast was killed.
I must finish here first.
This poor boy
has taken a terrific beating.
Well, I could carry on
for you, Doctor.
I'm a bit of a doctor myself,
you know.
Do you think you could manage?
Yes, I'm sure I could.
I think you really ought to go,
Dr. Watson.
Mr. Holmes was most urgent.
Oh, really?
I shall need some hot water,
Mrs. Barryman.
- Oh, I want it boiling, please.
- Yes, sir.
It must have been a terrifying
experience, Sir Henry, terrifying.
It was, it was indeed.
Yes, I can see you're still
weak from loss of blood.
I can't say I feel any too well.
Here, drink this, Sir Henry,
you'll feel much stronger.
I'll see to your other
bandages after.
Oh, it may taste a little
bitter, but don't mind that.
Sir Henry!
Well, feeling better?
Yes, thanks.
I say, that's uncomfortably
close to your eye, isn't it?
Along this side?
Well, well, well.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry,
that was clumsy of me.
It was only a bit of a tonic.
- Sir Henry's lost considerable blood.
- Yes?
Henry?
Henry.
- I'm all right, darling.
- Oh, no you're not.
We heard those dreadful noises
on the way home.
It's a mercy he's alive.
I owe you an apology, Sir Henry,
for jeopardizing your life.
Jeopardizing?
But you saved my life.
But there was no possible way
for me to foretell the final.
And I must apologize too,
for deceiving you last night.
When I told you that
your troubles were over,
I knew that they weren't.
But if I hadn't cleared out,
the crisis, which came tonight,
would have been
indefinitely postponed
with a shadow of death
hanging over you.
And over you too,
Miss Stapleton.
You knew this was
going to happen?
How could you know?
The person who wanted to snuff
out your life, Sir Henry,
was the same one
who plotted to kill your uncle.
He wanted to get you
both out of the way
so that he could lay claim to this
place, to the whole Baskerville estate.
In tracing back his lineage,
he discovered not only
that he was the next of kin,
but also learned that
old legend about the hound.
So he brought the hound to life
by the simple expedient of buying
the most savage dog he could find
and hiding it here on the moor
until he needed it.
If he had succeeded tonight,
the blame would have fallen
on the legendary monster,
and no possible suspicion would
have been attached to him.
A most ingenious device.
And I'm quite sure that he
would have had no difficulty
in proving his claim to Baskerville
Hall and all that goes with it.
A most amazing instance of a
throwback that I've ever seen.
- And you can see for yourself...
- Stapleton!
One move and I'll shoot!
- Jack!
- You two, stay where you are!
You're under arrest, Stapleton,
for the murder of Sir Charles
Baskerville, the murder of a convict
and the attempted murder
of Sir Henry!
You can't arrest me, Holmes!
Now, one move from any of you and
I'll blast you all to kingdom come!
So sorry, old boy!
What's the matter, old man?
What's the matter?
That's our man.
Stapleton, a murderer?
He won't get very far.
I posted constables on both the
roads, and the only other way
is across the Grimpen Mire.
I'm so sorry, Miss Stapleton,
I wish I could have
spared you this.
Well, that officially closes
the case, Sir Henry,
and a very interesting case
for your annals, Watson.
An ordinary dog
and an ingenious criminal.
And a more ingenious detective.
I owe you a tremendous debt
of gratitude.
We all do, Sir Henry.
Mr. Holmes, we've admired you in
the past, as does every Englishman.
Your record as our greatest detective
is known throughout the world,
but this, seeing how you work,
knowing that there is in
England such a man as you,
it gives us all a sense
of safety and security.
God bless you, Mr. Holmes.
Thank you, Dr. Mortimer,
thank you.
And now, if you don't mind, I've
had rather a strenuous day.
- I think I'll turn in.
- Of course.
- Good night.
- Good night, Mr. Holmes.
Oh, Watson, the needle.