Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext
Look here, look here.
Look carefully.
Look, look.
Get a good look.
Here we go.
Place your bets!
There's a hidden tile!
Hey you!
- Mind your own business!
- Get lost!
My name's Jin Hu.
Staying at Arashiyama Taniguchi Hotel.
If you want more of me,
find me there.
CHINESE NOODLES
Thank you.
Hey, hey!
Wait, you haven't paid
for your noodles.
Dammit! We have to pay?
- Why did you hit me?
- Stop!
Why didn't you pay for your noodles?
I'm Jin Hu. I'm Chinese.
C'mon, baby.
Dinner's on me, ok?
- My treat, ok?
- Let's go together.
Wait, wait!
Come on.
My name's Jin Hu.
Staying at Arashiyama Taniguchi Hotel.
Do you know
what it means to wander?
what it means to be lost?
When you look around
and see no horizon found,
then you'll know
what it means to be lost.
Do you know what desolation is?
Do you know what sadness is?
When your tears dried up
and your heart is down,
then you'll know
what desolation is.
I used to only know happiness.
I used to have so much hope.
But since I lost you,
then I knew what sadness was.
Do you know what sorrow is?
Do you know what disappointment is?
When you've lost your love
and he's forever gone,
then you'll know what sorrow is.
When you've lost your love
and he's forever gone,
then you'll know what sorrow is.
- Excuse me, have you seen this man?
- I'm sorry, no.
- Have you seen him?
- No.
- Excuse me, sir. You've seen this man?
And you, sir?
You're the only one who didn't clap.
Didn't like her singing?
How about another drink?
I don't have enough cash on me.
That's fine. It's on me.
No, thanks.
I don't want to owe you.
I'm sorry.
I only have enough money
for my drink.
It's ok.
Excuse me, have you seen this man?
Who is he to you?
He's my father.
No, I haven't.
Did you like my song?
It was too sad.
You're too young for that.
Then I'll sing a happy number
for you, ok?
I've already told you.
I'm out of money.
It doesn't matter.
As long as you like it
then I'm happy.
Farewell sadness, bye bye.
Farewell sorrow, bye bye.
From now on,
I'll always be smiling
because I have your...
Stop singing!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
We can talk this over.
What's your name?
My name is Yoshida Ayako.
Don't you know the rules?
What rules?
If you want to sing here,
it's 5,000 yen per day.
5,000 yen?
I don't have that kind of money.
Boss, go easy on her.
She's just a girl
looking for her father.
She just arrived from Hokkaido
and didn't have the time to...
Don't. He's Shimizu's top fighter,
Shigeo Hayashi.
Hmm... so you don't have money?
Hey, you got quite a lot here!
Please, I beg you.
Don't take my money!
- Get out of the way!
- I'm begging you!
A bunch of tough guys
bullying a poor little girl.
What gives?
You lecturing me?
I'm warning you.
I'm Jin Hu.
I'm Chinese.
Staying at Arashiyama Taniguchi Hotel.
You better get all that down.
I'll take you home.
You did the right thing.
Where are you staying?
- The same place as you.
- Really?
I'm also staying at
Arashiyama Taniguchi Hotel.
How did you know
I was staying there?
You forgot?
You just said it yourself.
My father
used to come back every year.
But recently,
there's been no sign of him.
So mother and I
came looking for him.
Your father must love you very much.
Yes. I'm his only daughter.
I'm his most precious.
Mother and I came here
from Hokkaido.
But we haven't found
any trace of him.
And you're making a living
by singing?
I've been very lucky.
Everyone's been liking my singing.
You do sing very well.
Be careful!
Climb up!
Stop fighting!
- Miss Zhang.
- What is it?
That guy hit our leader, Hayashi.
He's my tenant.
Any problems,
tell Shigeo Hayashi to find me.
Yes.
Alright, the fight's over.
We're going back. Let's go!
Mr Jin.
Care for a lift?
Thank you.
Don't let your mother know
what happened tonight.
It'll make her old heart worry.
My mother's actually quite young.
She's only 36 years old.
Sorry. I thought mothers
were all old ladies.
Goodbye.
Madam... see you tomorrow
You've got some real skills there.
That singer just arrived
and she's already hooked.
No man's ever impressed me before.
Except for poor you.
I'm warning you.
Don't get any big ideas.
Since you already know everything,
you can stop bothering me.
Mr Jin.
A man should have a heart.
You're Chinese too
so I lowered the rent.
That's on you. I owe you nothing.
At least I've treated you so well.
Don't get too close to me.
If I had money, I'd buy you for a night.
I'm not that kind of person!
Even if you had the money,
money can't buy me!
You certainly look the part.
Why else would you
be so thick-skinned?
Fine, I won't be going then.
And why not?
You just said I looked the part.
Then I'll show you!
I've already told you.
I have no money.
You can buy now
and pay later.
Get the hell out!
You!
Madam!
What is it?
Someone's here to see you.
Tell them I'm not here!
It's one of Shimizu's men.
Where is he?
In your room.
I knew you'd come.
I didn't expect you'd be so fast.
How about that Chinese guy?
Where did you hide him?
I know he offended you.
You want to get back at him?
He didn't offend me
in the slightest.
But he is a troublemaker.
Can you give me some face?
Don't make it hard on him.
It's not up to me anymore.
Mr Shimizu wants to see him.
Mr Shimizu?
Young man, you shouldn't be so stubborn.
Fists can't beat guns.
You have some skills there.
Better the devil you know
than the devil you don't know.
I see true value in you.
Think about it,
isn't all this goofing around
just wasting your time?
What should I do about it, then?
Join my organisation.
We'll rule the world.
What? As one of your henchmen?
I said I value you.
I want you to be my right-hand man.
And run my entertainment line.
Everything you need,
you got it.
Sounds good, I'm in!
From now on,
you'll be my right-hand man.
You can command anyone
including Shigeo Hayashi.
Remember,
our biggest enemy is Yamamoto.
They stole a lot of
business from me.
I hope you can win it back.
Bring the business back here.
I'll do my best.
Also, Miss Zhang now belongs to you.
Thank you, Mr Shimizu.
- Can I refuse?
- No way.
How could my right-hand man
lack a pretty lady by his side?
You should do
as Mr Shimizu says.
Is this taking care of me
or monitoring me?
It can be both.
Wait.
From now on, you can't collect
their money anymore.
What?
Where's your manager?
Boss!
Sir, what would you like to drink?
We're not drinking.
Your deadline was yesterday.
Why haven't you pay us yet?
Sorry, I can't give you
the money anymore.
Why not?
Who's your boss?
I'm Yamamoto's man,
Sano Taro.
I'm Jin Hu.
Go and tell Yamamoto
this place belongs to Shimizu now.
Scram.
Jin Hu, you're incredible.
I don't see you for a few days,
and now you're the top dog.
Where you've been recently?
My mother was sick.
Did you find your father?
No, not yet.
Can I sing here today?
You're welcome to.
But you should ask Mr Jin.
Mr Jin Hu?
He's Mr Shimizu's right-hand man.
You must be surprised.
Mr Jin, will you let me sing here?
Yes, not just here.
Anywhere that belongs to Shimizu.
Really?
But a fee is required
according to the rules.
100 yen a day.
Only that much?
I can afford it.
Chief.
Come, sit!
Have a drink.
Thank you.
I don't have the time.
What's the matter?
There's something
that requires your help.
No need to be so polite.
There's a Chinese restaurant
that won't pay up.
You need to bother me with that?
This restaurant's run by Chinese.
Doesn't matter who it is,
the same rules apply.
The owner's son's an expert
in Chinese martial arts.
He's a good fighter
and not easy to handle.
Hope you can personally handle it.
What do the rules say?
A warning. Then break up the place.
Let's go.
Strange.
How did Mr Jin become like this?
Society changed him.
Jin Hu, when did
you come back to Japan?
I'm here to collect
for Mr Shimizu.
You?
Why won't you pay UP?
Business is bad.
My father's ill.
Dammit!
You always have excuses!
What do you want?
What do we want?
Give us the money!
I don't have it now.
By the rules, deal with him.
Chief.
Jin Hu,
why are you doing this?
I don't need help from others.
According to the rules,
first a warning, no one dies.
If you don't pay up tomorrow,
I'll tear your place apart.
Let's go.
Farewell sadness, bye bye.
Farewell misery, bye bye.
From now on
my heart will blossom
because I have your love.
Farewell loneliness, bye bye.
Farewell pain, bye bye.
From now on
my heart will blossom
because I have your love.
The splendour of love
has brought me happiness.
The fire of love
has pushed away
the sorrow in my heart.
Farewell loneliness, bye bye.
Farewell pain, bye bye.
From now on
my heart will blossom
because I have your love.
The splendour of love
has brought me happiness.
The warmth of love
has pushed away
the sorrow in my heart.
Farewell loneliness, bye bye.
Farewell pain, bye bye.
From now on
my heart will blossom
because I have your love.
Excuse me, have you seen this man?
Thank you.
Miss Ayako.
Mr Jin.
Please sit.
I'm fine.
Can you finish early tonight?
What is it?
I need you to do something for me.
Alright.
I have 150,000 yen here.
Deliver it to Liu Hanming
at Horikawa Chinese Restaurant.
I just heard you and your men today
attacked his place.
Is this true?
I've sold out my conscience.
I want to buy some of it back.
Don't tell him I sent the money.
And don't tell anyone.
Why ask me to send the money?
Because I trust only you.
I heard from someone
you know that Liu Hanming.
He's my father's student.
What's your father's name?
Jin Keqiang.
You know him?
I've met him.
When he killed himself at Pearl Club,
I was there.
What happened on that day?
I suspect someone cheated him.
Cheated?
Is there evidence?
Evidence?
That'll be hard to find.
He didn't gamble with Yamamoto.
Yet Yamamoto now owns
your family fortune.
So I'm a bit suspicious.
Yamamoto Toshihiko...
I hear your old training school
will become the Yamamoto Amusement Park.
My father never gambled.
When I find out who cheated him,
his life is mine!
If you won't tell me who sent this money,
then I won't accept it.
If I tell you his name,
then you'll accept the money?
It was Mr Jin Hu.
Him?
That swine.
Take the money back.
I want nothing to do with him!
Mr Jin said he felt he wronged you.
I don't need his apology.
Look what he did to my place!
My master was an honourable man.
How could his son be like this?!
Even though he didn't tell me,
I think there's a reason
why he's like this.
I think he's heartless!
If he really was heartless,
why would he ask me
to bring you this money?
He was very sincere.
I'm sure he means well.
Mr Liu, you should take this money.
After you fix the place up,
you can resume your business.
Things will become clear
in the end.
Take it.
- Goodbye.
Miss Ayako, please ask him
to meet me.
I want to ask him myself.
Alright.
I will give him the message.
If I have any news,
I'll give you a call.
Alright.
I'm sorry.
I want to know why you're doing this.
What's really your plan.
And why did you mix up
with those hooligans.
It's on purpose.
I want to take a place among them.
And find out about everything.
Why?
To find out how my father died.
More importantly,
recover the overseas Chinese donations
my father was entrusted with.
They all said master was senseless.
He shouldn't have
gambled away their donations.
You know yourself,
he never gambles.
But master jumped to his death
from the casino building.
How do you explain that?
That's why I can't face anyone,
and it's also why I didn't ask
for your help.
Overseas Chinese compatriots
are good and honest.
What master did,
they chose to put it to rest.
Kind people donated from all around.
This devotion is truly admirable.
It hurts me more to hear that. Truly.
They donated their hard-earned money.
And entrusted it to my father.
Now he's dead for no clear reason.
And the money's gone without a trace.
I don't believe he'd be this senseless.
Something must've happened.
When I tended master's body,
one of his ribs was broken.
It's obvious he fought someone
before his death.
Someone who's definitely
a strong fighter.
I knew something was up.
I must avenge my father.
And get rid of them,
once and for all.
You'll be on your own.
Won't it be too dangerous?
I'll do my best.
The rest is up to fate.
Do you have any leads?
I only know that a Yamamoto Toshihiko
cheated my father.
I want to confront him.
Yamamoto?
I have a friend,
he's one of his henchmen.
He asked me to join them.
I refused every time.
I can join them
and help you investigate.
My hands are already dirty.
I won't drag you into this.
As long as our intentions are just,
who cares what happens,
why must we fight?
The hell's this?
You called me?
I heard you found a fat sheep.
He came to me himself.
I won't ask how.
I just want you to be honest.
What do you mean?
Are we going to split the share,
like we did before?
This deal has nothing
to do with you.
You mean I'll get nothing?
There's no reason
to give you anything.
Did you know that Jin Keqiang's son,
Jin Hu, works for me now?
Don't use him to threaten me.
I may have planned his father's death,
but you were the one who carried it out.
You think he'll believe you?
I'll stop at nothing to
protect my interests.
You don't want peace then?
I didn't start the problem with you.
Think you'll win me at a game of dice?
May the best man win.
We'll meet at the gambling table.
Fine. Let's see what you got.
Mr Shimizu, I'll show you.
Any time, any place.
Open.
How's your luck been?
Not great.
How about we try yours?
With your money?
If you win, it's mine.
Sure.
I'll bet the lot.
Go ahead.
Seven! Lucky seven!
Lucky seven!
Seven”.
I'm really sorry, we lost.
Let's try another one.
This time I'll buy the chips.
I didn't come here to win.
There's a show
in the club downstairs.
Let's find a quiet place to chat.
Chat? With Who?
With you, of course.
Let's go upstairs, then.
There's drinks and music here.
We can chat and dance too.
This place's not bad.
Even if you lost everything downstairs,
you wouldn't jump to your death
after coming here.
You're quite funny.
My name's Reiko.
What's yours?
Jin Hu.
What an honour.
You're very well known
in Kyoto recently.
What brought you to the casino?
My father jumped to his death here.
Jin Keqiang?
What's your intention?
To find out what really happened.
Oh, I see.
He lost miserably.
80 million, in fact.
I'd like to see the boss here.
He won't see you.
How do you know?
Do you know who you're drinking with?
Miss Reiko?
You're half right.
I'm also Yamamoto's woman.
I thought so. You work for Yamamoto.
I didn't expect you're Madam Yamamoto.
Pardon me.
You're mistaken. I'm not married to him.
I just belong to him.
I think you better leave here now.
And if I don't?
I wouldn't want anything
bad happening to you.
Is that a warning from Yamamoto?
Leave or not, it's up to you.
I never take threats.
Then you just wait here!
HOW long?
Hard to say. Maybe a minute.
That fast, eh?
Look over there.
You want your men to take me out?
It's the best way
to deal with someone like you.
Hold it!
The hell you doing?
Using force on a girl?
This is absurd!
Take me to Yamamoto.
I'll apologise later.
Thank you.
Who are you?
Jin Hu.
Jin Keqiang was my father.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
I want some answers from you.
Reiko, you may go now.
Please sit down.
Who sold you
my father's martial arts school?
Did Shimizu tell you that?
That doesn't concern you.
Then who I bought it from
doesn't concern you either.
Is that your answer?
My answer's simple.
Get the hell out!
No need to get so angry now.
You dare to make a scene?!
I'm not satisfied with your answer.
Teach him a lesson!
Talk! Who sold you
my father's school?
Why should I tell you?
Are you going to talk or not?
Talk, now!
It was through a broker.
Show me the deed!
Let me go first!
I'm warning you!
These guys are no match for me.
You wouldn't dare to shoot me here.
Do what I say. Show me the deed.
Show it now!
See for yourself. It's all legal.
DEED
SELLER: JIN / BUYER: YAMAMOTO
ADDRESS: 4TH BLOCK, KAWARAMACHI, NI-CHOME
BROKER: NAGATANI SHOKI
Sorry for the trouble.
After him! Quick!
Get up there, quick!
In the car! Get him!
Who are you?
Didn't expect me, huh?
It is unexpected.
Someone's following us.
Go faster!
With me driving,
they'll never catch up.
Take the key.
The car's over there.
Dammit! He escaped!
Let's go.
- Why are you helping me?
- I like men like you.
You're hard to make out.
Why? You think this is a trap?
I wouldn't fall for it anyway.
Even my sexiness and beauty
couldn't tempt you?
- Won't be easy.
- C'mon. Wanna make a bet?
- I won't admit defeat.
- Fine, come to the hotel with me then.
I'm not interested.
Why don't you admit
you don't have the balls.
Fine, I accept your challenge.
You're so brave!
But I have to go somewhere first.
You're gonna run away?
Don't worry. I'm not afraid,
even if it's the lion's den.
Good. So where you heading to?
4th Block, Kawaramachi, Ni-chome.
4TH BLOCK, KAWARAMACHI, NI-CHOME
Don't forget.
Tonight at Grand Hotel. I'll be waiting.
Excuse me, do you know
Nagatani Shoki?
That's my father.
I'd like to see him.
He went to Thailand.
Does he like to gamble?
He never gambles.
Does he work
in the realty business?
He doesn't have any business
except for this bar.
Thank you.
- Chief, I looked all over for you.
- What is it?
Mr Shimizu wants to see you.
Jin Hu, this is Mr Yama Hiro.
He tells me, Yamamoto's dealer
Ohmura is no good.
I think it's rather suspicious.
So you doubt my judgement then?
No, what I mean is,
Yamamoto's clever enough
to cook up something.
He'll definitely have
someone good tomorrow night.
No one's ever beaten me
except for my master.
Who's your master?
Nagatani Ichiro.
Can you find him?
I heard he went to Thailand.
Thafland?
Jin Hu, tomorrow's game
is very important.
You must protect Mr Yamashiro.
Yes, sir.
After your mission's complete,
I'll pay you the 10% bonus as agreed.
Thank you.
Mr Shimizu, do you need me
to go with him?
No need.
You two should have
an early night.
Yes, sir.
Dammit.
Hayashi.
- Sir.
- Unhappy, are we?
I'd dare not, sir.
Master, these jobs used to be mine.
It's not your concern.
I know what to do
Yes, sir.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Don't forget.
This is about gambling.
Without patience, how can you win?
Please stop tormenting me.
I admit I've lost.
I love you.
I don't want to use love to cheat you.
Cheat me?
Because I need your help.
You want to avenge your father?
I need you to tell me
how my father died.
I only know a little.
Yamamoto wanted the land
your father used for his school.
So he sent for Nine-fingered Ichiro.
Nine-fingered Ichiro? Who's he?
He's a dice dealer and a cheat.
My father wouldn't befriend a cheat.
I only know that he fell
from the roof.
I don't really know
much more than that.
Don't go to Pearl Club anymore.
Yamamoto sent
a professional killer after you.
Oh? Who is he?
Yoshida Ryohei.
He's a famous knife-thrower.
What can you tell me about him?
He's maybe around 40 years old.
He's missing
a portion of his left ear.
I heard he lost it in a fight.
He must be pretty tough then.
Promise me, please.
You won't go there again.
The money that your father lost...
I'll think of something.
Why are you so kind to me?
I love you.
It's dangerous
to love a man like me.
I'm not afraid.
Chief.
What are you doing in my car?
Something bad happened.
Only you can take care of it.
- Where?
- I'll take you.
Where?
Over there.
You can stop stalling around.
Guess you tricked me.
So what do you want?
You're a smart man.
I want to settle the matter today.
How do you want to do it?
I want to settle the score
with you!
Come out!
So what? You've came prepared.
Just this bunch though?
Jin, Shimizu's business
used to be mine.
Don't think you can
just show up, Chinaman,
and take what belongs to the Japanese.
Sorry to tell you,
today you die!
Don't be so happy about it.
We don't know
whose clay to die it is just yet.
Bring it on!
Get him!
Hello?
You lazy bum. Still sleeping?
Where are you?
Am I not in your heart?
I want to do something for you.
Really?
The funds for tonight's big game,
Yamamoto entrusted them to me.
I can steal them.
Consider this revenge for your father.
What do you think?
It's too dangerous.
I'd risk it for you.
Be at Arashiyama Station
tonight at 9:45.
There's a ship to Yokohama at 10.
We'll take it and leave Japan.
- Goodbye.
- Hello? Hello?
- Good morning.
I need your help again.
You're too kind.
If I can do it, no problem.
Can you come with me to the station
tonight to pick up a girl?
What do you need me for?
I need to hide her in your room.
If madam finds out, then what?
Madam won't be at the hotel tonight.
But you need to keep it a secret.
Aright, I promise.
Why didn't you say
you were back tonight?
Something came up.
I didn't have enough time.
Can't even call me?
Fine, I'll make it up to you.
Go on, what is it?
Don't ask now.
Be at Cat's Eye Bar tonight at 10.
We'll go to Pearl Club together.
Get in.
Thanks but I don't smoke.
I know.
If you see me being followed,
light this cigarette.
Then throw it out the window.
Sit in the back seat.
If anything happens
after I get off the car,
close the door.
I'll handle it.
You scared?
Yeah, a little bit.
Don't be. I'm just being cautious.
There won't be any danger.
Why are you trembling?
I'm... I'm not.
You're still a kid.
ARASHIYAMA STATION
Don't be afraid.
There's no one else around.
- Did you buy the tickets?
- Yes.
How are things at the club?
Everyone's busy gambling.
No one noticed me.
- How much altogether?
- 700 million.
I was so scared to death.
You were just too nervous.
Smoke one to calm your nerves.
I'll carry that for you.
I feel so dizzy...
So dizzy...
Mrs Yoshida.
Please hold onto this.
Thank you.
I'm sick. My apologies
I can't be more hospitable.
Not at all.
She'll sleep for about three hours.
If she wakes up sooner,
don't let her go out.
Wait for me to come back.
Alright.
Mr Jin!
Mr Jin.
What is it?
- Are you going to Pearl Club?
- Yes.
Can you not go?
Since I can't stop you,
please be careful.
I know.
Wear this on your neck.
It'll protect you.
Thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
A single lady waiting alone in a bar -
what kind of an impression
does that give?
I'm sorry. Let's go.
Wait here for a moment.
- Miss Emi.
- Yes?
Does your father
also go by the name Ichiro?
Ichiro? That's his nickname.
Does anyone call him Nine-fingered Ichiro?
No but two years ago,
the little finger of his left hand
was cut off by a car door.
Why are you asking me this?
There's an expert gambler called
Nine-fingered Ichiro.
He might come
to Pearl Club tonight.
It couldn't possibly be my father.
He's gone to Thailand.
He's an honest old man.
And he never gambles.
I hope it's not the same man.
Let's go.
Why do you keep saying
he's a gambler?
I'm not sure.
I'm just asking.
What's going on?
Xiao Li,
go with me to the club.
You're going to the club?
I want to see
if he's really my father.
Excuse me,
can you come here?
- What happened, miss?
- I sprained my ankle.
Do you need help walking?
It's alright.
Can you just help me park the car?
Sure. Sure.
Thank you.
PEARL CLUB
Are you Jin Hu?
You must be the assassin,
Yoshida Ryohei.
That's right.
The wait has been my honour.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
Please follow me to the roof.
I have something to tell you.
Can't you just kill me here?
You're not welcome at this casino.
So I'll find a comfortable place for you.
Save yourself the trouble.
Welcome or not,
I'm still going in.
If you try,
I'll have to kill you.
You wouldn't dare to shoot me here.
Don't shout!
Stop! Put the gun away.
Why are you still here?!
Mr Yamamoto,
does your club usually
use violence on its guests?
No.
This has nothing to do
with the club.
A misunderstanding on my part.
Everyone, please sit.
Everything's fine now.
Carry on please.
Please sit.
Carry on.
- Are you alright?
- I'm fine.
Please sit.
- How is it?
- Nothing much here.
10 million.
- 10 million?
That's a lot.
It's your bet. You decide.
Wow! A straight!
Wow! A high score!
He's faking it.
You mean he's pretending
to be nervous?
He lost the first roll.
This time he'll have six of a kind.
Open!
- All red!
20 million. Stacking dice.
Mr Nagatani, can I raise the pot?
Welcome.
Another 20 million.
Call.
1, 2, 3, 4...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6!
What? It's not a 6!
What happened?
Wait!
What is it?
Mr Yamashiro,
with big stakes,
please reveal the dice slowly.
May I open it now?
You may.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let's take a break.
We'll resume in one hour.
Please have some rest outside.
- Let's go. Alright.
- Take a rest.
Mr Shimizu, I'm so sorry.
I don't know what happened.
Mr Ma.
Boss, I'm sorry.
I failed you.
Don't worry about it.
Just stay calm.
Everyone, stay alert.
It's gonna be a rough night.
Strange.
I've never failed
at stacking dice before.
What happened?
We were tricked.
When he yelled out, "Wait",
there was something wrong there.
Boss, I'm sorry.
It's fine, don't worry.
Plenty of other chances.
Just stay calm.
It should be here.
What do you want?
We're here to gamble.
You're here to gamble?
What? Isn't this a club?
What if it is?
You have money?
Of course I do!
Would I'd be here if I didn't?
Show me your chips!
Chips?
Chips...
The chips are...
- The chips...
- Get out of here!
He's my friend. Let him in.
If not for you, I'd beat him up.
Why are you here?
I'm looking for Jin Hu.
He's inside.
Act like you don't know me.
What are you doing here?
You said there was a gambler
that looks like my father.
I asked him to take a look with me.
The heavy man in the corner,
brown suit, smoking a cigar.
See if he's the one.
No.
It's not him?
Then he's someone else's father,
I've found him by accident.
Whose father is he?
Ayako's.
He's the assassin
Yamamoto sent after me.
Where?
His name is Yoshida Ryohei.
He's been waiting for me.
The second I'm alone,
he'll make his move.
Then I'll bring Ayako.
That way you'll have one less enemy.
Alright.
Mr Ohmura isn't feeling well.
I'd like to switch with a new dealer.
That's fine.
I came here to gamble
and meet more professionals.
Excellent. Sit.
- May I know your name?
- Nagatani.
Oh? Nagatani?
I'm Nagatani Ichiro.
Is that your name, too?
What a coincidence.
Two people with the same name.
It is, it is.
Place your bet, please.
50 million. Stacking dice.
Wait.
What's the matter?
Remove your gloves, please.
Oh... my apologies.
Call?
WW aren't you calling?!
Wait!
Don't worry.
My dice will still stack up
even if there's an earthquake.
It's all red!
Please.
I lost this one.
100 million.
What's the matter with you?!
I'm truly sorry.
We have to stop here.
Why?
That dealer is my master.
Is he Nine-fingered Ichiro?
I'm not so sure.
Miss, you're awake?
Where am I?
How did I get here?
This is my home.
Mr Jin brought you here.
Where did he go?
Pearl Club.
Oh no! I must go and see him.
He told me not to let you leave!
You don't know the danger he's in.
I must go!
I know but he clearly said
you must wait for him to get back.
Miss Ayako!
That must be Mr Jin.
Miss Nagatani, Mr Li,
come in, have a seat.
This is my mother.
Miss Ayako, I got good news.
I saw your father.
- Really?
- Yes!
He's alive?
Where is he?
Pearl Club.
Is Yashida Ryohei your husband?
Yashida Ryohei?
That's Yamamoto's assassin.
Nonsense.
He's no hired assassin.
I don't believe you.
He's out to kill my friend Jin Hu.
That's why I'm here to see you.
You're lying!
My father isn't a bad person!
Mother, tell me, father isn't a killer.
He's not a bad person, right?
I didn't want to tell you.
Your father's not a good man.
He's killed so many people.
Miss Ayako, Mr Jin is in great danger.
And he's a good person.
We have to find a way to help him.
What can I do?
There's nothing I can do.
Please speak to your father.
At least Mr Jin can stand a chance.
Miss Ayako, I beg of you.
Please help us.
Tell your father, Mr Jin saved us.
He can kill anyone but not Mr Jin.
We have to go, now!
50 million.
Mr Nagatani,
you're on a winning streak.
Seems like you'll never lose.
Guess it's my lucky day.
It's not luck.
Your skills... reminds me of...
Nine-fingered Ichiro.
Nine-fingered Ichiro?
Is your real name Nagatani Shoki?
And so what if it is?
I win by skill and not by cheating.
If you're really Nagatani Shoki...
Now just hold on.
Mr Yamamoto,
I've already lost over 200 million.
Please remove these two
who only came here to watch.
Alright. You two, leave.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Don't move!
Let me ask you all,
are guns allowed in here?
Absolutely not.
Why are you still here?!
If you cause more trouble,
I'll take you to the police station!
Did you open this place
just to have a sure win?
Nobody can guarantee that.
But you can.
You have proof?
First, you don't have
any available funds.
Second, the cash guests
used for the chips...
has been stolen!
What proof do you have?!
There's not a penny in the safe.
- How dare you accuse me!
- He took all of our money!
I'm warning you!
If any money is missing, I'll kill you!
Give us the money back!
You know not to mess
with Mr Shimizu!
Cheat us and we'll destroy this club!
- That's breaking the law!
- We'll close your club!
- Give back the money!
- Everyone, calm down!
Facts speak louder than words!
Where are you going?
- I'll show you where the cash is!
- I don't believe you.
- You don't? Come and look for yourself!
- Fine!
- Everyone, let's follow him!
- Yes.
Though you've been forced
to be a tool by others,
what you've done
was for hurting.
Not only have you cheated yourself,
but also your daughter.
She always thought
you were a good father.
You know my daughter?
Emi is a nice and humble girl.
If she knew that her father
was a cheat...
imagine how hurt she'd be.
I'm no cheat!
Even now, you still deny it?
Who the hell are you?
Why do you want to expose me?!
I'm Jin Hu.
My father, Jin Keqiang,
committed suicide because of you!
Jin Keqiang?
I've never gambled with him! Really!
Oh?
He sold his house
to Yamamoto through me.
I don't know anything
about him jumping to his death.
You telling me the truth?
Everything I said is true.
Kill me, cut me to pieces,
do whatever you want.
Fine. I'll let you go this one time.
Never be a cheat again.
Go home.
Emi is waiting for you.
I promise you.
Where's the money?
Yoshida, stop fighting!
Your wife and daughter
are looking for you everywhere.
You're lying!
They're both in Hokkaido.
I'm Ayako's friend.
I sent someone to get her.
She'll be here soon.
I only want you
to help me as a witness.
Prove that Yamamoto's cheating
and that he sent you to kill me.
Yamamoto, killing Nine-fingered Ichiro
was useless.
This club of yours is a scam.
A scam? What?
Give us the money back!
Show us the money!
Everyone,
it's all a misunderstanding.
We've been running
for over 10 years
and nothing like this
has ever happened.
I've entrusted the money with Reiko.
She must've gone out.
When she returns,
you'll see the money.
We don't believe you!
Give us the money back now!
Everyone, Yoshida can
tell you it's a scam.
Yamamoto, he confessed
that you sent him to kill me.
What? There's that, too?
He opens a casino to kill people?
This is absurd!
Give us the money
or there's going to be trouble.
You dare betray me?!
Put the gun down!
I'm Officer Miyamoto.
You're under arrest!
No one leaves this place alive!
Hello, hello...
Kyushu. No. 47 Miyamoto,
calling Kyoto.
Send the men!
Inside!
Stay calm. We won't get involved.
Han Ming!
Han Ming! Han Ming!
Talk!
How did you kill my father?
It wasn't me!
It was Shimizu...
Get ready!
Hold it! Nobody moves!
- No one moves!
- Everyone, hands in the air!
Quickly!
You came at the right time.
I'm Officer Miyamoto.
No one is allowed to leave.
Carry away the dead
and the wounded.
Sir!
- You, go and prepare the stretchers.
- Sir!
Arrest these thugs.
Everyone, form a line!
Go over there. Let's go!
Father!
- Mr Jin, are you alright?
- Are you badly hurt?
Will you be alright?
It's not much. I'll be alright.
Thanks to this for protecting me.
Where's Shimizu?
Oh my, almost turned
into mincemeat.
Officer Miyamoto, you saw
how everything went down.
I hope you'll give me a fair trial.
Of course.
The police have been watching
this place for a while now.
I was disguised as a guest to investigate.
Officer Miyamoto, the 700 million
from the casino - I have it all.
But I have one request.
The 80 million they cheated
off my father
were donations from
overseas Chinese compatriots.
I hope you can return it to me.
You must have proof
and recover it legally.
We'll give you back what is yours.
My father never gambled.
They were the ones who ruined him.
I hope you'll clear his name.
Alright, I'll share all the details
with the press.
Thank you.
Miss Emi, I must apologise to you.
I took your father for a cheat.
The Nine-fingered Ichiro I saw today...
was not your father.
Don't be sad anymore.
Your father died an honest man.
Before I found him,
I was so hopeful.
Now I feel nothing but despair.
Don't say that.
You now have many friends.
They'll take care of you.
When you've lost your love
and he's forever gone,
you will know what sorrow is.
Get 30% OFF for VIP membership on MY-SUBS.com
osdb.link/bf2024