What's that, Mr. Howell?
I don't know, Billy.
Let's find out.
What do you make
of that cymbal, Malcolm?
I don't know, Howell.
Does it mean anything
to you, Tal Chotali?
The men of the hills
are gathering.
The cymbal says that
the white men are to be driven...
from the Valley of Tombs.
Lieutenant!
Close the stockade gate.
Man the machine guns.
Yes, sir.
Close those gates!
Take your places!
Man the gun!
Come on.
Give me a hand.
Take cover, Betty.
This may be serious.
What causes this attack?
The legend.
No white man shall desecrate
the Valley of Tombs.
That is not a true legend.
When there is desecration,
Scorpio will erupt.
See for yourself.
There is no eruption.
You have spilled blood
without reason.
Return to your people,
and counsel them to await
a sign from Scorpio.
It shall be as you say.
The true legend
must not be violated.
The white men must leave.
There is a curse which says...
that any white man
that enters the Valley of Tombs
shall die.
He's coming back.
It looks as if
Tal Chotali was successful.
I hope so.
Is the attack over?
Who are they?
What do they want?
We'll not be attacked again...
if we stop our work
in the tombs and depart.
But our visas and permits
are in order.
The chief warns that
no permit will protect us from
the curse of the Scorpion...
if we enter
the inner tomb.
The only reason I financed
this expedition...
was to examine the contents
of that tomb.
Surely you're not gonna
be stopped by a native curse.
It's superstitious nonsense.
That's what everybody said about
the curse of King Tut's tomb.
But a lot of them died.
We'll handle this, Billy.
We'll open the tomb at once.
We strike camp in the morning...
and be well on our way
before there is any further
danger from the natives.
That suit you, Tal Chotali?
I wish our danger
came only from the natives.
You don't take this curse
of the Scorpion seriously?
Believe me, gentlemen,
there is a curse
of the Scorpion.
Nonsense.
We'll be seeing ghosts next.
Let's get to work.
Will you and Carlyle get
these specimens back to camp?
We'll be glad too.
Look out!
Why, there's
an inscription here.
Can you translate it,
Tal Chotali?
Yes, I can translate it.
It says,
"Let what reposes...
"behind this stone...
"remain hidden from
the eyes of mankind...
for all time."
Why, the secret
of the Scorpion dynasty
must lie beyond this wall.
Perhaps it would be wise...
not to learn
what that secret is.
That's ridiculous.
Well, I think
Mr. Tal Chotali is right.
I feel as though I were
robbing a grave right now.
You afraid, Billy?
No, sir.
I just don't wanna pry
into anybody's secrets.
I'll go into these passages
and remove that pottery for you,
but I don't want
any part of this.
Very well.
Clearly Batson is
the wisest one among us.
I think I shall
follow his example,
if I may be excused.
Just as you like.
Look! The Scorpion!
Why, it's not
a tomb at all.
What on earth is it?
Well, that's hard to say.
Why, these are lenses
of a sort.
They're probably
a fused quartz of some kind.
Well!
If this is the dreaded secret
of the Scorpion Dynasty,
it seems to be
quite harmless now.
The sunlight seems to have
something to do with it.
Why, these lenses
are adjustable.
Here, bring them all
into focus.
I am Shazam.
- My name is—
- All is known to me.
Your name is Billy Batson.
You did not pry into
the secret of the Scorpion.
That is why I am here.
But where did you come from?
Out of the past,
my son,
down through the ages
to guard the secret
of the Scorpion.
You've been alive
all these years?
What you call life
returned to me...
when your friends violated...
the tomb of the Scorpion.
Well, they meant no harm.
Then they should've obeyed
the inscription on the tomb.
The harm has been done.
It is your duty...
to see that the curse
of the Scorpion...
is not visited upon
innocent people.
My duty?
Yes. So long as
the Golden Scorpion...
may fall into the hands
of selfish men,
it is the duty
of Captain Marvel...
to protect the innocent
from its evil use.
But who is Captain Marvel?
You are, my son.
All that is necessary
is to repeat my name—
Shazam.
By its repetition,
you will become
Captain Marvel...
and take on the virtues
you see recorded there.
The wisdom of Solomon;
the strength of Hercules;
the stamina of Atlas;
the power of Zeus;
the great courage
of Achilles;
and the speed
of Mercury.
You must never
call upon this power...
except in the service
of right.
To do so would bring
the Scorpion's curse
upon your own head.
And now, my son,
repeat my name
and return to the rescue
of your friends.
Shazam!
Oh, Mr. Malcolm.
Are you all right?
Why, yes.
It was a concussion
from the explosion.
What caused it?
Why, that device there.
Quick, call the others!
We've got to get
Lang and Fisher up to camp.
We'll bring the Scorpion.
Take care of
this scroll, Bentley.
It is said forth here that
a certain arrangement
of the lenses...
will transmute any substance
placed in front
of the base lens...
to pure gold.
That's impossible.
Sounds like rubbish to me.
We can soon find out.
Show us how to arrange
the lenses.
Uh, Billy,
bring me several stones.
Uh, place them
on the ground.
Um, step back, please.
Why, it is gold!
The purest I've ever seen.
Only the sun's rays
is needed to create it.
If we only knew the formula
for making those lenses.
What difference does that make?
We've got these.
Gentlemen, do you realize
that this Golden Scorpion...
makes us the richest
and most powerful group
in the world?
Too rich and too powerful.
Are you suggesting that
we destroy the Scorpion?
Think of
its scientific value.
- I am thinking of that.
- What do you propose?
That the lenses be
distributed among us.
And another take
the Scorpion itself.
And in that way,
the device could never be used
without the consent of all.
Well, what about the scroll?
The Scorpion is useless
without it.
I suggest that Billy Batson
be entrusted with the scroll.
But he's so young, Howell.
And this is of
such vast importance.
Nevertheless,
Billy is probably
the only one among us...
who can't translate it.
Ah, but Mr. Howell, I—
I think Mr. Howell's plan
is excellent.
Tal Chotali,
will you disassemble
the lenses, please?
Professor Fisher.
Mr. Carlyle.
Professor Bentley.
Dr. Lang.
Mr. Malcolm.
And, Billy,
this is for you to guard.
See that you guard it well.
It contains a precious...
and a dangerous secret.
Don't worry, Tal Chotali.
I'll guard it.
Well said, young fellow.
I'm sure you will.
See that
your personal belongings
are packed tonight.
We start to load
at 4:00 in the morning...
and start for
the base camp at daylight.
It's the signal.
Thank you, sir.
There's evil
in the air tonight.
Yes, sir. You know,
I feel the same way.
We all seem
restless tonight.
And for good reason.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Howell.
One who invites the curse
of the Golden Scorpion...
does well
to protect himself.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
Find the scroll.
Bring it, and return
to Rahman Bar.
You men of the hills
know the legend.
It is as old
as the rocks about you,
spewed up by Scorpio,
the guardian of
the Valley of Tombs.
If the hands of alien whites
desecrate our holy places,
Scorpio will give
the sign to war.
Scorpio!
- Scorpio has spoken!
Yes?
Yes, what is it?
Come here!
Why, Billy!
What's up?
Mr. Howell's been murdered.
Howell, murdered?
Yes, sir.
Dissenters
with knives, sir.
Round out your men.
Search the camp.
Yes, sir.
Where is Howell?
In our tent.
Radio the British troops
at Fort Mooltan. Tell them
we need immediate aid.
Yes, sir.
M.A.E. on 6-2-4,
calling Fort Mooltan.
Malcolm Archaeological
Expedition on 6-2-4
calling Fort Mooltan.
Fort Mooltan.
Come in, M.A.E.
We need immediate aid.
We were attacked
by natives this afternoon,
and two of our men
have been killed here tonight.
Stand by, M.A.E.
Yes, Sergeant?
Trouble with that
Malcolm expedition
in the Valley of Tombs, sir.
They're standing by.
Ask their exact position,
and tell them I'll send
a troop immediately.
Orderly!
Must have
your exact location.
Colonel Hudson says the troops
are well on their way.
Thank you, Billy.
One of my men reports
movement in the rocks, sir.
Tell him to keep
a sharp lookout, Lieutenant.
Do you honestly believe that
the volcano has anything
to do with the Scorpion?
That's the legend.
The natives will regard it
as a sign of war.
I don't believe there's a native
within 10 miles of here.
Look!
English troops are coming.
They've got a cannon.
Take men across through
Kala and ambush them.
Get me some ammunition!
Can't stand
much more of this.
If we could only get
across the gorge.
Get the others.
Yes, sir.
Come on!
What—
Get the cars ready.
We'll try to get through
to the troops.
Come on!
Halt!
Deploy!
Get behind the baggage, Betty.
It'll protect you
from the gunfire.
What about you, Billy?
I'll be all right.
They will try
to cross the gorge.
Send men ahead of them
and dynamite the bridge.
You'll have to hurry.
Shazam!
Back up, Whitey!
Back up!