Well, we finished earlier
than Ike and I expected.
- Are you going anywhere?
- No, I don't think so.
So the next time, I changed to
another tailor, but found out
that he was no better than the first.
I bought some pretty expensive cloth
and took it to him and you should've
seen the mess he made of it.
I told him I wouldn't pay for the thing,
but the trouble is, he's got my material.
Well, I left the suit with him
and it's been there ever since.
- Good evening, Miss White.
And how are you?
- I'm all right, thanks.
- I haven't seen you for a long time.
Have you come to take Frank for a walk.
- Yes.
- That's right. Well, I must push along.
- Good-night.
- Good-night, Frank.
- Well, dear.
- I've been waiting here half an hour for you.
- Good-night, Sean.
- Good-night, Frank.
Good-night, George.
- Sorry sir. Full up. You'll
have more room upstairs.
- Goaaannn.
I think I told you, there's
more room upstairs!
Sorry Sir. Full up here.
There's more room up...HEY!
Frank. I've lost one of my gloves.
I think I left it at the other table.
- Is this it?
- Yes, thanks.
Thought so, there's a
hole in two fingers.
Would you like a pair of
nail scissors for Christmas?
- Funny, aren't you?
- Oh Miss, Miss!
It's no good being impatient,
you'll have to wait your turn.
What's the matter with you today?
Got out of bed the wrong side?
- I don't like waiting about for you.
- Oh, don't you? Oh, Miss!
Do you expect the entire
machinery of Scotland Yard
to be held up to please you?
You and your Scotland Yard!
If it weren't for Edgar Wallace
nobody'd ever heard of it.
Funny, aren't you?
Anyway, what's the hurry? We're only going
to the pictures, we've got all evening.
- Well, I don't think I want
to go to the pictures.
- Oh, and why not?
- I've seen everything worth seeing.
- You haven't seen "Fingerprints".
I'd like to see that.
Still it's about Scotland Yard!
might be amusing. They're bound
to get all the details wrong.
I don't see why. I did hear they'd
got a real criminal to direct it.
- So as to be on the safe side.
- Oh, oh Miss!
Oh, blast!
Well, I've ordered.
- I'll go to the pictures with you, if you like.
- uh, changed your mind.
Have you got an ashtray Miss? I never
seem to get an ashtray where I sit.
Frank, Frank. I've changed my
mind again.
- About what?
- About going to the pictures.
- You mean you don't want to go again?
- No, not particularly.
- Why not?
- I don't know, I just don't want to.
- Isn't that enough?
- No, it's not enough. oy, Miss!
- What are you going to do?
- I'm going to get the bill.
I'm about fed up with you. If you
don't want to go, I do.
- Oh all right, I'll come too.
- oy, Miss!
Oh, don't let's have a row. I'm sorry.
I know I've been rather beastly today.
- Miss!
- Frank, I've said I'm sorry.
Here, that will cover it.
Hold on. I live here.
Do you? Then you
needn't come any further.
Oh, no now I said that I'd
see you home, and I will.
But I'm only just around the corner.
Do you know Whites? The newsagent?
- Yes? - In the Kings road?
- Yes. - That's my father.
- No!
- Yes!
Now isn't that fine?
Then we're neighbors.
- Have you ever seen an artist's studio?
- No, I'd love to.
- Come up and see mine.
- Oh, I can't now. Another time.
- Why not now?
- Why, it's so late.
- Are you frightened?
- No, course not.
Then why not now?
No, really. Thanks awfully.
I must be getting home.
- You are frightened.
- I'm certainly not. Take
more'n a man to frighten me.
Yes...that's what I thought...
at first.
- What is the time?
- Not very late.
- Come on. What's the harm.
Oh, no harm really. Besides,
I always think a girl knows
instinctively when she can trust a man.
Yes, of course she does.
Do you trust me?
- Alice? May I call you Alice?
- If you like.
Come on.
- Oh Mr. Crewe. Before you go in, could I...?
- Excuse me, miss.
No!
That chap's nothing but a sponger.
Always pestering people up and
down this street.
Well, here we are.
I'm right up there. Top!
Excuse me a minute, will you?
I say, I'm awfully sorry. I won't
be a minute. You start walking up.
That's all right.
Oh good evening. Sorry to disturb you.
About this note, did he leave any message?
No, he wouldn't leave any
message.
- Have you seen him before.
- Yes, the same gent what
called here several times.
I see. Thanks very much. Goodnight.
Bit of a climb, wasn't it?
What a lovely room.
Did you do it all yourself?
Hardly. I say, do you feel cold?
I think I'll light the fire.
- I say. That's good, isn't it?
- Oh that? Yes, that's a new one,
just finished.
- How do you hold this?
- What?
Oh, that.
That's easy. I'll show you.
Oh Lord, not like that. Let me show you.
You take this and hold it like that,
you see...Then you get the brush
and hold it there. You try.
- Like this?
- Yes.
- Oh, look what I've done.
- Ooo, yes
- Draw something Alice.
- Shall I?
- Yes.
Rotten.
Never mind. We'll finish this
masterpiece together.
Now you hold the brush. Steady.
There we are.
You are awful.
Wait a minute.
- There.
- Hooray! Already a pick ahead of me.
- I'll go and get those drinks...
- Right you are.
I say,
how would I do for one of your models?
That's an idea.
Let's see it on you.
- Do you mean, put it on?
- Yes, why not?
- Oh, it's so strong!
- Go on...
Oh no, I don't think so. Besides I
have to go home soon.
I see.
Pity. I would have like to have
sketched you in it.
- Would you have really?
- Yes, but perhaps you are right.
It wouldn't suit you.
I bet it would.
- Shall I really try it on?
- Yes, will you?
- All right.
- Good.
- Do you think this will be big enough for me.
- What?
- I said, do you think this
will be big enough for me.
- Yes, I think so.
- Go on, play something.
- Wait a minute, how does that thing go?
I know.
And that's a song about you, my dear.
You haven't said how you like it.
Marvellous.
- I can't do it up.
- Wait a minute. Where is this trouble?
- I can't do it all up.
- Never mind.
- How do I look?
- Well... wait a minute, it isn't quite right.
Put your hands there.
- I better go.
- I say.
I've got it.
- Please give it to me.
- All right, come on out.
There it is.
Don't be silly, Alice. Don't be silly.
No, no, let me go! Let me go!
No, no....
- Who did you say it was?
- Mr. Crewe!
- Mr. Who?
- No! Crewe, I tell you! It's horrible!
- All right. Don't you worry. I'll send round
straight away. What number did you say?
Seven or eleven?
- 31.
- 31?
- What?
- 31, I said.
- No, no, 31.
- Ah good. Just take a look around,
will you? - Right you are sir.
- Alice, wake up.
Anyone'd think you hadn't
been asleep all night.
What do you think!? There's been a
murder last night, round the corner.
And they tell me
the police are round there now.
We'll all be murdered in our
beds, soon, I'm sure we will.
'cause I don't think the
police are what they were.
Morning, Alice. 'eard about the murder?
- Yes, I heard.
- Do you remember Frank's
telephone number, dad?
- No, but here, you'll
find it in the book.
- I mean, some murders are so
different to others, aren't they?
Pushed his lady friends under the
water when they was having a bath.
What was his name, you remember?
I think that was ever so beastly.
It gave me the shivers.
After I read about it, I didn't
dare 'ave a bath for a month.
An' for weeks after that I
only used to 'ave a rinse down.
What was his name, you remember?
Smith, wasn't it?
What's wrong Alice? You don't look
very cheerful this morning.
- You do look a little bit peaky, I must say.
- Dad, Alice, breakfast!
- Good-morning, Mr. White.
- Good-morning, Sir, good-morning.
Breakfast!?
I couldn't look bak'n in the face
after what happened last night...
and under our very noses.
Mind you, I don't think, myself,
it's all together the police's fault.
What I mean is, they 'ave
to wink at some things.
I mean it's one thing to buy
chocolates out of hours,
but it's quite another to stick
a knife into a gentleman.
I must say I feel the
same way about that too.
A good, clean, honest whack over
the 'ead with a brick is one thing....
...something British about
that. But knives?
No. Knives is not right.
I must say that's what I think
and that's what I'll keep.
Whatever the provocation,
I could never use a knife.
Now, mind you a knife is
a difficult thing to handle.
I mean any knife...
...knife.... knife....
...a butcher's knife...
- Alice, cut us a bit of bread, will you?
Knife.... knife.... of a knife....
...you come up against a knife!
I mean, in Chelsea you mustn't use a..
KNIFE!
- Dear, you ought to be more careful.
You might have cut somebody with that.
Customer...
- No news of the murder yet?
- No, not yet.
- Thank you. Good-morning.
- Well, I must be going. I can't stand
here gossiping all day like some people.
Chatter, chatter, chatter.... give
'em a chance to talk about other
people's business, and they'll take it.
- What's the matter Alice?
Had another row with Frank?
- Another customer, Alice.
- Good morning, Alice.
- Dear, it's Frank. Hello Frank.
- I say, have you 'eard about our murder?
- Yes, they put me on it.
- Did they? That's good isn't it?
Well, I hope you get him Frank!
- If they do, that will mean
promotion, won't it?
- D'you reck'n you'll get him soon?
- Well, uh, I don't know.
- Well, I came in here to phone.
- That's all right.
- Alice? Come here a minute will you?
- Well I must be going now. Good-bye,
Mrs. White, good-bye, Mr. White.
Now you two.
- Sssshhhh..... Be careful...
What happened last night?
Why don't you tell me?
Look, you know where I found that?
It's the only piece of evidence that you
were there. I'm keeping it back at present.
For God's sake, say something!
- If you're not using the
phone...uh, may I?
I, uh, I want to get on to Scotland Yard.
- I say.
- I want the best cigar in the shop.
Certainly sir. Perhaps you'd like to
telephone while I get it down?
- No, thanks, that can wait.
- What does he mean?
- Very well sir. Now, uh, what sort of
a cigar would you like sir? I've got..
I've got 'enry Clay or Corona, Corona?
- Corona.
- Certainly sir.
- Any news of the murder.
- No, nothing yet.
- Have you heard anything?
- No, no news.
- Are you, uh, quite sure?
- What the hell business
is it of yours, anyway?
- You know, I looked everywhere
for that other glove last night.
But, of course, you detectives are
better trained at finding these things.
- Ah, here we are sir.
- Excuse me, will you?
Thank you.
Oh, they look good.
- They ought to. I've
had 'em for years.
Is it all right sir?
- Yes, I thought the top was
broken, but it's all right.
- Have you a light?
- Yes, here you are.
- How silly of me, hadn't noticed it.
- Uh.. all right sir?
- Oh, ha, of course, sorry.
Extraordinary actually...
I can't quite...
I say... would you pay for this?
Is this gentleman a
friend of yours, Frank?
Well, we're not exactly
friends. At least not yet.
But we're going to do a little
business together, aren't we, Frank?
I'll look after the shop, Father.
You go and finish your paper.
What for?
Oh....all right
my dear, all right.
Rather unfortunate that poor man
died around the corner last night.
Look here you....
Perhaps it's rather fortunate,
that your little secret only came
into the hands of a man like me.
D'you know, there are some men who
would make money out of a thing like that.
What a chance for blackmail!
Oh, oh that's awful.
I couldn't do a thing like that.
Morning, Miss. Two of each there.
By the way. You're a detective.
Let me give you a tip.
Don't wave important clues in telephone
boxes. They've got glass doors.
You know, uh, detectives in
glass houses shouldn't wave clues.
Come on, out with it. What do you want?
What do I want?
Oooooh, well, uh...
Couldn't we discuss that over breakfast?
Mother this is a friend of Frank's. Mr...?
- Tracy.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Mr. Tracy, would you like something to eat?
- Thank-you.
- Lovely weather, we're having.
- Yes, splendid.
- Who did you say that man was?
- He's a very important friend of Frank's.
I'll get the breakfast for him.
- Here! Aren't we rude?
Won't you take my chair?
- Oh, thanks.
- Did you see, or hear
anything during the night?
- No, sir.
- What time did you go to bed?
- About half past ten, sir.
- Did you write this?
- Yes.
- How old would you say this man was.
- I'm afraid I couldn't tell
you, sir, he had his hat on.
- Did you notice anything
particular about his clothes?
- Well, uh, he had a black
hat and a loose kind of collar.
'nd a tie and that's about all, I think.
- Was he dark or fair?
- Well, you couldn't say he was a blond
and you couldn't say he was a brunette.
He was a bit of both,
you know, kind of mousey.
- Anything else?
- No.
- Except when he spoke to you,
he went like this.
- All right.
Give me records.
- Well, bring him along. Let's
hear what he's got to say.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir.
- Right, get along with it..
- That'll do to go on with.
- How much longer is that man going to
stay? Don't tell me he'll be here to dinner.
- Don't make things awkward mother.
It means a lot to me and Frank.
- Well, I don't see why they should
carry on their business in my parlour.
- I'll take it.
- Very well.
- But I don't like that man and
the sooner he goes the better.
You are very clever.
I can see that all right.
- Frank? Just a minute, will you?
A pal of yours at the Yard, said
he thought you might be here.
- Oh, all right.
Hello?
Yeah. Yes.
Well, I thought you wouldn't mind if...
What?
Who?
- Any news Frank?
- Alice, lock that door.
As you were saying... rather
unfortunate the way that poor man
round the corner, uh, died last night.
On the other hand, perhaps it's
fortunate. For us, that is...
that a suspicious looking man,
with a criminal record, was seen
hanging around the place.
- You....
Look here, don't you try and
swing this thing on me. That
won't get you anywhere.
- Also rather unfortunate, that Scotland
Yard, are at present looking for that man.
- I say, Frank!
- Just a minute, Alice.
- But there's one thing you
seem to have forgotten....
- And what's that?
- Before we get to any hanging,
I shall have quite a lot to say.
And the first thing I shall say
is, that she was there too.
- Oh, you will, will you?
Isn't there one thing you seem to have
forgotten, that our word's as good as,
or perhaps a bit better...
...than that of a jailbird.
So we'll face that when the time comes.
Meanwhile, we'll just sit quietly
here until the squad van arrives.
- That surprises you doesn't it?
- No, it doesn't surprise me in the least.
When it comes, the
surprise won't be for me.
- Very well then, we are both satisfied.
- Yes, we're both satisfied.
It's my word, against hers.
- Frank, you can't do this.
- Why not?
- Well, because...
- Now, now, don't interfere,
Alice, I know what I'm doing.
You don't, you don't.
- Please, Frank.
- Oh, for God's sake, be quiet, Alice.
- Why can't you let her speak.
- You mind your own business.
In any case, she'll speak
at the right moment.
- Look here Frank. Why can't we,
both of us, chuck the whole thing now?
I've got nothing against you.
You've got nothing against me.
Except, of course, I had some
cash from you, but I wasn't serious.
Well, look here, have it back now.
Well, can't you see, that she wants to
chuck it up too? And so do I, you know.
Look here, Miss. You tell him.
Tell him that he's playing
with fire and...
And we shall, all of us,
burn our fingers.
I'm not bad really, I only...
things have gone wrong lately,
and one's got to live, you know.
All right then. It's still
my word against hers.
That's it?
You men meet me in the
back, Frank, follow me!
I say, it's not me you want...
It's him... ask him.
Why his own....
Hello. Not very often I see you so
early in the day as this.
- Called to see Frank?
- No.
I want to see Inspector Walls, please.
- Then you'll have to fill out
one of these forms, you know.
- All right.
- Do you know something about this?
- Yes.
George. Just a minute.
Take this along to inspector Walls.
Well, I suppose you're going
to tell him who did it.
Yes.
- You can come along now
- Here you are, Miss.
- Come in, please.
Won't you sit down?
You've something to
tell us about this case.
- Yes.
- Well, what is it?
Well, you see. I know who did it.
Is this worthwhile sir, now that
everything has been cleared up?
Yes. But let's hear what
she's got to say.
What I was going to say is this...
I'd better say, what I
have to say now...
I would rather not wait.
What I wanted to say is...
- I was the one...
- One moment please.
Hello. Yes, yes.
Yes, hold on.
Will you deal with this young lady,
I shall be busy for a minute.
- Yes, sir.
This way Miss, please.
Alice, whatever made
you come here?
I did it.
- I know.
- You don't know.
He tried oh, I can't tell you.
It's too terrible.
I was defending myself.
I didn't know what
I was doing and then...
- My dear.
- Ha, ha! So you found him,
Miss. Did she tell you who did it?
- Yes.
You'll want to look out, or you'll
be losing your job, my boy.
I suppose we'll soon have lady
detectives up in the Yard, eh.
But I shall be all right
on the door, won't I.