(chanting "God is Great'')
(credits)
Where the blazing desert meets the blue Mediterranean and modern Europe jostles ancient Africa
.
I'm not interested in hearing excuses about local conditions.
No doubt there are local conditions.
Here's a criminal whose exploits have made him notorious throughout Europe.
He escaped from France
with a fortune in jewels. And for two years, he's been living here in Algiers,
within a stone's throw of your headquarters.
As you say commissioner.
I'm here to settle this.
I want it done quickly.
We've been trying to settle the case of Pepe le Moko for two years.
In Paris, we handle more difficult cases every day.
Too bad you couldn't arrest him before he escaped from France.
Merely an oversight, no doubt.
Do you deal in riddles here?
Indeed we do.
Oriental riddles.
From my experience, there's no problem in surrounding a given area.
You close in, and you make a house-to-house investigation.
A house-to-house investigation?
You just arrived from Paris, commissioner.
You're not familiar with the Casbah.
Casbah? What's that?
Some kind of nut?
A very hard nut to crack.
You see. Pepe le Moko lives in the Casbah.
Why not go in and take him out of it?
You can't arrest a king in his own palace.
Pepe is well guarded.
Let me show you.
Fantastic.
As a civilized man, you don't like fantasy.
As a police officer, I don't believe in it.
But here it is.
The native quarter known as the Casbah.
As you look at it here, it's just a few lines on the map.
But the reality is something stranger than anything you could have dreamed.
It's only a step from the modern city, the Casbah.
But when you take that step, you enter another world.
A melting pot for all the sins of the earth.
Seen from a bird's eye view, the Casbah is a great staircase.
Each step is a terrace rising from the sea.
If you observe more closely,
you'll see that those terraces and courtyards and twisted streets
are like a crawling anthill,
a jungle of houses,
a labyrinth of narrow passages and winding alleys
rotten with vermin
and decay from the filth of centuries.
No one knows what mysteries are hidden behind those walls.
No one knows what crimes and hopes
are buried in those secret courtyards.
Forty thousand inhabitants from all over the world.
Some have been settled here for generations.
There are Kabulis in their white robes,
Chinese faithful to Confucius,
Gypsies with their fortune telling and their songs,
and there are many Czechos,
and there are Slavs far from home,
and Maltese,
Negroes from every corner of Africa,
Sicilians and Spaniards, hot-blooded and quick to hate,
and women,
women of every age and every shape,
women caught in the neck of the Casbah.
And everywhere there are terraces,
all connected together so that those who are accepted
can move to any part of the Casbah without using the street.
The terraces are the domain of the native women
and it would be dire for a foreigner to go there unless he was known and protected.
The Casbah rises like a fortress from the sea,
colorful, sordid, dangerous.
There isn't just one Casbah.
There are hundreds,
a thousand.
And in that labyrinth,
Pepe le Moko is at home,
and he's safe as long as he stays there.
You mean to say that you don't go into this quarter?
It's easy to go in.
Sometimes, it's no so easy to come out.
You cross the dead line.
Suddenly,
a bullet hits you feet.
It's just a friendly suggestion.
Don't take the next step.
From a roof up above,
a voice speaks.
Hello, inspector.
How did he know you were there?
Don't ask us.
Ask Inspector Slimane.
The Casbah is his territory.
How does Pepe le Moko conceal himself?
Disguise, no doubt.
You don't know Pepe.
He'd laugh at a disguise.
Then why don't you find him?
Oh, but that is singularly easy.
I see him every day.
What?
Our distinguished colleague is disturbed.
The man is wanted in all the capitals of Europe, and you see him every day.
Another example of what you call the local condition.
Gross inefficiency. No effort to make an arrest.
To arrest him in the Casbah, distinguished colleague, would be simple.
To get him out would be impossible.
So, you do nothing.
I flatter myself that I do a great deal in my humble way.
I learn about Pepe. I know his habits. I study his weaknesses.
When one can't use guns, one must work with brains.
I prefer guns.
In your case, honored sir, such a preference is unavoidable.
By his looks, I'd say he was too lazy to make an arrest.
I'm merely careful.
Which means to say you're looking after your own skin.
It's the only skin I have.
So Pepe le Moko wouldn't amuse me.
We'll find out.
I want twelve men tonight, inspected and ready for work.
And you might prepare a special cell for Pepe le Moko.
You and I have the same feeling, Pepe, for beauty.
This pearl belongs on a very special kind of ear,
like a pink shell
with a little curl of gold hair,
a special kind of gold.
I can see it.
No.
Pearls don't suit you at all, Carlos.
You're not the type.
He'd look better with rings in his ears.
Yes, and one in his nose.
He is definitely uncouth.
You took the words out of my mouth.
He's trying to cheat us, Pepe.
All his talk is so he can get a better price,
so he can make fools of us.
Yes.
So he's here to make a fool of me.
Why don't you try it some time?
Grandpere dealt with us for two years.
We must have confidence in each other.
That's the way to get along.
That's the truth, Pepe.
Well, why don't we get our money and be done with it?
He doesn't speak our language.
Pretend he is not here.
Yes, but I am here.
He doesn't know he's not here.
One more thing he doesn't know will make it practically a perfect score.
He was talking about beauty.
The more he talks about beauty,
the less he talks about money.
And I'm talking about how much.
Oh, you make me sick.
What?
Say that again.
You make me sick.
Since you make him sick...
Ok.
Look,
but don't touch.
You know, this was once my trade.
I began life in a jewelry store.
And when you left you took the store with you.
Yeah, it became a habit.
You know, I dream about sitting down in Paris sometime.
I'd make a collection of things like this.
Not just for myself,
for people to see
in glass cases.
With you in a uniform taking care of them together.
And you, Max.
Me?
You, Pierrot.
Oh, you'd have a uniform like a general,
and you'd be in charge of everything.
What about me?
What would he be?
Stuffed in a glass case?
What?
Say that again.
Stuffed in a glass case.
Like an Egyptian mummy.
Ok.
Hey.
Police !
Ah !
You.
Where's Pepe le Moko?
(speaks in arabic "moi...
I don't know him")
Cuff him.
Uh, uh.
Where's Pepe le Moko?
I don't know.
By the sword of the Great Prophet, I haven't set eyes on him in two weeks.
He hasn't let me look on his face in two weeks.
Let him go.
Grandpere?
Who is he?
Receiver of stolen goods.
Do you know where his place is?
We know it.
Pepe?
No.
It's Regis.
What's the matter?
The police.
They're looking for Pepe.
So soon?
Soon? Were you expecting them?
Always.
But especially tonight. Pepe said they sent someone all the way from Paris.
So he knew?
Of course. Pepe knows everything.
You're. You're going to him?
Tell him I've never seen so many.
He'll laugh.
That's what he expected.
Look. Look at my neck.
I thought they were going to wring it like a chicken.
But all the time I thought only if Pepe
kill me. I thought so long as Pepe.
Why should you feel that way about Pepe?
Don't you?
I?
Everyone knows how I feel about Pepe.
Pepe doesn't like me. He ignores me. Humiliates me.
But I have my revenge. Sometime he'll be sorry he didn't notice me sooner.
Oh, I'm very humble.
I do my best to serve him in my own way.
That's nice of you, Regis.
That's how I am.
Sensitive. But no one appreciates me.
Promise me you'll tell him that I came to warn you.
I will.
I don't want any favors.
I only want him to know that where there's trouble,
look for Regis.
Third door on the left.
Take three men. Cover the roof.
You men go 'round the back.
It's Ines. Quick.
The police on the roof, Pepe. They're coming.
They surrounded the house. They know you're here.
That's funny.
How did they know I was here?
Oh, one can't meditate in peace anymore. Always rush and bustle.
I'll take this one.
I rather like it.
You think that's a toy?
No.
When will you learn to obey orders?
See.
Don't take so many chances.
That's foolish.
I don't want a bullet to come between us,
the way that one almost did.
Break it down.
Every few weeks, I have to get new doors.
Ines.
Did you tell anyone where I was?
No one, Pepe.
Are you sure?
Try to remember.
Why don't you believe me, Pepe?
All I want is to please you.
I couldn't lie to you.
Couldn't you?
What about all that time you kept telling me that you didn't like me?
But this is serious.
Ah, so, love is not serious?
Pepe, it's serious if someone told the police.
I didn't talk to anyone. I stayed at home until Regis came.
Who came?
Regis.
Ahhh.
As soon as he told me, I ran to you.
What did Regis tell you?
Oh, about the police.
He wanted me to warn you.
It was nice of him.
That's what I thought.
Was that all you thought?
Wsa there anything else for me to think?
That's what I like about you.
What?
Nevermind.
This seems to be all.
All for me.
Search the place.
Hold out your hand.
Don't grab.
It's unlucky.
You want to give it to me, Pepe?
No.
It's for some fat, old woman.
Let me have it, Pepe. Some time, I'll get fat.
You'll lose it before that.
I'll keep it for a charm.
Then you must keep your fingers crossed.
Alright.
So.
This ring will mean that I'm always yours, Pepe,
with my fingers crossed.
(crashing sound)
Those baboons are turning my house upside down.
They'll be here next.
Let's get out.
No, you stay here.
When the police come, you know what to say.
No evidence?
Nothing.
Are you satisfied?
I'm never satisfied.
Take your men back to the roof.
The rest of you follow me.
There they go.
This way quickly.
Come in.
Make yourself comfortable.
What is this? What happened?
Oh, it's nothing.
You call this nothing?
Oh, you know how the police are.
They like to keep everything in an uproar.
A very profound observation.
The police have been trying to catch him for two years.
Police must be rather stupid.
As one of them, I consider that a triumph of understatement.
You're one of them?
I have that doubtful honor.
How does he do it?
Mademoiselle.
It's not his head that saves him. It's his heart.
A man with such a good heart could get around anywhere.
Sounds intriguing.
It's a matter of taste.
Oh, inspector.
Fix it up.
Permit me to hope that it's nothing serious.
Thanks.
A flea bite.
Why aren't you chasing the fox?
Oh, such a silly business.
I prefer to use my brains.
Well, your friends did a little better than usual tonight.
At least they found me. That's pretty good for them.
Shall we say a step in the right direction?
Excuse us madam if we talk shop.
Cigarette?
Please.
Let me help you.
So.
They surrounded the house?
Yes.
They thought I was at Grandpere's.
Poor old man.
He has no luck.
They won't even let him sleep in peace.
Sometimes, I feel sorry for them.
They'll never get me by this technique, you know.
I've tried to point that out to them.
For once we agree,
the inspector and I.
I am the one who will get you Pepe,
in the end.
I can hardly wait for the day.
And not only you, but the others,
Pierrot, Carlos, Grandpere, all of you.
And then what will you do?
Put us in the zoo?
You flatter yourself.
Oh, you mean
you won't show me in a cage?
You're important now because you're free.
Once you're behind bars, people will forget all about you.
He is funny, my friend Slimane.
He looks normal, doesn't he?
But he has delusions of grandeur. He thinks he can arrest me.
That's exactly what I'm going to do Pepe.
Sure.
Sure. Sure. Sure. Sure.
How you make me laugh.
Do you know what I like about you?
No, but I'm humbly waiting for you to tell me.
Your face.
It's a perfect face for your job.
To look that false is almost the equivalent of being honest.
I'm honored that my appearance pleases you.
Don't mention it.
You'll excuse me?
I'm afraid I have to go.
Business.
Goodnight, Pepe.
It's a shame, isn't it?
What?
A waste of talent.
An unusual intelligence.
One hates to see him buried so young.
Buried?
It's the same thing.
What makes you so sure?
I've marked the date of his arrest on the wall of my room.
High.
Where it reads black in the rays of the setting sun.
Shall we go?
And although we narrowly missed capturing Pepe le Moko,
he was evidently wounded while escaping.
In fact, his injuries may prove fatal.
In the event of his death, I shall inform you without delay.
Why don't you just declare him dead and be done with it?
You may rest assured that I have the situation well in hand
and will take whatever steps I deem advisable.
Wire that to Paris immediately.
What does he mean by saying he has the situation well in hand?
He means he's going to sit here and write letters to Paris,
while he waits for Pepe to die of old age.
That's better than going into the Casbah looking for him.
At least our friend from Paris has learned something about the Casbah.
We've all learned that there's only one way to arrest Pepe.
Oh, that's very intelligent of you.
As you know, my intelligence is at your service.
Well so far, it's hardly been enough.
Ah, but wait.
Suppose Pepe comes out of the Casbah.
Then it follows, his arrest is a matter of child's play.
Shall we send him an engraved invitation?
Pepe is too clever to fall into a trap,
but some of his friends are not so clever.
Get to the point.
Suppose Pierrot comes down into the town,
Pepe would be worried about his absence,
and he'll come down into the town to find him.
You've overlooked just one little point. How do you get Pierrot to come down?
Ah, that's my plan.
Magnificent plan.
I have here a letter.
I got it from Pierrot.
But he doesn't know that.
The letter is from his mother.
A letter of exquisite tenderness.
From France.
Can't see much value in that.
He's a bad boy but a good son.
So it isn't the good son that we'll lock up,
but the bad boy.
Then, we keep the arrest a secret
and Pepe will come down out of the Casbah to look for Pierrot.
Are we agreed?
Agreed.
And...
as to the price?
You know the reward has been posted.
But a little bonus besides
in view of the circumstances?
Agreed.
How do we know we can trust you not to make a better bargain with Pepe?
I'm an informer
not a hypocrite.
What are you laughing at?
It amuses me to see you sell your friend at bargain prices.
You have a flair for business, Regis.
He says that because he's jealous. It doesn't upset me.
I ignore him.
Double him, dear. He'll never make it.
Good morning, Tanya.
Good morning, Inspector.
And how is Carlos?
How would he be?
Don't tell me your charming husband has been beating you again.
You know how it is with a man.
Well, I can't say I do.
Thay seem to take to it naturally.
Morning, pretty.
Good morning, Pepe.
Hello.
Good morning.
You better watch out, Pepe.
Women will be the death of you.
It's a happy death.
I'm just warning you.
Don't worry. I'll keep my head.
I may need it one of these days.
No doubt.
Coming my way?
With pleasure.
Good morning, Pepe.
Morning.
Did you get home safely last night?
Why not?
Morning, Pepe.
Morning.
Nothing unpleasant?
Yes, we had one rather unpleasant experience.
Yeah?
With you.
She didn't think so.
What makes you so sure?
What is she saying?
Well, you know women. They talk about nothing. I hardly listen.
Was there anything special about her?
Yes.
Pearls.
The corner I like.
Handcuffs I can appreciate.
Platinum and diamonds.
And she didn't buy that perfume in Algiers.
So all you noticed were the jewels and perfume.
Was there anything else?
What about the eyes?
They all have eyes,
but all that shi shi and jingle,
you don't see much of that in the Casbah.
But you do where she comes from.
Thank you.
She asked quite a few questions about you.
Yeah? What did you tell her?
What could I tell her?
Why? Did you think she might be afraid of my past?
No, but she might be a little appalled at your future.
I told her you might get off in 20 years with a good lawyer.
You wouldn't want me to get 20 years. You're too fond of me. What's her name?
So, you're thinking about her.
How could I be thinking about her when I don't know her name?
-Good morning, Pepe.
-Hello, Aicha.
Pierrot at home?
No, he's at Shinee's.
Let's go to Shinee.
What do you want?
I have a letter for Pierrot.
Give it to me.
Oh, no no no. I can't.
I swore by the ghosts of my ancestors to give it only to Pierrot.
Whose the letter from?
A woman.
What kind of a woman?
I didn't look.
Well, you tell the woman I took it away from you.
(humming)
This vulgar game is hardly worth the compromise to ones dignity involved in playing it.
It's vulgar, but it's fast.
I don't know why I waste my time in such common pursuits
with such mediocre companions.
My youth?
I intended to become a statesman.
Or?
Philosopher.
But a man's destiny is written in the stars.
We play the game.
But Fate controls the cards.
Who?
Fate.
If Fate goes on controlling the cards,
he might find a knife between his ribs.
The moving finger writes.
Ans having writ
moves on.
Stop that nonsense.
He has an ear but not for poetry.
I'm trying to think.
I would have played the ace.
Do you smell something?
I've been wondering.
Onions.
Cheese.
A mixture of cheese and onions.
I don't like it.
Would it be to much to ask you to take your nose out of my hand?
But you haven't got a hand.
Don't blow down my back.
You seem nervous.
My dear fellow,
consider yourself blackballed by this club.
He means get out.
Oh.
What are you hanging around for? This is business.
Read this.
Bad news?
Pierrot.
Wait for me.
I would like it better if you didn't hang around so much
with Regis.
Why?
Did you ever see a clock that pointed to two and struck four
when it is really quarter past twelve?
Well,
you will find Regis is like that.
He doesn't ring two.
That's what you say, but you can't prove it.
Well.
If I say so, that's enough.
Regis gets along alright with me.
That's why I'm telling you. I don't like it.
Well I do.
In business, I'll do anything you say, Pepe.
But outside business I'll do as I please.
Oh, so.
You'll do as you please?
It's a good thing I like you.
Now get out.
Nice kid.
What did she write you in her last letter?
She had a cold. She said she'd start as soon as she felt better.
Ah, then you knew she was coming.
I sent her a money order.
In that case, it isn't so strange.
And yet it's odd that she should arrive in Algiers like that
without letting you know,
That's what I thought.
Ah.
Is this her handwriting?
Have you another letter?
Yes, I think so.
Good. We'll put them both together
like a pair of Siamese twins.
Then we'll see if they're both from the same mama.
Well, what do you think?
Same mistakes in spelling.
Our poor dear mamas can never spell.
Same 'n'.
Same what?
And the crossing of the 't'.
Well, that settles it. You can always tell by the crossing of the 't'.
Then, you think it's alright?
Well, you can see with your own eyes.
Then, I don;t want her to be there worrying.
-After all, she's 62.
-Oh, my mother lived to 84.
She never felt better than the day she died.
Where's that?
If I know it well, half hour's walk.
I can take you there if you wish to go.
I've got to go. I've got to see her.
Fortunately, you can rely on me.
It's good of you to help me, Regis.
You're a real friend.
Well, that's how I am. Sensitive.
You ready, Gaby?
Andre just phoned. They're waiting on the terrace.
If I sat for five minutes, Andre phones.
Well, don't you like having him so attentive?
Love it.
I've just been sitting here,
thinking that I'm the happiest girl in the world.
Well, you ought to be.
Marrying a man who adores you and can give you everything in the world you ever dreamed about.
That's my trouble.
I'm such a fool.
I go dreaming about the wrong things.
Well, that's a terrible mistake.
Marie,
remember the time
in the Baltoin Bargain Basement.
The two of behind a counter. Handkerchiefs. Gloves.
Hosiery.
And don't you forget it.
I won't.
After all, you don't marry for fun.
I didn't.
Hello, Inspector.
So you've already met.
I took the liberty of presenting myself.
As you see, I couldn't wait to take advantage of your invitation last night.
I'm glad.
Yes, we're all glad.
Inspector,
will you tell my fiance where I was last night during the shooting?
But with me.
There you see?
And who did we meet?
Pepe le Moko.
Nice friends you have.
In prisoners, one can't choose.
You don't mean Pepe le Moko,
the famous criminal?
The one they're all talking about?
He'd like to hear you say that.
Just a common law-breaker.
Have you seen him since?
This morning.
Did he say anything bout me?
Well, in a way.
Oh, I know.
My pearls.
A connoisseur can admire pearls without neglecting the wearer.
Oh, he means if he stole your pearls, he'd steal you with them.
Does that frighten you, Gaby?
Oh, it sounds marvelous to me.
I'd like to meet him.
It could easily be arranged
if you wish to visit the Casbah again with a suitable guide.
How's that, Andre? An adventure.
Well, that's what we're here for.
Once is enough for me. I don't like natives.
Then, we'll go with Maxim. You'll protect us. Won't you, Maxim?
I'm at my best among natives.
Tonight, Inspector? If it's convenient.
Uh huh.
Pepe.
Yes.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
What are you looking at like that?
France.
You can't see France.
Well, there is no harm in trying.
Pepe, what are you looking at like that?
A ship.
Doesn't it make you seasick to look at boats?
Doesn't it give you a headache to ask so many questions?
No.
Why? Have you got a headache?
No. I'm thinking.
Well, that's sure to give you a headache.
I don't think with my head but with my heart.
Then, you'd better tell me.
It's nothing.
If it's nothing, you'd better tell me.
Oh, I'll get mad if you go on like this.
I want you to get mad.
Shout at me and hurt me,
but don't treat me as if I'm not here.
Oh, I know you're here.
No you don't.
You're dreaming about something
with your eyes wide open.
I wish you'd dream about me.
Look.
You've always lived in the Casbah.
For you, there is nothing outside.
The Casbah is big enough.
Not for me.
It's like being in a grave.
Pepe.
Can't stand much more of it.
If you want to go away, I'll go with you.
Thanks.
Won't you take me?
I wish I could.
Paris is a long way off.
I don't care.
It's different there.
Couldn't you be happy with me in Paris?
You think I'd look funny in Paris.
Answer me.
Oh, but it isn't you, Ines.
It's the Casbah.
You belong here.
You don't understand the way I feel.
I've stood it for two years.
The time comes when you can't stand anymore.
Morning, noon, and night.
The same things. The same people.
I'm fed up.
I've had enough.
You're tired of me.
It has nothing to do with you.
I want to get away.
That has nothing to do with me?
Do you know when you're going away? Never.
You'll see.
You can't do it.
Never.
I am the Casbah. I'll keep you.
Just try to get away and you will find out.
It's funny for the police to come in and try to arrest you.
You're in prison already. You're in the Casbah with the wall around you.
Stop it.
There's nothing else. You'll never have anything else.
Stop it I tell you.
I am glad. There is no France for you. No Paris. No boulevards.
Are you through?
No.
Who is it?
Pierrot?
It's me, Aicha
Pepe.
I don't know what to do.
Pierrot.
I can't find him.
Did you go to Shinee's?
Yes.
And I Mother Teche's and the Ali Baba
and the Algerians.
Everywhere.
-He ought to be back by now.
-Back?
Why did he go into town?
To see his mother.
What do you mean to see his mother?
He got a letter from her.
L'Arbi brought it.
Then, he went down with Regis.
And then Regis came back, but Pierrot
I'm still waiting for him, that's all.
Where's Regis?
At the Algerians.
No need to go down.
See you later.
Hello, Regis.
What's your hurry?
Oh, I'm in no hurry.
Good. Then, come along with me.
I'm waiting for Pierrot. We can wait for him together.
But listen, Pepe. I've got to go down.
What's the matter? What makes you so nervous?
Me? Nervous?
Why should I be nervous?
That's just it. Why?
Well. It's only that usually you hardly say hello to me and when you do so I don't expect it when you don't.
I'm a little surprised when you do because you don't usually.
Well, you see. I haven't appreciated you at your real value.
That's the trouble.
So, I made a mistake.
Shall we go?
Where?
Oh, any quiet corner where we can talk.
I've been hearing great stories about your courage.
My courage?
You're surprised?
No.
I even hear you proved it.
Me?
Yes, you.
Well, it's possible. One can be brave without knowing it.
Of course.
How? How did I prove it?
Why by going down into town with Pierrot.
Ah, not everybody would have done that.
Oh, yes.
And after that you came back here.
That was a brave thing to do.
Yes. Wasn't it?
Now you see
why I have completely changed my ideas about you.
You're right.
I was helping the boy out. Nothing more.
Of course.
Tell me.
Where did you leave Pierrot?
Somewhere. I don't quite remember.
That's it.
You don't mind if I refresh your memory, do you?
He went to see his poor old mother.
How is she?
I didn't see her.
Why not?
She was in bed sick. He didn't want to disturb her.
It must have been an awful shock for Pierrot.
He thought she was in France.
I think he got a letter.
Did you see it?
Just a glimpse.
So you left him?
And you came back alone.
He wanted to stay with her.
That's natural.
Yes, very natural.
Exactly.
Of course.
Want me?
No, we're just talking.
Sit down.
Regis did a fine thing today.
He went down into town with Pierrot.
Fine.
And now you're waiting for poor Pierrot.
Why poor Pierrot?
Because he went down with Regis.
What of it?
Nothing.
Maybe I should say
and now you're waiting for Pierrot
with poor Regis.
What's the matter? Huh?
I've gotta have air.
Just relax.
Take it easy.
We understand how anxious you are about Pierrot. Here.
Take this.
Go ahead. Drink.
Don't take a bite out of it.
I don't know what's the matter with me.
You'll get over it.
In an hour, you'll feel much better.
Let me go.
With a fever like that?
You musn't think of exerting yourself.
Cigarette?
Don't make such a fuss.
Go on and smoke.
It'll settle your nerves.
Say, Pepe.
His hair is getting a little long here on his neck.
Don't you think we ought to cut it for him?
You were fond of Pierrot, weren't you?
Oh, I was. I am fond of him.
Well, then.
You don't want to leave before he gets back.
You want to know why he has been detained.
-Don't you?
-Yes yes yes.
Must be the fever.
I'm worried about you.
He's burning up.
I'm afraid he'll sizzle before too long.
I don't know anything about Pierrot.
Pepe. Pepe. Let me go. You know me; you know I'm alright.
Tell me you do. Last night, I was the one who came to warn you.
Yes, you were the one.
Let me go.
He's delirious.
This is terrible.
He may not last the next round.
How about a little game to calm him down?
Alright.
It is really alarming.
If I may say so, he is not at his best.
He must stay right where he is.
We can't be too careful.
What are you doing?
Ines.
Try to find him, and bring him back. Quick.
He went down with Regis.
If you bring him back,
Regis may recover.
Alright.
Cut 'em, Regis.
The black spot.
Oh, that's bad.
Suppose you can't find him.
Don't worry.
This way.
The women look so mysterious.
No doubt they'd say the same about you.
Trump?
But you've got a heart.
What's the matter with me? I'm not myself.
What kind of a game is this?
Concentrate.
He's thinking of Pierrot.
Yes, of course.
Worry about a friend can cause unutterable anguish to a sensitive nature.
Do you mean it makes him sweat?
A certain exudation hyper-actuated by an emotional stimulation.
You don't mean him?
Deal me out.
Take care of Regis.
Never go back on a friend when he is in trouble.
Still waiting, little one?
You know what this reminds me of? A little place in New York on 42nd street.
That's the thing about travelling.
There's always something different.
One time, I was in Corsica and I thought I was in Turkey.
Remember the time we were on the Nile and I thought it was Venice?
Tell me. Do they have native music here?
On the phonograph.
Oh. Well.
What's that one?
Never heard of it.
Must be native music.
So you wanted to take another look at this strange, wild animal.
Strange
but not so very wild.
How do you like my cage?
I don't know. Yet.
Do you like Algiers.
I don't like travelling; makes me homesick.
Does it?
I can't see Paris when I open my eyes in the morning.
I want to go right back to sleep.
Do you know Paris?
Do I know Paris?
Now is summertime.
Champs-lyses.
La Gare du Nord.
The Opra, Boulevard des Capucines
La Chapelle
Rue Montmartre
Boulevard de Rochechouart
Rue Fontaine
La Place Blanche.
What a small world.
Cigarette?
Thanks.
Got a light?
We are a long way from home.
Excuse me.
Well?
He still thinks he's playing his last card.
Not bad.
I'll tell her you said so.
No no no. I mean the rock she's wearing.
Now if it was me, I'd get them first and then do the fancy stuff afterward.
Shut up
You can't talk to me like that.
You heard me. Shut up.
Okay.
He was talking about me.
He was worried about you.
About me?
All that stuff you're holding.
That's nice of him.
You're not worried yourself?
No.
Not while I'm with you.
Right.
This is something.
Isn't it? And it hardly weighs anything.
At least
20,000 francs.
Add a zero.
I mean what I would get for it.
Here.
Put it on again.
You put it on.
Want to dance?
Yes.
What's your name?
Gabrielle.
They call me Gabby.
Married?
No.
Widowed?
Why not?
Who are you with?
My fiance.
What is he like?
Generous.
Stuck being at the hotel?
I let him.
What are you laughing at?
It's nothing.
-Too bad.
-Too bad?
Too bad I don't know you better.
Why?
Because I will slap your face.
When people laugh around me, I like to know why.
This all reminds me of when I was a kid.
We used to dance in the streets
on holidays, New Years, first of May.
14th of July.
Why do you know?
What do you think I was doing?
Too bad you weren't in my
neighbourhood, Rue de la Bruyre
Rue de la Bruyre?
That's where I lived.
I went to school on the hill.
That was almost next door to me.
No.
Let's go out.
Where to?
To the terrace.
Can you see the harbor?
You can see Montmartre.
And Les Champs-lyses.
And Place Blanche.
I love Place Blanche.
Oh, I can't.
I can't leave my friends.
But I'll come back.
When?
As soon as I can.
Tomorrow.
How can I be sure?
I never break a promise.
Let me go.
Why should I?
'Cause I ask you.
Say please.
You're rude.
Am I?
I'll be expecting you.
Here.
It would be nice if we could meet at Place Blanche.
Well, what about Pierrot?
I don't know.
Didn't you go down to find him?
I didn't want to leave you alone.
I'm not alone. I'm with madame.
Do as I told you.
Pierrot.
Where is he?
Who?
Regis. Where is he?
Come on.
They got me, Pepe.
The police.
I didn't listen to you.
I'll help you.
No. No.
No.
Oh, no.
Pierrot?
There's no sense to it.
That's what they said.
They?
Those people.
They were frightened.
Said they'd never come back.
I was fond of Pierrot.
I regarded him almost as a son.
Well, he's closed his umbrella.
Pepe,
there's no use in thinking about Pierrot.
Don't you tell me what to think.
This a sad thing.
Are you finished?
I beg your pardon.
You were fond of him. That's enough.
Can't a man talk?
Well?
Well.
It's finished.
I did everything you would have done, Pepe.
I was all alone at the cemetery.
I followed the custom of your people.
A handful of earth on the body.
And flowers
to make him feel at home in such a strange place.
It's hard not to be able to go sown to say
goodbye to your friend on his last journey.
I'm your friend, Pepe.
I lnow how you feel; you'er a prisoner in the Casbah.
But the day will come when they won't be able to prevent your leaving.
You'll go out of the Casbah in spite of them all.
I'll get out whenever I wish.
When you go, you'll go quietly the way Pierrot went.
Feet first.
Be patient.
When the time comes, they'll take off their hats and let you pass.
I'll go out alive.
I don't think you're as foolish as that.
Grandperre,
I've heard enough.
Music. Singing. Gibberish.
I'm sorry for you.
How is she?
She?
You know.
I'm afraid you won't see her again. The last visit was a little too much for her.
She got a bad impression of the Casbah.
It's a pity.
Why should it be a pity?
For your sake since it seems to mean so much to you.
To me?
So that's what you're so sorry about.
Why are you standing there staring at me?
Do as I tell you.
Go down.
And you too.
Get out.
I've had enough.
And you.
I'm sick of looking at you.
You seem to be sick of everything.
Right.
I'd bring her up to see you again if it were possible, but there's no chance.
So.
She's not coming back.
That's fine.
What?
All that swell jewelry, you had it right in the palm of your hand.
That's enough.
These people who look as if they can tear down everything
and when a woman looks at them, they get as soft as butter.
Get out.
Well, I'm not made of butter. Not me.
Ok.
Your friends have no tact, my dear Pepe.
They have no respect for the beauty of your anguish.
I know how it pains you to live among this cattle.
Let me assure you.
They can't keep me here.
I'm free.
Free to go.
I'm sick of it.
All of you.
I'm sick of listening to you.
And I'm sick of looking at you.
I'll get out when I feel like it.
None of you can stop me.
Listen to me, Pepe.
I don't need your advice.
None of you.
I'm free to do as I please.
Free. You hear that?
You're walking into a trap.
You know better.
They can't touch me. I'm going down. Get out of the way.
Let me. And when I please is now. Get out of my way.
He's gone mad. He's going down to the town.
He won't listen.
Hello.
Good.
I'll attend to it.
Inspector Slimane.
He says Pepe le Moko is coming out.
Pepe.
Pepe, don't go.
You're mad.
Pepe, don't go. Please don't go.
I didn't want to tell you this, but she's up there now
at your old house waiting for you.
Where is she?
You lied to me, didn't you?
Answer me. Didn't you?
It was the only way I could keep you from going.
If I had asked you not to go for me,
you wouldn't have listened to me.
So.
You ought to be fed up with a fellow like me.
I didn't know I could make such a fool of myself.
Ines, have something better than this.
It's not what you deserve.
It's what you want.
Why do you worry about me?
It's not good.
I have a sharp
that brings me luck.
You brought us both luck this time.
All the while I went running,
I kept my hand so.
But you caught me.
I didn't know you could run so fast.
Don't forget; I've had practice.
But nobody ever caught me before.
Next time, give me a head start.
Next time?
Don't worry.
Not 'til I catch my breath.
I'm thirsty.
I'll get it.
No you won't.
Here I am.
I said I'd be here.
Well?
You look as though you've seen a ghost.
You're beautiful.
That's easy to say.
I know a lot of people have told you.
But what I'm telling you is different. See?
For me, you're more than that.
For two years, I've been lost.
Like walking in my sleep.
Slowly I wake up. That's you.
I don't know what I've been doing all that time, waiting for you without knowing it.
Do you know what you are to me?
Paris. That's you.
Paris.
With you, I escape.
Follow me?
The whole town
is spring morning in Paris.
You're lovely.
You're marvelous.
And do you know what you remind me of?
The subway.
Close your eyes.
Listen.
Can you hear it?
That's my heart beating.
Dose it go like a subway train?
Faster.
You're all silk,
and you jingle when you walk.
And with all that shi shi, you make me think of the subway.
Isn't that funny?
And potato chips
and coffee on the boulevard.
What did you do before?
Before what?
Before the jewels.
I wanted them.
It's late.
I must go.
Suppose you don't come tomorrow.
Suppose I don't.
Can't you ever get away from the Casbah?
Why do you ask?
Can't you?
No.
I'm caught here
like a bear in a hole,
dogs barking, hunters all around,
no way out of it.
Do you like that?
Maybe it's lucky for you.
I don't like it.
And it's not lucky.
You're right.
If you don't come back, I might do anything.
I might go down to the hotel to get you.
Tomorrow, Pepe.
Tomorrow?
I never break a promise.
You smell good.
The subway?
Streamlined.
Hey.
Anton.
Tomorrow.
5 o'clock.
Did you get them?
What?
The hardware.
What's the matter with you?
If you didn't get the jewels, you're simply wasting your time.
What were you doing in there?
Where?
There.
You're mistaken.
We were not there.
Say that again.
We were in Paris.
What?
Okay.
Life is simple if you try to enjoy before you die every bit of happiness along the way.
Take the joy that comes to you.
Suddenly the world is too with the song that keeps you dancing every day.
That's the life.
Fall in love and life is sunny.
That's the life you don't need money
if you've got a little honey in your arms.
That's the life.
I'm in heaven and I know it.
Can I help it if I show it?
Life is sweet as can be for me.
Love is very necessary.
Fall in love and you'll be happy. That's the life.
You don't know just what you miss if you live without a kiss
for a kiss can bring your winter into spring.
Everybody will agree. If you fall in love like me, you'll be happy, you will laugh, and you will sing.
That's the life.
That's the life we should be living.
Kiss morning, noon, and evening. That's the life that I'll be living.
That's the moon. That's the life.
There is nothing like that feeling.
Tell me what is more appealing
than the feeling you're in love
for sure.
Love is very necessary. Fall in love and you'll be happy. That's the life.
Love is very necessary.
Fall in love and you'll be happy. That's the life.
Pepe, what's happened?
Don't you know?
It's a holiday.
No, I didn't know what day it is.
It's Sunday. Everyone gets a holiday.
But it's not Sunday.
If I say so, it's Sunday.
It's Thursday.
That's the trouble with you; you always think it's Thursday.
I didn't think so yesterday.
Just as a favor to me, let it be Sunday.
I want to stroll on the boulevard.
I have a date at the Place Blanche.
Hello, everybody.
How do you like my singing?
What's the good of it?
You ought to appreciate the finer things of life.
Who? Him?
When you feel like that, sing.
It quiets the nerves.
You seem pleased. You've seen her again.
Wouldn't you like to know.
Oh, well. If you don't want to confide in me.
Well, our inspector got himself a haircut.
Did she come back?
A regular Romeo.
You ought to get a permanent wave.
You're expecting her again today?
The trouble with you, Inspector, is that you do too much inspecting.
Now,
not a word about what I have told you.
Just between ourselves,
yup.
Inspector.
Good afternoon.
I was puzzled when you phoned.
My mission is a rather delicate one
but necessary.
I merely wish to suggest that
your fiance is a little too fond of
shall we say, the local color of the Casbah.
What is all this?
The Casbah is hardly the place for a woman alone.
She attracts too much attention,
excites too much desire.
If we, naturally, wish to protect her from any embarrassment.
Further embarrassment can very easily be avoided.
She must not return to the Casbah.
Come in.
Sorry to disturb you.
You're going out?
Looks that way.
Where are you going?
A walk.
But where?
In the Champs-lyses.
May I ask you to give me a sensible answer?
Then ask me a sensible question. Where could I go?
I don't know anyone in Algiers.
I just walk straight ahead.
Straight ahead?
And where does that take you?
I'll know when I get there.
No you won't
because you're not going.
Oh, yes, my dear.
Your hotel bores me.
The head waiter looks like an undertaker.
An every time I step into this apartment
it looks more like a funeral parlor.
Goodbye, darling.
I know where you're going.
Ah?
You're going to the Casbah.
So?
You go there every day.
Do I?
To meet Pepe le Moko.
So now you're spying on me?
You're going to be my wife.
You don't make it a very pleasant prospect.
And I won't allow you to behave like this.
I'm glad you told me.
What do you mean?
We've got to be honest.
Why do you think I'm marrying you?
Look at yourself, and now look at me.
I've never lied to you.
You knew I didn't love you when I promised to marry you, and you though it was alright.
Until we are married, I'll do as I please.
That's fair enough.
I forbid you to go.
It's a waste of time.
If you go now, there'll be no use in you coming back.
You've thought it all out pretty clearly. Haven't you?
And I advise you to do the same.
Alright.
Goodbye.
Do it, Gaby. Don't.
No.
What?
You can't go to the Casbah.
But really.
Your fiance was trying to spare you.
He didn't want to tell you the truth as I told it to him.
An attempt was made to capture Pepe le Moko this afternoon.
The attempt was successful.
He was taken?
Not alive.
He was killed.
I just came to tell you, it's Thursday.
I know.
I was right all the time.
You see, I'm not just a fool as you think.
So this is the Place Blanche.
It's not much fun on Thursday, is it?
It doesn't seem like Paris.
What's got into him?
Weren't you ever disappointed in love?
Yes. Badly.
I'll try to please you.
I'm like Pepe.
I like 'em with diamonds.
Now he's missed his chance.
So I guess I'll have to go downtown and give my personal attention to madam's hardware.
What steamer?
The Ville d'Algers? Ten o'clock? Good.
Make the reservation.
Are you leaving?
I suppose you won't stay for the funeral.
Four. First class.
Oh. Send up some whiskey and soda.
You'll have a drink.
Just a short one.
Make you feel better.
Anything wrong?
Why don't you sing?
Why don't you mind your own business?
I am.
Only I just though you might be interested.
I'm going downtown.
What for?
Unlike you, I'm bored.
Anything in your mind?
Just to look things over.
-When are you going?
-Now. No use to see a lawyer about it.
-Do me a favor.
-Sure.
I want you to deliver a letter.
I'd take anything that isn't loaded.
Ok. I get the idea.
Maybe I don't look like Cupid, but I'll manage.
Pen and paper.
Go to the servants' entrance.
Give someone a good tip.
And tell them you've got to have an answer.
Don't worry. I won't come back empty handed.
I'll wait for you at your house.
I'll be back in two hours. Tell Tania.
Good luck.
What time is it?
9 o'clock.
Is that all?
In the morning.
Sun is out.
I slept all that time?
Carlos?
He hasn't come back.
He hasn't come back?
I sat up all night.
I'd like to see him back with what I've got to tell him.
This time, I'll make him listen to me.
Poor Carlos.
Same old story.
Well.
Life is like that.
Yeah.
And we're dumb enough to hang on because we don't want to stir it when.
Smart.
Is Pepe here?
What do you want?
We've been looking for you everywhere. Why weren't you at home?
Because I'm here.
What do you want, L'Arbi?
I must speak to you alone.
What's the matter with us?
Ever got small pox?
-It's alright; you can talk.
-Pepe, I'm ashamed of myself.
What's new about that?
-Oh, It's more than you think.
-I doubt that.
Go ahead and insult me.
I deserve it.
You flatter yourself.
It's about the letter from Pierrot's mother.
I brought it and gave it to Aicha, but I didn't know it was from the police.
If I had known the letter was written by Regis, I wouldn't have done it. Never.
Go on.
It was really a woman who gave me the letter.
I, if I had known the truth, I wouldn't have touched it.
I'm an informer.
Yes, but I wouldn't have done a thing like that.
Oh, you're only half an informer.
The other half is alright.
Oh, that's why I'm here.
For what?
I couldn't stand it any longer. Forgive me, Pepe.
Alright. Stop grovelling; it makes me sick.
I want you to have a good opinion of me.
So?
I want you to believe me.
That's why I'm here,
to tell you
they got Carlos.
What about Carlos?
The police took him.
-How much did you sell him for?
-I wouldn't be here if I'd sold him.
First Pierrot, then Carlos.
Bad luck always runs in threes.
Your turn will be next, Pepe.
Don't be so sure.
So they arrested him.
Who did it?
Inspector Louvain.
They were about a dozen of them surrounding him.
Was there any shooting?
No, no. They managed very quietly in a nice way.
What did you have to do with it?
I was at the police station when they brought Carlos in.
I had the chance to see him in his cell.
They gave me a letter,
the one you had given him.
Told me to take it to the hotel.
Every time there is a letter, he is the one that brings it.
It looks funny to me.
Be quiet.
Oh, I am to be quiet while you write letters to other women?
Never mind that.
You never wrote a letter to me.
Shut up.
So you went to the hotel with the letter.
I did it for you, Pepe.
You get it?
What?
The answer.
Oh, she wouldn't write you.
But she couldn't.
She's being closely watched.
But she expects you this morning.
You can go down without any risk.
Go to her.
Service entrance in the back of the hotel.
She'll be watching from her window.
Is that all?
She wants to come out, but she couldn't get away.
-You're not going out, Pepe. You can't.
-I told you to shut up.
Go on.
She's waiting for me to bring the answer.
What shall I tell her?
She's waiting for it.
Yes.
I'll take the answer myself.
You wait here.
But Pepe.
Don't worry.
My friends will take good care of you
until I come back.
But she expects me.
What?
Nothing.
I'll wait.
Tell me.
What about Carlos?
Didn't he say anything else?
Nothing.
They search him?
Yes.
Then they took away the five thousand.
-You're sure he didn't slip the five thousand to you?
-No.
You're sure?
What?
Lovain took the money. I saw him put it in his desk.
You said Gaby couldn't write because she was watched.
Yes.
But in a little while she'll be able to see me.
That's funny.
He's going to move away.
Oh, I see.
-But why couldn't she write to me?
-He was there.
But she talked to you.
Because.
Because you don't know.
Now there is another thing that doesn't fit in your story.
How was Louvain able to take 5000 francs from Carlos
when Carlos didn't have a hundred?
I don't know.
Do you think Carlos is dumb enough to give you my letter?
All joking aside.
Do you think me so stupid as to believe he would give it to you?
-All joking aside.
-I give you my word.
-And then I will go down to see her.
-Yes.
A woman who is closely watched,
it's funny the way she can do things.
Now I've laughed enough!
Do you hear me?
You've made a fool of me!
Carlos was arrested.
Now tell me what happened.
Shall I break your neck to refresh your memory?
No, Pepe.
Slimane planned it all.
Yeah?
He told me to come for you.
- Go on.
- He thinks you'll come down.
- Then?
The hotel is surrounded, they're waiting.
Did you see the girl?
No.
Why didn't she come up yesterday?
He told her you'd been killed.
Slimane planned the whole thing.
Is that all?
Yes.
Thanks.
You can't do it, Pepe.
You can't leave me. What have I done?
It has nothing to do with you, Ines.
You're a good kid, but this can't be helped.
It's not your fault.
I won't let you do it. I won't let you. You'll be killed.
Blame it on the Casbah.
It's for her. You don't care about anything else, so you're throwing away your life.
But it's my own life.
Don't do it, Pepe. Don't go. Listen to me.
Pepe.
Wait.
We didn't expect you.
He's not coming here.
He's gone to the boat.
You expect me to believe that?
He is going away with her.
So you're the one to betray him.
You couldn't wait to run to me.
You call it love, but it means you'd kill him before you'd let him go free. That's what you've done.
Sure as if you'd held a gun in your hands.
I couldn't let him go.
I couldn't lose him.
I thought I'd figured all the moves, but I miscalculated.
I didn't think of you.
That's just fine.
In a few more minutes, it might have been put of our hands.
Don't go.
-Give him a chance.
-I did.
But you knew. You planned it this way.
So he'd walk into a trap. And he's done it
with your help.
Come on.
You know, the pleasant thing about travelling is going back home.
It's like going away again.
Oh I had a good time. Didn't you, Andre?
Me?
I never laughed so much in my life.
You see, Pepe,
we meet at the appointed time.
Tell the truth.
I almost missed the appointment.
Not here.
As you wish.
I can't refuse an old friend.
All aboard who goes on board.
Let me wait here until it leaves.
It's not much to ask.
I can't get away.
I know I can trust you.
Gaby.
I'm sorry, Pepe.
He thought you were going to escape.
And
so I have,
my friend.