Th I rty thousand.
F rom the Russians?
N o , from the F rench.
F rom the Russians , we captu
re more than that every day.
M r. Postman.
War is war and sch napps is sch
napps , but busi ness m ust go on.
You d id n't leave
the mai I yet th is morn I ng.
Ah , I'm sorry, M r. Meyer.
H el lo , H I m melstoss .
Anyth I ng for us today?
N o , no , Master Peter.
C' mon ,
there m ust be someth I ng.
H ere , here you go , you
ng rascal . (LAU G H I N G)
There . Th is is the last
mai I I del iver, anyhow.
What?
Tomorrow
I change u n iform.
You're goi ng
I n the army?
Yes , I was cal led.
I'm a sergeant I n the
reserves , you know.
I ' I I be cal led myself, if it
doesn't end I n a few months.
It wi I I , thoug h.
I'm su re you're rig ht,
M r. Meyer.
(MARC H I N G BAN D AP P ROAC H I N G)
(TAL KI N G I N D I STI N CTLY)
...and joi n the m ig hty army
that is defend I ng ou r
cou ntry, ou r fatherland.
N ow, my beloved class ,
th is is what we m ust do.
Stri ke with al I ou r power.
G ive every ou nce of strength
to wi n victory before
the end of the year.
It is with rel uctance that I
bri ng th is su bject u p agai n.
You are the I ife of
the fatherland , you boys.
You are the I ron men
of Germany.
You are the gay heroes
who wi I I repu lse the enemy
when you are
cal led u pon to do so.
It is not for me
to suggest that any of you
shou ld stand u p and offer
to defend h is cou ntry.
B ut I wonder if such a th I ng
is goi ng th roug h you r heads.
I know that
I n one of the schools
the boys have risen u p
I n the classroom
and en I isted I n a mass.
B ut, of cou rse , if such a
th I ng shou ld happen here
you wou ld not blame me
for a feel I ng of pride.
Perhaps some wi I I say
that you should not
be allowed to go yet,
that you are too young, that you
ha ve homes, mothers, fathers,
that you should
not be torn away.
Are your fathers so
forgetful of their fatherland
that they would let it
perish rather than you ?
Are you r mothers so weak
that they can not send a son
to defend the land
wh ich gave them bi rth ?
And after al I ,
is a I ittle experience
such a bad th I ng
for a boy?
Is the honor
of weari ng a u n iform
someth I ng from
wh ich we shou ld ru n ?
And if our young ladies glory
in those who wear it,
is that anything
to be ashamed of?
I know you have never desi
red the ad u lation of heroes.
That has not been
part of my teach I ng.
We have soug ht to
make ou rselves worthy
and let acclai m
come when it wou ld.
B ut to be foremost
I n battle
is a vi rtue
not to be despised.
I bel ieve it wi I I be
a q u ick war,
that there wi I I be
few losses.
B ut if losses
there m ust be ,
then let us remem ber
the Lati n ph rase
wh ich m ust have come to
the I I ps of many a Roman
when he stood em battled
I n a foreig n land ,
"Dulce et decorum
est pro patria mori."
"Sweet and fitti ng it is
to d ie for the fatherland. "
Some of you
may have am bitions.
I know of one you ng man who
has g reat prom ise as a writer
and he has written
the fi rst act of a tragedy
wh ich wou ld be a cred it
to one of the masters.
And he is d ream I ng ,
I su ppose ,
of fol lowi ng I n the footsteps
of Goethe and Sch I I ler,
and I hope he wi I I.
B ut now ou r cou ntry cal ls.
The fatherland
needs leaders.
Personal am bition
m ust be th rown aside
I n the one g reat sacrifice
for ou r cou ntry.
H ere is a g lorious
beg I n n I ng for you r I ives.
The field of honor
cal ls you.
Why are we here?
You , Kropp ,
what has kept you back?
You , M uel ler, you know
how m uch you are needed ?
Ah , I see you look
at you r leader.
And I , too ,
look to you , Pau I Bäu mer,
and I wonder what
you are goi ng to do.
I ' I I go .
I want to go.
Cou nt on me.
Me , too.
I'm ready.
I'm not gon na stay home.
(AL I C HANTI N G)
Fol low me ! E n I sit now!
N o more classes!
Don't be a q u itter.
Come on , Beh n!
Stick together. That's
what we've got to do.
Let's al I stick together.
Come on , Beh n.
Al I rig ht.
I ' I I go.
That's the way!
Let's go!
S I ng ! Let's si ng ! Come on!
(AL I S I N G I N G I N G E RMAN)
Keep I n I I ne ,
there , sold iers.
(LAU G H I N G)
Anyth I ng you say, General.
Detai I , halt!
Left face!
Get I nto u n iform ,
ready to report. Fal I out.
(AL I EXC LAI M I N G EXC ITE D LY)
I bet you a place I I ke th is
gets you I n good cond ition.
You have to be
for the long marches.
I'm gon na get I n
the caval ry and ride.
N o caval ry for me.
I nfantry's where
you see the fig hti ng.
Where are al I the g u ns?
That's what I want to know.
O h , you don't get a g u n
for a long wh I le yet.
Wel I , if I'm gon na bu m p off the
enemy, I gotta have some practice.
Ow!
Bayonet d ri I I .
That's what I want.
(EXC LAI MS)
You won a medal
that ti me , M uel ler.
You wait. I n about a month ,
I ' I I be covered with them.
Say, keep you r boots
out of my face.
Why, it's an honor to have
those boots I n you r face.
They're the best pai r I n the
army. My u ncle gave them to me.
Just look at that
special I m ported leather.
P ut them anyplace you I I ke ,
except I n my face.
N ot even a kitchen
maid ' I I look at me I n th is.
Attention!
Wel I , for the love of.. .
It's H I m melstoss!
So it is.
And al I d ressed u p.
H el lo , H I m m ie.
You d id n't th I n k you 'd see
me agai n so soon , d id you ?
You see my ran k?
S u re.
Fal I back, then!
H I m melstoss , we certai
n ly are g lad to see you.
What d id you say?
I was goi ng to say.. .
N ever m I nd!
What's the matter
with you , H I m melstoss?
When you add ress you r
su perior officer, say "si r. "
Where'd he get
such a n ice u n iform ?
Wi I I there be any
mai I for us , H I m m ie?
Q u iet!
My dear fel low,
you ' re shouti ng.
Come on , H I m melstoss .
We know you.
Take off
the false wh iskers.
I bel ieve you mean it.
You ' I I fi nd out
that I mean it.
B ut on ly th ree days ago
you were ou r postman.
S I lence!
Come back here!
Li ne u p!
Li ne u p ! Get I n some ki nd of a
I I ne ! Don't even th I n k about it.
Al I of you !
Li ne u p , I say!
(LAU G H I N G)
H m m.
What a pretty sig ht that is.
H ave you never heard
of stand I ng I n I I ne?
You make
a fi ne mess of it.
Wel I , I'll have to
teach you.
We' I I spend
the whole day on it, h u h ?
You may be stu pid ,
but I'm used to that.
And then there' I I be
plenty of other th I ngs , too.
O h , I'll not neg lect you.
H m m.
You're not m uch to beg I
n with , but I'll do my best.
I see that we have come here
with a sl ig ht m isu nderstand I ng ,
and we' I I correct that,
too , won't we , h u h ?
And the fi rst th I ng to do is to
forget everyth I ng you ever knew.
Everyth I ng you ever learned ,
forget ! See?
Forget what you've been and
what you th I n k you ' re goi ng to be.
You're goi ng to be sold iers ,
and that's al I!
I ' I I take the mother's m I I k out
of you . I ' I I make you hard-boi led.
I ' I I make sold iers
out of you or ki I I you!
N ow, sal ute!
Attention!
Detach ment, I ie down!
Down!
H ead down!
Keep you r head down , Bäu mer!
Detach ment, get u p!
Advance!
(G IVI N G MARC H I N G O RD E RS)
N ow, si ng!
(AL I S I N G I N G D I S I NTE RESTE D LY)
Do you cal I
that si ng I ng ?
Detach ment, halt!
So , we have
no spi rit, h u h ?
We are I n no mood
for recreation.
Work is what
we want. Good!
Then we' I I go
back to work.
Detach ment, I ie down!
Keep you r head down.
N ow, si ng!
(AL I S I N G I N G LO U D LY
I N G E RMAN)
Men , halt!
O rder, arms!
I nspection at 3 : 00 .
D ism issed!
(I N D I STI N CT)
O h , that swi ne ! That
means we get no ti me off.
It wi I I take fou r hou rs
to get ready for I nspection.
I 'd I I ke to know
what's I n h is m I nd.
H e hasn't got any!
I'm gon na cut h I m open
someti me and fi nd out.
H e's too th ick-ski n ned .
H e won't cut.
Th is is the fou rth ti me he's
made me d isappoi nt that poor g I rl.
Arms!
O rder, arms!
Left shou lder, arms!
Sq uad , rig ht.
To the rig ht, march!
Left, left, left, left.
Col u m n , left, march!
Left, h ut...
Sq uad , left march!
Forward , march ! Left.
Detach ment, halt!
P resent arms!
H I m melstoss.
Excel lent work. They're
goi ng u p front tomorrow.
I recom mend
leave ti I I'm id n ig ht.
H I MM E LSTOSS : Very good , si r.
Left shou lders , arms!
Forward march . Left,
left, straig ht ahead!
N ow, left.
We're clear.
(LAU G H I N G)
H I MM E LSTOSS :
Left, left, left.
Detach ment, I ie down!
C rawl forward!
H e spoi led ou r leave . I ' I
I never forg ive h I m for that.
The rat!
Leave ti I I'm id n ig ht.
(SCO F FS)
It' I I take ti I I'm id n ig ht
to d ry ou r clothes.
There goes
the fi lthy ape now.
Wh I le we slave over th is m ud ,
he goes off to have a few d ri n ks.
Someday I'm goi ng to take
one smack at h I m , j ust one.
Me , too . That's gon na be
my I ife's work from now on.
Why on ly one?
I'm gon na take several.
I'm ig ht even kick h I m
when he's down . I feel mean.
What are you doi ng ?
You're not goi ng
to desert, are you ?
What?
Listen .
I've got an idea.
(I N D I STI N CT)
(M U M B I I N G I N D I STI N CTLY)
C rawl forward .
Lie down.
(LAU G H I N G)
Lie down .
C rawl forward.
What?
(YE I I I N G)
(WH I S P E RI N G)
H ere comes an officer.
Get h I m out of here.
(AL I TAL KI N G I N D I STI N CTLY)
(EXP LOS I O N S I N D I STAN C E)
(EXP LOS I O N)
Cover!
(AL I EXC LAI M)
(BOM B WH I STL I N G)
Pau I , are you al I rig ht?
You al I rig ht?
Beh n ! Beh n!
Beh n ! Come on!
Beh n , come on .
You fool , Beh n.
Get u p ! Come on.
Sou nds I I ke more
replacements com I ng I n.
Yeah. Tjaden m ust have
gone home for that wood.
H ere's some more ,
fresh from the tu rn I p patch.
I su ppose th is
is where we bu n k.
That's me , " I. Westh us , "
and th is is where he I ives.
I d id n't know.
Wel I , you know now.
Yes. Yes , of cou rse.
It's al I rig ht.
H ere's a bu n k, Pau I.
When d id we eat last?
Don't rem I nd me.
I was fi ne
u nti I you spoke.
Where are we , anyway?
I don't know. The name on the
rai I road station's been shot off.
Wel I , there m ust be
someth I ng to eat somewhere.
I ' I I tel I you
what I'll do.
I ' I I ask those fel lows.
Sorry to d istu rb you ,
M r. Westh us.
O h , meet Deteri ng .
A better farmer never I ived.
And M r. Tjaden.
S it down.
You see , we haven 't
eaten si nce breakfast.
We thoug ht maybe you cou ld tel
I us what we oug ht to do about it.
Eat without
fu rther delay.
(LAU G H I N G)
Wel I , what's fu n ny
about that?
Th is is a bad town to bri
ng an appetite to , sold ier.
We've been here
si nce yesterday morn I ng
and we've been I ivi ng on
baled hay and razor blades.
We're wi I I I ng to buy ou r
food . Where's the canteen ?
(LAU G H I N G)
The on ly canteen
I n these reg ions
is out looki ng
for su ppl ies.
Ever hear of
Katczi nsky?
Who?
Katczi nsky.
H e's u ncan ny.
If there's any food with I n 25 m
I les , he' I I be the one to get it.
H ey !
(G RU NTS)
Whoa , whoa , whoa.
Attention!
(LAU G H I N G)
What is th is?
Vol u nteers for
the futu re general staff.
Someti me I'm gon na take
one of you vol u nteers apart
and fi nd out what makes you
leave school and joi n the Army.
At ease .
Th is is no parade g rou nd.
H u ng ry?
AL I : Yes.
Wait ! Wait a m I n ute . Wait a
m I n ute . That's no I nvitation.
Can you pay?
Yeah , su re .
I have some money.
N o , not money. That's
j ust pieces of paper.
H ave you got any
cigarettes , cigars ,
or soap , cog nac...
Yeah , yeah. Yeah.
C hewi ng tobacco?
Yeah , yeah.
TJAD E N : H ey, Kat !
Yeah ?
Are you crazy? There
ai n't enoug h here for us.
I wish you th ree
wou ld get bu m ped off.
I'm ti red of feed I
ng you for noth I ng.
B ri ng everyth I ng
you've got.
SO I D I E R 1 :
I'm so h u ng ry...
SO I D I E R 2 :
I 'd be g lad to g ive you ...
Come on!
Is th is enoug h , si r?
(AL I TAL KI N G I N D I STI N CTLY)
Kat !
H m m ?
You've got the
wi ri ng detai I ton ig ht.
Where?
Past the g raveyard.
With th is bu nch ?
It's q u iet ton ig ht. You can
teach them a cou ple of th I ngs.
Than ks .
I 'd rather do it alone.
These babes get
ki I led off too fast.
Wel I , the lorry's waiti ng.
Last n ig ht I was
too h u ng ry to sleep
and ton ig ht, when I get
the wri n kles out of my g ut,
they th I n k u p wi ri ng d uty.
Wel I , here's
you r chance , heroes.
For the fatherland!
Come on , get you r stuff
and let's get out of here.
Is that any way
to d rive?
Let h I m d rive
any way he wants.
S u ppose he breaks you r arm .
You get sent home , don't you ?
A lot better than
havi ng a hole I n you r g uts.
If there's any of you left, I ' I I
pick you u p I n the morn I ng.
Wel I , if that ride you gave us
d id n 't ki I I us , noth I ng wi I I.
And be on ti me . I don't
want to m iss my breakfast.
Yeah ?
You better wait
for you r army, Papa.
(LAU G H S)
H ere , here .
Don't be so backward.
Listen , ch I ld ren . Al I we got
to do is to stri ng a I ittle wi re.
We pick it u p at the d u m p
and carry it to where we need it.
N ow, you're gon na
see some shel lfi re ,
and you're gon na
be scared , see?
(BOM B WH I STL I N G)
(EXP LOS I O N I N D I STAN C E)
It's al I rig ht, boy.
Get u p.
H ere. N ever m I nd.
It's happened to better men
than you , and it's happened to me.
When we come back, I ' I I get
you al I some n ice clean u nderwear.
That ki nd of shel I you don't
have to pay m uch attention to.
Those big fel lows
j ust make a lot of noise
and land about five m
I les beh I nd the I I ne.
The th I ngs we've got to
watch out for are the I ig ht ones.
They don't g ive you
m uch warn I ng.
They go "waah zi ng. "
And when you
hear that, down!
Mother Earth.
P ress you rselves
down u pon her.
B u ry you rselves
deep I nto her.
Just keep you r eyes on me.
When you see me flop ,
you flop.
O n ly, try to
beat me to it.
(EXP LOS I O N)
(CO NTI N U O U S EXP LOS I O N S)
(S H U S H I N G)
(WH I S P E RI N G) N ow, I isten.
I ' I I show you
how it's done.
G ive me a cou ple of those .
That's to ki I I the noise.
Tjaden.
(EXP LOS I O N)
(G U N F I RI N G)
See that?
What's that mean ?
Bom bard ment.
(CO NTI N U O U S EXP LOS I O N S)
(SC REAMS)
(SO B B I N G)
My eyes!
(SC REAM I N G) I'm bl I nd!
I can't see ! God!
My eyes ! I can't see!
O h , God!
It's Beh n ! It's Beh n !
B E H N : I can't see!
(F I RI N G CO NTI N U ES)
I ' I I go get h I m.. .
You ' I I get ki I led!
Leave h I m .
What?
Let me.. .
Lay down and stay there!
You ' I I get you r
head shot off.
H e's dead.
Why'd id you risk you r
I ife bri ng I ng h I m I n ?
B ut it's Beh n.
My friend.
It's a corpse ,
no matter who it is.
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
N ow, don't any of you
ever do that agai n.
P ut h I m over there.
SO I D I E R 1 :
M I nd the wi re.
SO I D I E R 2 :
Al I rig ht, come on.
Al I rig ht, come on . Get you r
packs and fal I I n. H u rry u p.
Come on . H u rry u p.
Come on . Make it snappy.
Get you r packs
and fal I I n.
Kat, what are we doi ng ?
What's happen I ng ?
You heard h I m .
O rders to march.
B ut where to ,
for the love of...
Another party.
And th is one is gon
na last a long ti me.
Come on.
H ere we go.
Com pany, attention!
S hou lder, arms!
March rig ht, march!
(EXP LOS I O N S)
Take you r hands off that!
Q ueen takes it!
Wel I , if you th I n k
that's a q ueen , look agai n.
It's a jack.
Yeah.
H onest, these cards
al I look al I ke.
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
It's too noisy !
I can't play.
I su ppose you r del
icate nerves.. . Get u p.
...can't stand it.
That's Oscar.
The son of a ...
Look at that!
Don't be so snooty. You
may wish you had th is back.
About two more
days of th is
and th is rat-bitten end
of a piece of bread 's
gon na taste j ust I I ke
a h u n k of fru itcake.
It wou ld n 't.. . It wou ld n't
last two more days , wou ld it?
D id n't I tel I you th is
was gon na be a bad one?
I don't m I nd
the days so m uch.
It's keepi ng u p
al I n ig ht that's ...
Two more days
makes a week, kid.
Then you can say
you've been u nder fi re.
You're not scared ,
are you ?
N o. I was j ust aski ng ,
that's al I.
Want to play
some more?
Do you ?
S u re.
Al I rig ht. My deal.
You better get you r boot
back before Oscar eats that.
(LAU G H I N G)
The kid's al I rig ht.
KEMM E RI C K: Beh n.
Beh n.
KAT: Yeah , yeah . Let h I m
sleep. H e's d ream I ng . Beh n.
KEMM E RI C K: O h , God .
Can't you see it's Beh n ?
H e d id n't want
to come to war.
N o , no.
It isn't Beh n.
It isn't Beh n!
It's Kem merick ! It's me!
S h ut u p , wi I I you ? It's
bad enoug h I n here as it is.
Every...
Everyth I ng 's
al I rig ht, F ranz.
You're d ream I ng.
I see someth I ng.
You're j ust d ream I ng ,
I g uess.
(BOM BS CO NTI N U E EXP LO D I N G)
Attention !
At ease.
The barrage is
getti ng worse.
Men I n two more
d ugouts , gone.
H owever, we' I I do ou r best to
get some food u p here by even I ng.
(WH I M P E RI N G)
(SC REAM I N G)
(SC REAMS) Stop!
(AL I C LAMO RI N G)
Let me out.
What d id you
do that for?
S h ut u p ! G rab h I m.
N o .
N ow hold h I m.
(SO I D I E RS WH I M P E RI N G)
You al I rig ht now?
I th I n k so.
I cou ld n't hold out
m uch longer.
(SC REAM I N G)
Let me out!
It's goi ng to ki I I me!
PAU I : Very good.
O h , my God , it's F ranz !
Th is is terri ble!
N o , don't. H e's been
h it I n the stomach.
H e can't have
anyth I ng to d ri n k.
Get a stretcher.
Where'd they get you ,
Kem merick?
H ere it is , si r.
Take h is head.
Al I rig ht.
Take h I m out.
Is it serious , si r?
I'm not su re.
Tel I the others
he's al I rig ht.
Yes , si r.
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
If we're goi ng to fig ht,
why don't we fig ht?
Why don't we go over?
You cou ld go
crazy stayi ng here.
Let's do someth I ng!
Let's go after them!
S it down!
If that cook of
ou rs had any g uts ,
he'd try to bri ng
someth I ng th roug h.
H e's so far beh I nd the I I nes
he can't hear the shooti ng!
H ere's Kat.
Get anyth I ng ?
Any I uck?
We' I I have to spl it
th is u p among us.
Someth I ng to eat!
(AL I C LAMO RI N G)
We need butter, too.
Yes. And dessert. And
a feather bed to sleep on.
SO I D I E R 1 : Rats !
SO I D I E R 2 : Rats!
Rats. Rats.
Get out of the way!
(AL I S H O UTI N G)
That's enoug h.
That's enoug h , boys.
(EXP LOS I O N S STO P)
What's that?
(WH I STL E B LOWI N G)
Come on!
Come on !
G rab you r rifles!
Come on!
Come along.
Come on , everybody.
H ere they come.
Get you r g renades here.
I n th is space.
H u rry u p. Th is is an attack.
Come on , h u rry u p.
(BOM BS WH I STL I N G)
(G U N S F I RI N G)
(AL I YE I I I N G)
Come on!
(F I RI N G)
(SC REAM I N G)
(G U N F I RE)
Ai m. F I re.
H ere you go , troops.
(F I RI N G CO NTI N U ES)
Let's go ! Let's
go ! Let's move!
(F I RI N G)
We can't hold th is position ,
men . Back to you r own I I nes!
KAT: We've got
a I ift from caval ry.
N ow, then.
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
(CO NTI N U O U S G U N F I RE)
(M E N S I N G I N G I N G E RMAN)
F I I I it u p .
And h u rry u p.
I've got other th I ngs to do.
I've been waiti ng
for th is for th ree weeks.
When they al I get here.
What do you want?
Beans , you homely-looki ng
son of a frog's leg.
What do you th I n k I want?
M E N : We're h u ng ry.
(M E N C LAMO RI N G)
S h ut u p ! I'll feed you
when you're al I here.
We're al I here now.
O n ly half the com
pany's here . Get the rest.
Wake 'em u p.
(LAU G H S) Yeah.
I wish I cou ld wake 'em u p .
There's 80 of us left.
The rest is I n d ressi ng
stations or push I ng u p daisies.
E ig hty?
And I cooked for 150!
Al I rig ht. We' I I have enoug
h for once . Come on , d ish out!
You mean , you've cooked beans
for 150 , and you've got bread for 150 ,
and sausage for 150 ,
and tobacco for 150?
Everyth I ng ! It's al I wrong .
I shou ld have been notified.
What a feast !
Everyone gets two issues.
H ey, get back I n I I ne !
Get back I n I I ne!
O h , no ! That won't do.
I can't g ive 80 men
what's meant for 150.
Listen.
You d rew rations for the 2
nd Com pany, d id n't you ?
Yeah.
Al I rig ht.
We're the 2 nd Com pany.
I've got my orders.
Kat's rig ht.
We're the 2 nd Com pany.
And if on ly half of us get
back, that's ou r good I uck.
Come on. D ish it out.
Come on!
N o!
H ey!
You're the yel lowest baboon
that ever d rew a cook wagon
and you're scared it shows.
Al I we want to hear out
of you is one more I ittle yi p
and we' I I cut you u p
and eat you raw.
Why, you keep you r kitchen
so far back of the I I nes
we never get anyth I ng to eat
u nti I it's cold and we're asleep!
N ow, you low-down rat, get out
or we wreck the joi nt, so hel p us.
(AL I S H O UTI N G)
Come on ! G ive us ou r food.
SO I D I E R: Attention!
At ease.
What's goi ng on here?
H e's cooked for 150 , si r, and
he on ly wants to g ive us half.
Looks pretty good.
Yes , si r.
Serve the whole issue !
The men can use it.
Yes , si r.
And bri ng me
a plate , too.
Yes , si r.
Al I rig ht. Take it al
I . Take everyth I ng.
G ive 'em honey.
G ive 'em what they want.
F I I I it u p ! F I I I
it u p ! F I I I it u p!
Anybody else?
Al I I want is to get goi ng.
Don't m I nd me.
O h , that's al I rig ht.
Don't mention it.
You know,
I cou ld do with
some more beans.
Go hel p you rself.
There's more over there.
(G ROAN S)
It's too far.
(KAT LAU G H I N G)
I wonder, when are we
goi ng back to the front?
Tomorrow.
It's enoug h to take away
a man's appetite.
You know, if they're gon na
march us I n agai n tomorrow,
we oug ht to go see
how Kem merick is.
That's a good idea .
Let's do that.
H ow far is
the d ressi ng station ?
About two m I les.
We cou ld take
h is th I ngs to h I m.
Good.
It seemed rotten to th I n k of a th I
ng I I ke that happen I ng to h I m ,
a n ice fel low
I I ke Kem merick.
The F rench certai n ly deserve to
be pu n ished for starti ng th is war.
Everybody says
it's somebody else.
Wel I , how do they
start a war?
Wel I , one cou ntry
offends another.
H ow cou ld one cou ntry
offend another?
You mean , there's a mou
ntai n over I n Germany
gets mad at a field
over I n F rance?
(AL I C H U C KL E)
Wel I , stu pid , one
people offends another.
O h , if that's it,
I shou ld n't be here at al I.
I don't feel offended.
It don't apply
to tram ps I I ke you.
Good. Then I can be
goi ng home rig ht away.
You j ust try it.
KAT: Yeah .
You want to get shot?
The Kaiser and me ...
(AL I EXC LAI M I N G)
Me and the Kaiser felt j
ust al I ke about th is war.
We d id n't either of us want
any war, so I'm goi ng home.
H e's there al ready.
Somebody m ust have wanted it.
Maybe it was the E ng I ish.
N o , I don't want to
shoot any E ng I ish men.
I never saw one
ti I I I came u p here.
And I su ppose most of
them never saw a German
ti I I they came u p here.
N o , I'm su re they
weren't asked about it.
N o.
Wel I , it m ust be doi ng
somebody some good.
N ot me and the Kaiser.
I th I n k maybe
the Kaiser wanted a war.
You leave us out of th is.
I don't see that. The Kaiser's
got everyth I ng he needs.
Wel I , he never had
a war before.
Every fu I I-g rown em peror
needs one war to make h I m famous.
Why, that's h istory.
Yeah , generals , too .
They need war.
And man ufactu rers .
They get rich . H m m.
I th I n k it's more
a ki nd of fever.
N obody wants it I n particu lar
and then , al I at once , here it is.
We d id n't want it. The E ng I ish d id
n't want it. And here we are fig hti ng.
I ' I I tel I you how
it shou ld al I be done.
Whenever there's
a big war com I ng on ,
you shou ld rope off
a big field ...
And sel I tickets.
Yeah. And ...
And on the big day
you shou ld take
al I the ki ngs
and thei r cabi nets
and thei r generals ,
put them I n the center
d ressed I n thei r u nderpants
and let them
fig ht it out with cl u bs.
The best cou ntry wi ns.
(AL I AG RE E I N G)
Wel I , now that Kat's settled
everyth I ng , let's go see Kem merick.
M ig ht cheer h I m u p.
Someth I ng I nteresti ng
m ig ht happen on the way.
Boys , me and the Kaiser want
you back I n ti me to march tomorrow.
Don't forget.
We' I I be back.
G ive the boy
my regards.
Whoa.
O h , there he is.
H el lo , Kem merick.
H ow are you ?
H ow's it goi ng ?
H ow are th I ngs goi ng ?
Are they looki ng
after you al I rig ht?
H ow are they treati
ng you ? F ranz?
I'm al I rig ht.
They're robbers here.
Robbers.
They stole my watch.
I always told you nobody shou
ld carry as good a watch as that.
And they took it
wh I le I was u nder ether.
F ranz. F ranz.
You ' I I get it back.
Do you feel
al I rig ht?
Just look at
my hand , thoug h.
That's because
you lost so m uch blood.
Just eat decently and
you ' I I get wel I agai n.
O h , no.
F ranz, you m ust eat. That's the
mai n th I ng . It looks good , too.
I have such a terri
ble pai n I n my foot.
Every toe on
my rig ht foot h u rts.
Wel I , how can you r foot h u rt
when you r leg's been ...
O h , I know what you mean!
I know! I know now!
They've cut my leg off.
Why'd id n't they tel I me?
F ranz ! F ranz !
... they tel I me.
N ow I can't wal k anymore!
F ranz, you m ust be than kfu I
that you've come off with on ly that.
I wanted to be
a forester once.
You can yet. They make
artificial legs that are wonderfu I.
And you're th roug h , too . You
can go home . Th I n k of that.
We broug ht you r
th I ngs for you. See?
P ut them u nder the bed.
That's a marvelous
pai r of boots.
Look at that leather.
What comfort.
I was j ust th I n ki ng.
If you're not goi ng to
be usi ng these , F ranz,
why don't you
leave them with us?
What good are they
to you ? I can use 'em.
My boots g ive me
bl ister after bl ister.
Wel I , we' I I be
goi ng , F ranz.
O h , don't go. Stay j ust
a I ittle wh I le longer.
I ' I I come rig ht back.
We' I I be com I ng
soon agai n , F ranz.
I know you ' I I be feel
I ng better, F ranz. Bye.
Bye.
Good bye , F ranz.
You th I n k he' I I last
ti I I after mess?
You don't th I n k...
Done for.
PAU I : Boys , you go along .
I ' I I see you later.
SO I D I E R 1 : Good bye . Al I rig ht,
Pau I . SO I D I E R 2 : Good bye , Pau I.
I'm sorry, Pau I.
I wou ld n't touch a th I
ng of h is if he cou ld use it.
I 'd go barefoot over barbed wi re
for h I m if it'd do h I m any good.
O n ly why shou ld some
orderly get those boots?
I u nderstand , M uel ler.
We're al I al I ke out here.
And good boots are scarce.
Tel I the doctor
to come , please.
Doctor, the man I n the next
bed wou ld I I ke to see you , si r.
I've done everyth I ng I can for
h I m . There's no hel pi ng h I m.
Poor I ittle fel low.
H e says next ti me , F ranz.
Do you th I n k
I ' I I ever get wel I ?
Why, of cou rse.
Do you real ly th I n k so?
S u re , once you
get over the operation.
I don't th I n k so.
F ranz. Don't tal k nonsense .
Why, you ' I I be as good as new.
They fix u p
worse th I ngs than that.
Perhaps you ' I I go to the
convalescent home I n Klosterberg
among the vi I lagers.
Then you can look out of
the wi ndows , across the field
to the two trees
on the horizon.
The lovel iest ti me of the
year, now, when the corn ri pens.
And you can go out
without aski ng anyone.
You can even play piano
if you want to.
O h. .. O h , but, F ranz,
you m ust try to sleep now.
(SO B B I N G)
O h , God ,
th is is F ranz Kem merick,
on ly 19 years old.
H e doesn't want to d ie.
P lease , don't let h I m d ie.
Pau I. (GAS P I N G)
Pau I .
Yes , F ranz.
Take my boots home
for M uel ler.
O h , no , F ranz, no.
And if...
(M UTTE RI N G)
Pau I , you can
fi nd my watch ,
send it home.
F ranz!
Doctor. Doctor!
Doctor!
Where's the doctor?
Why isn't there
a doctor here?
Doctor, come q u ick.
F ranz Kem merick is dyi ng!
Wh ich one is that?
Am putated leg.
I've am putated
a dozen legs today.
Bed 26 , si r.
You see to it. I'm d ue
I n the operati ng room.
O ne operation after another
si nce 5 : 00 th is morn I ng.
S ixteen dead today,
you rs is the 17th.
There' I I probably
be 20 by tomorrow.
(SO I D I E RS TAL KI N G
I N D I STI N CTLY)
SO I D I E R: You're looki ng good ,
very good today.
What's you r h u rry?
H ey ! I'll bet he
stole those boots!
Why'd id n't you stop h I m ?
(SO I D I E RS LAU G H I N G)
I got it, Kat.
H u h ?
Listen , "The su m of
an arith metic series
" is S A   I x N over 2. "
I nteresti ng , isn't it?
What do you want to
learn that stuff for?
O ne day you ' I I stop a bu
I let and it' I I al I be wasted.
I get a lot of fu n
out of it.
My boots!
M uel ler.
I saw h I m d ie.
I d id n't know what it
was I I ke to d ie before.
And then.. . Then I
came outside and it felt...
It felt so good to be al ive
that I started I n to wal k fast.
I began to th I n k of
the strangest th I ngs ,
I I ke bei ng out I n the
fields . Th I ngs I I ke that.
You know, g I rls.
And it felt as if there were
someth I ng electric ru n n I ng
from the g rou nd u p th roug h me.
And I started .
And I began to ru n hard.
And I passed sold iers and I
heard voices cal I I ng , but...
And I ran and I ran.
And I felt as if I cou ld n't
breathe enoug h ai r I nto me.
And. .. And now
I'm h u ng ry.
M U E I I E R: I don't
m I nd the war now.
Be a pleasu re to go to the
front I n boots I I ke these.
(EXP LOS I O N S)
(G U N S F I RI N G)
(WH I STL E B LOWI N G)
(SO I D I E RS LAU G H I N G)
TJAD E N : It's a good I
nvention , j ust the same.
If you crack
each separate louse ,
th I n k of al I the energy
you use u p. Watch.
B u rned to death.
H ow was patrol ? Bad ?
M ust've been terri ble if they
had ti me to gather I n the harvest.
We passed a cherry tree and
when he saw it, he sort of went crazy.
I cou ld hard ly
d rag h I m away.
It was beautifu I.
I have a big orchard
with cherry trees at home.
And when they're
I n fu I I blossom ,
from the hayloft it looks
I I ke one si ng le sheet.
So wh ite.
Perhaps you can
get leave soon.
You may even be
sent back as a farmer.
A woman can't ru n a farm
alone . That's no good , you know?
N o matter how
hard she works.
H arvest com I ng on agai n.
What's the matter
with h I m ?
Got a letter yesterday
from h is wife.
H e wants to get
back to h is farm.
We'd al I I I ke to get back
home , it comes to that.
I wonder what we'd do if it were
sudden ly peaceti me agai n ?
Get d ru n k
and look for women!
I 'd go looki ng
for a C I nderel la
that cou ld wear
th is for a garter.
And when I 'd fou nd her, nobody
wou ld see me for two weeks.
I ' I I go back to
the peat fields
and those pleasant hou rs
I n the beer gardens.
And there's worse th I ngs
than cobbl I ng , too.
Look. My fam I ly.
I oug ht to g ive you a kick I n
the backside for starti ng al I th is.
It's al I rig ht
for al I you to tal k.
You've got someth I ng
to go back to.
Wives , ch I ld ren , jobs ...
B ut what about us? What have
we got to go back to? School ?
Why not? You know
everyth I ng al ready?
A man can't take al I that ru
bbish they teach you seriously
after th ree years
of shel ls and bom bs.
You can't peel that off
as easi ly as a sock.
They never taug ht us
anyth I ng real ly usefu I ,
I I ke how to I ig ht
a cigarette I n the wi nd ,
or make a fi re
out of wet wood ,
or bayonet a man I n the bel ly I
nstead of the ri bs where it gets jam med.
What can happen
to us afterwards?
I ' I I tel I you .
Take ou r class.
O ut of 20 ,
th ree are officers ,
n I ne dead ,
M uel ler and th ree others wou
nded , and one I n the mad house.
We' I I al I be dead someday,
so let's forget it.
H I MM E LSTOSS : H u rry u p !
Get I n there ! H u rry u p!
H I m melstoss!
(LAU G H I N G)
What's u p?
What are you , crazy?
It's H I m melstoss!
H I m melstoss? There
is j ustice I n the army!
Wel I , wel I .
So , we are al I here , h u h ?
A bit longer
than you , H I m m ie.
And si nce when have we
become so fam I I iar?
Stand u p there and cl ick
you r heels together! Al I of you!
Take a ru n n I ng j u m p
at you rself! (LAU G H I N G)
Who's you r friend ?
Wou ld somebody get General
Ludendorff a n ice , comfortable chai r?
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
I com mand you as
you r su perior officer!
Do you want to be
cou rt-martialed for th is?
I do!
There's goi ng to be
a big attack ton ig ht
and I 'd j ust love
to get out of it.
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
Wi I I you obey my orders?
Kiss my foot.
It isn't customary
to ask for sal utes here.
B ut I'll tel I you
what we' I I do.
We're goi ng to attack a town
that we tried to take once before.
Many ki I led and many wou nded .
It was g reat fu n.
Th is ti me
you ' re goi ng with us.
If any of us stops a bu I let,
before we d ie ,
we're goi ng to come to you , cl
ick ou r heels together and ask stiffly,
" P lease , Sergeant H I m melstoss ,
may we go?"
You ' I I.. .
You ' I I pay for th is , you ...
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
(BOM BS EXP LO D I N G)
H ere it is.
Rig ht on ti me .
Better get ready, boys.
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
(B LOWI N G WH I STL E)
(BOM BS WH I STL I N G)
(WH I M P E RI N G)
I'm wou nded .
I'm wou nded!
It's j ust a scratch , you yel low rat
! U p ! Get on with the others ! U p!
N o ! N o ! N o!
You yel low rat!
You sti n ki ng yel low rat !
Let the others do it, eh ?
Get u p ! Get u p!
Forward , forward !
Get out here!
The com mand was forward.
Com mand was forward!
Forward!
Forward ! Forward!
(BOM BS CO NTI N U E WH I STL I N G)
(I NAU D I B I E)
(EXP LOS I O N S STO P)
Cou nterattack.
(SO I D I E RS S H O UTI N G)
(CO NTI N U O U S G U N F I RE)
(GAS P I N G)
I want to hel p you.
(M U M B I I N G)
(EXP LOS I O N S CO NTI N U E)
(SO I D I E R MOAN I N G)
Stop that !
Stop that!
I can bear the rest of it.
I can't I isten to that!
Why do you take
so long dyi ng ?
You're goi ng
to d ie anyway!
(I N D I STI N CT)
O h , no. O h , no .
You won't d ie.
N o , no. You won't d ie .
They're on ly I ittle wou nds.
You ' I I get home .
You ' I I be al I rig ht.
You ' I I get home
long before I wi I I.
(F I RI N G CO NTI N U ES)
You know I can't ru n away.
That's why you accuse me.
I tel I you , I d id n't want to ki I
I you . I tried to keep you al ive.
If you j u m ped I n here agai n ,
I wou ld n't do it.
You see when you j u m ped
I n here you were my enemy,
and I was afraid of you.
B ut you're j ust a man I I
ke me , and I ki I led you.
Forg ive me , com rade.
Say that for me .
Say you forg ive me.
O h , no. You're dead.
O n ly, you ' re better off
than I am . You're th roug h.
They can't do
anymore to you now.
O h , God , Why'd
id they do th is to us?
We on ly wanted
to I ive , you and I.
Why shou ld they send us
out to fig ht each other?
If we th rew away these
rifles and these u n iforms
you cou ld be my brother,
j ust I I ke Kat and Al bert.
You ' I I have to forg ive me ,
com rade . I ' I I do al I I can.
I ' I I write to you r parents .
I ' I I write to ...
I ' I I write to you r wife .
I ' I I write to her.
I prom ise she' I I
not want for anyth I ng.
And I'll hel p her
and you r parents , too.
O n ly, forg ive me .
Forg ive me!
Forg ive me .
Forg ive me.
(SO B B I N G)
(EXP LOS I O N S STO P)
Terri ble th I ng
happened yesterday.
I stabbed a man . With my
own hands , stabbed h I m.
I know how it is .
You r fi rst ti me.
N ever m I nd . The
stretcher-bearers wi I I fi nd h I m.
N o , no. H e's dead , Kat.
I watched h I m d ie.
You cou ld n't do
anyth I ng about it.
We have to ki I I .
We can't hel p it.
That's what we are here for.
Look there , for I nstance.
(G U N S H OT)
That got h I m . You shou ld 've
seen how he leaped I n the ai r.
That fel low headed the shoot
with us for today with th ree h its.
If he keeps it u p ,
he' I I have a decoration
for h is button hole
th is even I ng.
N ow, don't you lose anymore
sleep over th is busi ness.
Maybe it was 'cause I was out
there with h I m so long , h u h ?
S u re , that's it.
After al I , war is war.
(G U N S H OT)
(SO I D I E RS S I N G I N G I N G E RMAN)
SO I D I E R: March!
Forward , march!
Q u ickly ! Forward!
Com pany, halt!
D ism issed!
N oncom m issioned officers ,
en I isted men , d ism issed!
H ooray ! Come on ,
let's get out of here!
(AL I S I N G I N G I N G E RMAN)
G ive me you r
best sausage.
Two.
G ive me a beer.
AL I : O ne , two , th ree , hoorah!
(M E N S I N G I N G I N G E RMAN)
H ey, come on. A beer.
H ey, get out of here!
Come on .
G ive me a beer.
(EXC LAI M I N G I N F RU STRATI O N)
A beer. O ne ...
BOTH : Prosit!
Wel I , here's hopi ng we get
fal I I ng-down d ru n k ton ig ht.
H ere's how it started.
I 'd forgotten there
were g I rls I I ke that.
There aren 't.
Just look at those
th I n , I ittle shoes.
S he cou ld n't march
many m I les I n those.
Pau I. Don't speak
about march I ng.
You're bori ng
the you ng lady.
A thousand pardons.
H ow old do you
th I n k she is?
O h , about 22.
N o , you know, that'd
make her older than us.
S he's 17.
A g I rl I I ke that. That'd
be good , eh , Al bert?
We wou ld n't have m uch of
a chance with h I m arou nd.
We cou ld take a bath ,
wash ou r clothes ...
Al I rig ht.
I'm ig ht even go so
far as to get deloused.
Wait a m I n ute !
Wait a m I n ute!
S he's a long way
from here now.
Look at the date .
May 1917.
Fou r months ago.
That's true.
Wel I , here's
to her anyway.
H ere's to 'em al I ,
everywhere.
Al bert, we m ig ht as
wel I wash u p anyway.
Al I rig ht.
(WH I S P E RI N G)
Personal ly, I I I ke
them bigger arou nd.
Th is conversation was on a
h ig h moral plane u p to now.
N ow we do need a bath.
A bath ?
For what?
You wou ld n 't
u nderstand.
Th is water's freezi ng . Th is
romantic busi ness has gone too far.
B ut th I n k of her
beautifu I eyes!
O h , and her hai r.
H ere we are ! We're
not gon na m iss a th I ng!
Go away!
What are you
doi ng here?
Bath I ng!
They tel I me there's
some people I n th is world
takes a bath
every week!
(WOM E N S I N G I N G I N F RE N C H)
Women!
(I NAU D I B I E)
PAU I : Mademoiselle,
you want to swi m ?
(M E N LAU G H I N G)
(I N D I STI N CT)
(S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
Mademoiselle,
you cou ld be me!
(AL I CO NVE RS I N G I N F RE N C H)
TJAD E N : O h , baby!
AL B E RT: Kiss me!
(CO NTI N U E CO NVE RS I N G
I N F RE N C H)
N o , g I rls !
Don't go away!
O h , mama!
(BOYS EXC LAI M I N G)
P lease don't go!
Don't go away!
Mademoiselle,
we want you.
(WH OO P I N G)
(S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
Food ! Food ! Whoo!
H alt!
You know you ' re
forbidden to cross.
You fel lows stay on th is side or you '
I I get you rselves I n a lot of trou ble.
(CO NTI N U E S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
What are they
jabberi ng about?
They want us to swi ng over
ton ig ht. They're expecti ng us.
That's fi ne !
We' I I do it!
That blonde's
crazy about me.
B ut there's fou r of us
and on ly th ree of them.
I was the one
that stopped 'em!
That blonde piece
of work is m I ne.
You th ree fig ht
for what's left.
F ig ht's the word . Al
I's fai r I n love and war.
H u h ? What do you mean ?
What are you gon na do?
You ' I I fi nd out.
(B I D D I N G FAREWE I I I N F RE N C H)
(KN OC KI N G O N DOO R)
(WOMAN S P EAKI N G I N F RE N C H)
(BOYS S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
S he means the door.
(S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
PAU I : N ot on ly modest,
but dash I ng!
AL B E RT: A perfect fit.
It m ig ht've been
made for me.
An officer's coat. We're cal I I
ng , d isti ng u ished com pany.
(S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
(G I RLS S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
H ave another
I ittle d ri n k, com rade.
Is th is you r bi rthday
or m I ne?
Why?
You've been buyi ng me d ri
n k after d ri n k for two hou rs.
What I'm tryi ng to
fig u re out is why.
Why? Why?
O h ! (LAU G H I N G)
It's j ust that the boys
told me to am use you
for a I ittle wh I le.
O h , n ice boys.
Yeah!
Yeah , they said you 'd u
nderstand . (LAU G H I N G)
I've been betrayed!
Yeah , you certai n ly have.
Take that for a m I n ute!
I ' I I g ive you more!
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
(S N O RI N G)
It's too loud.
(S I I E N C E)
(G I RL S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
PAU I : Darl I ng.
What's you r name?
(G I RL CO NTI N U ES
S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
N ame .
H ow do you say name?
Georgette? Cam I I le?
S uzan ne.
Pau I.
S uzan ne , I wish I cou ld
tel I you someth I ng.
I wish you cou ld
u nderstand.
Darl I ng , I'll never see
you agai n . I know that.
And I wou ld n't even
know you if I d id.
And yet,
I ' I I remem ber you always.
If you cou ld on ly know
how d ifferent th is is
from the women
that we sold iers meet.
(CO NTI N U ES S P EAKI N G F RE N C H)
N o , no , no .
N ot the war.
You. That's what
I'm tal ki ng about.
It seems as thoug h al I war,
terror and g rossness
had fal len away from me ,
I I ke a m I racle.
Li ke someth I ng
I never bel ieved.
Cal I Pau I.
We're goi ng , Pau I.
H ave a look.
N ice , new coffi ns.
For us.
I'm ust say,
that's a very cheerfu I
preparation
for th is offensive.
That's very
considerate of them.
B ut I don't see any long enoug
h for ou r com rade , Tjaden.
M I nd you , I'm not speaki
ng to you , you traitors.
B ut no coffi n 's
gon na get me.
I shou ld say not,
heartbreaker.
You ' I I be than kfu I if
they sl I p a waterproof sheet
arou nd that Au nt Sal ly
of a carcass of you rs.
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
(EXP LOS I O N S)
(AL I S H O UTI N G)
(G ROAN I N G)
(G ROAN I N G) My side!
My side.
Cathol ic hospital , Al bert.
(G ROAN I N G)
They say you always get
good food and good treatment.
We're I ucky.
After that rai ny
d ressi ng station
and 24 hou rs on the trai n ,
we deserve to have some I uck.
(G U F FAWI N G)
I'm H am macher.
Yes , that's my name.
I got a crack I n the head and
they gave me a certificate stati ng
that J oseph H am macher
is period ical ly
not responsi ble
for h is actions.
And ever si nce then , H am macher
has been havi ng a g rand ti me.
I hope you boys are
not too bad ly wou nded.
The others d ie off so q u ickly we
don't have ti me to get acq uai nted.
You ' I I get to
know us very wel I.
Than k you .
You , too.
I'm sorry, my dear.
It's ti me to go now.
Yes , S ister.
Watch.
If they take h is clothes away,
you've seen the last of h I m.
See? They're taki ng h I m
to the dyi ng room.
Dyi ng room ?
When you're ready
to kick the bucket,
they get you out of the way
so they can use the bed.
I n the corner
of the bu I ld I ng
there's a I ittle room
rig ht next to the morg ue!
It's so conven ient.
It saves a lot of trou ble.
B ut su ppose
he gets wel I ?
I've seen a lot of them
go I n that dyi ng room ,
but nobody
ever comes back.
S ister. S ister. S ister.
S ister.
AL B E RT: Is that you
ri ng I ng , Pau I ?
PAU I : Yes.
Is someth I ng wrong ?
I th I n k I have
a hemorrhage.
The bandage is al I wet. I've been
ri ng I ng forever and nobody comes.
I th I n k I'm bleed I ng.
S ister, get me a steri le
d ressi ng and an ice pack.
Why'd id n 't
someone cal I me?
AL B E RT:
H e's been ri ng I ng.
N obody can wal k, S ister.
S ister, is it bad ?
N o. N o ,
we' I I be al I rig ht.
We've got it I n ti me.
What's the matter?
What are you doi ng ?
We m ust rearrange
you r bandages.
Where are you taki ng me?
N U N :
To the bandag I ng ward.
N o , no ! I'm not goi ng !
I'm stayi ng here!
AL B E RT: Pau I ! Pau I!
N ow, now!
I'm not goi ng to
the dyi ng room!
B ut we're goi ng to
the bandag I ng ward.
Then why are you
taki ng my clothes?
You're lyi ng to me ! B ut
I'll come back ! I won't d ie!
I ' I I come back !
I won't d ie!
I'm not goi ng to d ie !
I ' I I come back!
HAMMAC H E R: S ister
Li berti ne , how is he?
Poor boy. They had
to am putate h is leg.
Pau I.
Pau I. Pau I.
O h , he is gone.
Gone.
H el lo. Welcome home , Al bert!
H ow do you feel , kid ?
Al I rig ht.
B ut I've got
such an awfu I pai n.
My foot...
H am macher.
D id they cut my leg off?
Of cou rse not ! H ow
many d id you have? Two?
You sti I I got 'em !
O ne , two!
Don't play the fool , H am
macher. Tel I me truthfu I ly.
Of cou rse not.
And you look fi ne.
Look. See?
I won't be a cri pple .
N ow, now.
I won't I ive I I ke that !
Be cal m.
I ' I I ki I I myself
the fi rst chance I get!
Al bert!
I won't I ive ! I won't
I ive ! Yes , you wi I I.
PAU I : Al bert ! Al bert!
Al bert, I've come back!
I told you I 'd come back. Look,
everybody ! I've come back!
AL B E RT: Pau I ! Pau I!
That's not where I'm goi ng .
I I ive over there.
AL B E RT: Pau I ,
I'm so happy.
H am macher, I've
come back from the dead!
It's most I rreg u lar.
N ever happened before.
Al bert, we m ust get wel I q u
ickly so we can go home soon.
Al bert, everyth I ng
wi I I be al I rig ht now.
Yes , Pau I. Everyth I ng
Pau I ! Pau I ! Pau I!
Pau I.
What's the matter, Pau I ?
N oth I ng. N oth I ng.
Pau I.
G ive me you r
hand kerch ief.
Mother?
MOTH E R: H ere I am , Pau I .
H ere I am.
Mother's I I I.
Are you wou nded ?
N o , Mother.
I got leave.
(C RYI N G)
H ere I I ie and cry
I nstead of bei ng g lad.
An na , get down
the jar of blackberries.
You sti I I I I ke them ,
don't you ?
Yes , Mother. I haven't
had any for a long ti me.
We m ig ht al most have known
you were com I ng.
I'm maki ng potato cakes.
MOTH E R:
Don't let them bu rn.
Pau I , sit down beside me.
My Pau I.
My baby.
I al most forgot, Mother. I've
got some I ittle presents for you.
Look, Mother.
B read , sausage and rice.
Pau I , you've been
starvi ng you rself.
H ad n't I better go and
tel I Father Pau I's home?
Pau I cou ld watch
the th I ngs on the stove.
N o , no , ch I ld ,
I'm getti ng u p.
O h , Pau I , you ' re
a sold ier now, aren't you ?
B ut somehow,
I don't seem to know you.
I ' I I take these off,
Mother.
I ' I I get you r su it, Pau I . It's I n
the ward robe , j ust where you left it.
Are you real ly here , Pau I ?
You won't...
You won't d isappear,
wi I I you ?
N o. I'm here.
You r th I ngs are
ready for you , Pau I.
I remem ber when you
caug ht that one.
Yes. And you took it
away from me , d id n't you ?
Yes , I d id.
We're beh I nd the I I nes ,
but we know how to
honor the sold ier
who goes on I n spite
of blood and death.
Gentlemen , my son.
Prosit.
M E N : Prosit.
I'm g lad to know you , you ng
man , I am g lad to know you.
And how are th I ngs out there?
Terri ble , eh ? Terri ble.
B ut we m ust carry on.
After al I , you do at least
get decent food out there.
N atu ral ly, it's worse here .
N atu ral ly.
B ut the best for ou r sold iers
al I the ti me . That's ou r motto.
The best for ou r sold iers.
The best for
ou r sold iers.
B ut you m ust g ive the F
rench ies a good I icki ng!
(AL I LAU G H I N G)
And if you boys
want to come home ,
let me show you what you m
ust do before you can come home.
G ive us a hand there , men.
N ow, then ,
there's the I I ne.
Ru ns so , I n a "V. "
H ere is St. Q uenti n .
You can see for you rself.
You're al most th roug h now.
Al I rig ht?
S hove ahead out there and don't
stick to that everlasti ng trench warfare.
S mash th roug h the J oh n n ies !
And then you wi I I have peace.
When you get I n it, the war
isn't the way it looks back here.
(SCO F FS) You don't know
anyth I ng about it.
Of cou rse , you know about the
detai ls , but th is relates to the whole.
You can't j udge that.
Of cou rse , you do you r d uty
and you risk you r I ife.
B ut for that, you receive
the h ig hest honor.
I said that every man I n the
war oug ht to have the I ron C ross.
F I rst, the enemy I I nes m ust
be broken th roug h I n F landers.
O n to Paris!
P ush on to Paris !
Rig ht.
N o , not I n F landers .
N ow I'll tel I you
j ust where the break
shou ld come.
H ere.
The enemy has
too many reserves there.
I I nsist u pon F landers!
I know, but, my dear man ,
why shou ld they do that
when they're halfway th
roug h St. Q uenti n al ready?
Why go the other way?
Because F landers
is a flat cou ntry.
There are no mou ntai ns ,
no obstructions.
B ut there's
many rivers there.
P RO F ESSO R: F rom
the farms they have gone ,
from the schools ,
from the factories.
They have gone bravely,
nobly, ever forward ,
real izi ng that there is no other d
uty now but to save the fatherland.
Pau I ! H ow are you , Pau I ?
G lad to see you ,
P rofessor.
You've come at the rig ht moment,
Bäu mer. Just at the rig ht moment.
And as if to prove
al I I have said ,
here is one of
the fi rst to go.
A lad who sat before me
on these very benches ,
who gave u p al I to serve
I n the fi rst year of the war.
O ne of the I ron youth who have
made Germany I nvi nci ble I n the field.
Look at h I m , stu rdy
and bronze and clear-eyed.
The ki nd of sold ier
every one of you shou ld envy.
Pau I , lad ,
you m ust speak to them.
You m ust tel I them what it
means to serve you r fatherland.
N o , no , I can't
tel I them anyth I ng.
You m ust, Pau I .
Just a word.
Just tel I them how m uch
they're needed out there.
Tel I them why you went
and what it meant to you.
I can't say anyth I ng.
Can't you remem ber some deed
of heroism , some touch of nobi I ity?
Tel I about it.
(STU D E NTS U RG I N G)
I can't tel I you
anyth I ng you don't know.
We I ive I n the trenches
out there. We fig ht.
We try not to be ki I led ,
someti mes we are.
That's al I.
P RO F ESSO R:
N o. N o , Pau I.
I've been there !
I know what it's I I ke.
That's not what
one dwel ls on , Pau I.
I've heard you I n here
reciti ng that same old stuff,
maki ng more I ron men ,
more you ng heroes.
You sti I I th I n k it's
beautifu I and sweet
to d ie for you r cou ntry,
don't you ?
We used to th I n k you knew.
The fi rst bom bard ment
taug ht us better.
It's d I rty and pai nfu I
to d ie for you r cou ntry.
When it comes to dyi
ng for you r cou ntry,
it's better not
to d ie at al I!
There are m I I I ions out
there dyi ng for thei r cou ntries ,
and what good is it?
(STU D E NTS M U RM U RI N G)
P RO F ESSO R: Pau I.
You asked me to tel I them how
m uch they're needed out there.
H e tel ls you ,
"Go out and d ie. "
O h , but if you ' I I
pardon me ,
it's easier to say, "Go out
and d ie" than it is to do it.
STU D E NT: Coward!
And it's easier to say it
than to watch it happen.
Coward !
Get out!
P RO F ESSO R: N o ! Boys , boys!
I'm sorry, Bäu mer,
but I'm ust say...
It's no use
tal ki ng I I ke th is.
You won't know
what I mean.
O n ly, it's been a long wh I le si nce
we en I isted out of th is classroom.
So long I thoug ht maybe the
whole world had learned by th is ti me.
O n ly now they're send I ng
babies , and they won't last a week.
I shou ld n't have
come on leave.
U p at the front you '
re al ive or you're dead ,
and that's al I.
You can't fool anybody
about that very long.
And u p there we know
we're lost and done for,
whether we're
dead or al ive.
Th ree years we've
had of it.. . Fou r years.
And every day a year,
and every n ig ht a centu ry.
And ou r bod ies are earth ,
and ou r thoug hts are clay,
and we sleep
and eat with death.
We're done for because
you can't I ive that way
and keep anyth I ng
I nside you!
I shou ld n't have come on
leave . I ' I I go back tomorrow.
I've got fou r days more ,
but I can't stand it here.
I ' I I go back tomorrow!
I'm sorry.
Mother, you ' I I catch cold
here . You m ust go to sleep.
There' I I be plenty of ti me
to sleep when you're gone.
M ust you go tomorrow, Pau I ?
M ust you ?
Yes , Mother.
O rders were changed.
Are you very m uch
afraid , Pau I ?
N o , Mother.
There's someth I ng I want
to say to you , Pau I. It's ...
Just be on you r g uard
agai nst the women out there.
They're no good.
Where we are there aren
't any women , Mother.
Be very carefu I
at the front, Pau I.
Yes , Mother, I wi I I.
I ' I I pray for you
every day.
And if you cou ld get a job
that's not q u ite so dangerous ...
Yes , Mother. I ' I I try
and get I n the cookhouse.
That can easi ly be done.
You do it then , and if
the others say anyth I ng ...
That won't worry me ,
Mother.
N ow you m ust
go to bed
and you m ust get wel I q
u ickly before I come back.
I put two sets of u nderwear,
new ones , I n you r pack.
They' I I keep you n ice
and warm . They're al I wool.
That's sweet of you.
Good n ig ht, my son.
Good n ig ht, Mother.
O h , Mother, Mother.
You sti I I th I n k I'm a ch I ld.
Why can't I put my head
I n you r lap and cry?
Is th is the 2 nd Com pany?
Yes , si r.
Is th is al I of it?
We had 150 men , but th is is
al I that came back yesterday.
B ut now they're goi ng to g ive
us enoug h to make 150 agai n.
H ow old are you ?
S ixteen.
N o use .
I cou ld n't fi nd anyth I ng.
We' I I have to eat
the sawd ust.
N ot me ! I ' I I go h u ng ry
fi rst. Th is makes me sick.
N ow it's gon na be
a real war agai n.
Pau I ! H ow's old Pau I ?
H ere I am.
You know, the 2 nd Com
pany's getti ng hard to fi nd.
N obody seemed to know
where you were.
I'm g lad you fou nd it.
I g uess I don't
get m uch of th is.
There used to be some food I n
the sawd ust. N ow it's al I sawd ust.
N o joke , either.
Eats you u p I nside.
Th is doesn't look m uch I
I ke the old 2 nd Com pany.
The replacements
are al I I I ke that.
N ot even old enoug h
to carry a pack.
Al I they know
how to do is d ie.
I g uess some of the
old-ti mers are here yet.
Pau I , they're tryi ng to I nvent
someth I ng to ki I I me rig ht now.
Where's Westh us?
Messenger dog was wou nded .
H e went out to get it.
(C I I C KS TO N G U E)
Is it true about
the arm istice , Pau I ?
Doesn't look
that way back there.
You mean they want us
to go on fig hti ng ?
That's what they say.
They're crazy!
Germany' I I be
em pty pretty soon.
Where's Deteri ng ?
H e got homesick. You remem
ber about the cherry blossoms?
I g uess he never
got over that.
H e started out
one n ig ht to go home
and hel p h is wife
with the farm.
They got h I m beh I nd the I I nes ,
and we never heard of h I m si nce.
H e was j ust homesick, but
probably they cou ld n't see it that way.
Where's Kat? Is he ...
(LAU G H S) N ot Kat!
If he were out,
the war wou ld be over.
You remem ber
what he always says ,
they're savi ng h I m
for the last.
Where is he?
H e's out
looki ng for food ,
tryi ng to col lect someth I ng
to make sou p with.
Wh ich way?
Down the road about
two m I les that way.
I ' I I see you later.
Kat!
Pau I!
(EXP LOS I O N)
H el lo , Pau I.
H ow's the side?
O h , it's al I rig ht now.
It's fi ne.
H ave any I uck?
N o , the general 's staff's been
over th is cou ntry with a rake.
Let's sit down
a m I n ute.
Tel I me , Pau I ,
how was it at home?
H ave a good leave?
I n spots.
What's the matter?
O h , I'm no good for
back there anymore , Kat.
N one of us are .
We've been I n th is too long.
The you ng men thoug ht I was
a coward because I told them that
we learn that death is stronger
than d uty to one's cou ntry.
The old men said ,
"Go on. P ush on to Paris. "
My father even wanted me
to wear my u n iform arou nd.
(LAU G H S)
It's not home
back there anymore.
Al I I cou ld th I n k of was , " I 'd I I
ke to get back and see Kat agai n. "
You're al I
I've got left, Kat.
I'm not m uch
to have left.
I'm issed you , Pau I.
At least we know what
it's al I about out here.
There' re no I ies here.
P ush on to Paris?
You oug ht to see what
they've got on the other side.
They eat wh ite bread
over there.
They've got dozens of
ai rplanes to ou r one
and tan ks that' I I
go over anyth I ng.
What've we got left?
G u ns so worn they d
rop shel ls on ou r own men.
N o food , no am m
u n ition , no officers.
(C H U C KL I N G)
P ush on to Paris!
So that's the way
they tal k back there.
I g uess we'd
better be goi ng.
H ow I I ied
to my poor mother.
I told her it wasn't so
bad out here because
there was always
a lot of us together.
N ow that I'm with you ,
I'm beg I n n I ng to bel ieve
that I told her the truth.
Down!
That's another one that m
issed us . Come on. Let's go.
Wait a m I n ute.
Looks I I ke the old
bread wagon's broke down.
I g uess I don't wal k
the rest of the way.
D id that get you , Kat?
I th I n k
it broke my sh I n.
That's not so bad .
H old it together.
Just my I uck, h u h ?
Good I uck.
That means the war is over.
O h , no , si r.
Th is war don't end
ti I I they real ly get me.
N ow th is one.
Easy, now.
H ey!
Easy!
Come on . I ' I I take you
I n . G ive me you r hand.
Easy.
Al I rig ht.
Wel I , kid , now we're
gon na be separated.
Maybe we can do someth I ng
together later on when the war is over.
Yes , kid.
You g ive me you r add ress
and I'll g ive you m I ne.
(EXP LOS I O N)
You can't get both
of us I n one day!
We' I I su rely see
each other agai n , Kat.
Remem ber that day when you
broug ht the whole pig I nto the factory?
And that day I n the woods when
you taug ht us how to dodge shel ls?
And my fi rst bom bard ment.
H ow I cried.
I was a you ng recru it then.
H ere we are .
H ere we are.
(G RU NTS)
Al I rig ht now, Kat.
You cou ld 've spared you
rself the trou ble . H e's dead.
O h , no. H e's j ust fai nted .
H e was h it I n the sh I n.
H e's dead.
Wou ld you I I ke to
take h is paybook?
You're not related ,
are you ?
N o , we're not related.
You r deal . D id you get
h is name and n u m ber?
Yeah , Corporal
Stan islas Katczi nsky, 306.
I don't get it.
(I N D I STI N CT)
(G U N S H OT)