Give me that horse.
He couldn't go on,
nor could you.
You're injured, man.
Let us take you into the house.
I gotta go on. Gotta get to
the Telegraph station.
We'll take you.
Penelope!
Sorry, closed down for the night.
I know, but this is urgent...
No. Come out of there, you!
Can't go against the schedule.
Closed down.
Can't you make this one exception?
- No.
Get in here.
- What?
Bring a light with you.
You can't do this to me.
I won't stand for it!
The Union Pacific
won't stand for it.
Night prowling round here,
like this.
You've got your gall busting
into my office.
Who do you think you're anyway?
My key's closed down for tonight.
You can write it,
but I won't send it anyway.
Here, let me!
Territorial Recorders office,
Fort Lacey.
have filed corner stakes...
...on plots 234... 235.
Chart 1089,
record in my name...
...that's all.
- How shall I sign it?
Quirt Evans.
All sent, Mr. Evans.
Why! He ain't dead, is he?
No just knocked out!
That's Quirt Evans...
Look at his gun, see how many
notches he has got in his gun?
Not any that I can see.
Sure ain't going to touch it to find out
might wake up and
take it the wrong way.
he was deputy of Wyatt Earp
in Tombstone.
...the two of them shot it out
with the whole Clanton bunch.
So, that's Quirt Evans...
...he's quite a man
with the gals...
.it says he closed the eyes
of many a man
...opened the eyes
of many a women.
Would you call
my father please?
Yes! ma'am...
Where are you taking him?
- To the wagon, to take him home.
Quirt Evans?
Crazy!
I'd just a soon have a black powder
bomb in my house.
Heavy, ain't he?
I know of a dozen men
who'd ride night and day
...to catch Quirt Evans
helpless like this.
I'm worried about you people...
...I know you don't believe in guns or
anything like that, only doing good.
Take my advice...
I'd stay plenty far away
from Mr. Quirt Evans.
Thank you very much for your advice.
Goodnight.
Good night.
So long, Quirt.
That Quirt Evans
is surely something.
Quirt Evans?
You know him?
Do I know Quirt Evans?
Do I know Quirt Evans!
What a question!
Quirt: No... No...
If that doesn't quiet him...
I don't know what will?
...never get that bullet out of him
kicking around like that.
I'm afraid to give him any more sedative,
he has already had enough.
Please be quiet...
the doctor...
He can't hear you.
What do you suppose that
delirious mind is searching for?
He must be in great pain.
- Not with that much laudanum in him.
As if he was reaching for something.
Something specific.
I don't understand. By now he
should be completely inert.
Quirt: No.
Thomas, how is the young man?
- Delirious.
A gun in this house, Thomas?
Please put these back in the gun belt...
Maybe we'll have to get something
to tie him down.
Are you crazy?
- It's empty.
That was it. A gun.
- It's a pity.
It's stupid! These wild ones,
I keep picking bullets out of them,
...and setting their bones, why?
It's their destiny to wind up on Boot Hill.
No!
I forgot! Never speak evil, eh!
Well, get me some more hot water,
young lady.
Start patching him up for
whatever is in store for him.
Come on, help me with his boots.
Mother...
- Yes?
Tell me again.
What, Dear?
- Oh, about meeting father.
Thee have heard that
a thousand times.
He was working on the roof of
the new meeting house.
...he fell off, and I picked him up
out of the dust and held him in my arms.
He always said that I hugged him
before I even knew his name.
And you both knew right away?
- Of course.
Of course I knew he
was a peaceful man....
...a member of the society.
An evil man will seek a more profitable
way of life
...than being a member
of the "Friends".
Father had a beard then, didn't he?
- Yes.
I should think that
would scratch...
I prefer a man clean shaved.
He's got the constitution of a
mountain lion. He'll pull through.
Barring blood poisoning.
These wild ones never seem
to get blood poisoning...
...though it's common enough
among the Godly.
You so called Atheists. You always feel
so compelled to stretch your Godlessness.
Wash him.
The bullet's out.
He's in no danger.
I bet he killed a lot of people.
- No, he didn't.
How do thee know?
- That's enough, John...
...a "friend" doesn't speak
of such things.
Mrs. Worth, get that
man out of here.
But he's badly injured,
doctor.
This isn't civilized Pennsylvania...
...this is the raw frontier.
You must take a realistic attitude.
This is the place where mayhem, theft
and murder are the common place...
...instead of the unusual.
Would that justify leaving
a wounded man to die?
Build your house by the side of the road
and be a friend to man.
Ye who believe.
I don't mind your mocking us,
you've been a good friend to us.
I'm glad I have
a logical mind.
And a good heart.
Goodnight, doctor.
Goodnight.
Still having delirious spells.
Keeps mumbling about his past.
...I'm afraid he's had
a very violent life.
[Quirt mumbling]:
Cards...
...cover my bet on the black ace...
...you're a shapely hussy...
...you get real conformation, Margaret...
...you fill out that dress just right...
...red's your color...
...alright Margaret...
...chart 1089...
...1089...
...Margaret, you're a nuisance!
Let's call it off, Margaret...
...I've got places to go and
country to put behind...
...sure, sure, alright...
...Lila... Lila...
...Lila..
...if I owned a mint...
put your head on every coin...
...I use to smoke corn silk
when I was a kid...
...your hair is just like that, Lila...
...lite brown, yellow all mixed up...
just like corn silk, Lila...
...all gold...
taunt...
Will you bring some
hot coffee, Penny?
Here, the doctor says that he's
completely out of danger.
Just sleeping.
You know, Doctor...
...Penny considers him her
own personal patient.
Sit down.
Will you bring some milk, dear?
And when you finish you can
go up and watch him...
while you card your
wool on the loon.
He doesn't need watching. He has no
temperature in the past few days.
...just a superlatively healthy animal.
...restoring his depleted strength with
sleep. He's no longer delirious.
But of course, if you're determined
to watch over him, Penny...
...perhaps you better take a
pencil and paper with you.
His first conscious words
should be recorded.
It may be of great interest
to history.
And more possibly to
the United States Marshal.
Who knows what violence is involved
with his battered frame and bullet holes.
Would you care for a donut, doctor?
They're not as light as it should be.
- Listen, Mrs. Worth...
...you can carry this
head-in-sand attitude
just so far in the
world of reality.
Let me get this man
out of your house.
I can dump him in an establishment
that passes for a hotel...
...in this oft times dubious
community of ours.
In Madame Sanitary hobble?
- Then he will be off your hands.
But he's much better off here
- Of course he is.
Who cares what happens to him?
- We do.
I don't know what to say.
Once, when I was studying
medicine in Europe...
...I had a friend,
an artist.
He drew portraits of people
and made them...
resemble the animals
they reminded him of.
He would have drawn this man
as a coiled cobra.
Doctor, your analogy's terribly imperfect
and your naturalism faulted.
Cobras don't coil.
Doctor, we are so fond of thee
and we respect you so greatly.
We assured that you
will finally realize...
...that realism untempered by
sentiments of humanity
...is really just a mean hard cold
outlook on life.
A frightened outlook.
I stand defeated.
And furthermore, there are
times in this house...
...that I feel as if I'm living in
a never never land.
But don't hesitate to call on me
anytime you need help.
Hello.
You're awake?
- Sure, I'm awake.
What is all this?
- What?
Where am I?
Don't you remember? Father and I
drove you into town.
Is anything wrong?
- No.
The doctor says you will be alright
in a week or two.
You were delirious, you know?
Two days and two nights.
Oh, maybe that's why
I'm so hungry.
I could eat a yearling steer...
...if I can catch one.
We will get you something.
Mother!
You talked a lot in your delirium.
Mother, he's awake.
- How is he?
Hungry!
If he's hungry,
he's going to be alright.
Thanks a lot for housing.
- You're welcome.
Smoked sausages and eggs?
Sounds great.
- 2 eggs or would you like 3?
I would like 6.
- Ye shall have them.
Penny, get one of your father's
shirts here, and a razor.
I'll go get him some food...
So I talked a lot?
- Yes.
I listened only because
I thought that you might
say something that would
aide us in helping you.
Notifying your wife,
for instance.
What did I say?
- If you had a wife.
What did I talk about?
You talked of Margaret,
she...
...filled out a red dress...
What else?
Oh, you mentioned someone
named "Lila".
Is that all?
If you have a wife,
we could notify her.
No wife.
That's 12.
I haven't been so flattered
since my donuts...
won first prize at the fair
back in Pennsylvania.
They must be smart
in Pennsylvania.
Some of the members thought it's an
exhibition of pride to enter my donuts.
But what harm can there be
in a little donut...
...unless, one eats so many
of them they explode,
which is likely to happen
to you, young man.
Well, there's worse ways
of checking out.
I'll help you with the dishes.
- No, you stay and watch Quirt Evans.
I'm curious to know
the effect of 6 eggs,
a pound of sausage
and 12 donuts.
I'll call thee in
time for the milking.
Do all you people from Pennsylvania
talk like that?
Like what?
"Thee."
We're "Friends".
"Friends" of who?
- Of all.
The society of "Friends".
Many people call us "Quakers".
Oh! It's a religion.
- It's a belief.
That on the wall...
"Each human being has an
integrity that can be hurt only...
..."by the act of that
same human being.
"And not by the act of
another human being."
Is that Quaker stuff?
You mean nobody can
hurt you but yourself?
That's what the "Friends" believe.
Well suppose somebody whacks you
over the head with a branding iron...
...won't that hurt?
- Physically, of course.
But in reality, it would injure only the
person doing the act of force or violence.
Only the doer can be hurt by
an evil or mean act.
Are there many of you Quakers?
- Very few.
Sort of figured that.
Good morning, gentlemen.
- Good morning.
Carrot from our garden.
I found these out
at the road.
It belongs to a fella
named "Quirt Evans".
I understand you're
a friend of his,
maybe you can see to it
he gets them back...
Leave it here. I'll make sure
that he gets them.
That Quirt, he'd lose his shirt
if it wasn't buttoned on.
...careless about everything.
I keep telling him,
sooner or later.....
On second thought you can just
tell me where he's, and..
I can take it on back to him, myself.
Where is Quirt Evans?
You mean where is he?
Ever notice how fella keep
repeating the question,
when he's stalling
about answering.
Yeah! Maybe if I bend this gun over
his head, he'll quit stalling.
But gentlemen,
I hardly know Quirt Evans.
He lies, too.
You've been bragging all over town
of what good friends you two are.
You know, this fella ain't got
many good qualities, has he?
Sit down, friend.
Maybe that will help your memory.
I'm asking about Quirt Evans.
Well, all I know is...
Thanks for sewing the shirt...
...but I can't find my pants.
Get back in bed.
Laziness is the only thing
that's kept me there this long.
The doctor said that you're to stay
in bed 4 more days.
Oye, you're up.
That's no way to speak
to an older person, John.
We're pals...
...you wouldn't expect a pal
to call me "Mister", would you?
See, doctor said to tell you that some
men in town are looking for you.
Said one of them is
a Mister Laredo Stevens.
Get my pants.
- But your leg.
Johnny, get me my pants.
- No, John.
Will thee get my pants?
Get the pants,
John.
But you said...
What are you looking at?
- Thee.
Oh boy, it's a good thing
I'm not a tattletale.
What set him off?
"Thee" is a familiar term.
- The what?
The familiar, the plain language.
"Get thee my pants," ye said.
What about it?
Oh, among us, "thee" and "thou" are used
only among the loved ones.
...to all others, we use
"You, he, and they"
...mother to children, husband to wife
and children to...
Between lovers of course.
I'm sorry.
- I'm not.
What?
I'm not! I wished thee would
speak that way to me.
Well.
I knew right away.
That night.
It's supposed to be
a dull kind of life.
I could take you
a lot of places...
I'd go.
- What?
I would rather stay
here with thee
but if thee rather go someplace else,
then I would go someplace else.
I sound very bold?
Well, it's just that...
...I didn't think religious people
were quite so, sudden and direct...
Well that's the way I feel and it would
be dishonest to say anything else.
Yeah!
I used to wonder about it,
I suppose every girl does.
About what?
About love......
About whether or not you got to know
someone whom you know a little by little
...or it happened at once...
Thee are shocked....
Well, I wouldn't say shocked exactly....
...you sure get to the point.
- Should I be different?
No, Penny, I like you
just the way you are.
Who emptied this gun?
- Father.
Quirt, a gun is a symbol of force, evil.
We never have one in our home.
It's a concession that father
allowed even an empty one.
It's only because you couldn't rest without...
- Where are the cartridges?
Outside.
Hey! Why don't we
just bust in?
Because busting through doors with
Quirt Evans on the other side,
...ain't my idea
of a healthy past time.
Tell them to "come in".
"Come in."
You can stand right there.
...against the light.
Howdy, Quirt.
You sure ran a ring
around me alright.
I don't think it was right
friendly of you to beat me
..to locating that tract
after my boys found it.
I'm willing to listen
to your side of it,
I'm a reasonable man.
Sure, Laredo is always reasonable.
That's why he's the biggest man
in the territory.
You're the biggest man
in the territory, Laredo?
So a lot of people say.
- I hadn't heard.
You nervous?
- No, Evans.
I can't figure out why you keep
stepping on my toes all the time...
But, that's your business.
I'm a good loser.
...I like a good loser.
Course I like any kind of loser
better than a winner.
...yeah!
You know I had a chance to
do a heap of thinking
while I was following your
trail across the territory.
I followed it by the string of
ran out horses you left behind....
Well, I figured it out this way.
Quirt don't really
want that land.
Because working isn't
exactly in his line.
[Quirt]:
Is it in your line?
No, of course not. I was getting
it for another fella.
And well, I figured maybe you'll sell.
I don't hear anything jingle.
Is it alright to put my hand
inside my shirt?
Why not?
$5,000 in gold there.
I want 20.
Well okay, but I have to owe you 15,
that's all I got on me.
I have the deed in my pocket, here.
- Get it out.
Now, if the young lady could find us
something to sign this with.
Still Laredo's hired boy,
eh, Hondo?
Picking up after him,
carrying matches for his cigars.
You mind yourself.
- He'll mind himself...
... Won't you Hondo?
- Miss...
..Would you mind taking this over
to Mister Evans, please?
Thank you.
You know, I'm sure glad to see
you up and around, Quirt...
...we heard you were
flat on your back.
Sorry to disappoint you.
You come on over and get the
rest of that money anytime.
Anytime that is that you feel
you're able.
I'll see you one
of these days.
Well... ah,
so long, Quirt.
Saddle up my horse, will you kid?
Throw on my war bags.
What would have happened if they
knew the gun was empty?
It would have been: "Saturday
night in Sioux City."
Tie on my slicker, too.
Sorry.
- Oh, no, Quirt, no.
What kind of a boarder
do you think I am?
You can't do that. We'd have tended
any wounded human, and not for pay.
You don't believe in force, so you
can't force me to take it back.
I'm afraid you're outwitted,
Thomas.
How long I have been here?
- Almost 3 weeks.
Kinda hate to get going.
But you can't. Your leg!
You are in no condition to travel.
Don't worry, your cooking has me
grained up and ready for market.
Adios, amigos.
Quirt.
Shall I pack my things?
Why?
- Thee leave without me?
I got places to go...
Quirt, I didn't care, it doesn't make
any difference to me how far...
I know so little...
I.....
...I didn't know that it could happen
to one and not the other.
..I thought it always
happened to both.
That isn't it.
It isn't?
Well...
- So thee do feel..?
Look, Penny...
...I'm not that kind of a guy
that does things suddenly.
I gotta look before I leap.
You can ask anybody,
they'll tell you that...
...Quirt Evans is a
mighty cautious citizen.
Oh then, it's just that thee
are not sure yet?
Yeah!
Sorry.
Please stay.
It's all saddled, Quirt.
Unsaddle it.
You gonna stay?
A double eagle!
Well there is something that I'd
rather have than this.
A favor. A big favor.
- Well, you got them both. What is it?
Will you ride past my
schoolhouse with me?
Because a lot of boys who don't
believe that I know Quirt Evans.
Sure.
Everybody says that you're the
fastest man in the territory.
Well, there are those
who'd say I'm pretty slow.
A man should be able to do
a good days work
after a breakfast like that.
Well, see that thee do it...
Penny, where is the bucket?
I declare, Penny, I don't know
what's happening to thee.
Funny thing about pan cakes
...I lose my appetite for them
after the first couple of dozen.
They weren't very good
this morning, too heavy.
Wild Indian... put water
on those vegetables this morning.
There's always work round
here to be done.
Thee wanted to be a farmer,
didn't thee?
Not any more,
I don't...
[Rooster Crows]
Surely you could walk to
the barn without that.
What?
- The gun.
It balances me, one leg is longer
than the other.
...you know the weight.
- Thee are a liar.
[Rooster Crows]
Throw the cows
some hay.
There's the pitch fork.
Before I was 15, I learned to
hate those things.
...I swore I would leave ploughs
and pitch forks to farmers.
I'll do it.
No, I'll do it.
But it's an occasion.
Thee...
- What?
Nothing... just...
just "thee."
Penny!
Why, you wanted hay, didn't you?
Didn't "thee"?
15.
Better put this little one
in the box.
16.
Now get a bucket of water.
Water, water.
All I do is carry water.
No force.
Say, wasn't this place irrigated?
I see all these flumes
and ditches.
Frederick Carson
turned the water off.
Frederick Carson?
He's the man who bought
the ranch up above from the friends
who couldn't make a go of it.
We had built a community dam,
but... It was on his property.
Whatcha you do about it?
Don't tell me. You prayed.
Of course.
- Getcha any water?
We didn't pray for water.
We prayed for Frederick Carson.
Carson turned off the water
and you prayed for him?
Of course.
Can't you see? By committing an evil act
the poor man injured his soul?
I'm glad there's a well.
Cause it sure gets thirsty
around here.
...if we had to wait for Carson.
Gotta walk this pony.
Penny.
Nothing.
Be sure you don't leave any
slack on that cinch.
Boss will sure howl...
This ain't the first pony
I ever saddled.
...he'd squawk no matter
how I done it.
He's sure getting mean these days,
ain't he?
You can take it as his natural born.
That boil on his neck don't
help him none either.
Get out of my way.
You belong behind a plough.
Who's Carson?
Don't get down. We ain't taking
on no saddle tramps on this spread.
Are you deaf?
I said get moving, tramp.
Nice dam.
- Yeah, what's that to you?
Take out the top two planks.
What did you say?
The top two. There are 16 inches
of water over there.
Who says so?
- I do.
And who might you be when
you're at home?
Quirt Evans.
Well anybody might ride up here
and say they're Quirt Evans.
He ain't known round
here by sight.
Anybody can say
they're him.
Sure could.
There's a "Q.E."
stamped on his saddle.
Well, take the top planks out of
the head gate, you stupid idiot.
I don't need all that extra water.
Step up on that pony.
Now, look here Mr. Evans, I've done
what you've told me to.
You sure did.
Step up on that pony.
Well, I'm the kind of fella who tries to
get along with everybody.
Side me.
- Wait a minute.
Maybe we better take off a
couple more of them planks...
cause I have 10 times
the water I need.
That will do for now.
Well, if you ever need more, Mr. Evans,
all you got to do is say so...
I figured that...
Hey, Mom! Water!
Water, water!
Mother, look at the flow.
Mother all the ditches are full of water.
Water! Water!
- Wonderful!
Thomas!
Let's start off from the scratch...
...you got more water than you need.
Absolutely right, Quirt,
I mean Mr. Evans.
Do you mind if I call you "Quirt"?
Not a bit...
So it's no skin off your moccasins if
you let a little water over that ditch.
Absolutely no, Mr. Evans...
I mean, "Quirt".
You're going to be neighborly or not?
- Well, I sure am, Quirt.
That's the way to talk.
Thomas!
Frederick Carson.
- Howdy, Mrs. Worth.
We always knew you would
change your mind.
Yes ma'am,
I did.
Thank you, Frederick, all of us here
in the valley are grateful to you.
Worth, it's like what
I was saying,
I ain't got any use
for all that extra water...
Why shouldn't I let my
neighbors use it?
I believe that neighbors
should be friendly.
What have you got there on your neck?
A boil?
Mrs. Worth, I have wrestled with
that dang burnt boil...
Have you tried putting soap into it?
No, ma'am. I ain't.
You get down for a minute and into
the house and I'll fix it for you.
You are going to hurt me?
- No...That's a shame... it looks awful.
Well, looks like your prayers
straightened everything out.
So, you think your gun changed
Frederick Carson?
Who says I pointed a gun?
I do.
- Well, I didn't.
He gave in more easily
than I expected.
Thee remember this, Quirt:
"The lord moves in
mysterious manner...
...at times using strange methods
and odd instruments."
Me?
It would be odd.
I just get a gnawin' hankerin' after
good pies and truck like that...
Frederick Carson!
- Yes, ma'am?
I want you to have these,
they're awfully good with
coffee in the morning.
Makes me to go home
and shoot my Chinese cook.
You just come back for more anytime
you like, there are always plenty.
Thanks.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye, Frederick.
A man outta see more
of his neighbors.
Wonderful woman that Mrs. Worth...
She fixed my boil.
[Mother]:
Penny!
Excuse me. But I think father
wants to give thanks...
You know, he already
thanked me.
I know, but now I think he wants to
thank someone else.
Hold my pondering when I get aboard.
Will you?
Mrs. Worth is going to keep me
supplied in pies
... I ought to bring her a quarter of beef
now and then.
Finally, come to an understanding
with my neighbors.
You sure did.
Oh! You knew I was scared to death,
when I made that speech to them people.
...I'm glad you made me do it.
Makes me feel good.
Adios, amigo.
Dinner.
What's the dinner
going to be?
Roast venison, vegetables, and
of course a skimpy chicken.
With the pie and cake
I'll try to make out.
Chicken or venison?.
- Both. I feel real good.
Oh, thee do?
New dress.
Oh! It's first day.
You call it "Sunday".
Quirt, do me a favor,
hitch up the ponies for father.
Sure.
And will you do me
another favor?
Go for a ride with us.
- Where?
You're not to ask,
it's a surprise, a pleasant one.
Hey, Quirt!
We got a surprise for you.
He knows,
I told him.
Thought you weren't allowed
to work on Sunday?
Quirt, there is nothing we're
not allowed to do...
...it's just we don't believe
in doing what we know is wrong.
That makes it pretty much
"Each fella's own guess".
Each fella knows, inside.
There's a lot of gents I wouldn't
wanna give that much leeway to.
I didn't mean to
frighten you, miss.
Is there a fella named Quirt Evans
around here?
Yes, I'll get him.
Never mind.
I can do my talking to you.
Has he been here long?
About 3 weeks I guess.
He didn't disappear for say,
2 days, during that time, did he?
No.
- Hello, you weather beaten old hang man...
Penny, this is Wistful McLintock...
the marshal of the territory.
Hiya, Miss!
Don't let that grey hair fool you.
He's a curly wolf.
Hello, Quirt. I thought I had
you about half hung.
Tall fella. Fast with a gun, held up
the Baker's stage. Killed a couple.
Well, you're tall and some say
you're a fast man.
..but I guess, I'll have to take
the little lady's word for it.
When you and Laredo Stevens going to
get around to killing one another?
Laredo?
We water our horses out of the
same trough...
Well, I'm sure looking forward
to hanging the survivor.
You know, I'm a figuring man...
...sometimes I don't know
all the answers....
...like that fella
"Quirt Evans"
Handy man with a colt...
...while he was acting as Wyatt Earp's
deputy over in Tombstone.
...one day he turns in his badge,
and starts to build himself
a nice cattle spread.
Suddenly sells out
and he goes on a pry.
Why? That's what I
ain't figured yet.
Sometimes things connect.
About that time a fella,
called "Walt Emerson"...
...went down in front of
Laredo Stevens...
...Walt was reaching at the time,
some say a gambler standing there
grabbed his hand....
...maybe that's connected...
How did you stand
with Walt Emerson?
I knew him.
Two things connected?
I know a lot of people.
Well, I'll figure it out...
...I usually do.
I'm patient.
Little lady, don't be looking at him...
with your eyes all bugged out
like a cow would a bull.
...there ain't no future in it.
So long, folks.
Quirt, please stay away
from Laredo Stevens.
He owes me money. And don't worry,
I might come out on top.
That would be even worse.
Worse! Would it be worse if he
goes down than I go down?
Of course,
don't you see?
Oh, I'll be a guy
with a marked soul.
Don't make it sound so crude, Quirt,
you see why- I couldn't love you.
Alright, I won't
look up Laredo.
It's better this way
...every time he opens his door,
every time he hears footsteps
coming round the corner...
...Laredo will start sweating,
thinking it's me.
...His food won't set well
for the rest of his life.
Well alright, if I'm going to be holy
I gotta get some fun out of it.
You know I feel like such a gadabout.
It seems hardly a whole week
since last First day.
Hey, Quirt!
I thought it was you.
Well, well, well.
- Hello.
Mister and Mrs. Worth, Miss Worth,
Randy McCall.
How do you do?
- How do you do?
Just fine, thank you.
Well, well, well...
- You said that before.
We don't want to keep you
if you're in a hurry.
I'm not in no hurry. I've got no place to go.
- Well, we have.
Would ye care to come along with us?
- Sure, where?
To a meeting.
Both men: To a meeting?
Yes, to meeting.
You don't wanna go do you?
It would be nice if he could.
- We'd be happy to have any friend of Quirt's.
You would?
Well that's just fine.
You know, ma'am...
I sure am an old friend of Quirt's.
I remember one time we were chasing some
cattle down the Lawanda river...
...herd stampeded, Quirt pulled me out
from underneath it.
And there was another time, remember?
In Opus Palace, down at San Antonio.
We're late.
- I know, but...
Good bye.
If you can join us it is in the grove,
just on the other side of the town.
Thank you, ma'am.
- Good day.
Get along.
"Why asketh thou me concerning
that which you should do?
"One who is and is good.
But if thou wilt enter unto life...
"...keep the commandments.
"He sayeth unto him 'which?'
And God said...
"Thou shalt not kill ...
"...thou shalt not steal...
"...thou shalt not bear false witness...
"...honor thy father
and thy mother...
"and thou shalt love thy neighbor
as thy self."
What comes out of this thing
that makes it worth all this work?
Frozen pudding.
Hello, Nelson.
- Hello, Penny.
Nelson, meet Quirt Evans.
- How do you do?
- Howdy.
Nelson's our horse shoer.
By the way, I brought that
maple sugar you like so much.
Oh, excuse me, I'll put it here.
- Thank you.
Isn't this the Morgan baby?
- Yes, I'm minding her.
He sure is a cute little fella.
Looks just like his father.
I'm coming out next week
to shoe the horses.
Oh, fine.
I'll get some water.
- Here, let me help you.
Here, twirl this thing.
Frozen pudding.
Hold him a minute, Quirt,
I want some of those flowers.
Sick or something?
I don't believe it.
It's a baby.
- Yeah, I know.
Is it old enough to talk?
- Of course not.
If it can't talk,
it can't snitch.
I've got something I think
you would like to hear.
Laredo Stevens
is planning a big play.
...he's going to jump
up some guys
that are moving a trail herd
down from the north.
I figured, it maybe you, me and
couple of friends can play copycat.
You heard me,
didn't you?
You can have
my part of it.
What am I listening to?
You passing up a chance
to blister Laredo?
That's right.
What's the matter with you, Quirt?
Is farm life...
Oh, the Jane....
Sticking in your head into this bucket
will shut you up.
You are getting awful touchy lately... you never
used to mind what I said.
Hello.
- Hi.
Come along with the water, Quirt.
Shut up.
Quirt, would you
come over here?
Sit down.
May I have your attention?
Friends, we all know the purpose
of this meeting is three fold.
As always, to give thanks to the
goodness bestowed upon us.
...but also to give thanks for the particular
that the fields are getting water.
... and the crops and
the livestock thrive.
There are two marsh's
right at the top of the valley.
...if you take a look from out there, you
can see a herd coming from 10 miles.
[Mr. Worth]:
...Quirt Evans.
Friends...
We are happy to present you with this
token of our friendship for you.
This is "Quirt Evans".
We are happy to have him here with us,
because he provided another incident
...which reaffirms our belief...
...that all men are good
if they're shown the light.
He persuaded Frederick Carson
to let down the water...
...by showing him, that a man who
is a friend to other men...
is a happy man himself.
May I shake your hand,
Quirt Evans?
I want to talk to you.
This will sound like I'm butting
into your business and I am.
And you outta give me a watch
with a gold case for doing it.
You dim witted nail bender!
Marry that girl.
Marry her? Why sure, you know...,
she knows how I feel.
How would she know?
Stop yammering about shoeing horses,
that's no way to talk to a girl.
Talk to her about her.
And marry her. And do it quick.
Hey!
- Come on!
Listen to this.....
"And Benaiah the son of Jehoiada,
"the son of a valiant man of Kabzeel,
"who had done many acts of valor,
"slew two men of Moab and
"...went down and slew 3 lions in the
midst of a pit in time of snow"
Whoo! Three lions!
"And Benaiah slew an Egyptian
who had a sword.
"He took away his sword and
slew him with a staff."
I guess that must mean
a club.
Oh, brother, this is good writing.
- Let's go.
What about the Bible?
You can't throw it away.
That would be bad luck.
Then keep it.
Alright. This is one book
I'm sure going to read.
I'd better take you back
to the Morgans.
Why did Quirt leave
so abruptly?
I don't know...
Hey, Boss!
- Yeah?
Right on time.
Look behind you.
Let's saddle up, men.
Let's get out of here.
Look! Coming down
off the hill!
Come on...
Hey Quirt,
what does "beget" mean?
I think I hear them.
Yeah!
- Let's get hitched up.
I don't know how I
missed this book.
You know you're very strange.
But I like you just the same.
On account your head works.
Much nicer this way....
You know anybody can
just shoot these guys.
...you think of an interesting
way of doing it.
...and you know, Quirt.
I hate to shoot people.
Remember I shot a waddie
once in Montana?
I dreamed about it,
all the next night.
Then of course, there's always witnesses,
then you gotta shoot the witnesses.
Stop jabbering and let's go.
- Okay, take it easy pal.
Settle down,
don't wanna lose my war bags.
Then again, I figured you may
have changed your mind
about shooting it out with Laredo
along with these guys.
Step up on that horse.
- Okay, you got it.
Maybe you're just crowding Laredo
into drawing in front of a lot of people.
Gonna save him for a big night
in town, eh?
Hey... look!
Let's go.
Take the outsider, Dennis.
Start turning them, Hondo.
I ain't, Hondo.
That's a horse like Quirt has...
Yeah! That's just who it is.
Next time we face...
- Yeah! I know...
Wipe those new boots off
and see if you can run him down.
You know that champagne may be
a lot fancier than whiskey.
..But sure it don't give
you quick action.
To tell you the truth, I don't really like it.
- It's very fashionable.
How do you like it, Lila?
Tickles going down and it's expensive.
So I like it.
You sleepy, Tommy?
- Nope.
Tired?
- No.
Worried, or maybe
just plain bored?
Not a chance, baby.
You never bored me.
I wish I had that in writing.
You know it's a long time
since you told me that...
...my hair reminded you of corn silk.
Alright! Your hair reminds
me of corn silk.
All golden, darling?
- That's right...
All golden.
You have changed...
You're less romantic.
...a lot more absentminded.
Take a turn at the wheel.
Win yourself a farm in Kansas.
I don't want a farm in Kansas.
Well alright! I'll win you
a trip around the world.
Miss Lila, the customers are waiting,
and that's no way to treat customers.
25 hot one on the red.
Give me a stack of blues.
"There's something in your eyes...
"...a little bit different.
"Something that appeals to me.
"I love the way they change
from angels to devils...
"always full of mystery.
"There is something in your smile
a little bit different...
"Something I've been looking for.
"If I could just be sure
that you're on the level...
"...I would never ask for more.
"I got a funny little feeling...
"...the first time we met.."
17 odd on black.
17, there goes the last button
on my shirt.
Alright buddy, you gonna let it ride?
Going to ride on 17?
Cash me in.
Place your bets.
Something that I never knew...
"In every way...
"...you're just a little bit different.
"That's why I - love - youuuu!!!"
Thanks for the money, daddy.
I hope you didn't think
I was hinting.
Bourbon,
large glass.
There's plenty of rooms on either side,
you have to come bullying
in between us?
I didn't see you...
You interrupted a very
important discussion
on serious matters
regarding big things.
Me and my brothers
don't like it.
Gentlemen, gentlemen...
no trouble please.
We just put the place back together
after the last difference of opinion..
...gentlemen, more over the breakage
and the overhead. Mainly the breakage.
I've had a dreadful time
keeping body and soul together.
What I think is going to happen,
happens...
...it will round off a full day.
There's your trip.
What's eating you, tall man?
You had words with
those Baker brothers?
Who?
- Those 4 rhinos.
No.
Told around they're some
quarrelsome citizens.
Gentlemen, lets consider the incident
closed. Watch our tempers.
Maybe I oughta go
and apologize.
More whiskey.
-That did it!
I'll be right back.
I hope.
Where have you been?
- Oh, Randy always on tap.
You don't know what you
are doing to me...
Please...
I've got a large family.
Hey, wait a minute,
it's me.
Billy, get him.
That's my old friend, Billy.
Come on get him... come on
get hold of him.
Go on, you got him.
You've got him!
Thanks.
I must have hit the wrong man.
- I'll say you did, you...
Hey, for...!
- Sorry, Quirt. How you doing?
Don't worry about me.
Come on.
You wait outside. Check them
and count them as we throw them out.
One!
- Don't count!
It's gettin' late.
Oh honey, I was so afraid
you'd get hurt.
All singing: "And I'll never see my
darling any more
"I'm sitting by the river
and I'm weeping all the day!!!
"For you've gone from the
old Kentucky shore!!!"
It's wonderful. We have money,
whiskey and lovely ladies,
and just had a beautiful fight.
...I tell you, we would really oughta
be thankful for our blessings.
Ah, you have been reading
that Bible again.
That's something I never
thought I would see.
What?
A Bible with your name on it.
Now where would you
get a Bible?
Quirt!
Oh Randy,
stop him.
With what?
Where is he going?
Has he forgotten something?
No.
Penny, what is wrong with thee?
Table cloths don't belong in there.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Quirt!
Unsaddle my horse,
will you kid?
Sure!
Want a boarder for a while?
Of course. You're always welcome.
- Quirt!
Hello!
I haven't had a decent meal
since I left here. Chocolate?
Not very good, the flour you know.
I'll just stick around
till you get one right.
I'll feed the chickens.
- So early, Penny?
Yes. Can you help me, Quirt?
Does it take two to feed
a few chickens, mother?
At times, Thomas, at times.
Remember?
You came back?
Yes.
Why?
I don't know exactly.
Why did you go away
without saying anything?
I don't know that exactly, either.
I think it's because
I frightened you.
I know that sounds strange
that I should frighten you, but .....
...but I mean it.
You were frightened
because I was stupid.
You thought that living with me
would be tiresome ...
..and dull after a while.
Tiresome and dull because....
...all I knew, raised since a baby,
here among the farmers was our belief...
...that people love, marry, and
stay together forever after that.
I'm not such a fool not to know that
outside worldly places that people love...
...it doesn't have to follow that they
marry and stay together forever.
I know that sometimes
they separate.
Are you ever going to run down
and let me talk?
No, Quirt, that's what you were afraid of,
that I tie myself around your neck..
...and when you get tired you
couldn't be rid of me...
and I made up my mind that if you
come back I'd tell you this.
...but whatever you want,
Quirt, you can leave...
If I go away
ye go with me.
If I go away,
thee go away.
I used to be an Injun fighter.
Just can't help walking up
soft on people..
Morning, missy...
This young man been doing
any traveling since I was here last?
A fellow over Castle Verde Way lost
a big herd a few days ago.
Well, missy...
Cat got your tongue?
Why ask her?
You know I have been traveling.
You look at my corral
to see how my horse shaped up..
I did just that...
You sure covered a lot of country.
It's a right weary animal..
I just want to see if the young lady
would lie for you.
I was going to...
You have been over to Castle Verde Way?
I've been to Rimrock
and I got witnesses to prove it.
Witnesses!
For instance?
Randy McCall, Christine Taylor.
That's what I call witnesses.
Who else?
Lila Neal, I suppose.
She'd make a good
alibi witness for you.
Randy, Christine and Lila...
...there's three to draw to.
So Lila saw you there too, huh?
Yes.
Come here, jug head...
You dollar and a half bush jumper...
Well, guess I missed you again, Quirt.
...but I'm patient..
...that's what hangs all you fellows
in the end.
...I'm patient.
Lila?
You talked about her
when you were delirious.
Quirt, I...
...I wish my hair were...
...golden like corn silk, like you said.
There is a sight
I never thought I'd see.
Quirt Evans behind a plough.
The pony walks as soft as you do.
I taught him.
Oh, I figured you'd have heard him.
...except you were thinking too hard.
Haven't you got some real important
business to attend to?
Some place else.
- Sure.
But I always liked to keep track
of your whereabouts.
You know, Quirt...
...I always figured on using a
new rope in hanging you...
'Cause I kind of respected you.
You never took the best of things....
...and all your men went down
looking at you.
Go and mind your own business.
I usually do.
It's a shame things don't always
turn out the way they should.
Now that little gal... she might marry
some young fella..
...who would know what to
do with that plough...
Why don't you kick up that horse
and move on?
Some young fella that would
raise up a lot of grain.
...cows, sheep, kids..
..the kind of a fella that she'd
always know where he was..
Do I have to run you off?
Well now I tell you. I never have
been run off no place yet.
...where I aim to stay.
But it just so happens
that I gotta be going.
No, Quirt...
...you don't rate a
new rope with me.
Look, ah...
...does a lot of potpourri and
nonsense have to go with it?
..I'm not going to stand
for a lot of...
dressing up and a batch
of jabbering people...
...looking at me,
just because I'm getting married.
Oh Quirt,
come along with me.
Well, yes or no?
- Come on.
Picking black berries?
Alright.
I think we have enough, Quirt.
Never did like black berries...
Now I know I was right.
It's too much work connected with it.
- I'll get some more ferns.
Look out there's a wasp on the petunia!
- Don't kill it.
Well it's alright to for you to trust
wasps and people but...
...he might have known that I don't trust
him and decide to take first bite.
And incidentally that's not petunia,
that's a daisy.
That's a petunia.
Petunias, daisies,
daisies, petunias.
Quirt Evans.
Oh nothing.
I just like the sound of it.
Quirt. Where did thee ever get
such an odd name?
Fellow who half raised me,
gave it to me.
He found me somewhere along
a big cattle trail.
Folks had been bushwhacked
by Indians, I guess..
He was a big fella.
Cattleman.
Swung a wide loop in his younger days,
I think.
Wide loop?
He wasn't too careful
whose calf he threw his rope at..
Most of the old cattlemen
were like that.
He raised me. Quite a guy.
His name was Walt Emerson.
He was down in a gambling place...
...a fellow grabbed his gun-arm just
as he drew. He was murdered.
Stop it.
Then what?
Well I just bounced around
from place to place.
Quirt Evans.
I don't see any gun.
- I know him, he's got a gun alright..
...I know him.
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Well, what are we waiting for?
Nothing, I guess.
Let's find a saloon.
You don't have to be worry
about Penny, mother.
Oh, I cant help worrying about it,
Johnny.
Get that doctor.
Burn up the roads both ways.
A drink?
It's amazing...
...the various uses to which
men put alcohol.
To each different individual,
it's either a stimulant, a depressant
or an anodyne.
Just now I'm using it
as an anodyne.
Get to the point.
Practice of medicine...
...is one of the most infuriating
professions known to man.
It takes 30 years of experience
to teach you...
...that in the final analysis there's
nothing to do but stand and watch.
If she has a lucid moment...
...you better speak to her.
...I'm not trying to argue you out
of anything.
Maybe you ought to
stop and think.
She wouldn't like this,
Quirt!
...I'm not arguing for or against
her point of view.
...I know to her, the world's worst
tragedy would be
if you should kill a man.
Of course, you could
argue logically...
that she wouldn't know whether
you killed him or not.
I think she'd know.
Any discussion has to have
at least two participants.
Of course if you refuse
to answer me.
Quirt!
If I felt cynical....
...this would be a good opportunity to
observe that we are about to see,
...a perfect example of
"An eye for an eye" etc.
Unfortunately I can't quote
chapter and verse.
...I'm too tired
to be cynical.
Father, father,
come upstairs!
But thee are very ill,
thee must not be moving about.
Mother, I've got to go ...
Thee must get back into bed.
- But he needs me.
This is insanity. I told you
to keep her in bed.
Do you want to commit suicide?
If you don't stay under
those covers, young lady...
There's no fever.
Thee must do what the doctor says.
- Mother, please.
I can't understand it.
I can't understand it at all.
There must be some logical
scientific explanation.
I'm too old to start
believing in miracles.
Wrap her in blankets.
You know if the two hadn't
had me covered...
I would never let that Hondo Jeffries
pistol whip me...
Wait till Quirt Evans hear about this...
Quirt will take the starch out of
the whole caboodle of them.
Why, Quirt and me once...
...well, it was Dodge City
several years back.
...when the Earps and Clantons were gunning.
Well me and Quirt...
Come here.
- Yes, Mr. Evans.
Know Laredo Stevens?
He's in the Eagle,
and that pistol whipping Hondo
is with him.
Take him a message.
Hey, buy the boys a drink.
- Celebrating?
Sure,
why not?
Don't you get excited when you
make a big win like this?
Why get excited... sometimes you win
and sometimes you lose.
Don't get excited,
gentlemen.
I ain't looking for trouble...
I'm just a carrier of a message.
- Yeah? What is it?
He said to "Come out in the street...
...he's waiting for you."
- Who says?
Quirt Evans.
[Hits sour note on piano]
What is this, a joke?
Quirt Evans is...
Take a look out at the streets.
See, if it really is.
Jack, take a look at the street.
There's a tall hombre in
a black hat standing...
...at the blacksmith's shop.
Mind if I use the back door, Pete?
- So long, Pete.
Well, they say "a cat got nine lives."
Maybe ole Quirt's part cat.
He also said "He was curious to know
how much whiskey it would take...
"...to build up your nerve
to come out."
You're fixing to get
your ears pin back?
There's a better pair of ears
out in the street...
if you wanna pin
somebody's ears back.
Hey, you drink this.
Sure, if I don't have to
stand near you.
Come on.
I wonder whether if that sharp
shooting Marshal is around town?
Oh, I saw him ride out of town
an hour ago.
That's good, we don't want him
around here to spoil our play.
Yeah, I bet that's just exactly
how you meant it.
Look out, there's going
to be a shooting!
Hyah, hyah!
Quirt!
Quirt...
...step away from those women.
Why don't you
turn around, Quirt?
[Gun shots ring out!]
Nothing ever works out right.
Had them dead to rights.
They got the Baker stage...
...so I figured I'd watch the ruckus.
You down them
and I'd hang you....
...sort of...
..Sort of killing three hawks
with one stone.
...so to speak.
Nothing, nothing ever works out right.
I may have missed you again, Quirt,
but I'm patient.
It's only a matter of time,
and I hang you.
Not me,
mister.
From now on
I'm a farmer.
That Quirt!
Hey, Quirt might need that.
No, only a man that carries a gun
ever needs one.
What are you going
to do with it?
Hang it on the wall in my office,
with a new rope!