[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BOAT HORN SOUNDS]
-Why do these boats always have
to dock in the cold grey shore?
-Yeah, there oughtta be
a law making them stay out there
'till after
breakfast anyway.
-Don't worry, Barney,
after today
you'll be shooting
that one-eyed monster of yours
for Uncle Sam.
-Yeah, you'll be seeing
plenty of cold grey dawns
then, brother.
-You'll find out in the signal corps
there's a lot of other things
besides corps signals.
-After ten years in this
racket, it'll be a vacation.
[LAUGHTER]
-Ah, sinful soul,
isn't he, boys.
-Wooh!
[LAUGHS]
-Hmm, well what do
you think of that?
Sounds fishy to me.
[BOAT HORN SOUNDS TWICE]
You're Dr. Randall, no?
-Yes.
You hear me,
Agatha Brewster, find her.
-Well, I--
-Bye for now.
You're Carter of the
Globe Tribune, aren't you?
-Mhm-mm.
-Say, there's a
woman on that boat
by the name of
Agatha Brewster.
-Yeah?
What about her?
- Ghost fodder.
She's a sister of that,
uh, missing Dr. Brewster.
Good story.
A great story.
The best.
-Hey, what gives, Jeff?
Trying to sell you
bootleg again?
- Yeah well, a screwball, I guess.
-That's her over there
with the perfume.
-Agatha, I'm awfully
glad you're here.
-Come on, Barney.
-George, it's terrible.
What happened?
-Miss Brewster?
-Yes?
-I'm from the Globe Tribune.
-Hello.
-Miss Brewster's too upset
over her brother
to give an interview right now.
-Yes, some other time.
-Oh, well, uh, may
we have a picture?
Go ahead, Barney.
-A pretty smile now.
-Smile?
-Oh, excuse me.
-Thanks, now about
that interview.
When I may I see you.
-Oh, some other day.
Next week.
-Where?
-Miss Brewster will phone you.
-Don't let her give
you the brush off.
It's a great story.
-Hey, what is this anyway?
(whimpers)
-That's all right.
-If he'd only have
listened to me
all this wouldn't have happened.
-But what about the police?
Haven't they been
able to trace him?
-Fortunately no.
-Fortunately?
-Yes, very fortunately.
Agatha, Jim was involved.
Except in this way:
He's hidden away at
Poindale, in the old mansion.
He'd be better off in
the family cemetery plot.
-No.
-Sorry, but it's true.
-But why?
-Six months ago, we made
an astounding discovery.
It was so far in advance
of anything
that's been done to
date, but Jim decided
to be the guinea pig
for this experiment himself.
I tried to talk him out of
it, but you know how stubborn
he is when he
gets an idea in his head.
We made the experiment
and unfortunately it
was a great success.
So great in fact that we've
been unable to counteract
the results.
And Jim, he's
-He's still alive, isn't he?
-Yes.
-And the story of his
disappearance is a fake?
-Yes, I put that out because of
the whole affair was sordid.
If the worst comes
to the worst, it'll
save him a great deal
of unpleasant notoriety.
-George, what can we do?
-Prepare yourself for
a great shock, Agatha.
I warn you.
It's, it's frightening.
-Well, where is he?
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
[GROANS]
-Courage.
(whimpers)
-Agatha.
You shouldn't have
brought her here.
Stop shaking, Agatha.
I won't hurt you.
-Oh, you poor boy.
[SIGHS]
-Open the door.
Get back!
[GORILLA GROWLS]
[JIM GROWLS]
Close the door.
What a mess I've made of things.
Look.
-Jim.
[GORILLA GROWLS]
-Quiet!
[CRYING]
[PHONE RINGING]
-Yeah?
-How are you coming
with that boat yarn?
-I couldn't get a thing
out of her at the boat.
Now I'm going
through the morgue.
Boy, is she a screwy dame.
-I don't that junk.
I want a personal interview.
And get me some more pictures.
Good ones.
Barney's smell.
I'm sending someone down
to replace him.
Name's Billy Mason.
-Okay, chiefy.
-Now hop to it.
And don't call me chiefy.
-Okay, chiefy.
-Going into the Army has sure
done something to Barney.
Looks more like a ghost
than a ghost hunter to me.
Now just what
could have happened
to get such a piece of trash.
-Well, it's out of focus.
It's underexposed
and overdeveloped.
And besides, there's two
pictures on the same negative.
-Is that all?
-Yes.
-Yes sir.
-Take Miss Mason down to Carter.
She's taking Barney's place.
-Yes.
-Well, thank you very
much, Mr. Martin,
for giving me the break.
I'm sure I can--
-Ah, forget it.
But remember, I'll be
satisfied with just
one picture on each negative.
-I'll do the very best I can.
-Carter, Billy Mason.
-Okay, sit down, take the
load off your feet.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Hmm, Opium Night.
What went by when
I wasn't looking?
-I see you know your perfumes.
-I know that one.
In fact, I never forget it.
Or the first girl I met
that used it either.
-Was she nice?
-Yeah, but she lied to me.
-Oh?
-She told me her boyfriend
was in boot camp.
Okay, Mason, let's go.
Mason?
-I'm Billy Mason.
-Huh?
-I said, I'm Billy Mason.
I'm taking Barney's
place, whoever he is.
-Well, why didn't you say so?
Come on.
Let's go.
-Where are we
going if I may ask?
-The Poindale, the
old Brewster home.
Gonna interview a screwy old
dame and get some pictures.
Good pictures, I hope.
-Why the I hope?
A good reporter generally
gets an interview.
-I'm not worried about
the interview,
it's the pictures
I'm worried about.
-Oh, I get it.
Well, listen, Mr. Insane,
you take care of your end of it
and don't worry about mine.
My pictures will be as
good as your interview.
And maybe a little bit better.
-Cocky little wench, aren't you?
-Well, I've had to hold my
own against four brothers
all my life.
I guess I can handle a
4F like you.
-All right.
And what gives you the
idea I'm a 4F?
-Well, I can't think of
any other good reason
you're not in uniform.
-Listen, baby, you're looking
smack dab at a 14 carat 1A.
Totally fit, physically perfect
with a personal letter
in his pocket from
the president.
30 days from now
I'll be Jefferson B. Carter,
seaman first class.
-Oh.
-Oh, yes.
30 days hath
September, April,
June, and Jefferson B. Carter.
-Well, I'll take back the
part about 4F.
But the rest of it still stands.
-It makes me wish I was
in the Navy right now.
-That makes two of us.
All right, sailor.
Shove off.
-You have no idea
what I have gone
through in the
last three months.
Sometimes I am perfectly normal.
But later,
I sit for hours and hours
looking in the mirror
hoping
and praying for
the slightest sign
on my face to change.
It doesn't come.
And I feel myself holding back
the animal instinct.
I try to fight it.
And I try to fight it
with all my willpower.
And I feel it's not limited.
I locked myself in
there with him fearing
that I might do
something terrible.
Oh, I can't stand it any longer.
I can't stand it.
But I am the
master of me.
I must do what I am asking him.
-What did you ask him to do, James,
and he refused?
-I must have human spinal
fluid injected into me.
It's my only chance.
Randall and I both agreed to it.
It's the only way to counteract
the ape fluid injection.
But he won't do it.
Won't do it.
-Please, James, please.
I'll talk to George.
I know he'll do
anything to save you.
I'll ask him.
-No, he won't.
I pleaded... and begged.
-James tells me you refused
to help him any further.
-Did he tell you why?
-No.
-Then I'll tell you.
I'd have to commit
murder to do it.
-Murder?
-Yes, cold blooded murder.
You see this spinal fluid,
it might might cure him.
And there's a great
possibility it would.
Discuss the chance with him.
That fluid must be taken
from a living person.
And the taking of it
means instant death.
-Oh.
-Well, I must say the house
matches the old girl to a t.
-What do you mean?
-She's a ghost hunter?
-Did you say ghost?
-Yeah.
Ever see any?
-[LAUGHS] Don't be silly.
-She has.
[LAUGHS]
No kidding.
She's written books about them.
She's been all over
the world poking around
in cemeteries and
haunted houses.
She just got back from a Cook's tour
of haunted castles in Europe.
[CHUCKLES]
Come on,
let's go over there.
-Oh, I, ah, forgot my camera.
-That's your job.
[BANGING]
-Shut up!
Stop that racket!
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
-Well, here's a chance for
you to photograph a ghost.
-Very funny.
Very funny.
-Better see who it is.
It may allay any suspicions
those screams arouse.
Jim has probably seen who
it is in the televisor.
He won't give himself away.
-Hello.
Remember me from the boat?
Jeff Carter?
-Oh, yes.
-Uh, this is Billy Mason.
I brought her along to
get some more pictures.
The others were lou--
they weren't good.
-Well, uh, I'm afraid it's
too dark in here for pictures.
-Oh, no, it'll be perfectly okay.
-Oh sure, it's okay.
She, eh, takes pictures
in tunnels.  [LAUGHS]
-All right.
-I'll be going, Miss Brewster.
Just keep on with the
prescription I gave you.
-Oh, I, I will, doctor.
Won't you come into the library?
-If you don't mind,
Miss Brewster,
I'd like to know a little more
about your work, your book,
your successes.
I think our readers
would be interested.
-Oh, certainly.
Won't you sit down?
-Thanks.
-I hope you'll pardon the
affairs of this room.
But I don't dare change a thing.
The entities that haunt this
house will not appear
if they spy a difference.
They only want the old
familiar things.
-You mean this house
is really haunted?
-Certainly, child, all
houses are haunted.
All prisons are haunted.
Throngs of spirits
follow us everywhere.
We are never alone.
This room is crowded right now.
-I don't see anything.
-Oh, you can't see them,
anymore than you can see the room.
They can destroy you
just for peering through the veil.
Some spirits are honest,
gentle and kind,
and all they want is to
bring happiness and peace.
But a few are evil.
And having been wicked in
life are wicked in death.
And they haunt
is the scene of their crimes.
revelling
-in death.
-Hmm.
That must have been
what we heard when we drove up,  huh?
-Yes.
You heard it?
-Is it here?
Right here?
-Oh, no.  That's what
I brought from Scotland.
A phonograph record?
-No kidding?  [LAUGHS]
I thought I heard everything.
-Would you like to hear it?
-Well, what can we lose?
-This here is from Scotland.
It's known as
'The Galloping Ghost of Glen Eyrie.'
[SCREAMING ON RECORD]
Does it bother you, child?
-Oh, no.
I just won't sleep all night.
That's all.
-I'll go get the picture
before Miss Mason passes out,
huh?
-Certainly.
-Now listen, Miss Brewster,
you stand right over here
by the phonograph and, uh,
you hold this record.
Hold it like that.
Beautiful.
All right.
Now, come on, come on.
Get yourself together.
Thanks very much, Miss Brewster.
-Oh, just a moment.
One more, seriously.
-Oh, yes.
Do you mind?  Go ahead and sit down.
I'll take the 'Galloping Ghosts.'
Now you sit there and
try and give me a,
uh, pose like you were
hunting for a ghost.
That's it.
Get it.
That was very kind of
you, Miss Brewster.
I'll send you a some of those pictures.
I'll bet you look great.
Come on, honey.
Let's go.
I'll, uh, send you
a copy of the article.
I might wanna check
with you later.
May I come out again?
-Um, I guess so.
But please phone me first.
-Oh, certainly, certainly.
-Thank you very much.
Well, uh, goodbye.
-Jim, are you mad...
to come up here?
-What did Randall say?
-He will not be an
accomplice to a murder.
-Hmm.
Please let me go.
You are expected.
I sorry to be fantastic.
I'm sorry.
-Hey.
-Huh?
-Are you going to town?
-Yeah.
-Fine.
Go right ahead.
-Uh, that could be the galloping
ghost himself, Flutters.
-Even if I felt all right, that wouldn't
get a laugh out of me.
All right.
Let's go.
If you've got any gas.
-What a lot of hooey.
This is the
galloping ghost, huh?
Wonder who thinks she's kidding.
-Meaning what?
-Did that racket
sound like the noise
we we heard when we drove up?
-Come to think of it, no.
-Darn right.
Well, there's something
screw about the whole thing.
I feel it in my bones.
Maybe it's rheumatism.
-Help me.
-No.
All he see is the corporation.
Leave like this.
You won't get away with it.
-Oh please, James, help me with it.
-Oh, leave me alone.
Go on.  Get out.
Get upstairs.
Before you make me sick.
-But...
-Get out of here!
-Oh, all right, James.
[YELLING]
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
-Are you completely insane?
How did you get here?
-You left our experiment
to start a new fiction.
-No, I thought there
was something wrong.
Why did you take such a chance?
I supposed I had
to try something desperate.
-You must have.
-Definitely, as it looked.
-Do you realize what
you're asking me to do?
Murder.
-Oh, call it what you like.
Call it what you like.
I must have the fluid.
It's my life against
somebody else's.
And I don't want to live the
rest of my life this way.
And I won't.
Well... I'll--
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
-Yes?
-Someone from police headquarters
to see you, sir.
-All right.
Ask him to wait in the library.
I'll be right there.
-Very good, sir.
-Do you suppose anybody
saw you coming here?
-No, I'm sure not.
-Stay right here.
Don't take a chance on leaving.
-Oh, the captain sent me over
to get some more dope on
Brewster disappearance case.
-But I've already
told him all I know.
-Well, there's a few things
I'd like to check on.
-Very well.
-When was the last time you saw him?
It was Thursday, is that right?
[GRUNTING]
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
Come here.  Come
[DOOR BUZZER]
Weren't you?
-Huh?
-Uh, you were very closely
associated with Dr. Brewster,
weren't you?
-Oh, yes.  Yes.
-Right.
-Hello, Townsend.
-Dr. Brewster.
-Yes.
Dr. Brewster.
[MUFFLED YELLING]
-Hmm, I see.
Get out!
-Perhaps I could
drop in tomorrow sometime and--
-Oh, there's just
a few more things.
Uh, wait till I get this down.
Well, I guess that's all.
Thanks a lot, doc.
-Not at all.
-Oh, if you think of
anything else
in connection with Dr. Brewster,
let us know.
Looks like we sure could use
a lot of help on this one.
-All right. I will.
Good day.
Goodbye.
Get me the police.
-Did anyone come in tonight?
-No one, but one of your men.
-And who was that?
-I don't know. I didn't get his name.
Came about the Brewster case.
-When did you discover this?
-Right after he left.
-You mean this happened
while a cop was in the house?
-Evidently.
Townsend admitted him.
-That sounds enough.
-Right there.
-What's that?
-Strangulation.
And by someone with
terrific strength
by the looks of the
marks on his throat.
-Hmm.
-Whoever did it
sure needed a haircut.
-Sure looks like it.
-Hello.
-Say, isn't that the guy we
saw at Brewster's?
-It does look like him, doesn't it?
-Yeah.
-Here are those pictures.
-Okay.
-What's happened to him?
-Just lost his
butler boy to strangulation.
Doctor's trying to
pin it on an ape.
Do you buy that?
Here.
Well, I see you got
something on the film anyway.
-Now listen, old man River.
-Uh oh.
Trying to pull a Barney, huh?
-What do you mean?
-Two pictures for the price of one again.
Look at that.
-Where?
-Right there.
-Well, I never saw that before.
-What is it?
How did it get there?
-Looks like a gorilla to me.
-A gorilla?
-Yeah.
-How was it done?
And what heading
does that come under?
Trick photography?
Is it a game?
-I didn't do it.
If it's in the picture,
it was there when I shot it.
[LAUGHS]
-Hey, wait a minute.
Maybe this is
'The Galloping Ghost of Glen Eyrie.'
or whatever his name was
in the flesh.
Remember those sounds?
-Yeah.
-Isn't that the way
a gorilla sounds?
-I'm not much of of a Tarzan,
but could be.
So, the butler of the guy we saw there
was murdered by an ape.
I wonder...
-What are you gonna do?
-Try to sell the boss a bill of goods.
-Don't you want me to go along?
-Oh, no, honey.  You stay right there.
Say, maybe
you're my lucky number.
-Has anyone come yet?
-No one I'm expecting.
-Yes.
I got it, Agatha.
I've got it.
-What?
-The fluid.
The spinal fluid.
-You know you've got it?
-Yes.
That's why I expected him.
-Oh, he said he wouldn't--
-He didn't do it, I did.
He is going to
make the injection.
He may refuse it.
I cannot.
Think!
-I mean just what I said.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
That's bad for him.
Tell him he's
wanted in surgery.
-Forgive me, but go
ahead if you want to.
-Thanks.
-Taking Billy Mason with you?
-Oh no.
I might have to do
some second story work
and she might get a
run in her stocking.
-Jim, do you realize
what you've done?
-Yes.
Doctor Randall,
I have got it.
And I have a chance
to be cured.
That's more important.
-Even if it costs a man his life?
-Yes. It's my life
I'm thinking about.
But we are wasting time.
Look.
Everything is ready for
you to make the injection.
Come.
Don't sit down.
-Jim,
I lied to the police
to save you yesterday
and made myself almost
as guilty as you are.
But I won't incriminate
myself any further.
I'm through.
-Oh no you're not.
-Threats will do you no good.
If necessary I'll go to the police
and tell them the whole story.
-You'll do as James says.
Go on. Hurry.
-Ready, doctor?
[LAUGHS]
George, it's working.
Look, I can stand up straight.
-Just that old pest of a
newspaper man again, Miss Brewster.
-I thought you said you'd
phone before coming back.
-Uh, I-- I did.
But, but, your-- your phone
seemed to be always busy,
or, uh, out of order maybe.
Have you tried
your phone lately?
It could be, you know.
Oh, those things
get out of order.
Funny thing, I know a fella
that had a telephone
that was
always out of order.
Well, uh, shall we, uh, go
in with the 'galloping ghosts?'
-You haven't given me much time to go
over my notes, Mr. Carter.
-Oh, I'm not here on
that ghost business.
-No?
-No.
My boss is saving that
story for a Sunday edition.
But, he does want me to work
on your brother's case.
Have the police had
anything definite to report?
-No, he's
completely disappeared.
I can't understand it myself,
but it's dreadful.
-Yeah, suppose work had
anything to do with it?
A nervous breakdown or amnesia?
Anything like that?
-I don't know.
Uh, I was in Europe as you know.
I haven't seen him
in over a year.
-But his work was
difficult, wasn't it?
Seems to me I heard something
about his terrific experiments.
-Yes, he has a very
scientific mind.
-Eh, just like my uncle.
[CHUCKLES]
His house was always full of
guinea pigs, and rats, even monkeys.
Big ones, too.
Scared the daylights
out of my aunt.
-Oh?
-Yeah, one day she
just up and left him.
And I don't blame her.
Just imagine,
opening that door right now
and coming face to face
with a gorilla.
Oh, but I suppose you're
used to that sort of thing.
I understand that your
brother did a lot of work
on gorillas and apes.
Didn't he?
-I wouldn't know. He never
discussed those things with me.
Well, I guess if you can't
be any help to me,
I'll, uh, just have to dig
up what I can for myself.
Good night.
Oh, by the way,
uh, Miss Brewster,
did your brother have
a laboratory here
in the house
where he worked?
-Not that I know of.
-Okay. I thought
maybe I'd find something there
that might give me a lead.
Well, thanks and goodbye.
-Goodbye, Mr. Carter.
[DOOR CLOSES]
A very clever young man that.
-Yes, I heard.
-George, do you think
the fluid will cure James
completely and harmlessly?
-I don't know,
but it's useless for him to
look to me for any more help.
I warn you,
I'll go to the police first.
-I can not straighten up.
Oh no!
It wasn't enough!
It wasn't enough.
I need more.
George!
Agatha!
I must have more!
That's it!
I need more!
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
-There.
[SCREAMS]
-I wouldn't go down that way
if I were you.
-But why?
-Well, don't ask questions. Come on.
-There have been three murders
committed in this precinct.
And not one single
suspect brought it.
Where's that put us?
Right on the spot.
-They all look like they were committed
by the same person, captain.
Outside of that,
we haven't got a single thing to go on.
-Not a thing, captain.
-I suppose you expect the killer
to come in and give himself up, huh?
Now listen, get out
and get that guy.
Or I'll transfer you
to so far back in the sticks
the birds will be
chasing you out of the trees.
Come on now.
Get out. Get out.
[DOOR CLOSES]
-Comfortable?
-Well, hello, stranger.
Where have you been all week?
I thought your draft board
caught up with you.
-I've been parked in the bushes
outside the Brewster home
so long I nearly took root.
-Waiting for the
galloping ghosts to go by.
No, I've got a hunch there's something
screwier than ghosts in that joint.
-Well, why didn't
you let me in on it?
-Cause if my hunch is correct, it's
no place for a babe-in-the-woods like you.
Oh, by the way, if
you need any more bobby pins
you'll find mine
in the second drawer.
-[MOCK LAUGHS]
Thanks.
-Do you see what we got?
Plenty of it this time!
Plenty!
[GORILLA GROWLS]
-But George,
it's his only chance to become--
-Absolutely, no.
And, don't call me again.
The police have been here
several times this week.
They may trace the call.
-Well, what did he say?
How soon will he be here?
-He's not coming.
-He's not coming?
-That's what he said.
-He must.
The fluid is all ready.
It won't keep!
Go. Summon him, quick!
-It won't do any good.
He won't do it.
-Won't do it?
Alright... this...
is better.
-James, what are
you going to do?
-If he won't come here,
I am going to him.
-But you mustn't the
police are watching him.
-I don't care.
I'm going.
-James, please!
-Let me go.
-They'll kill you!
- Oh, let me go!
[GRUNTING]
-Oh, it's you.
-Yeah. Were you
expecting someone else?
-No. No, that is, uh...
come in.
-Hm-hmm.
Little touch up on the
hair, a new pair of lips,
and you're as good as new.
-Where are you going?
-Back to my listening post.
-Brewster's?
-Uh huh.
-Can I go with you?
-Nu huh.
-Well, why not?
-No place for little girls.
There's so many snakes,
frogs, and lizards.
Big ones,
big as alligators.
And besides, if I have to run,
I don't wanna wait for you.
Oh, uh, don't wait up for me.
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
[GORILLA COOING]
[GORILLA GROWLS]
-We're no nearer to the
killer than we were before.
Yes sir.
All right, we're coming in.
C'mon Tim.
-Goodnight, doc.
-Goodnight, gentlemen.
-Goodnight.
-All right. Let's go.
-No, I've got a hunch
he's expecting somebody.
Let's wait around and see.
-I could kill you
before they got here.
So be careful.
It's here, George.
Plenty of it.
Look.
It's enough for
half-a-dozen injections.
And can't fail.
Come on. Hurry.
You are going to do it,
you hear me?
-All right.
-Good.
Here.
[GROWLING]
[YELLING]
[KNOCKING]
[WINDOW SHATTERING]
Is he dead?
-Neck's broken.
-Jim's going to--
Oh...
-Who's going to what?
Ah...
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
[GORILLA CONTINUES]
-Jeff.
Oh, Jeff!
Jeff, honey!
I didn't know it was you.
Jeff, please wake up.
Jeff, talk to me.
Jeff, I didn't mean it.
Forgive me.
Jeff!
[SCREAMING]
Oh, help! Help!
-Billy?
Bill--
Come on, baby...
Give me the police!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Hurry up, hurry up!
-You came to Randall to
warn him about someone.
Now who was it?
[PHONE RINGING]
O'Brien speaking.
What?
What?!
- Okay.
- Okay!
-Get over to the Brewster
home as quick as you can.
There's trouble over there.
Take her with you.
-Come on, lady.
-Come on, hurry up.
[SCREAMING]
-Jeff!
-Billy? Billy!
-I'll kill you!
[SCREAMING]
-Don't worry,
I'm coming into ya.
-Help!
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
-Go back in there.
Go back in there!
Run!
[GROWLING]
-Billy!
-Get off.
-Help!  Help!
-Billy, there's a button back there
or a loose panel or something.
-Jeff!  Please help me!
Get me out!
[GROWLING]
Help!
Ahh!
-[GROWLS]
-[SHE SHRIEKS]  [HE SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
Oh, Jeff!
Help!
[SCREAMING]
-Fagin, stay here.
Macy, cover the back. Go on.
-He took her down in there and
I can't open that thing.
She knows how it works.
Come on.
Make her open it up quick!
-Jeff!
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
-Alright, open it up.
-Oh, Jeff!
[GORILLA SOUNDS]
[CRYING]
-Jim!
-You know, I should put you
over my knee and paddle you good.
-Don't be a chump.
(THUMP)
-Hey, what are you
doing it my car?
Who are you anyway?
-Me?
Oh, I'm the author of the story.
Screwy idea, wasn't it?
[LAUGHS]