Old.
A who's.
Up. I won't even.
Try to get
a three year hedge and I only came
in to tell you goodbye. Goodbye. I
thought over. You had your choice. Either
me or the local profession you're working
at you're still working let me. Oh please
don't take it like this that you know
your ship is about to say that I brought
it here if I go away is either one or even
more than we both have already you know we
belong to each other. And then the snow
. Of all the people out there they
want to do whatever now do
another number on the job.
How. Will you know. And.
What you might like to. Remind. Your days
now. I could read the truth in
the eyes of the bit of hope.
Pick. You might as well be prepared
for the way but it won't make
any difference from one who brought it up
I don't what it is but it would be by you
know
a little. She
has no family not even friends because
of the worry about news that go to
that anyone know you in the clinic no one
and no one must know that Jeanette Moreno
is coming here. I have come the THANK YOU
ago and I know that actually exist you're
going to need me I'll be here oh.
You know why
out who I bet
you're going to hold out at the point.
That one thousand eight
thousand head south.
No you mustn't give up all
hope yet who are you.
Don't ask me questions there
isn't time I'm an assistant to
a great scientist who has come to hear of
your case and wants to know more about
you he wants to give you treatment but
the use of treatment what's the use you
have to believe me we have discovered
a new therapy together and it's
miraculous I guarantee it.
A little earlier I buy now don't tell me
you're here because you want to interview
me you don't think so then I would tell you
that did you read about that good what
do you mean Och come
on what about this for
a big headline Jeannette war I know I've
been beautiful as ever think I might
publicity good clinic it sure but that's
one headline you are never going to see in
print when that doctor waiting at the
address of the long right here on the speak
with you. And I need absolutely
not a word to
a soul this is the only hope you
have keep that in mind always you
will drop out of sight for short time real
for weeks at the very most and when you
appear everything will be
before as to the week and from
a horrible dream Don't you believe me
well then do just as you wish
I have never been to see you
really expecting you.
Don't disappoint me. I'm not
being immodest when I speak of
a whole new year in biology and. Destructive
and in general to the fact of atomic
explosion and didn't find
more than ever before in. The
regeneration rebuilding
abnormal or totally destroyed.
In correcting at normal growth as well as
storing which have been destroyed often
grows out of there are twenty eight has
grown out of Burma twenty five the serum
which provoked an exhilarating not normal
development. When I finally succeeded in
stabilizing effect I produced the ant account
in the bank scene which for years had
been the major goal of the most.
Repeated experiment using
Dharma twenty eight on specimens deformed
by injections of Norman twenty five
proved regular. Single and
there were twenty eight.
What are you doing don't you realize that
you must be completely insane yet the
drama twenty five that we've been injecting
in so many of those political control
make them into monsters you're aware of
its effect that come on you have to be
exposed to treatment up front in the
radiation chambre No give me an injection
after twenty eight you know it's never
been tried in human beings I would never
cover it that's just why I did it to push
the current No that's right for the girls
and that Maureen I know I want to share
this on with you. Before as I have at this
moment and you will always
remember if we don't need you.
Don't be troubled about me but
it's all we could bring so.
Quickly every second we have especially.
During the twenty eight represents months
of work and anxiety and when the day comes
when we can prepare it is rapidly as we
do drama twenty five Give me
a. Yes no doubt it's not the strike to
start. It removes every trace of
the generation of cell structure.
The day to come but once in
a lifetime that is our life that's right
I shall always remember everything you've
done for me thank you tell me that in
some other way tell it
to. The kind of right.
They hold together with our record.
You look at me that right. There you seem
to be performing some sacred ritual.
If you want to return.
This profession that.
You have come to
a I'm happy to see you and your luggage
in the check room at the station as you
instructed with the ticket.
Are you sure that no one knows you
come here. Go and pick up your luggage
that's going to the party.
But this isn't like
a clinic. Not
a clinic it's the place where Dr Levin
studies and does his work with me to help
him.
Show me
a face show
me
a face have. No
doubt to be. Disfigured forever
as if I can say that's beyond
control like leprosy. Is the
one who can help. Me go away.
I give you my word that I will restore
your faith restore all you if you think it
was done all the other because you want
to defeat. The public like that put
yourself together we have
succeeded in discovering
a great secret secret of spontaneous
reproduction of living he could like the
secret of life and also of death just not
I deliberately spoke of cancer cells
which proliferate unexpectedly at the
expense of the all going to them until they
have destroyed over this remarkable
discovery we have succeeded in creating
spontaneous reproduction of we can rebuild
those which have been destroyed we have
paid the months that were drunk devoured
us and made it serve all our own and you
must know it's
a miracle and you will be the first person
in the world to benefit from it I shall
perform this miracle. To believe
that I didn't forgot not
a great speech that me go
now rather than go on I.
Preferred it to yourself.
That if you've given up all
hope Why didn't you do it before that you
have condemned for the rest of your life
and you know you know they all
told you that. Right now.
If you really are so desperate to take
your own life if you want to. Give this
back to you. I don't know on that day when
you look me in the face and tell me that
I paid you do you understand Jeanette
I don't till that day come. We
do pride. I beg you.
Do you think I had
a room prepared oh. And now
we must pick up Stan She's
a beautiful human specimen you to fool.
About oh I didn't hear anything
about the we just sailed but you
mean today she had all her belongings
collected from the hotel tour and had them
delivered here at the clinic toward the
on the. You told that you were going back
without
a problem to tell you what she did with
him to talk to Jeanette must still be in
town I mean she's gone away they're
going to be running the news
at the next I'll have to between Janet what
I know didn't want you to again and she
.
Read.
In.
Who's to.
Talking of and then thank you very much.
All right are you going
back to the cinema for
a person disappear
overnight without leaving
a trace. But it won't help the
Scotch I don't weigh the prizes on June.
Eighth. Eight.
The Democrats never mind when Gump.
Has no effect.
On the reasons. That I.
Used to. Help you.
Much to.
Give you
a lift to might. Not
a drop of the serum next five injections
without any effect at all and I know I was
not mistaken that took effect on you because
then you applied it immediately in the
case of pills to destroy you will have
to be continued complication perhaps to
correct but it will take months to prepare
serum enough. Sandra we will find
another subject when we can use the
plight of the twenty and never go around
telling everyone what we did we left to
kill and besides what if the demo to date
should have some unusual effect on
a don't forget we derived from down the
twenty five I can't bear to think of her
becoming
a monster is that it you worry
too much about her. Thank
.
You.
You think I never had
a moment. If you don't mind. A
big. Stick up there.
And
a sticker shock is completely over and it
can't be any more thought of that we've
won. Yeah. That's right at the moment
all I'm able to.
What the after effects now with the
regeneration of sound continue as the truth I'm
sure it will. To.
You yes you know it's purpose
and I think that I'm with.
You.
You know when
you. When
you. Lose.
I know you more than my
life it's the Senate
that second that you have suffered great
physical shock with all that you've
recovered yet but we must wait
a bit we must be certain what
the results are absolutely
sure don't Dr Janet miracle
has happened to you
and you will remain with us and Kubiak
sure that we can proclaim it to the entire
all were.
Another. One. Don't you feel happy and
you want to laugh and sing of joy.
And money. I wonder what young. You
had an experiment is going on.
Anyways like this.
Do you want here.
You embraced me when you first saw that
you were cured then gratitude is already
become. You shouldn't believe that if
I love you I would surely tell you.
That. You weren't able to see clearly in
your heart and you're still too upset by
everything that has happened. You
must know you love me I have
snatched you away from desperation and from
there it is I who restored your beauty
it is I who need you never be able.
To nothing if not. To me.
Wait
a moment I'd almost forgotten
excuse me one moment. Tell
me what it did nothing nothing at all
something rather original which I forgot him
when he. Was
a wonder. I
don't know what's wrong it's just
so much Bayfront fire down here
a moment. You'll be all right
Monique I don't understand.
What's wrong with me I'm
here should just relax
you're very tired now she was sleep soundly
for several hours time is pressing over
to the laboratory at once it must be
a success Afghanistan don't count any
longer on the money she means what you know
than just an experiment. I cannot
do it without you then I'll make
a condition you know what it is yes never
see her again I give you my word Believe
me I shall help us
carry her to the laboratory
I prepared everything but what's
to be done back if there were only
a single drop of it still next but there
isn't any I refuse to give up and I'll try
radiation. And you've gone mad I know
it's madness and I'm going to take
any risk you know very well that this
just got this with palming again and
radioactive treatment is effective only
gets down to twenty five and that.
She mustn't suffer like this. There's
always surgery and insertion you're out of.
The only possible solution transplant
directly from another human being those plans
with produce number twenty
eight from another woman
a young one out there has been saying you
cannot open her I give you my childhood
now I know that I can trust you how would
you accomplish it by marrying the first
woman that passes the picture look different
look at another woman another does the
best but if that's going
to. Come back yeah.
To me on a topic we've already said enough
to each other she's lying down there
a lot not possible to taper What can we do
I am still here and tell you what do you
want to be sacrificed myself possible.
To. I mean that you know but it will pass.
Not love really intimidated going to
compulsion if you like I want to dominate the
girl the possessor created. This also
helped me overcome this and that you may
struggle along with me as you
always have done. Yet you
manage to convince yourself doing
things like this like this.
Has nothing to do with the
two of us. I promise you and
a far away. Way. I will forgive. Start all
over again and be successful Please try
to be the same intelligent woman you've
always been. And I would kill
a thousand times probably to defeat. The
reasonable.
You. Know that we are bound together or.
You.
At least commission the Bush effort that's
a lesson that you haven't met before that
your name is sell well no photographs do
a television interview. Apologise not
a my assistant I'm sorry we had the deputy
personally the way you did telephone is
the I'm all alone here at the moment. Good
grief I'm out of cigarettes do you mind
if I get if you go half
an hour without smoking
why does it not sure why did you come
in without knocking on that door
professor that and send you. Have
a date Oh yes champagne
there is money.
What do you mean.
Oh no not. By the good. Name.
And showed no symptom warning
before hand oh yeah I've kept on
a special for almost two years. Make up
of the difficult ones without an autopsy
autopsy I've already confirmed the
diagnosis. Out of consideration I don't know
if it is
a practice. If the decision lies within my
jurisdiction I say no autopsy if one is
absolutely not she was from.
You will find her identity card in papers
in her room she suffered from and the
patient. Should show you something.
This is the most recent electrocardiogram
I get that she wouldn't find
a better show this things are
pathologist but the Chinese you know
Professor I'd say I know you intimately
that amaze you well it doesn't take
a long white there to be
a scientist. But I know your articles I've
read your interviews and I saw you want
television when you returned from Japan
Oh by the way strange looking bottles are
they from Hiroshima
a process of the formative fusion of
bottle glasses Remick near each other the
people here will see most of
them a souvenir Well anyway it's
a rather shocking sight
and that you remain
a long time the. Right month at
a Japanese Institute for Radiological
Research Oh how interesting.
Thank you I gave up smoking then you had
a close look at those poor creatures. And
from then on I've devoted my life what
research exactly. Are you acquainted with.
That after the atomic explosion.
What extraordinary development. What
you mean. By extracting at the.
During your television. Shows.
Like
a logical. Relationship between. A
problem.
Well then Dr.
Thank.
You. While Caracas I don't know some you.
Know God I. Need my face
pointing like the other night tonight money
don't get excited they're going back
home I would do what he
did put them on. Blast.
And then there's
a room you will wake up for several
hours and I want you to watch outside
a door and that's when you see
me put this stuff come around.
All right and you come I can
buy one. I. Have that you
don't. Know I.
Have that now that I think about what. I
have don't have the guy right I don't want
to look at everyone now if
you. Give up if I know I know.
All the while. You're
a. Coming
out anything you're right.
Why.
Oh.
You.
Think.
Without the. I know you think. You're
afraid that you will not be permanent
but you're mistaken outgrown the question
of growth I've already called the problem
the must allow the self be regenerated
to achieve lasting ability now or some
artificially for a time
and especially with
a transfer. And it must
be done more than once
why are you staring at I told you I'm
tired and up that I spent the whole night
rotting in the laboratory so you could
wake up as you walk. How many more times
would you have to tweet
a few very few One hopes someone and I do
You could never understand what it has
cost me to make you well again on I would
have to do is tell you to make you
realize how deeply you should I have.
Maybe
a little bit of these go and get that while
we can see each other they go out to
God.
And.
Hello Yes Lieutenant more name is still on
board the got out is now on tape I have
a communication problem it's very urgent
that I reach him could you possibly
forward a letter certainly by email yes
a stop over on the return
voyage please don't mention.
Me Sasha.
I haven't any more sticking with you know
I only hope this kind you can buy me some
.
While you read it would you mail this
letter and get something for your own of
these take it to you will remember.
Yeah my darling nothing seemed
between at least not. Yet I'm afraid
Thank you Sasha very well. I know I
can rely on you at any time. Of her
you know no no I want it work don't you
permitted to be out of your sight when I'm
not around and disconnect the telephone the
rational do. This evening I have to do
some writing around here and I don't want
to be disturbed it's all in this I call
you myself you understand.
I mean.
The you know the you.
Know. I don't get it. What are you doing
around here what do you know I don't
write you leave the gorilla I've
got let me Jim and then I know.
Good evening.
Oh. That would make.
A lady. I'd better wait yeah.
I can't believe that. Jeannette. Act.
Recovered. Why didn't you tell me at the
clinic when I looked for you but they told
you I would be disfigured Did
you ever want to see me it was
a took the other killed by swell.
Jeanette Where have you been you can let
me know where you're staying what happened
to you to proceed by that you're
a real piano Take your way
on the right tell me why I.
Heard one. News
has.
No doubt about it and this one showing the
card was given to me at the clinic and I
waited but your brother had yet or
rather the same girl I agree. But I was
referring to the person you met tonight.
Don't think Bono commissioner it was she
in front of me but in the dark
with the problem and. What I know
or I couldn't possibly be mistaken. Listed
with the Bureau of myth and she's not
a missing person she's here I've seen or
she has no relatives in town you know
she'd been kidnapped listen you know I
want to believe you I remember the auto
accident which in that Moreno barely
escaped with a life but this story of
a recovery is impossible yet she's cured
perfectly normal same fate but who would
be likely to hide to do
a miracle is that whoever it was it
tried to kill me. An hour ago and rude
automate police sergeant Rondo recovers
from an automobile This is the license
number you want to rejuvenate me how
long has it been since I bought it about
stolen car the same automobile or short
time before just about the same moment the
assault occurred with spot for speeding
on the esplanade work past the waterfront
by patrolman shellacked inside as well as
the driver there was an unconscious woman
and
a doctor taking her to the hospital you see
that the hospital I was already telephoned
there's no record of or
maybe I was taking it to
a private clinic the name of the doctor.
Didn't bother asking that under the
circumstances it could have been a doctor
coming to the first automobile he found
a clever criminal who would say anything
to avoid identifying themselves or the
woman. But there happened to be
a real doctor who might give us some
information about this miraculous recovery
that may come with you yet but I want
condition however that no thank you in the
car.
Good evening Professor Levin excuses if
we're. This is police sergeant Durand.
I think you already know excuse the
interruption if we disturbing you at this hour
but passing in front of you also I thought
why don't I leave it up to you Professor
level to clarify
a scientific problem we had you were so
extremely kind in the when we met each
other that time before in those unfortunate
circumstance. And that's the way
when he created. You may go Sasha.
Sasha He's
a strange one. For the garden more than
anything. The soul of fidelity an expert
with flowers the classic one to suspect in
a mystery story if there were
anything to suspect him of offer you
a drink in fact yes yes let's be comfortable
You must try to make it easy for with
us eleven to forget that we're policeman
you notice the bottom got them as
a souvenir of Hiroshima
interesting aren't they do or.
Don't have to blow smoke
on them I know excuse me.
Thank you if you please.
Not expected. I'll make it brief look
here Professor if you've been following
a class well that's on the right about Doc
not coming right in the right word for
it sensational journalism Jane. Go
up in smoke if you don't mind it but
I still don't comprehend the
time before I asked you
a question which you were kind enough
to say was intelligent about the
psychological reaction of the victims of
an atomic explosion Well then perhaps my
own supposition will be an absurd one but
think of the ships that arrive here from
Japan and this dock is it possible
that he's one of those. You're
going to be pressed by the recurring factor
in these cases of the wound from the
throat to the start of the obsession of
the vindictive minded men who has been
poisoned the disfigured forever by
atomic radiation I might even say that
a pair of the atom made you want to become
a Exactly what do you say hypothesis
another dramatic but not to be excluded.
You just said the hypothesis is melodramatic
but the fact that you don't exclude it
altogether puts me how shall I say more at
peace with my own conscience we mustn't
let off get too far off the ground the
photograph. Right excuse me I had another
purpose in coming here to see you look
here examine these two photos you believe
that
a woman would do such as this might recover
altogether but I mean is without any
scar without
a trace I should think. That the
duration is permanent nevertheless Professor
Wright made or the talking to write
Nevertheless there is someone who swears
that he seen this woman the way she was
that's impossible and if that did exist
a cure I don't know what process we never
any men who had discovered one would be
a celebrity and I assure you I'd be the
first Indian. Magine All right then this
other photo which was submitted to me as
proof of her actual recovery must have
been taken to some time
prior to her accident if
the signature was not dated. Right and
besides even if it had been it could easily
have been
a professor I'm ready to swear that they
are on we've been disturbing you long
enough most grateful Professor
accompany you all right relieving.
You must feel about the
lonely here. You have
a new assistant think it's so simple
to find one and moreover I am enjoying
a period of repose right now I merely study
for relaxation you know Professor what
I envy you with your gardener Sasha really
a bit difficult to believe
that no it's just that I'm
a flower garden on my days off imagine
inspector even worse at night maybe I know
what you mean by dying to have
a look inside that Green House but I don't
think no no no no I should be delighted
. I'll wait for you in the
car. Why don't you come to
a. Business not just kingdom
there is plan there is. Pressure you're on
a gentleman have come to admire your beautiful
green house it's really beautiful to
. You want to know. Nothing
else of any interest as always
live in the doesn't even have time to
read mystery stories no wonder Well good
night professor and excuse us again
company the gentleman to the gate
there on your coming. Tonight professor.
What is the purpose of this autopsy now
doctor I've already arranged for the body
to be exhumed I must ask you to proceed
without any for the argument that the money
went on. I want my car at the door
in ten minutes Good morning doctor.
I want
a cigarette you. Have just had an idea
I want you to keep that Villar progress
alive and under observation I think that
well. You want to good lesson.
Back yet.
Yes. Done
it. For you. What's wrong with.
Me the man to whom you'll always be thinking
who loves you you're not telling the
truth you want to go back to bear but
I'm going to save you not when spite of
yourself I want to go to the I don't care
if I've got one I think I know nobody
will love me anyway. Yes Cars are already
returning embryonic still and old but
invisible I think this action is not the
written almost immediately you will turn
into just what you wrote before. Nothing
will get worse it will devour you.
Transform you into an animal like
a monkey done to the very eyes of
your parents the game I don't want.
I give you my word of
honor it would only take
a few days perhaps only one day to make
the final occupation and then you will be
cured forever Prita go where you please
and with whom you please if you run great
for enough to leave me for
a man who has done nothing for you you
deserve nothing else but until you're cured
don't try any want to run away don't
try to see anyone you promise.
I'll even give this back to you you
have no more reason to kill yourself.
What is it. Really.
Care. Who she had.
Better go. Run to him let
him see you like this
go away with him as you are. Remember I
give you my word and I shall keep it it
will be your decision then in the
meantime you will help me to finish it
it is not how bad it was speaking now but
Professor Levin. I have to when you see
this is all I'm asking of you.
You want to use Arjan I'm sorry to disturb
you why you started this different part
of your profession I'm not really
a policeman. And explain why
you did pass itself up as
a policeman and for what reason the
commission I was the last just to learn more
about your research but I asked permission
to come with him but on the other hand
coming here so late at night and
not having time explaining what
should you have said that you had
a personal interest in the case of that
unfortunate young lady what is the name
again. You know you're
not very convincing as
a police. I guess I wasn't your
representative through the photo
Jeanette with the signature was retaken
before the accident. But I know I've seen
it I know it was she she just
met yesterday in front of me.
And if they hadn't attacked me right then
you were attacked yes and from behind
because I know there's some mystery concerning
Jeanette and I was about to learn it
you love her that is evident I wonder if
you had parted with her sentiments of the
I mean before you were actually separated
How did you know that I'm also psychotic
. You're not suffering from an
obsession to find her again capable of
seeing her in every woman you run into
and perhaps yesterday on that very same
field where often before
Jeanette was waiting after
a long voyage No it was no IT WAS THE NATION.
And how can you explain the attack on
me well maybe an attempted
robbery. It wouldn't be the first
time on the waterfront. And perhaps the
night was. Perhaps you'd also been drinking
it you know I wasn't drinking.
Will you please tell me what you wanted me
to do for you please help me to convince
the police tell them that this miraculous
recovery is possible they will go on
looking for and for
a woman not to find them that's to be
excluded. Me to give up every hope your
position. I would say yes. I
love her too much for that.
Entirely different woman. No longer.
I see there's nothing I can do. Thank you
no no no need to thank you.
Accompanied. By Mr. No.
I don't think I'll be any
further occasions that.
You have to do with. I didn't do it because
you didn't. Know that I could rely.
I leave you alone because I have. No
other man ever did for the woman.
To.
Be back in.
His automobile. Exactly where is the.
Let's see. The right.
You know all right what you. Now.
Have
a lot. Like. The
AS. The the.
The on
the on.
The the.
The on the right. I know
the the yes
another woman in the waterfront
neighborhood again but is the woman dead.
And yes naturally
a lot Rob is going to
learn of our. Professor
level film and then he went out. For the
structure I told you we are both inside
the one and we both turned it in move
one. Let's go in there on. What are
you up to complain we did not achieve if
you won't let me take that up then I'll
see if you can see it's your fault from now
on your mind your own business getting
your orders.
Where was the setting I asked
you right here in this role.
Sitting in the seat you never let
him out of sight. Outside for
a minute about his cigarette but I never
let him out of sight and who was there
sitting next to you when I think
it through you'll be back in
a beaten uniform remind me what was he
wearing. One of the have on he was wearing
a camel. Like opening a phonebook with
a name. That Here you see right
here where we were back to.
Headquarters told me I would probably
find you here. Top got it on money could.
Never be able to forgive myself You mean
like the others and this what do you think
it is. No doubt about that.
I don't know if it's human or what I think
it might be. I don't examine right away
rest of you come with me.
I don't have the courage to
kill. Her life I don't have.
I feel. I'm not what I was before. I.
Don't want.
To they make anything and there's nothing
more I can do there's no hope. I mean it
you. Know. The trick I think
in the fact that last.
Year I had me say that. Now Janet we must
leave I don't believe you but you're
completely cured then this part of us. Who
did it when I began to think that come
on get. Any more time you must get away
from the things that's going to. Have you
lost your mind yet those policemen suspect
about the time the police well you don't
explain it to you I don't want to harm me
now how do you know I'm not leaving would
you try next. You made me
a promise and this is going
to be the day you. I want. To
do for you I. Live on the
star of the fourth but then you know I can
no longer control you I don't you know.
Tell me that you will never abandon
me no. You begin to understand.
Can you tell me that you will run away with
me is my only hope of salvation. In the
menu into for help and we love
it so much. And the drug.
Trade mark of the man who condemns help
when you have that much covered you think
because in
a moment or two you will go mad that
was already you don't go. Right. Back
to that you don't look at me I'm going
to be when I say you can save me if you
would say to me. I guess if I know well.
You know one minute. Coming with
me when you want to or not.
I don't come about because I'm
a turning on to never see
your peril given. That
.
You did. I ask.
Why. Oh.
Whatever.
I mean.
I'm. I'm I'm.
I'm I'm. I'm. Deciding
whether. I.
Think I.
Asked or I really am and
so I sat at. I was. I
was. So.
It but I don't never look back
I recall it with the wind up I
hope I'm.
Back.
I'm. Sure.
You will. You know.
That man I.
Well I want to feel like.
The you.