(ominous music)
[Man Voiceover] On this
fifth day of December,
in the year of our Lord, 1648,
by virtue of the power vested in us
by our noble sovereign,
this tribunal of justice
hereby sentences you,
the Crimson Executioner,
to death.
You will die by one of
the very instruments
you devised to torture and
kill your innocent victims.
You dared to take into your own hands
the laws of both God and man.
You set yourself up as
both judge and executioner.
You caused inhuman suffering
and took like not from
any sense of justice
but from hatred and self-gratification.
(ominous music)
You showed no mercy to your victims
and no mercy will be shown to you.
- [Crimson Executioner]
- You'll never kill me.
Move along.
- [Crimson Executioner]
- I'll return and be avenged!
Turn around.
[Crimson Executioner] Fools, all of you!
I am the Crimson Executioner!
(laughing)
This day shall be written in blood.
No man can judge me.
I am the supreme law!
I shall have my revenge!
(ominous music)
(groaning)
(screaming)
(ominous drumming)
(sizzling)
[Man Voiceover] The
seal of this tribunal
will entomb, forever, both
your body and your evil soul.
Let no man dare to break the seal.
You are cursed, eternally
damned, as are these dungeons.
As is this castle that has witnessed
such indescribable horrors.
Your castle will stand
throughout the centuries
as a reminder of the barbarism and cruelty
committed within its walls.
May the dust of time not
erase from the memory of man
the infamy of the Crimson Executioner.
(clock ticking)
(ominous music)
(pleasant music)
Ah.
Not bad. This seems exactly
what we've been looking for.
Yeah, from here it looks great.
Just what we need.
I think we should be able
to wrap up our work here in a day.
This will look good.
[Woman] Come on, Nancy.
[Nancy] Oh gosh, I'm
stiff from that long ride.
It's made to order.
Yeah.
What a view.
Hey, we don't wanna lose you.
Sure looks gloomy.
How would you girls like to have
a castle this old to live in?
You'd have to be a creep
to live in a place like this.
I'd love to have a house
like this all to myself.
Imagine the peace and
beauty of living all alone.
You're a funny one, all right.
All right, girls.
Wonder what it looks like inside.
What's wrong?
Are you tired?
I don't know what it is, Perry.
I just feel very uneasy.
No.
Suzy?
Let me alone, Raoul.
Don't be like that, baby.
- Everybody will see us.
- (bell ringing)
- Have it your way.
Are you all dead?
Lay any odds you want.
Our dear publisher will wind up saying,
"This place isn't suitable
after all, let's go home."
- [Gray Suited Man]
- Hello? Is everybody out?
If they're all out, how
can anyone be in the house?
The brain has spelled it out.
I'm not just a dumb blonde, you know.
[Annie] Who says you're a blonde?
Hello? Why doesn't anybody answer?
Maybe nobody lives here.
What a nuisance.
Someone shoulda told
me the castle's empty.
We might as well try to get in anyway.
Maybe one of the boys
could scale that wall.
That's a job for Tarzan.
[Gray Suited Man] Who's gonna
volunteer to climb the wall?
Okay, okay.
Here comes Uncle Perry, the
greatest acrobat in the world.
(laughs) Watch this.
He's a good boy. I
bet he gets us inside.
Yeah, you're right.
Three years for unlawful
breaking and entering.
Take care, Perry.
(sighs)
Mags, you owe me a bonus
for this little stunt.
A double whiskey. (Laughs)
What about that?
I still think you're playing with fire.
Ah, you should know me by now.
I'm not the kinda man to
let obstacles get in my way.
I'm a man of action.
Well, what do we do now?
We follow the leader. What else?
(door creaking)
(laughs) Ladies and
gentlemen, welcome to the old-
- Well done, Perry. Let's go.
(eerie music)
(somber music)
Hey, what a funny place this is.
Looks like a Frankenstein film set.
(somber music)
Perry, there's something
evil about this castle,
I'm sure of it.
You Hawaiians are far
too impressionable, Kinojo.
Raoul?
(gasping)
(ominous music)
(yelling)
(laughing)
You idiot!
Why must you play these
childish jokes all the time?
Raoul?
Take off that silly costume.
(gasping)
(ominous music)
These uninhabited castles
always have their family skeleton.
Uninhabited?
There's not a trace of dust around here.
Who are you? What're you doing here?
I'm very sorry.
Nobody answered the doorbell
and we thought the castle was empty.
Could we speak to the owner?
I'd like a word with him
about a business matter.
Could you take us to him?
Follow me.
Let's go.
The rest of you wait in there.
[Man] Stop where you are!
How dare you force your way
into my castle like this.
What do you want here?
I want to apologize.
We didn't think anyone
lived here, that's all.
[Man] It's no excuse for trespassing.
I don't like having my privacy disturbed.
I'm sorry, sir.
You're quite right.
My name is Parks.
I'd like to explain.
We've been scouting for suitable locations
to photograph material for book jackets.
I'm a publisher.
That's no concern of mine.
Look here, I'd like to
show you one of my books.
I'm preparing an anthology of horror-
- He told you to stay where you were.
We took the liberty of coming in here
only because no one answered
our knocking at the door.
I don't like intrusion.
I insist that you leave
my castle immediately.
Could you make just one exception?
We've been on the road for several days.
Everybody's so tired.
I don't want any visitors here.
I'd be only too glad to pay, of course.
Pay?
Now you're beginning
to annoy me, Mr. Parks!
(somber music)
I know my friend
didn't mean to offend you
and we ask you to forgive us.
(somber music)
(foreboding music)
You and your practical jokes.
Raoul.
(upbeat music)
Hey!
On your feet, everybody!
We've been old to shove off.
The master of the house doesn't
like having visitors around.
What? Again?
Oh no.
Not after all I went
through to get you in here.
So we're right back where we started.
One castle's too modern, one's too old.
Why don't we build our
own and get it over with?
Suzy, wouldn't it cost an
awful lot of money to build one?
Oh, can't you change his mind?
We're all tired.
Well, I'm tired too.
But we have no choice.
We've been told to go and that's it.
Let's get moving quickly.
Edith!
Wait!
Perhaps I was a little
too hasty, Mr. Parks.
I'm not usually so inhospitable.
I realize you must all be very tired.
You see, I don't usually receive people.
You can stay here overnight.
But I'll have to ask you to leave
first thing in the morning.
Thank you, sir.
We really do appreciate
your kind hospitality.
Do you mind if we take a few pictures?
All right.
But please remember,
I don't like to be disturbed.
My servants will show you
the chambers where you can do your work.
Perfect! Let's get to work, girls!
We mustn't waste any time!
Go and change quickly.
Dermott, you better check
out the setting we need.
Edith, you go along with him.
- Good girl.
- Come on, Edith.
Don't go near the dungeons.
They're absolutely out
of bounds for everybody.
Okay, we won't.
Get moving, Dermott, we're in a hurry.
(creaking)
I'll bet Max'll flip over this one.
Can you imagine finding
a thing like this here
that wasn't a (indistinct)?
I'll take credit for that, I found it.
Yeah.
Food for everybody.
Hey Max, I want a bonus
for finding this thing.
All right, we'll see
about the bonuses. Now eat-
- It would be perfect
for the Skeletrix series.
Hey, that looks great.
Fine boys, fine, but now
let's get to work.
I'll take the food to the girls, right?
No, I'll take care of that one myself.
What a picture this'll make!
(somber music)
(throat clearing)
- (gasping)
- Max!
Why don't you ever knock?
Come on, now what's all this nonsense?
I'm just like a father to you girls.
[Nancy] Turn around, we
have to get into our costumes.
Okay, have your little
games but hurry up.
We haven't any time to fool around.
We've got work to do.
You can turn around now, if you want.
Edith, bring the girls downstairs.
We can't afford to waste any time.
All right.
How's the food?
Terrible.
As usual.
Bottle of wine they call
it. It tastes like water.
Yeah, it's awful, isn't it?
But I know where we can find real wine.
I discovered where the cellar is.
Come on, I'll show you.
See ya. Come on, Perry.
(eerie music)
You know, Perry,
I wouldn't mind being
the owner of this castle.
You can have it. It gives me the creeps.
Skeletons don't have nerves.
What do you mean, it gives you the creeps?
(eerie music)
(gasping)
(clanking)
(shushing) You'll wake up the ghosts.
Come on.
This way.
(eerie music)
(foreboding music)
Now don't breathe. Perfect, like that.
All right, hold the pose.
I wanna take another shot.
Edith, hand me the other camera, will you?
Thanks. Now don't move, darling.
Hold it. You make a
beautiful corpse, you do.
Just keep it. That's right.
(pleasant ukelele music)
Perfect.
- It's no fun being dead.
- Nobody ever said it was.
- You mean it?
- You were very convincing.
Okay guys, come on.
Just imagine what Daddy will say
when he sees this photo.
- Go and change now.
- Yeah.
Okay, Susie it's your turn now.
Sure, here I am, but where's Perry?
He's in it too.
Here I am, your personal skeleton.
Always ready to die at
the hands of a beautiful woman.
How are you going to change?
Annie's first.
You're never around when you're needed.
Right, but look what I dug up for you.
Rick, can I have your knife a minute?
Thanks.
What is it?
Just a little homesick, I guess.
Are you all asleep over there?
Get behind that camera, Dermott.
(upbeat whimsical music)
Here's a pistol, Dermott.
Come on now.
No, it's too heavy anyway.
Let's try a long sword, huh?
It's light as a feather,
sweetheart, let me show you.
What's wrong with it?
I can't unsheath it. It must be rusty.
Don't just stand there looking, help me.
Let's pull together. Pull, pull pull.
Forget it, we don't need it out.
Okay I want you to
hold it aloft menacingly,
it's not heavy, you can lift
it without much effort at all.
Watch. Like this.
(grunts) Give me a hand, will you?
Well, you do it, Annie.
You've got the general
idea now, haven't you?
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
(silly music)
Come on, sweetie.
Hold it.
(silly music)
Hmm, now let me see what we can do here.
Yeah, that's a possibility.
Put your head down.
Lower, right on the block.
Haven't you ever been beheaded before?
These actors...
Put your arms down. That's more like it.
That's cool, stay there.
Now then, give me the axe.
Really these actors.
(silly music)
Hold it.
Now Nancy, honey, give
me the feeling of a cat.
You know what I mean.
Meow.
(hissing)
No, Nancy, that's too domesticated.
I want you to think wild, fierce.
Meow!
Meow.
Can't you think like an alley cat?
For instance, you're
about to fight another cat
for a fish head or something.
Meow.
No! No, Nancy, that's
the intellectual approach!
You'll never be an alley cat.
Let's try something else.
I've got an idea.
There, now raise your leg up.
Up! Up!
Ow.
That's it.
Now, imagine you're floating in the air
like a thistle blown by the wind.
That's it, beautiful.
No, not like that.
You've got to go up.
Gently, that's right, baby.
Now hold it. No!
Can't you keep that arm over you head?
Now everything's in place.
Arm, leg, head, everything.
Now don't move.
Come on, Nancy, get that
lovely foot of yours up.
Like a feather, like a
thistle blown by the wind.
No, I can't.
It's too heavy.
I can't.
Do it for me, baby.
Let's fly together, hold it.
What are you writing?
The start of another one
of those murder mysteries
my readers love.
This is one of yours too?
Yes, of course.
You know you're my favorite writer?
Say, thanks!
(soft romantic music)
Rick, I could fall in
love with a man like you.
You're a swell guy. I
could, I really mean it.
You're a sweet girl, Nancy,
but you deserve something
better than a man like me.
- May I have this, Rick?
- Sure. Why not?
Go ahead without me, there's
something I wanna look into.
Okay, we'll set up the
next shot in the meantime.
Camera about here.
There.
Dermott, can we take a
break for a few minutes?
No, we've gotta be
finished before morning.
Put the spots over there.
Okay.
[Guard] What're you doing here?
[Edith] I'd like to see
the owner of the house.
It's not possible.
My master doesn't want to be disturbed.
- But tell him-
- I said it's impossible.
Your master has a right to his privacy
but that's no way to speak to a lady.
Rick.
You met the owner of the
house. What's he like?
It's difficult to say, really.
He was half hidden behind a table.
Have you noticed the windows?
They're all barred.
What a strange place.
If I was still a reporter,
I bet I could discover
a lot of interesting
facts about this castle.
Rick, why are you wasting
your time on horror stories?
You should be doing the kind
of work you were cut out for.
Reporting.
I guess you're right
but I'm a little lazy.
I've been taking the easy
way out by doing this.
I started out with the usual dreams
and found out there's more money
in writing this kind of commercial book.
Edith, I realize I'm being indiscreet
but why did you want to speak
to the owner of the castle?
Just curiosity.
Nothing more than that.
Everything's ready, Dermott, can I go?
Not more than a few minutes, though.
Time's running short.
You bet.
Come on, Suzy.
Don't pull me like that.
Come on.
But where?
Oh, come on.
Okay, I'm all set.
Everybody out of the way.
That's right.
Hold that pose, Perry.
Don't move. I'll be done in a minute.
Now, here we go.
(gasping)
Perry!
(screaming)
Oh no!
(eerie music)
Oh my God.
I seemed to know as soon as we arrived
that this was a place of evil.
And Perry laughed and said
that I was being emotional.
Raoul, didn't you hear that yell?
I didn't hear anything at all.
Come along.
Where are you taking me?
You'll find out.
Look at that.
What is it?
I don't know.
Maybe it was an old torture cell.
You know these old castles.
Nothing in it.
Let me alone, Raoul, I'm scared.
Suzy.
(somber saxophone music)
Come, Kinojo.
Staying here won't help any.
Come with me.
There's no point in
disturbing my master.
He's been informed already of
what has happened down here
and he hopes that you
will all remain calm.
The rope was badly worn, Rick.
We overlooked that, I'm afraid.
What're you gonna do now?
I don't know.
We'll see.
Remember Rick, even
the master of the house
suggested that we keep calm.
Tomorrow we notify the police.
What do you mean tomorrow?
Listen, after all it
was only an accident.
A tragic one, but an accident.
And besides, it's too late now.
Look Max, this double
talk leaves me cold.
What do you really mean?
- Well, I'm an editor.
- You've got to see my point.
I've a deadline to meet.
I know exactly how you feel, girls.
But we must finish our
work before daybreak.
With poor Perry lying dead?
Oh, it's a big tragedy.
You know Perry was like a son to me.
Don't you think I have a
heart, like the rest of you?
How do I know?
I never had a chance to see it.
Perry would've known what I meant.
Yeah but he's dead
and I wanna go on living.
I'll double your salary.
[Kinojo] My life's worth more than that.
Triple it.
[Kinojo] Okay, it's a deal.
[Nancy] Me too.
Then let's get back to work.
Where's Suzy?
I think she went off with Raoul.
That's just like her.
They always disappear at the wrong moment.
We'll worry about her later,
let's go back to work now.
Well I thought I'd seen
just about everything.
But this kind of bargaining is
really more than I can stand.
Rick, look at this.
What is it?
It's the negative of
the photograph I took
right when the accident occurred.
Poor Perry.
What a terrible thing.
What's this?
What's that strange shadow
near the frame of the door?
It almost looks like a man's head.
Yes, it does.
That's exactly what I thought.
But it just can't be.
Still, it does look like a man's head
with a hood on.
(somber music)
(gasping)
(menacing music)
(eerie music)
(groaning)
No!
(eerie music)
No! No!
(whimpering)
No!
(menacing music)
(water sloshing)
[Rick] Will it show up
more clearly on the print?
It should.
We'll see in a minute.
I've done the best I could.
Of course, it's only a small detail.
There.
This is the maximum
enlargement I can make here.
Of course, it's still not very clear.
Hmm.
This doesn't help us
very much, I'm afraid.
It's hardly at all visible.
You think the negative
coulda been defective?
No, it was perfect.
May I see that photograph?
I heard about the accident
that took place tonight.
A most appalling accident.
Unfortunately it's blurred.
Yeah, it was out of focus.
Perhaps this will sound strange
but I have something to tell you
that may provide an explanation
of the shadow in your photograph.
Have you ever heard of
the Crimson Executioner?
Who did you say?
The Crimson Executioner?
He was a maniac and a killer
who was put to death for
his crimes centuries ago.
He was buried in his own castle.
What you don't know is
that this is the castle
where the Crimson
Executioner lived and died.
When I came here the castle
had been uninhabited for centuries.
For me it was ideal
because I desired solitude.
Everybody else feared the curse
that had been placed on it.
When they sealed up his tomb,
the Crimson Executioner swore
that he would avenge himself.
He was a man of extraordinary
physical strength,
obsessed by an ideal of purity.
For centuries he was entombed,
there in the dungeons,
and only a seal has protected mankind
from his supernatural powers.
If the shadow in the photograph
is the Crimson Executioner,
I fear anything might happen.
I had to tell you.
(eerie music)
Well, I can see you two
already know each other.
I've never had the pleasure.
This is the first time
I've seen this lady.
(clock dinging)
I must retire now.
I'm a creature of habit.
I hope you will sleep well.
Goodnight.
Edith, I know the accident upset you.
You're terribly tired.
What happened was a
very bad shock for you.
You stop crying now.
Now, she's been through
more than the rest of us.
(ominous music)
(girls giggling)
Do you think it's too daring?
No, I bet Max will like it.
He always does.
Hi girls. Has Suzy come back yet?
No, maybe we should go on without her.
She'll be along.
You'll make a big hit
in that costume, Annie.
Won't I too?
Oh no, what's gotten into you?
You mustn't hide those
beautiful legs of yours.
They desecrated your world of beauty
with their sordidness.
The day of the Crimson
Executioner has now come!
I've been wondering about
the owner of this castle.
If you want my opinion, I
think he's slightly off his nut.
You would be too if you
lived isolated in this place.
You'd end up the same way he is.
(chuckling)
Hey, Dermott.
Yeah?
Look at this.
This must be where the
Executioner was killed
if the legend is true.
What is it?
Looks like a coffin.
No, it was a medieval
instrument of torture.
The infamous iron maiden.
(groaning)
Suzy!
What?
(menacing music)
No one can dare say that
this was a accident.
Come on.
(ominous music)
Just as I thought.
The rope wasn't worn.
It was cut.
At this point there's
only one explanation.
Deliberate murder.
Deliberate murder?
But why, Rick?
It doesn't make any sense.
That's what we've got to find out.
Any idea where Raoul is?
Raoul?
No, no, I don't mean he
had anything to do with this.
But perhaps he saw who did it.
He was near Suzy all the time.
Here, take this.
My car is the fastest we have.
Go to the nearest police
station and try and get help.
Okay, Rick, I will.
But how about you?
What're you going to do, stay here?
With a murderer at large,
we're all in danger.
I know but it's impossible to leave
with things as they are and
we've got to find Raoul,
he might have some evidence.
I'll be as fast as I can.
(ominous music)
How much longer do we have to wait now?
We get paid, why should you care?
You get prettier by the minute, girls.
Take a look at this,
Max. I have a new idea.
I don't want the girls to know this yet.
Suzy's been murdered.
What's that?
So you like the idea?
Sure, it's great.
You better watch out.
Dermott's already on his
way to the police station.
Don't tell the girls.
They'd only get panicked.
But then Perry was killed too.
We completely agree then?
Well, what do we do now?
I'll have a look around.
You better stay with the girls.
See you later.
(ominous music)
What are you doing here?
I wanna see your master right away.
No, he doesn't want to see anybody.
It's urgent that I see him
no matter what, understand?
I said you can't see him.
(ominous music)
Edith, what're you doing here?
I want you to see what I found.
I'm sure you recognize her.
What's your portrait
doing in this castle?
Then you do know the owner.
Yes, Travis and I were engaged.
Travis Anderson.
Isn't he the actor who
disappeared several years ago?
Yes, he used to be a
muscle man in costume films.
It all happened so
suddenly, so unexpectedly.
He left without a word.
He just vanished.
He's always been a little strange.
Even with me, he seemed so cold.
Yet I'm certain that he really loved me.
In all this time I
haven't stopped wondering
why he disappeared like that.
Now I've found him here in this castle.
I thought I recognized his voice
and now that I've found
this I know it's Travis.
I must try to speak to him.
Edith, we have no time for that.
You've got to trust me.
[Edith] What is it?
I'll tell you later.
Where's Kinojo?
I left her downstairs
when I went to find Travis.
There's not a moment to
lose, we must find her.
What's happened, Rick?
Don't ask any questions, hurry!
We've got to reach the others.
It's important we all stay together.
But what's going on?
I don't understand.
(Kinojo moaning)
Kinojo?
(ominous music)
Kinojo!
(whimpering)
Watch out, Rick!
Don't try to get any closer
to me, you'll get killed.
There's no escape for me, I know it.
You must save yourselves while
there's still a chance.
Don't you see?
It's a diabolical trap.
It's impossible for anyone to reach me.
These wires are connected
to the bows on the walls.
The slightest touch
will release the arrows
in every direction and
anyone nearby will be killed.
Nobody can stop the mechanism
that operates the spider.
It has poison in its claws.
I'll be killed the moment it reaches me.
(eerie music)
No, it's hopeless!
Watch out, Rick.
Don't do it, Rick!
You'll be killed!
(Kinojo whimpering)
(eerie music)
I tell you, it's hopeless.
Don't do it, Rick.
Leave me, it's no use.
(ominous music)
Please don't come any closer.
You're mad to risk your life like this.
(Kinojo sobbing)
Rick!
(eerie music)
(Kinojo whimpering)
No!
[Edith] Rick, your jacket's caught!
(eerie music)
(Kinojo whimpering)
It's all over for me.
It's the end for all of us.
(whimpering)
(eerie music)
Give up Rick, it's no use.
It's too late.
Rick!
(whimpering)
(Kinojo screaming)
(ominous music)
Kinojo!
Oh, Kinojo.
What a horrible death.
I've gotta get her down from here.
Edith, go find the others.
Hurry up!
You've gotta get out
of the castle at once!
At once!
No, Rick, no!
Not without you!
Do what I tell you!
Go away, Edith, go away!
Don't worry about me!
Dermott will be back here
soon with the police.
(motor buzzing)
Open the door!
Let us out! Let us out!
It's no use. We've been locked in.
No! What do we do?
Max!
Max, what's happening?
Where are the others?
I don't know but don't lose your head.
Just come on down here.
Go and tell Rick that we need him.
All right.
We have to get out of here.
Rick!
Rick, all the doors are locked!
We can't get out!
Keep calm, Edith, we'll make it somehow.
Just a minute.
(Edith whimpering)
(Edith moaning)
(whooshing)
Edith?
(thudding)
(ominous music)
Travis!
Don't come any nearer.
Don't touch me.
You are the murderer.
Now I know it, Travis.
How could you?
You're a monster!
(groaning)
You!
You no longer mean anything to me.
Even though I missed you
when I abandoned the world.
I was forced to retreat to this castle.
Mankind is made up of inferior creatures,
spiritually and physically deformed,
who would've corrupted the
harmony of my perfect body.
(ominous music)
I came to the isolation of this castle
to avoid the contagion of human sentiment.
And a woman's love
would've destroyed me.
It's because of that.
I abandoned you.
Travis, you've lost your sanity.
You're an egotist,
obsessed with your sick thoughts.
You're wrong, Edith.
Last night I had a moment
of weakness because of you,
when I first caught sight of you
and I said you could stay
together with your friends.
But that was a mistake!
I know of only one who is
never overcome by weakness.
The Crimson Executioner.
He despised your world.
(eerie music)
As passionately as I do.
Look at him.
His magnificent body
was preserved, intact,
through all these centuries undisturbed.
His spirit lives in me
and I'll continue his
mission of vengeance.
This is the sacred duty I've sworn to.
We're alike.
(eerie music)
Now that you have profaned his tomb
and broken the seal that
imprisoned his great spirit,
his power has been released at last.
And his noble crusade against
sin lives again through me!
Yes, the black fire of the long
awaited vengeance is here.
And your friends cannot escape.
The Crimson Executioner
has passed judgment.
(eerie music)
And now,
at last,
you'll witness the glory of his return!
And you'll pay just like the others.
(whimpering)
Travis!
Don't do it!
Come back!
(ominous music)
(suspenseful music)
Now you'll be punished for your lechery.
The Crimson Executioner will torture you.
Yes, will torture you!
Till death!
(menacing music)
(girls whimpering and screaming)
(ominous music)
That's just a small portion of
the torture that awaits you.
I promise you that none
will escape the wrath
of the Crimson Executioner!
(ominous music)
As for Rick!
This is how he will die.
Why are you doing this?
Why don't you let us go?
What have we done to you?
(metal clinking)
You're torturing innocent people!
Come back to your senses!
You're the owner of this castle.
Not the Crimson Executioner.
(yelling)
You'll see.
I am the Crimson Executioner!
(wood creaking)
Raoul!
(groaning)
(wood creaking)
(sighing)
[Nancy] I can't stand
it anymore! Let me go!
The Crimson Executioner
invented the torture of icy water
for creatures like you.
(whimpering)
(ominous music)
(groaning)
My vengeance needs blood.
The Crimson Executioner
cries out for blood!
(groaning)
(yelling)
(screaming)
You better prepare to die.
You sinner!
(screaming)
(menacing music)
(Travis laughing)
(groaning)
(suspenseful music)
(thudding)
(moaning)
(gagging)
Rick!
(suspenseful music)
(crashing)
(groaning)
(gasping)
Rick!
Edith.
Where are you?
You mustn't worry about me.
I'm not in danger.
Try to find the others if you can, Rick.
They're in Anderson's hands.
He took them to the dungeons.
He's insane.
He thinks he's the Crimson Executioner.
You've got to stop him
or he'll kill them all!
Hurry, Rick!
[Rick] Yes but where are you, Edith?
[Edith] Watch out!
(clinking)
(suspenseful music)
(gasping)
(eerie music)
I'm not through with you yet.
What more do you want with me?
You're insane!
You can't get away with this.
Let me out of here, I'll
pay you anything you want.
What're you going to do now?
This fire will purify
your miserable soul!
You're impure!
This fire will cleanse you!
No!
You can't do this to me!
Stop! Stop!
Stop!
No, I don't wanna die like this.
No, let me out!
[Travis] Burn, fire, burn!
(whimpering)
(yelling)
Mercy!
(screaming)
(eerie music)
(gasping)
(ominous music)
(screaming)
Your new lover!
There he is, the lover of death!
Embrace this poisonous man!
Go on, he's waiting!
(footsteps thumping)
The lover of death!
No, I don't wanna die!
Embrace him!
No! No!
No!
Why do you resist?
Annie! Run! Run!
(screaming)
Annie!
(suspenseful music)
No!
Let me go!
(screaming)
Now it's your turn!
Travis!
You'll pay too!
No! No!
(whimpering)
Let me go!
Stop!
Travis, don't!
Don't!
Oh please, stop!
Please let me go!
(sobbing)
You're mad!
(ominous music)
No! No!
Don't do this to me!
(eerie music)
Travis! Travis!
The Executioner has risen from his tomb.
Your atonement has just begun.
(eerie music)
It's done. I killed the writer.
Ah!
It's not true.
No, it's impossible!
No!
They'll all die!
(screaming)
No, I can't stand this!
No, I beg you, Travis!
What're doing is insane!
Stop it!
(screaming)
Oh my God!
The Crimson Executioner
(eerie music)
No! Go away!
I am the Crimson Executioner!
[Edith] Rick!
It's impossible!
It can't be!
It's impossible that
he's alive, I tell you!
I killed him myself!
I saw him die!
It wasn't me you murdered.
You hit the dead body of poor Raoul.
I put his corpse on the tower
and that's what your arrow hit.
You'll have to try again.
Kill him!
Go on!
Kill him, I said!
(suspenseful music)
(groaning)
(gasping)
(chains rattling)
(suspenseful music)
(groaning)
(gagging)
Watch out, Rick!
(chains rattling)
(thudding)
(suspenseful music)
(banging)
(whip cracking)
(whimpering)
(gagging)
(eerie music)
My perfect body
in the poisonous clutches
of the lover of death.
(ominous music)
Edith!
Rick!
My body.
My pure body...
(groaning)
Has been contaminated.
The body of the Crimson.
Executioner.
(eerie screaming)
Edith.
(somber music)
He was completely mad.
Like the Crimson Executioner,
Travis was obsessed with
the dream of absolute purity
and physical perfection.
That's why he retired to the
isolation of this castle.
Our intrusion into his
world was too much for him
and it was then that he assumed
the identity of the Crimson Executioner
and decided to carry out the
ancient legend of revenge.
His striking resemblance
to the real the executioner
made it easy from him to
believe his own hallucination.
Striking resemblance?
Anderson in his folly created
the legendary executioner
in his own image.
The Crimson Executioner has
been dust for centuries.
It was terrible.
Please take me away from this castle.
It was a nightmare.
I won't write any more horror stories.
The man that said life
is stranger than fiction
made no mistake.
(ominous music)
(eerie music)