1
00:00:45,000 --> 00:01:05,000
<font color=Yellow>
English Subtitle Adel Salem - IRAQ
<u>www.OK.ru/adelsalem</u>
<u>www.YT.com/adelsalem</u>
</font>

2
00:01:18,710 --> 00:01:21,907
As the world observed the
MEIN KAMPF's first successes...

3
00:01:22,110 --> 00:01:26,786
few people knew
the existence of an Eastern Hitler...

4
00:01:27,390 --> 00:01:29,950
Baron Giichi Tanaka.

5
00:01:30,190 --> 00:01:33,580
The success of his plan to conquer
the world, depended...

6
00:01:33,790 --> 00:01:38,659
of the secret. This film narrates
how was he unmasked by...

7
00:01:39,110 --> 00:01:43,865
an American journalist in Tokyo.

8
00:01:46,870 --> 00:01:50,226
TANAKA PLANS AN ATTACK
THE UNITED STATES.

9
00:01:51,430 --> 00:01:54,422
CHINA, FIRST VICTIM OF THE PLAN
TANAKA OF CONQUEST OF THE WORLD

10
00:01:54,550 --> 00:01:59,101
UNVEILS A COPY
ATTACK PLAN.

11
00:02:30,000 --> 00:03:00,000
<font color=Yellow>
English Subtitle Adel Salem - IRAQ
<u>www.OK.ru/adelsalem</u>
<u>www.YT.com/adelsalem</u>
</font>

12
00:03:05,190 --> 00:03:07,340
Gentlemen, I did not know anything about
Publication of this article.

13
00:03:07,470 --> 00:03:09,381
I was not in town.

14
00:03:09,550 --> 00:03:12,144
I will read what your newspaper publishes.

15
00:03:13,350 --> 00:03:17,502
If Japan wants to control China,
we must first crush...

16
00:03:17,630 --> 00:03:20,508
the United States just like
in the past, we had to do...

17
00:03:20,630 --> 00:03:22,507
the Russian-Japanese war ..

18
00:03:22,950 --> 00:03:25,510
Gentlemen, as you know
for 25 years the Chronicle...

19
00:03:25,630 --> 00:03:27,939
supported the government, all
governments.

20
00:03:28,070 --> 00:03:29,822
It's too late for explanations.

21
00:03:29,950 --> 00:03:33,704
This insult to Baron Tanaka and
the Japanese people caused...

22
00:03:33,870 --> 00:03:35,189
great troubles.

23
00:03:35,350 --> 00:03:38,148
You know the penalties in case
of non respect of censorship.

24
00:03:38,270 --> 00:03:42,468
If my editor broke the law,
I will fire him.

25
00:03:44,150 --> 00:03:45,150
Nick!

26
00:03:48,350 --> 00:03:48,941
Nick Condon!

27
00:03:49,070 --> 00:03:50,470
Someone knows where Nick Condon is!

28
00:03:50,510 --> 00:03:53,350
He came out, something important ..
He asked that we do not disturb him.

29
00:03:53,510 --> 00:03:56,590
It would be with the Emperor that I am
do not worry, let him come immediately!

30
00:04:02,470 --> 00:04:03,949
Call him, Kitchan.

31
00:04:04,150 --> 00:04:06,345
As you wish, Mr. Sprade,
but he will not love.

32
00:04:06,470 --> 00:04:08,062
Call him anyway.

33
00:04:08,990 --> 00:04:10,787
Hello...

34
00:05:27,590 --> 00:05:29,820
- Hello Oshima, What is it?
- Nick.

35
00:05:30,030 --> 00:05:33,340
We need to discuss, if
it does not bother you.

36
00:05:33,670 --> 00:05:34,670
No, very good.

37
00:05:34,710 --> 00:05:36,630
This is an official question
of great importance.

38
00:05:36,790 --> 00:05:40,180
Well, come on, we can start.

39
00:05:40,310 --> 00:05:43,108
- Nick, please!
- Okay, okay...

40
00:05:43,310 --> 00:05:44,902
Give me that towel, will you?

41
00:05:48,630 --> 00:05:50,780
Lies, lies, these are only lies.

42
00:05:51,230 --> 00:05:52,902
There is not a word of truth.

43
00:05:53,110 --> 00:05:54,110
A moment.

44
00:05:54,270 --> 00:05:56,306
You must disclose the source of
information.

45
00:05:56,430 --> 00:05:58,261
The police must know the name
of the traitor.

46
00:05:58,430 --> 00:06:01,024
Well, that seems fair to me,
they have the right to know.

47
00:06:02,110 --> 00:06:04,670
The traitor is the American press.

48
00:06:05,670 --> 00:06:08,059
This article appeared in three
New York newspapers.

49
00:06:08,270 --> 00:06:10,147
- I can not believe it.
- Ah really?

50
00:06:10,310 --> 00:06:12,460
Ask your consul in New York.

51
00:06:12,670 --> 00:06:16,629
It's a shame when newspapers
Americans publish these insanities...

52
00:06:16,790 --> 00:06:20,703
the good Americans get an idea
false the friendship of the Japanese people

53
00:06:21,190 --> 00:06:23,420
I agree, I agree.

54
00:06:23,670 --> 00:06:26,628
You know, if there's one thing I hate,
is someone to get a wrong idea...

55
00:06:26,830 --> 00:06:28,229
of Japanese friendship.

56
00:06:28,350 --> 00:06:31,262
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.

57
00:06:37,430 --> 00:06:39,830
You can not do that to me anymore
my tension will not resist.

58
00:06:39,950 --> 00:06:41,065
Suppose they took me down.

59
00:06:41,190 --> 00:06:43,499
When I arrived here two years ago,
to take care of the newspaper...

60
00:06:43,630 --> 00:06:45,905
it was on one condition: to direct it.

61
00:06:46,070 --> 00:06:47,742
I know Nick, but you can not.

62
00:06:47,870 --> 00:06:49,462
You sell twice more
of copies we have increased your...

63
00:06:49,590 --> 00:06:51,820
salary, you never won
that much money!

64
00:06:51,950 --> 00:06:54,418
You do not shoot yourself
not bad.

65
00:06:54,550 --> 00:06:55,824
You win double that
you were given in Shanghai.

66
00:06:55,950 --> 00:06:56,621
You want to come back on our agreement?

67
00:06:56,750 --> 00:07:00,709
I appreciate what you did for the
Chronicle but publish this.

68
00:07:00,830 --> 00:07:03,264
That's why newspapers exist,
that's why people buy them.

69
00:07:03,390 --> 00:07:04,948
Not for Japanese propaganda.

70
00:07:05,110 --> 00:07:06,748
But it was only a rumor.

71
00:07:06,870 --> 00:07:08,861
Yes, and American entrepreneurs
have the right to know these...

72
00:07:08,990 --> 00:07:09,706
rumors.

73
00:07:09,830 --> 00:07:13,300
I know, I know Nick, but a lot
Japanese read us too.

74
00:07:15,190 --> 00:07:18,705
Well, I think it's more than a rumor
for these two zigotos to come here.

75
00:07:18,910 --> 00:07:21,708
- I think I'm going to dig up this story.
- Crease?

76
00:07:21,910 --> 00:07:22,945
You must forget it!

77
00:07:23,070 --> 00:07:24,628
You must write a disclaimer!

78
00:07:24,750 --> 00:07:26,990
I will write it when I get
demonstrated that it is a lie.

79
00:07:27,070 --> 00:07:29,789
Nick, Are you sure this article
appeared in New York newspapers?

80
00:07:29,910 --> 00:07:31,866
The Japanese censored them.

81
00:07:31,990 --> 00:07:33,901
- In New York they read it yesterday.
- Hier?

82
00:07:34,030 --> 00:07:35,429
So how did you read it?

83
00:07:36,910 --> 00:07:39,105
Read it? I have written it.

84
00:07:40,030 --> 00:07:42,942
Nick, Nick, for heaven's sake.

85
00:07:46,870 --> 00:07:48,701
Hi Nick, I thought you were in jail.

86
00:07:49,110 --> 00:07:51,499
Someone will have to kill you
to save face.

87
00:07:51,630 --> 00:07:52,745
Is not it a little early for that?

88
00:07:52,870 --> 00:07:54,428
No, no, it's just an impression.

89
00:07:54,550 --> 00:07:58,179
I learned that the police withdrew
the Chronicle of all kiosks.

90
00:07:58,310 --> 00:07:59,743
I hope you all have yours.

91
00:07:59,870 --> 00:08:01,349
I can provide you with copies.

92
00:08:01,510 --> 00:08:04,707
No thanks, I want to stay in Tokyo,
I just renewed my contract.

93
00:08:05,350 --> 00:08:06,988
- Have you seen Ollie, Ollie Miller?
- No, no, me no.

94
00:08:07,270 --> 00:08:10,103
When Ollie Miller is not in this
bar is that he is sick.

95
00:08:11,310 --> 00:08:12,538
- See you soon.
- Goodbye.

96
00:08:25,070 --> 00:08:28,426
Hi Nick, this is Joe Casel,
coming from Shanghai.

97
00:08:28,670 --> 00:08:29,790
- Nice to meet you.
Sit down.

98
00:08:30,030 --> 00:08:31,907
- Yes.
- Thank you.

99
00:08:33,510 --> 00:08:35,068
- You drink?
- Scotch and soda.

100
00:08:35,230 --> 00:08:36,060
Me too Thanks.

101
00:08:36,190 --> 00:08:38,070
- What would you like?
- Three Scotch with soda.

102
00:08:39,550 --> 00:08:41,381
Joe Casel... Joe Casel...

103
00:08:43,030 --> 00:08:45,339
You worked for the Daily Telegraph of
New York.

104
00:08:45,470 --> 00:08:48,507
Then you went to Russia and Beijing,
you worked a while for...

105
00:08:48,630 --> 00:08:51,542
the American Press Association
since I lost track of you

106
00:08:51,670 --> 00:08:54,423
- You are famous
- No, you have a good memory.

107
00:08:54,830 --> 00:08:57,788
- Are you looking for work?
- No, I'm going home.

108
00:08:57,990 --> 00:09:00,550
This morning, I was at the embassy.

109
00:09:00,710 --> 00:09:03,065
Your article has upset them.
It was fun.

110
00:09:03,230 --> 00:09:04,822
- That breaks the monotony.
- Where did you shoot him?

111
00:09:05,110 --> 00:09:06,941
A little here, a little there...

112
00:09:07,270 --> 00:09:09,625
There is not an atom of truth
and you know it.

113
00:09:10,470 --> 00:09:13,143
- I do not know anything, do you?
- Enough.

114
00:09:13,430 --> 00:09:15,421
Our Chinese friends are trying
to raise public opinion...

115
00:09:15,590 --> 00:09:17,069
against Japan.

116
00:09:18,270 --> 00:09:19,270
Why?

117
00:09:20,030 --> 00:09:22,100
To divert the attention of
their internal mess and trust me...

118
00:09:22,230 --> 00:09:24,585
"disorder" is a weak term.

119
00:09:24,750 --> 00:09:28,265
- I just spent 4 years there.
- I have lived here for 6 years.

120
00:09:28,630 --> 00:09:31,383
4 years are enough for me and note that
I have a great admiration for the...

121
00:09:31,550 --> 00:09:32,778
Chinese people...

122
00:09:33,590 --> 00:09:37,947
I'm sure some of your
best friends are Chinese, right?

123
00:09:40,030 --> 00:09:41,179
Finally.

124
00:09:48,510 --> 00:09:52,708
- Hello guys, Hi Gugaloo,
- Johnson...

125
00:09:52,910 --> 00:09:56,061
Did you read Nick's article from this
morning? It's Dynamite, huh!

126
00:09:56,470 --> 00:09:59,030
How about drinking something?
It's my tour, I pay.

127
00:09:59,270 --> 00:10:02,899
- Do you pay?
- All you can drink!

128
00:10:03,190 --> 00:10:06,262
- So a double whiskey with soda.
- A Bourbon with water.

129
00:10:06,430 --> 00:10:08,182
- And you, Gugaloo?
- Me, a lemonade.

130
00:10:08,310 --> 00:10:09,823
You know what I drink.

131
00:10:09,990 --> 00:10:12,299
- Finally, Mr. Condon, China through the centuries...
- Sorry, gentlemen, here...

132
00:10:12,430 --> 00:10:13,863
Ollie Miller.

133
00:10:17,710 --> 00:10:20,907
"Yes, gentlemen, I am leaving.
- Again?

134
00:10:21,110 --> 00:10:22,623
Have you ever seen this?

135
00:10:22,790 --> 00:10:24,189
- Thank you.
- Keep the change.

136
00:10:24,470 --> 00:10:27,906
Two tickets for the house, and on the
first boat leaving tonight.

137
00:10:28,110 --> 00:10:29,509
The Nagata Maru.

138
00:10:29,670 --> 00:10:31,069
Where did you get the money?

139
00:10:31,270 --> 00:10:34,740
A new invention. A machine
secret, you press a button and...

140
00:10:34,870 --> 00:10:37,259
there are 10 and 100 bills.

141
00:10:38,710 --> 00:10:40,790
In this case, what happens to
30, what do you owe me?

142
00:10:40,990 --> 00:10:46,189
It's a pleasure, it's a pleasure and here
the 10 you did not want...

143
00:10:46,310 --> 00:10:48,380
lend me. Pay yourself another drink.

144
00:10:48,670 --> 00:10:51,503
We will continue next time,
Miller has arrived.

145
00:10:51,750 --> 00:10:53,308
- See you soon.
- Goodbye.

146
00:10:54,910 --> 00:10:57,299
Yes sir, I leave this blessed land.

147
00:10:57,430 --> 00:11:02,220
Who has cherry blossoms but
no cherries, what kind of...

148
00:11:02,350 --> 00:11:03,942
cherry trees is this here?

149
00:11:04,870 --> 00:11:06,781
I probably settle in
Connecticut and...

150
00:11:06,910 --> 00:11:09,378
I will write a book...

151
00:11:10,630 --> 00:11:14,179
Nick, hello I was looking for you.

152
00:11:14,430 --> 00:11:19,743
320 that I owed you all this time,
It's an honor to repay you..

153
00:11:20,230 --> 00:11:23,825
You must have trafficked on
Shanghai money.

154
00:11:27,110 --> 00:11:29,260
Johnson invited us to have a drink.

155
00:11:36,350 --> 00:11:40,787
Where did you get the money?
- I found it.

156
00:11:41,390 --> 00:11:43,142
Do not talk nonsense, where
does he come?

157
00:11:44,070 --> 00:11:47,187
I could take offense to your
tone of skeptical voice...

158
00:11:48,350 --> 00:11:53,788
but I prefer to be generous and Remember
that you are my friend and former boss...

159
00:11:54,030 --> 00:11:57,864
and attribute it to a bitter desire
of my good fortune.

160
00:11:59,070 --> 00:12:00,423
Ex boss?

161
00:12:00,630 --> 00:12:04,543
We're leaving tonight, Edith
and me with Nagata Maru.

162
00:12:06,910 --> 00:12:08,628
Where did you get the money?

163
00:12:08,750 --> 00:12:11,662
Nick, accept my advice, come in
to the fold.

164
00:12:11,790 --> 00:12:15,226
It gets hotter
than the guts of Fuji-Yama.

165
00:12:15,950 --> 00:12:19,022
There will be blood on the streets tomorrow
morning, it will flow like a river...

166
00:12:19,150 --> 00:12:20,469
before the summer ends.

167
00:12:20,590 --> 00:12:22,262
Are you involved in something fishy?

168
00:12:22,630 --> 00:12:25,747
Me, Ollie Miller?

169
00:12:27,550 --> 00:12:30,462
Do not forget, deck A, cabin 23.

170
00:12:30,590 --> 00:12:34,550
Come tonight around 11 o'clock with a bottle from
the field and I will tell you how much I love you.

171
00:12:35,070 --> 00:12:38,142
The men's best friend, your dog.

172
00:12:39,550 --> 00:12:43,987
Goodbye, my friends, goodbye good people.
Goodbye...

173
00:13:27,670 --> 00:13:30,138
Nick, is not it wonderful?

174
00:13:30,270 --> 00:13:32,909
Go back home, I will not believe it
as long as I have not had seasickness.

175
00:13:33,030 --> 00:13:34,030
Yes, fantastic.

176
00:13:38,430 --> 00:13:39,749
Are you the luggage?

177
00:13:39,950 --> 00:13:42,987
Yes, I have never been so
far in advance of my life.

178
00:13:43,470 --> 00:13:44,186
Come on, tell me.

179
00:13:44,310 --> 00:13:47,780
Nick, suddenly, everything is wonderful,
from poverty to wealth.

180
00:13:48,110 --> 00:13:49,150
How does Ollie explain it?

181
00:13:49,190 --> 00:13:52,182
As he explains everything. Sorry.
By dodging.

182
00:13:52,630 --> 00:13:55,463
- He said nothing?
- Vagently, very vaguely.

183
00:13:55,710 --> 00:13:57,746
Something about a
book that he will write...

184
00:13:57,910 --> 00:14:01,266
a big literary contract, a big
advance on rights...

185
00:14:02,910 --> 00:14:04,502
Well, good.

186
00:14:10,670 --> 00:14:12,979
Nick, no matter how he got it.

187
00:14:13,150 --> 00:14:15,266
Maybe he stole the treasure from
the Emperor, all I know is that...

188
00:14:15,470 --> 00:14:20,749
we're going home. This country
Kill him on fire and me too.

189
00:14:20,870 --> 00:14:23,145
Well, well, privacy
Ollie does not concern me

190
00:14:23,270 --> 00:14:26,865
but I would not want you
you put in trouble for something...

191
00:14:27,550 --> 00:14:28,983
irregular.

192
00:14:29,110 --> 00:14:32,147
If he had to confide in someone,
it's up to you, Nick.

193
00:14:32,270 --> 00:14:34,147
My concern is that he did not do it.

194
00:14:35,590 --> 00:14:36,705
Will you come tonight on the boat?

195
00:14:36,830 --> 00:14:40,505
Yes, of course, with two magnums of
Champagne.

196
00:14:40,870 --> 00:14:43,430
- To make Ollie talk.
- He already talked for less than that.

197
00:14:43,550 --> 00:14:44,300
Yes.

198
00:14:44,510 --> 00:14:45,510
Well, until then.

199
00:14:45,550 --> 00:14:48,701
Nick in case I could not
tell you that night...

200
00:14:50,590 --> 00:14:53,150
You'll be the only one I miss here.

201
00:14:53,270 --> 00:14:55,340
I would like you to come back with us.

202
00:14:58,710 --> 00:15:00,621
Thank you, I'll see you on the boat.

203
00:15:29,670 --> 00:15:30,898
Now I go there.

204
00:15:31,390 --> 00:15:33,665
Good night, Condon-san,
Are you going to America?

205
00:15:33,870 --> 00:15:37,579
Oh no, that would please you too much.
I'm taking leave of some friends.

206
00:15:38,950 --> 00:15:41,100
- Your name please.
- My name?

207
00:15:42,230 --> 00:15:43,549
Just ask Nishikata.

208
00:15:43,670 --> 00:15:46,138
He followed me all day long...
- I am the control officer...

209
00:15:46,270 --> 00:15:48,181
answer the question.

210
00:15:49,270 --> 00:15:51,386
Okay, I'll answer it.

211
00:15:51,630 --> 00:15:54,827
I think this is the new record
stupidity of the imperial police.

212
00:15:54,990 --> 00:15:57,424
I'm coming to see Mr. and Mrs. Miller,
cabin 23.

213
00:15:57,550 --> 00:15:58,699
Any objections?

214
00:15:58,990 --> 00:16:04,110
Yes, the Miller is not
still arrived.

215
00:16:04,230 --> 00:16:07,779
Can I wait for them on the bridge?
- Sorry, it's forbidden tonight.

216
00:16:07,910 --> 00:16:09,662
- Excuse me.
- Yes sir.

217
00:16:09,950 --> 00:16:11,941
Armstrong, let's go darling.

218
00:16:12,190 --> 00:16:13,623
- Stop!

219
00:16:50,830 --> 00:16:51,979
Edith!

220
00:17:25,430 --> 00:17:26,499
So what!

221
00:17:26,630 --> 00:17:28,666
You did not want to believe the police.

222
00:17:32,670 --> 00:17:35,662
Now you know, that we have told the truth.

223
00:17:36,030 --> 00:17:38,669
You have seen it yourself, your
friends did not arrive.

224
00:17:52,990 --> 00:17:55,106
Charly Sprade, yes.

225
00:17:57,550 --> 00:17:59,666
- The Chronicle, yes?
- Charly!

226
00:17:59,790 --> 00:18:03,226
Charly, there is a problem, and a big one,
I can not tell you anything now...

227
00:18:03,350 --> 00:18:06,023
I have to go. Try to find
Ambassador...

228
00:18:06,710 --> 00:18:07,938
Call him immediately.

229
00:18:08,230 --> 00:18:11,586
- Very well Nick, did you talk to Ollie?
- To Ollie?

230
00:18:11,710 --> 00:18:13,790
He wanted to talk to you, he said that
it was urgent.

231
00:18:13,910 --> 00:18:16,822
- Where is he?
He said he was going home.

232
00:18:17,470 --> 00:18:21,145
Well, well, I'll go, call me at
the house, yes ..

233
00:19:12,270 --> 00:19:14,625
Ollie! Ollie!

234
00:19:15,670 --> 00:19:16,670
Nick.

235
00:19:18,910 --> 00:19:23,347
Wait, slowly.

236
00:20:11,350 --> 00:20:15,628
Ollie, here, drink it, slowly.

237
00:20:19,750 --> 00:20:23,948
Well Ollie, now tell me
what happened.

238
00:20:27,910 --> 00:20:32,426
If I had known they were going to be
if bastards, I would have...

239
00:20:32,670 --> 00:20:34,467
asked for more money.

240
00:20:36,990 --> 00:20:43,463
This morning, you saw right with your
article, but you could not...

241
00:20:43,590 --> 00:20:45,023
guess more...

242
00:20:48,070 --> 00:20:49,742
The Tanaka plan.

243
00:20:49,910 --> 00:20:51,662
How?

244
00:20:56,590 --> 00:21:01,903
I'm glad Edith was able to leave.

245
00:21:03,150 --> 00:21:04,424
Tell him I'm sorry...

246
00:21:06,510 --> 00:21:08,182
having...

247
00:21:08,910 --> 00:21:13,267
missed the boat...

248
00:21:58,470 --> 00:21:59,107
What do you want?

249
00:21:59,270 --> 00:22:01,545
- Sorry to disturb you.
- And me, goodbye!

250
00:22:03,830 --> 00:22:07,709
A criminal escaped.
He might be here.

251
00:22:07,830 --> 00:22:09,627
We must search.

252
00:22:11,070 --> 00:22:12,822
There is no one here, I do not have
need protection.

253
00:22:12,950 --> 00:22:13,950
Get out!

254
00:22:14,030 --> 00:22:15,543
An accident?

255
00:22:21,990 --> 00:22:24,709
- Here is the criminal.
- You mean the victim, I suppose?

256
00:22:30,910 --> 00:22:32,229
We must search the house.

257
00:23:00,550 --> 00:23:03,223
You see that there is nothing, and
now, get out of here!

258
00:23:03,470 --> 00:23:06,860
Yes, but you will come with us
to file.

259
00:23:08,270 --> 00:23:12,309
Okay, okay, that's what
I intended to do.

260
00:23:12,590 --> 00:23:14,740
If you do not mind, I will call
my desk...

261
00:23:14,910 --> 00:23:17,470
You are not allowed to call.

262
00:23:19,350 --> 00:23:22,023
Listen to Oshima, I'm getting sick of it
of all that..

263
00:23:22,150 --> 00:23:25,187
Your leader, Yamada, is a good friend,
I do not want to have to get caught.

264
00:23:25,310 --> 00:23:27,778
- Please come.
- Good.

265
00:24:11,670 --> 00:24:12,898
Condon san.

266
00:24:16,710 --> 00:24:19,668
Tobacco, give me some tobacco.

267
00:24:33,830 --> 00:24:39,780
Hello, Condon san, I did not think
find you a day here, except as a friend.

268
00:24:41,070 --> 00:24:42,423
Can I call?

269
00:24:43,390 --> 00:24:44,425
Hello?

270
00:24:44,630 --> 00:24:46,461
Here is the Tokyo Chronicle.

271
00:24:47,710 --> 00:24:52,386
You will have to explain, Yamada.
Yes? Pass me Charly Sprade.

272
00:24:53,910 --> 00:24:56,743
Among other things, my government
do not like being imprisoned...

273
00:24:56,870 --> 00:24:59,020
its citizens without the slightest burden.

274
00:24:59,590 --> 00:25:03,344
The Japanese government would not do that
to an American, Condon san.

275
00:25:03,630 --> 00:25:09,387
Here is the indictment: Nicolas
Condon, esteemed editor of...

276
00:25:09,510 --> 00:25:15,187
the Tokyo Chronicle, celebrated a feast
private at his home, there was a lot...

277
00:25:15,430 --> 00:25:19,867
cheerful and a lot of noise, causing
complaints from neighbors.

278
00:25:20,030 --> 00:25:24,103
These complaints remain unanswered, the
police was forced to ask politely...

279
00:25:24,270 --> 00:25:26,545
let the noise stop.

280
00:25:26,670 --> 00:25:31,949
This request remains ignored, the police
entered your house at 10:30.

281
00:25:32,950 --> 00:25:36,386
Where she found Nicolas Condon
with two girls.

282
00:25:37,310 --> 00:25:45,581
Two, Condon-san? Mr. Condon,
very affected by excessive sake

283
00:25:46,190 --> 00:25:49,785
requires the departure of the police, the
police demand the departure of the two girls...

284
00:25:51,270 --> 00:25:56,424
Condon tries to chase the police, Condon
was very drunk.

285
00:25:57,030 --> 00:26:00,739
Aimably, the police brought him
at the station to protect him from himself.

286
00:26:01,870 --> 00:26:04,304
Hello? Hello?

287
00:26:04,510 --> 00:26:07,263
I was cut off, take me back
Tokyo Chronicle, please.

288
00:26:07,550 --> 00:26:12,305
And as he is a very esteemed man
and of great prestige...

289
00:26:12,430 --> 00:26:15,263
he is no longer mad at
police protection...

290
00:26:15,550 --> 00:26:17,461
you can leave.

291
00:26:17,870 --> 00:26:19,462
Thank you. Hey Charly...

292
00:26:19,750 --> 00:26:24,028
Nick, please, go home and sleep a little.
Yesterday you have us...

293
00:26:24,150 --> 00:26:27,028
all panicked. We even
woke up the Ambassador.

294
00:26:27,190 --> 00:26:28,908
I do not know how to tell him things...

295
00:26:29,030 --> 00:26:31,021
Newspapers only talk about your exploits.

296
00:26:31,190 --> 00:26:33,863
Too bad, too bad, I'm happy
that we have called the Ambassador.

297
00:26:34,070 --> 00:26:36,300
Remind him and tell him I have to see him
immediately and then come...

298
00:26:36,430 --> 00:26:38,341
pick me up, huh!

299
00:26:38,470 --> 00:26:41,064
Yes, and take a camera, yes.

300
00:26:43,150 --> 00:26:47,189
Sergeant Oshima, do you know our
good friend Condon san, Chronicle?

301
00:26:47,350 --> 00:26:49,500
We see each other often, it's
an honor.

302
00:26:49,750 --> 00:26:53,186
It is not mutual. You murdered
two Americans last night Oshima...

303
00:26:53,310 --> 00:26:55,540
One on Nagata Maru and another
in my house.

304
00:26:55,750 --> 00:27:00,949
A serious accusation, Condon san,
Do you have proof?

305
00:27:01,270 --> 00:27:05,821
Condon san and sake fought each other
tonight. Sake won.

306
00:27:06,750 --> 00:27:09,981
I guess you were not at
port nor to my house.

307
00:27:10,110 --> 00:27:13,022
We took our families
admire the cherry blossoms towards...

308
00:27:13,150 --> 00:27:17,268
the middle of the night,
a beautiful evening.

309
00:27:17,710 --> 00:27:21,703
Forget the nightmares
and go to sleep

310
00:27:22,350 --> 00:27:27,822
Goodbye Condon san, and if I can afford
a joke, I hope I do not see you again...

311
00:27:28,030 --> 00:27:30,305
here too fast.

312
00:27:32,270 --> 00:27:36,627
I think you are an experienced judoka
maybe we could...

313
00:27:36,830 --> 00:27:38,627
measure us one day.

314
00:27:38,790 --> 00:27:42,385
Of course, but that day,
it will be face to face ..

315
00:28:07,910 --> 00:28:09,582
You can put away your device.

316
00:28:09,870 --> 00:28:12,304
Ollie broke this window last night
and they replaced it.

317
00:28:12,950 --> 00:28:16,181
Proof number one, there is even lipstick,
proof number two...

318
00:28:16,390 --> 00:28:18,301
Yes, they did not neglect the details.

319
00:28:24,790 --> 00:28:26,348
They even cleaned blood stains.

320
00:28:26,470 --> 00:28:27,823
Yes, good work.

321
00:28:34,590 --> 00:28:35,625
What's going on Nick?

322
00:28:37,750 --> 00:28:39,581
We call, will I see who is it?

323
00:28:39,710 --> 00:28:40,710
Yes.

324
00:28:53,910 --> 00:28:55,343
Mr. Condon, please?

325
00:28:55,550 --> 00:28:56,778
- Come in.
- Thank you.

326
00:28:59,870 --> 00:29:01,064
Mr. Condon.

327
00:29:07,310 --> 00:29:07,981
Thank you.

328
00:29:08,150 --> 00:29:09,549
Ministry of Foreign Affairs.

329
00:29:09,670 --> 00:29:12,787
Let me lead you
with his excellence...

330
00:29:13,070 --> 00:29:15,903
Prime Minister Tanaka.

331
00:29:19,910 --> 00:29:22,219
That's it I'll be busy during
a few hours. Tell him...

332
00:29:22,390 --> 00:29:24,350
that I will go through his
office this afternoon.

333
00:29:24,390 --> 00:29:29,510
Wait, not the offices, his
excellence awaits you at his residence.

334
00:29:36,030 --> 00:29:37,224
It is an honor.

335
00:29:37,870 --> 00:29:41,306
Give me a few minutes, please.

336
00:30:03,150 --> 00:30:07,428
- You accompany us Miss Hilliard?
- No thanks, prínce Tatsuki...

337
00:30:07,590 --> 00:30:08,943
I'm tired.

338
00:30:09,310 --> 00:30:12,143
Iris is not very happy these days.

339
00:30:12,470 --> 00:30:16,668
Unfortunately, it was necessary
to involve him in this unfortunate...

340
00:30:16,830 --> 00:30:20,539
case. Colonel Tojo wanted it.

341
00:30:21,550 --> 00:30:25,338
Since when, Baron Tanaka,
give in to the sordid demands...

342
00:30:25,470 --> 00:30:28,030
Colonel Tojo?

343
00:30:28,190 --> 00:30:32,263
I did not give in, prince
Tatsuki, I approved them.

344
00:30:32,430 --> 00:30:35,627
In the future, I would be very happy
that one does not oblige me anymore to...

345
00:30:35,750 --> 00:30:38,947
search the luggage of a
woman horribly murdered.

346
00:30:39,230 --> 00:30:43,303
It will not happen again, my dear.
I promise.

347
00:30:50,310 --> 00:30:52,983
- An interesting woman.
- Yes.

348
00:30:54,110 --> 00:30:56,305
- Metisse?
- Yes.

349
00:30:57,390 --> 00:30:58,743
- His mother was...
- Chinoise.

350
00:31:02,950 --> 00:31:07,944
Baron, I shared my fears
to the Emperor as to...

351
00:31:08,110 --> 00:31:11,546
the road on which you
want to lead the nation.

352
00:31:11,750 --> 00:31:16,141
Your Highness, the decisions have already
been submitted to the emperor.

353
00:31:16,510 --> 00:31:20,822
Your great influence could
to curb the militarists.

354
00:31:21,390 --> 00:31:25,986
I'm just an old man, whose voice
no longer has any authority.

355
00:31:26,270 --> 00:31:32,823
But you are one of the members the most
esteemed of my cabinet, your highness.

356
00:31:33,390 --> 00:31:35,108
Valued?

357
00:31:35,310 --> 00:31:38,063
Esteemed as a liberal screen.

358
00:31:38,230 --> 00:31:41,142
I am the parchment of the poet,
behind which we sharpen...

359
00:31:41,270 --> 00:31:43,386
the sword of the Samurai.

360
00:31:43,990 --> 00:31:47,824
Without an armed force, we will perish,
That is my opinion.

361
00:31:48,030 --> 00:31:51,261
These views will lead Japan
to disaster.

362
00:31:51,510 --> 00:31:53,819
We see the problem differently.

363
00:31:54,070 --> 00:31:58,985
That's for sure, to defend my ideas
I will die in honor...

364
00:31:59,630 --> 00:32:03,543
You, Baron Tanaka, you will only die
to clear your shame.

365
00:32:28,990 --> 00:32:31,265
Mr. Hayashi and Mr. Condon.

366
00:32:34,710 --> 00:32:36,826
Nice to see you again,
Mr. Condon.

367
00:32:37,830 --> 00:32:42,665
Colonel Tojo, of the Imperial Army,
you already know the major...

368
00:32:42,830 --> 00:32:46,061
Kayoka from the secret police
imperial.

369
00:32:46,910 --> 00:32:48,343
Mr. Nicolas Condon.

370
00:32:48,470 --> 00:32:49,789
Sit down, please.

371
00:32:52,990 --> 00:32:56,983
Thank you for being here, it's
much nicer than at the office.

372
00:32:57,350 --> 00:33:01,628
Here, journalists do not bother us.

373
00:33:04,630 --> 00:33:11,741
We consider your article yesterday,
Mr. Condon was a bit boring.

374
00:33:13,710 --> 00:33:15,302
I can not please the world.

375
00:33:16,190 --> 00:33:20,786
Of course, we understand that you
could not foresee the inappropriateness...

376
00:33:20,910 --> 00:33:22,980
of your statements.

377
00:33:23,190 --> 00:33:26,546
In short, Mr. Condon, some
subversive liberal factions of our...

378
00:33:26,670 --> 00:33:31,425
country want to create an incident
to weaken this government.

379
00:33:31,710 --> 00:33:34,950
These are the authors of the malicious
rumors that you have regrettably published.

380
00:33:37,790 --> 00:33:42,784
As I said, Mr. Condon, the article
in itself is not important.

381
00:33:43,030 --> 00:33:45,942
These rumors about a document
planning the conquest of the world are...

382
00:33:46,110 --> 00:33:51,787
ridiculous, but if this rumor was taken
seriously by the wrong people...

383
00:33:51,990 --> 00:33:54,948
that would cause a fire that
for Japan would be...

384
00:33:55,150 --> 00:33:57,425
expensive to extinguish.

385
00:33:57,790 --> 00:34:02,102
I see, what you would like is the chronicle
launches campaign to put out the fire...

386
00:34:02,270 --> 00:34:05,182
- Is not it?
- No Mr. Condon.

387
00:34:05,310 --> 00:34:08,541
In the last 24 hours we have discovered
a plot to leave the country...

388
00:34:08,710 --> 00:34:10,507
this false document.

389
00:34:10,630 --> 00:34:14,305
A man named Oliver Miller,
one of your former employees, is involved.

390
00:34:14,990 --> 00:34:19,427
We could have retrieved the document
by force, if we had wanted it...

391
00:34:20,070 --> 00:34:24,780
but we would prefer that you
persuade us to return the document.

392
00:34:26,350 --> 00:34:28,705
It seems like you did not know,
Excellency,

393
00:34:28,910 --> 00:34:31,788
as well as your secret police, major,
that Mr. and Mrs. Miller...

394
00:34:31,910 --> 00:34:34,265
were murdered last night.

395
00:34:37,590 --> 00:34:42,618
Yes we read in the press your
that little night's escapade Mr. Condon.

396
00:34:43,350 --> 00:34:48,902
In your inconsistent state you have
evoked this unpleasant fantasy.

397
00:34:49,670 --> 00:34:51,740
Since we were even more
concerned that you...

398
00:34:51,950 --> 00:34:56,228
Mr. Miller's fate, we made a
small survey of the captain of...

399
00:34:56,350 --> 00:35:01,060
Nagata Maru, a man of all trust.

400
00:35:03,830 --> 00:35:06,219
Mr. and Mrs. Miller, are at
edge of Nagata Maru...

401
00:35:06,390 --> 00:35:08,750
both in perfect health,
both surprised by the investigation.

402
00:35:08,910 --> 00:35:12,390
Is everything clear?
<font color=Yellow>
The END
Adel Salem -IRAQ
<u>www.OK.ru/adelsalem</u>
<u>www.FB.com/AdelSalemlraq</u></u>
</font>

