oh don't make me nervous I've been
jumping all right son stage you will
almost midnight for the record the
solver holding up stuff and vilification
oneself they happily hero star or
cuddling and writing on like when you
lose sleep for did you see in second
color I'm all in expectin trouble before
please round here like what's going on I
got it I wrote you see that knuckle the
only cup do is form about just one side
we proceed with your every called a
visual let me say that if my daughter
calling Wednesday this is really I think
tonight there is to binge up which one
I want a room with a children I'm
Shirley now and I have to sleep me a cup
of hot tea well hold on sole member rule
AGG this time mr. mrs. right there
I suppose you folks would like the
battle Kamath how much
well we always get two dollars for the
visor change
you see it's fit invest in the house
and the please be inspired became the
man makes you can suppertime butter the
bottom delight right wha
hello boss loan mom happy to be safe
here
let's take away the face to get it
well pick up young man what it is but
esposas whatever Angela I ain't lost
nothing well what were we diffic it if
you can't
it's tricky go all right I reckon ahead
my trip another CI would this offer hope
you got fenders here about but you don't
restrict them out in the storm like this
for you you can expecting many where
their money
oh wait
I doing is for pokey duck
reckon your tip was right there how they
hit the combination I don't know why
then does it taste combination of us you
watch the through the window when you
I'm just kind of sailing tonight know by
morning he'd be miles away just the same
I'm gonna run him down
it takes me ten years
oh whoa laughs your guy
everything's all right old timer just in
time for me so now think you're pretty
slick new cheese
no just careful well you might have been
the Polka Dot bend some other notorious
outlaw and oh you know lean just by your
look come on let's see
being sure smell good I'll help yourself
pretty slick on the draw to inky Sun oh
I'm hurt just for Saheb well don't get
excited
see I carry this for snake why see you
we do it your snake here's to me you
right now is good time to open a gym
drink Oh in this particular case yet
mind if I roll up here for the knife
oh you're right glad to know you better
and I ain't too sure anyway here's mud
in your eye and see any sign of Mason in
the game
so I plotted us down by cotton quick
maybe the outlaws hard you think so how
could they know when Mason was coming to
LA how did they know before I tell him
as a skunk in this town and we oughta
rollin down there ought to be here from
Sacramento that letter was sent three
weeks ago
all right the government don't care
nothing bother we got to help ourselves
you can't ride out long for that
ammunition and we can get it
just ever in the past you boys know what
to do
remember no harm would come to the girls
no sign of applause yet Betty but I
still insist you shouldn't have come
now don't go dad it's been a wonderful
trip
why'd you decide to do so long with me
it's kind of lonesome trail on the load
yeah I Ain't mistaken you're going to
have plenty of company
how long please help
well we got both up we better make sure
no sign of them I reckon they're on the
bottom
well I forgot you old-timer the feel of
my head they did get me what happened I
always shot you off your horse and you
fell over the cliff you know the water
you pull me out all right I reckon I owe
you my life
are you freaking don't worry about that
that we got to get out of here think you
can make it now make it or bust a cinch
everything worked out just as you
planned only we bumped into a couple of
strangers
we had a real em fight they got Jake for
fear on the bottom of the river
what about the girl are you sure you
didn't recognize you ah we didn't get
close enough for that she's probably in
town by now come on
hello boy oh yeah words in the factory
yes I'm studying on where's the home
would sadden Thomas did alright then hey
children who killed them Heather tell us
all about it mr. Dees well we were just
coming through the pack and
then these men rode a Fiat Road I ran
into a din from him there
I'm ready
let me take care of you I want you to
consider my ranch your home so we can
make more definite plans for your future
I want you to know that everything
possible to help you and you'll send
someone for him I'm going myself right
away Oh mrs. Williams I want you to take
care of any until I return
town I reckon good daughter just told
her we're just going to bring him into
town yeah whereas you can give us a hand
then
Oh
how do you take care of me you know one
of you now talk and talk that where is
the rest of your gang in the provision
why was it necessary to kill you could
have taken up packs without committing
murder then is on these two going
through Mason's pockets I wants to be
done that guy my King covered then we
didn't tell Mason if you'll call his
daughter she'll prove it is Tatars no
condition if it dragged out here in
question we're not trying to question
anyone but under the circumstances I
think miss Mason be glad to explain here
she comes now does Mason these men have
accused us of killing your father oh no
mr. Melrose these are the men that will
be on goes away and saved my life
well that case we certainly owe you
gentlemen apology you of course don't
realize but this town is in the most
desperate state there are without food
nomination terrorized by a panda
murdering outlaws to attempt have been
made now to bring in supplies only to
have our men killed and the full ticket
we don't get provider share before snow
sets in we're crack we're trapped now we
can owner that a few days longer let's
all today I tell is the only solution I
think you're right how can we get out
now money is all gone for food we never
cost then I have a little money not much
but I'll do this and all that we can get
out I'll give you $100 each for your
homestead I'm taking a long chance of
ever get my money back when I'll risk it
oh no
don't you think before you sell your
homes for a few dollars you should take
at least one more chance at getting the
provision through our main half families
there's been enough killing
yeah cricket if you can get us
provisions I'll pay you well
forget that you give us an order and
we'll have the provisions back here
inside of four days court and come to my
ranch this afternoon I'll give you an
order for a thousand dollar supply be
that Palermo girl you're gonna be mighty
interested in him right soon who is
keeping that first surprise yeah when
I'm keeping a surprise for you two
so miss Mason affair rule
remember this is to be your home Betty
is what if you have great pleasure to
have you with me
I thought you said those two men with
the bottom of the river I'd swear those
were the two was shot down hmm that's
better those two Meadows a town would be
moving out right now well anyway you got
the girl and remember this
she's private property hands off and you
better tell the board not to be talking
around here she might find out who you
really are
Kent made another inspection hosted
Valley swears it'll be the richest pool
strike ever discovered runs right
through the middle of all the ranches
you'll soon be rid of those hombres the
town will move out and we loan the gold
field and you're a hypocrite and all
take it to the high out we'll keep her
there until the town is deserted you
don't dare
I'm going over to Melrose and get that
order
only one cream over what's he doing
bunkhouse I don't know now is your
chance remember no shooting
you boys tell me where I meligrove is oh
yeah I think you'll find him right come
on
what's this all about
I asked these men here my boys have
orders to hold all strangers they didn't
understand I'm very sorry
all right I'm no girl we were just
playing here's your order
and I wish you luck what are you leaving
right now
we expect to be back before daylight you
see The Outlaws won't be expecting is
that to I hope you get through Oh will
be our fault if we don't eh Jake you
sugar son won't be expecting MA they'll
find out it's a things we least expect
that usually happens
what we was going to send you
we're not going to be that Felicia
Alzheimer's they'd be waiting for us at
the Pat you think now grown video with
the other one there's no doubt about it
who must be done what all depends on
what happens between on tomorrow morning
everyone happen in this nation
you
and the scale go to the high right we
leave at dawn
they'll be coming to early where's the
girl in the throne room she won't eat
you get over that I'll have a talk with
her tomorrow this nation ready oh so
glad you found me
tell me briefly what's happened they
caught me overhearing their plans and
brought me here noble is a leader you're
trying to force the people out so if you
get their life for one when you see
under their topsoil is a rich gold
deposit and it runs right through all
the ranches Tennyson with them they'll
be leaving early I'll be back shortly
after gone to get you I'll try and get
some sleep
good night I got old Ivor
yeah wasn't it stay off them here I got
a world of news for you
well you then I followed no girl to the
hideout and that's how you should go on
while they're holding this mace and
prisoners and I got to talk to her and
she gave me the lowdown on the whole
deal
I'll listen to it
I'll be back by noon I want you to guard
this place boys keep your eye on the
girl anybody comes shoot okay boss
you trying to find a wagon I'll go get
the grill
I've rotated a wagon in the hostage what
give me a left here we're taking this
number with it I'll take it
that's nice and play and get ready
they've gone
you've been tricked malgrove
I had it going to hide out keep back I'm
gonna break this in hi ray all the baby
my boo
only to the colonel
hey Sun is enough bloody inator last
year
come on
now just what do you think look they're
coming back
good work Ron but we gotta hurry they're
coming back take that long walk the line
little trees and rapers out hey son
here's the bucks dynamite might come in
handy
what happened what's the matter
take just a girl
they blocked it out we've got to swim
the narrow $1,000 to the man who gets
that girl
here they come Alzheimer don't miss your
mark means the lives of everyone in town
now Grove is the leader and honor your
task Allah is a Richard goldfields ever
discovered
oh man your troubles are all over the
outlaws are riding the path all about it
old timer
I suppose we're like this I don't know
how I can ever repay well don't worry
about that it's only my line of duty as
a government marshal well I am leaving
for Sacramento today and you don't know
it but you're going with me
and he's dead mice got shrunk wonderful
men shall congratulate me I was at the
future mrs. John for others wait a
minute young man you can't do this you
see I know who your soul is miss Mason
you mean to say your words has out here
young feller I ain't forgetting you
saved my life for what you've done for
this town I got my duty to perform and
you see I gotta take you in
don't you realize I know you're the
Polka Dot uh Sheriff you must have seen
me through the novel you write by cracky
ideas but you saw the wrong man the
Polka Dot bandit left just ahead of me
he lets just raw chicken in the floor
you must have seen me just as I pick
that up and that roll belongs to Daddy
Oh what do you make of it Oh found all
in Danny's room yesterday daddy's the
Polka Dot bandit there's a $5,000 reward
for him chef I guess it's up to you to
collect when a Denny's a pokey done who
in blazes are you why is the United
States Marshal he's your man from
Sacramento