CITIZENS
OF PARIS
A killer
is among you!
A criminal who
strangles young women.
Anyone who has information
about this Cyanopogon ...
please contact
the Police immediately!
I am! Why didn't you open
before, when I hit you again?
You scared me, Pol.
What do you want here?
I came to accompany you home.
With Cyanopogon free ...
the streets of Paris
are no longer safe at night.
Donet! The Blue Cane did not catch you
! Where were you;
What are you trying to do?
Are you going to kill me?
Constance, it is already
dark outside.
Lucille, will you hurry? Do you want us to
leave and come back alone?
I'm coming, Bamitet.
- You did not have to wait for me.
- Do you hear her?
As if we would not be afraid
of her walking alone at night!
Why do you say
the police did not catch him?
-Whom;
-Whom; Cyanopogonas, of course!
Who else has terrorized
the whole of Paris?
-But yes! I forgot about.
- Come on, I want to go home.
Let's stay close,
for safety.
The puppet, he is!
Hello.
Constance is afraid
of her own shadow.
-When will you play in the park again?
- Probably very soon.
These are my friends,
Constance and Lucille.
- I forget your name.
- Gaston Morel.
I always think of you
simply as the puppet.
You have seen his performances in
the park, of course.
- No, I lost it.
-The wonderful operas with dolls?
- They are a lot of fun.
- I would like to see one, someday.
I would like it too. I do not show
my puppets much lately.
It is difficult to gather people
lately, due to the Cyanopogon.
But if you tell me you will come, I will
give a show tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night;
What do you say;
-I ... -Of
course it will!
- He is afraid of Cyanopogon.
- You are not afraid of him?
-What to do with me?
- He would find you irresistible.
-Show tomorrow, then?
-At the same place.
-We will come. Right, Lucille?
-Yes. Tomorrow night.
Margarita, convinced that
Faust has abandoned her ...
and being in despair,
having killed her child ...
he finally found the courage
to surrender.
He was tried and
sentenced to prison ...
where Faust finds her with
the help of Metastofolis.
Rene, help him show the
puppets to whoever comes back.
I want to raise the money myself , tonight.
Thanks.
-Did you like the show?
-Very much.
Thanks.
I made the puppets myself .
-Did you make the costumes too?
- I designed them. Why;
Lucille is a seamstress. It is
natural for her to be interested.
Dressmaker;
Could you make me
some new costumes?
Come back,
let me show you the costumes.
If she was a woman ...
you would not need a rope
to make her talk!
-How do the eyes move?
- This is very simple.
Do you see these
two threads here?
- Do you like my little people?
-Very much.
- They look very real to me.
- Rescues of people I know.
-And Metastofolis?
- Yes, and the bad guy.
And he is also
my manager
-And Margarita? Is she your girlfriend?
-It was.
-It was;
-Unfortunately, it had a tragic end.
It must have been very beautiful.
They said you will show me
how puppets work!
Let's go, until
the world's gone. They will constantly ask.
I can not talk
to so many people around.
With your work, I would expect
a lot of people to like you.
The puppet, you mean?
I prefer to create them,
than to give performances.
you make them
play so well!
But there is
something in your voice ...
which made me feel
that you have suffered.
- You are very insightful.
-Your Margarita, is she?
-The memory of the tragedy?
-Partially.
But you deliberately keep
the songs alive, right?
If you wanted to forget it,
you would make a new puppet.
One that would remind you of another.
Which may have made you happy.
-Is it difficult to make one?
- It takes time.
-First I make a sketch ...
-Painting? Do you even paint?
Enough to have the
result I need.
Do you know that you have very beautiful
eyes? Honest eyes.
Will you let me make
a puppet like you?
-Would you like it?
-Very much. Let's see...
Are you trying to decide
how to paint me?
I will not paint you.
Lucille!
Better to go with them.
And stay close to them.
Don't you want me to make you
a Margarita costume?
As you wish.
Where is Rene?
He is looking for you.
Was it difficult?
As always,
when you avoid it.
-If she comes, tell her I'm looking for her.
-What you will not do!
Of course not.
Good night, old man.
-Did you collect anything?
-What;
-Nothing money, you mean?
-For the musicians, you know ...
In the word of my honor!
-Why didn't you stay in the show?
- Can I see you flirting?
-Who is she;
-I do not know. A girl.
Another one that will take my job
for a few days, weeks!
And then you think you
will come back to me.
- Better to leave, now.
-No, not this time!
I will not tolerate it!
I warn you.
You will regret this.
From the beginning, I regretted it! From
the first day I met you!
I did not ask
you to fall in love with me.
Then why did you say that I was
necessary for your success?
-What should I believe?
- What did you believe, Rene?
I know all these girls
meant nothing to you.
Because you always
came back to me.
But what happened to Gaston?
You think...
This is the master. Inspector
La Febre, Gaston Morel.
-Did you see the corpse?
-It's really Rene.
Rene Cremont. He has been singing in
my shows for a year now.
Understood. Sorry, these are
all routine questions.
-How did you understand that he disappeared?
- We would rehearse this morning.
When she did not show up,
I went to her room.
No one answered and I told
the concierge to open it for me.
- Her bed was intact.
-I went again, a while ago ...
but had not appeared.
The porter told me that
another girl was found in the Seine.
Another victim of Cyanopogon.
So I was worried.
Do you know who may have been
motivated to kill her?
I can not think of anyone.
She was always so kind.
-When was the last time you saw her?
-In the show. He left before me.
And you have proof of that.
-Did you see if he left with anyone?
-No.
It always has a lot of people behind,
after the performances.
People come to see
how we shake the ropes.
Renee left,
without realizing it.
Did you notice any
unusual type in the viewers?
Sorry, I have no information
that can help you.
We are grateful that
you made the recognition.
I will call you if you
can help in any other way.
Renault, send to alert
Francine Natshang.
To return to Paris
as soon as possible.
- But, inspector ... -
Immediately!
Good Evening.
Did you come to tell me when
we will play Faust again?
How to play him, if we do not
find a new Margarita, first?
Miss Renee
is not with us anymore, is she?
What a shame!
He had a nice voice.
-Do you have another in mind?
-No.
I'm thinking of uploading
a new show.
Something from ballet,
with lots of new costumes.
She, what do they call her?
-Prisila Kan.
-Where will I find her?
At
Madame Blanche's dressmaker.
When do you want him to pose for you?
- I will not paint her, she.
-No;
Of course not. I just want him to
make me some costumes.
New, this!
It is a reality,
nothing more.
-Just make me costumes.
-In your studio?
I do not know where he will make them.
Not even if he will fix them.
- This is what I want you to know.
-Never;
As soon as possible.
Hundreds ..
They are also two of her friends.
- You will exclude them, I imagine.
-Because of my honor.
How do you get in here?
We do not accept beggars!
I did not come here for
business reasons.
I came for a very
confidential mission.
- To see Miss Lucille.
-I am. Did you want me?
Particularly.
A gentleman told me to ask
if you would do him a great favor.
-Who;
-Gaston Morel, puppet.
The puppet!
He asks if you will make costumes
for his new puppets.
-With great pleasure! Never;
-Now.
-Where is;
- In his studio.
I will come with you immediately.
Yes, he has so
many ideas.
No one knows what he
will think next.
I always hope one day,
he makes one like me.
Lucille!
Let me go.
Passed.
- So you work here.
-Yes.
It's perfect.
-Did you make them?
-Yes.
- You are not happy to see me.
- I'm excited.
These are the costumes.
Can you make them?
-He is very well. Did you make them?
-With difficulty. It's seasonal.
-Why so much?
- I will dedicate time to the dolls.
Until now, it was just
a game. A hobby.
-Regarding painting?
-Yes,
- I give up painting.
-Why;
-I have my reasons.
-Of course...
Do you want me to make one, for approval?
Choose whoever you want.
This.
It is obvious that
women's care is missing from here.
- Is the house so dirty?
-Like any bachelor space.
- Give me this.
- It is torn.
- I wanted to throw it away.
-Wonderful fabric.
- It was my favorite.
-Canadian stitches, needed.
-Throw it.
-It would be criminal!
In a few seconds,
it will be fine.
Why did you decide
not to paint me?
In the park you said you
would make me a doll.
You showed a lot of interest.
Something happened. What;
- I can not tell you that.
- Did I say, or did I do something?
Were you disappointed when
you saw me up close?
-Instead.
-Why, then?
- You ask a lot of questions.
-Don't you like the questions?
Do you have anything to hide?
Nice!
-If I promise not to ask again?
-You are very charming.
Unlike the ones I have
painted. I wonder...
Να'το. Ready. Now you
can use it again.
What brings you here, Lamonte?
Police found the body
of the last girl.
Why do you keep throwing them
at the Seine and they find them?
You know why.
This is your scariest
passion of all, Gaston!
I paid a lot to get
your paintings from France!
You will make enough to
constantly ask me for new ones.
Is that why you came now?
Before you get rid of the last one?
- I sold him, the last one.
- Already?
The Duke of Canner was
looking for something unusual.
-Don't tell me he took it!
- Known for his stinginess.
-Only 5,000 francs, he gave.
-Fool! He always exposes them!
If
anyone recognizes the girl?
Those who go to his exhibitions
will not know such a girl.
They are public exhibitions,
anyone can enter
- Convince him not to expose him.
- This will raise suspicions.
Buy it again.
You said he only gave you 5,000.
I do not think she will
want to leave him.
The girl in the painting is one
of the victims of Cyanopogon.
-A victim of Cyanopogon?
-The 4th, to be exact.
-Are you sure?
-Absolutely.
It's shocking!
One of my guards
here noticed the resemblance.
I researched it and there is no
doubt that it is the same girl.
- Terribly unfortunate.
- Luck for us, that you bought it.
- I know you will work together.
-Of course, I will do what I can.
Thanks.
What do you know about the painter?
Nothing. I bought the painting because
it was suggested by the gallery owner.
Although, of course, I recognized
its great value.
-Who was the gallery owner?
- Jean Lamonte. Do you know him?
Hearing, only.
Lamonte ...
-What did he tell you about the painter?
- It was a bit vague, I would say.
It was hinted, however, that he
was someone famous ..
which I created under
the pseudonym Albert Garon.
Lamonte ...
I say pay him a visit.
I do not remember such a painting.
Of course, the Duke buys a lot
of paintings, not all of them from me.
He typically remembers
that he bought it from here.
It was painted
by an Albert Garon.
I do not remember the name.
Strange, because he told me
that he paid him 30,000 francs ...
because you told him that one day
the painter would become famous.
Maybe I had said he was
a very talented painter.
I often bet my judgment
, always successfully.
Do you have any other
paintings by this Albert Garon?
I'm sorry to say that,
but no.
But I have a project of another,
very promising young man.
- Maybe I'm interested.
- From here, please.
Thanks.
And he is
at a very reasonable price.
Yes, it is quite good. But not
as impressive as Garon.
Can you find me?
You have something else that I like.
-You will have a file for the table.
-I remembered the painting, finally!
A simple, brunette girl,
on a bizarre background.
- An old man had brought it to me.
-The painter himself?
No, an unknown hawk.
He said he needed money.
-Do you know his name?
- I gave cash. I was not interested.
Do you know from whom
he got the painting?
He only mentioned that he had
been in his family for years.
But why all this interest
in Albert Garon?
I am interested in his work.
Surely you can not find him?
I have no idea
how to locate him.
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we
can not work together, then.
-If I knew where I could find you ... -I might
go again, at some point.
-Francin!
-Lusil!
-My love! When did you come back;
- I just got off the train.
Awful trip! I went in for a bath,
before I showed up at the office!
Do you have to go
to work tonight?
I received a telegram, as if
the whole of Paris was waiting for me!
- Was he with you?
-Who;
- You know who I mean.
- You never say the name.
Jacques! No, he was not with me.
He sent the telegram.
It is outrageous!
You are never home, anymore.
-This is your position!
-Did you forget our agreement?
I will not get involved in
your work, nor you in mine.
If someone is for me,
they should wait!
Good Evening.
I brought you a little man,
to have as a model.
- Who is it, Lucille?
- A client of mine.
-Since when do you sew for men?
-For puppets, I sew!
- Let it pass, I will not appear.
-My sister, Francine.
I'm sorry she's not decent.
I would like to meet her.
- Let it pass. I will not be late.
- You do not go inside?
What's wrong with you; Are you afraid to ..
Good evening.
-Francin, Gaston Morel.
-How are you;
Much better, usually!
I'm leaving in a minute.
I can not stay. I thought
of bringing one, for testing.
Almost all the same
dimensions, they have.
Do you want me to make all the
clothes?
-With great pleasure.
Forgive me, now.
- I was very happy, miss.
-Similarly.
Good night.
Simply, "customer"?
Yes, just a customer.
For the first time I hear
them called "puppets"
-Just accompany the puppet.
-Of course! In order not to break!
He is not ugly. The one who
moves the threads, I mean!
You can not imagine how happy I am,
how happy we are all, that you came back.
Thank you, Inspector.
Let me introduce you to my sister.
You did not tell me that you have
such a charming sister.
-I am not stupid!
-Nice to meet you.
My pleasure. Francine
has told me a lot about you.
Gentlemen, you can leave.
Now you have to tell me
about your success.
Sit down.
And you.
Now we can talk.
Tell me everything about you.
I thought you called me for
work. For Cyanopogon.
It's a thorn in my side!
We are not going anywhere.
-What have you done so far?
Here is the complete file.
Read it when you can.
Until recently, I had
identified him as a painter.
But we interrogated every Artistic
Authority in Paris.
Professor Wazang,
even Recomian Down.
And now we are interrogating models.
Nobody knows his technique.
I do not understand.
I have the painting that
the Duke of Canir bought.
But it will be shorter to
show you. Will you come too?
- No, go. I will stay.
- It is next door. We are coming immediately.
-Next model.
-Elen Berro.
Elise Berro.
Duke of Cannery,
Miss Francine Kahn.
-How are you, Reno?
-Very well thank you.
-Are you an Artist model?
- At Boz Arts.
Study this
table, please.
Do you have any idea, who
could have painted it?
No.
You will pay attention
to the characteristic style.
Where do you think
this difference is located?
- In the background.
-Exactly.
Do you know any painter who
uses such a background?
-No.
- The next girl.
Mimi Robert!
And so it goes.
Nobody knows his job.
-If I interrogate Lamonte?
- No, he is already very suspicious.
Lamonte is the gallery owner
who sold him to the Duke.
I suspect he knows the
painter, but I have no proof.
Will you interrogate some,
Inspector? I do it for hours!
Of course, Reno.
You understand that you are not being
tried for a crime.
-This is good!
- We just codify witnesses.
-Are you an artist model?
-Of course. Why are you passing me by?
This is not the issue.
Quiet, in the audience
I have posed for the most
important French painters!
Undoubtedly, we are
only interested in contemporary artists.
And for the most
famous sculptors.
You will know, of course,
Aphrodite of Milos!
Historical masterpiece. But you will
not tell us that you posed for it!
Quiet!
I am an exact copy
of its dimensions.
Last time, did you work
as a model?
Not as a model, exactly.
After I retired, I do ...
We do not need to
get into that.
Only one question.
Do you know Albert Garon?
-Of course!
-Who is;
-The Blue Cane.
-Look at the table.
Do you have any idea who
the painter might be?
-When I posed for Monet ...
-For him, we ask you!
No!
The next model!
Listen up.
I have an idea.
The Duke writes to me that you want
a portrait of your daughter ...
and asks me to help
you find a good painter.
Being strangers here, we turn
to the Duke, who is a relative ...
to guide us
to various things.
-For my dowry, mainly.
-The Duke has great taste.
One of his paintings
caught my attention.
The portrait of a girl
with an unexpected background.
I was wondering if this
painter is available.
-What did the Duke say about the painting?
- We could not ask him.
Last night, we came. Just
before leaving for a trip, out of town.
And since we are leaving again for
South America before he returns ...
we said very little personally and
I told him I wanted a portrait.
-What was the name of the painter?
- He could not see very well.
-Karof, or Karon?
-Garon?
Probably. Whoever it is, it
colors the flesh exceptionally.
This was what made me
decide that he is the ideal ...
to capture the subtle
beauty of my daughter.
Father, please!
Unfortunately, I do not know the
painter you mentioned.
For a good supply,
you could spot it.
I would not know where to find him.
For a supply of 75,000 francs,
you can place an ad.
-150,000 would be an acceptable amount.
- Agree.
Be careful, though. I do not promise
success.
You will try, at least.
Let me give you a deposit.
It is not necessary.
If I find the painter, but ...
and it turns out to be a famous person
who paints under a pseudonym ...
he may not want to
use his name.
I do not care
what name he will paint.
As long as he is the one who made
the portrait that I liked so much.
-Good accounts are required.
-It should be done soon, though.
- I want to take him with me.
-I will do my best.
If I have good news, I will contact
you immediately, at Doukas.
We will be infinitely
grateful, Mrs Lamonte.
You're! Why didn't you come
through the front door?
If you paid, you could tell me
where to get my house from.
You have removed many of my
paintings in the past.
A small profit, I made.
Do you think that I'll continue to
let you live here?
I will pay you.
What; How much do you make
with puppets?
-I'll make it.
- Do not say nonsense.
I will make you a suggestion, though.
25,000 francs, if you accept.
-25,000 -I
may provide you with 30,000.
-With these I would make an amazing show!
-With dozens of puppets!
What is the proposal?
A rich South American
wants a portrait of his daughter.
I imagined it. No, I told you I
stopped painting.
And you can do it,
forever. After that!
Think about it, Gaston!
30,000 francs!
I'm thinking about it.
No, it is very dangerous!
Besides, I told you I would not
paint your girlfriend again!
But this is different.
It is a portrait. It is safe.
She will leave immediately, she is getting married!
And she will take him with her!
-It's a trap!
- Do you think I risked it again?
If there is no risk, why not
paint it in your studio?
In the workshop, above the
store. Makes me paint.
-Yes! So is!
Either there, or I do not paint it!
Okay, Gaston.
Paint it there.
The store will be surrounded.
Every exit will be guarded.
But how do we know that
Garon went to Lamonte?
We will signal. He will stand
at the window and light a cigar.
You know the window at the
back of the desk.
Have someone watch
the window, let us know.
Do not enter too soon, though.
Let him start, first.
We have to have something
on the canvas, for proof.
Persuade him to show you the background
he intends to use.
I will try. The signal will
mean that it has come and started.
I leave the choice of the
moment to you, Reno.
This means, however, that
you are also considered fully responsible.
He also stated that there should
be no visitors.
Not even you, sir. In order
not to risk denial, I accepted.
-Yes, but my daughter ...
-Don't worry about me.
Lamonte will not object
to staying here and smoking.
-Not at all.
-Very well.
But forgive me. I will lead
the lady to our painter.
The painter asked to be able
to work without you seeing him.
He is satisfied with this way.
The senorita has come!
-Are you ready;
- Absolutely.
I hope you are comfortable.
If you want anything ...
as long as you shout from
the communication pipe.
The artist feels the
rush and completely agrees.
Therefore,
I will not bother you anymore.
You better make me
the pose.
Better on your own. The
result will be more personal.
- You were not late.
- Not much, I hope.
-Was our painter ready?
-Started.
If you do not mind, let
us arrange our outstanding issues.
- I brought the amount you requested.
-The whole amount;
-150,000 francs.
-Nice. I will write you a receipt.
You will have made other paintings
besides that of the Duke.
Here you go;
I would like to see some
of your other paintings, I said.
Thanks. Higher
head, please.
Do you have a match?
-Cigar;
-Thanks, I do not smoke.
But I always have matches.
They often prove useful.
I have some antiques, back here,
if you want to see them.
But I would not want
to tempt prying eyes!
I put on a simple dress, to
put an interesting background on me.
I especially liked that one
in the portrait of Doukas.
- Are you doing the same to me?
-I could.
You did not light your cigar.
I smoke a lot lately. And
the statue caught my attention.
Then you would not mind going
to see how the table is progressing.
Please, go.
- I should not ...
- I will tell you when.
Straighten your shoulders!
Not so square!
I asked you to help me!
I am incapable of such a thing.
It can not be so difficult
to be yourself!
-What happens;
-Lusil's puppet!
-So you are the Cyanogon!
-Who said it;
Lamonte!
And do you believe what
Lamonte told you?
No!
How many more did you tell that I
made the Duke's paintings?
To nobody!
You are not telling me the truth.
And you try to leave secretly.
You blame me for that too!
I did not do
that!
You had arranged
the time, right?
You would have left here
as soon as they entered.
We will enter by force!
Warn others to have
their eyes on fourteen
Break it!
He is finished.
Hot, fast
Yes, his death will certainly
not help us at all!
-Where is Francine?
- He took her out there.
What about him now?
We are no closer to conception
than we were before.
Lamonte was the only one
we had to watch.
Unless I can figure out what
's going on with that necklace.
But I went around all the shops
in the city and nothing.
-The necktie?
-Yes, him.
-What happens;
- You say she used him?
Yes, as a stranglehold.
And do you think the owner
is the killer?
Most likely. If not, it will
lead us to the killer.
Lucille, I do not know
how to say that.
But you know how
I felt about Francine.
She was your sister.
Believe me, I would do what I
could. And for you.
Thanks.
-Now we have something in common, right?
-Yes.
- Better to go inside.
-Yes please
-My sincere condolences.
- Is this where I patched you?
- Very likely.
-And what happened to the stitches?
Maybe she's not.
I have many of the same.
-A lot;
-Half a dozen. Home, in the drawer.
- Where did you buy them?
- In a shop.
In Place de Glasse.
Why;
I was just wondering. It is a very
unusual fabric for a tie.
Yes, fragile.
-Will you have the kindness?
-Don't you want to go inside?
The living, I'm interested.
I came to mourn you.
-I have to see you. To pass;
-You are welcome.
-Where is the necktie?
-Who;
- The one I mandated to you.
- He ... I threw him.
-I would like to believe you!
- You spent a lot. Have a seat.
Let me
bring you something. A little brandy?
Nothing, thank you.
-Where were you last night?
-Here. I made the puppets.
-All night long;
- I went out for a while.
-To paint one?
- I said that I do not paint again!
I thought you just did not want
to paint me. Why;
What substance would I have to tell you?
Whatever I say, I do not believe it.
-Why;
- I had started to like you very much.
- Do you like me?
-Yes. But it was something more.
I felt like I was in love with you.
I really fell in love with you.
Why does this stop
you from painting me?
I want to tell you something
that no one else knows.
Then you may understand
how much I love you ...
and why I do not want
to paint you.
I was a very ambitious young man.
And terribly sensitive.
I almost starved
when I was studying Fine Arts.
I did not mind
physical hunger.
There was something inside me.
An ambition to paint
something that was really worth it!
Something great! I worked
feverishly at Borz Arts ..
but I did not seem
to be going anywhere.
I painted all the models
that came in there ...
but the paintings, one after the
other, came out ordinary.
And then, one night ...
As I was walking back to my attic, I
met a girl.
Collapsed.
I did not know what to do.
My attic was close,
so I carried it there.
I took care of her as best I
could. I had little money.
Just for the paints. He needed
food, otherwise he would have died.
Somehow, I was able to
provide her with what she needed.
Until one day, to pass
the time, I started painting it.
Janet Lampo.
That was her name.
Her fever-stricken
eyes had something spiritual.
Something that reminded me
of someone I had seen.
And then I realized that.
Oliya's Daughter!
I had seen her grave
and it inspired me.
Then I happened to sell
the painting to Lamonte.
Janet recovered until
one day, without a word ...
disappeared.
Until one night
Lamonte appeared in my attic.
He told me that the Academy
had awarded my painting.
It would be exhibited at the Louvre ...
I too would recommend
for the Legion of Honor.
My job,
at the Louvre!
I almost went crazy,
from my joy!
Of course, I wanted to share
my joy with Janet.
I looked for her,
I looked everywhere.
Eventually, I spotted her
through a dark man.
He gave me the address.
I went there.
Outside her door,
I heard laughter. Terrible laughs!
That was when
I really saw her.
He invited me inside.
It was not Janet herself.
This was the real Janet.
A cheap, hateful creature.
He offered me money.
He would consider that he could
repay me with money.
Suddenly, the sight of this
Janet did something to me!
Something that was
terribly outrageous.
I wanted it to stop staining
the image I had created.
To humiliate my work I
thought that would be the end of it all.
But not. Whenever I painted again,
I painted Janet.
I started making puppets
because they were made of wood.
When they became Janet, I could
vent my anger!
Puppets have no money.
Not enough for Lamonte.
And I owed him a
lot of money.
Only he knew
I had killed Janet.
So I had to paint
for Lamonte.
He wanted girls' paintings
that he could sell.
And when all my paintings
ended up in Janet ...
I could not allow it!
I could not stop!
Every time I painted it,
I had to kill it again!
After all, life meant
nothing to me. Not even mine.
And then I saw you.
In you, I knew that I found what
was missing from my existence.
What I thought I would find
in Janet and I did not find.
In you, I saw an
opportunity for completion.
I could not relive
my life, to deserve you.
I could not
recall my mistakes.
But I could have
avoided further mistakes.
That's why I decided to stop
painting, once and for all.
How for your sake, there should
be no more murders.
That's why I could
not paint you.
-You understand now;
-Yes...
Why Francine?
I did not want to kill her.
I accepted the last job,
because it would mean independence.
There was no possibility of error.
That's why I painted in Lamonte.
When I realized it was
your sister, it was too late.
I only saw that he was coming
between us, you and me.
It destroyed our only
chance for happiness.
Do you think you
can justify her murder?
Anyone who wants to destroy
our happiness is a threat.
A threat that must
come from the middle!
-What are you going to do;
- The only thing I can do.
-Are you thinking of going to the police!
-Why not;
- You would not do that.
-Truth;
You can not
do that to me! Not you, Lucille!
And if you could, I would not let
you turn against me!
Break the door!
Quickly
Stronger!
-How did you get here?
- I followed you.
When you looked at the necktie,
I realized you knew something.
Editing Subtitling
VIDEOPRESS SA