Louis? Louis?
- Beretti?
- Shh!
Put that out, you sap!
Don't you know no better than that?
- Hey, is this your hack?
This? Sure.
Well, what's your name?
Mine?
Joe Fleischer.
- Fleischer.
- Yeah.
Say, Cassidy.
Look up, uh, taxicab 67081-19.
And hustle it.
Let's go.
Let's go, Big.
- Everybody okay?
- Okay, Big.
- Nobody hit?
Nobody hit.
All right, Joe, step on it.
- Get under that elevated quick. Come on!
- We're all right, Louis.
- Louis.
- Here.
- How's tricks, Sal?
- Oh, tough.
- Yeah?
- I figure on usin' dishwater for soup tonight.
Yeah? Well, here's a buck.
Get yourself some ham and eggs.
- If you eat ham. Do you? Yeah, you do, all right.
- Oh, thanks.
It's all right.
Bighearted, huh?
- Well?
- Gee, you sure look swell in that makeup.
- Yeah?
- A regular working guy.
Aw, go on.
I'll sock you in the jaw.
Nobody'd wanna work
but a dumb guy, see?
- How is it, babe? All right?
- Swell.
So long.
- Hello, Mom.
- Luigi!
- Hello, Pop.
How are ya?
You're all right, Mom, huh?
Working so hard, my boy.
Sit down.
Yeah. Yeah, those bosses
think a truck driver ain't got no home.
Late delivery
over there in Greenpoint.
How about the old spaghetti?
- They make you work too much, those bosses.
- Yeah.
- They are drive-slavers.
- "Drive-slavers."
The old man.
Say, who's in there?
Rosita has a nice young man there.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay. Okay.
Louis, you know I don't paint.
You better not.
Who is this guy, Rosa?
I, uh-Well, you see,
Mr. Beretti, I'm-
I know, I know.
What are your intentions, fella?
Mr. Beretti,
my intentions are quite-
Okay. I can tell by lookin' at ya that
you don't mean nothing wrong.
How are you?
Oh, Louis.
My sister's a good girl, fella.
She'd better be.
I'm gonna take you down to the club
tonight after supper, fella.
I want you to meet my friends.
They're a great gang.
I'll send him back to you, Sis.
I'll close the door.
- Her first suitor.
- Her first.
He seems... okay.
- I come to see Rosa, Mrs. Beretti.
- Rosa?
Why, Rosa, she don't-
she don't- I don't-
Rosa ain't home.
- Oh, she ain't home, huh?
- No, she ain't.
And what's more,
she's never gonna be home... to you.
Well, you needn't get sore
about it, Louis.
- You're just in time, Louis.
- Okay?
- Okay. They're in Jersey by now.
Say, I got a guy out here
I want you fellas to meet.
I want you to give him the once-over.
He wants to marry my sister.
I'll bring him in.
All right, fella.
This guy's name is Banks.
Banks, meet the mob.
- Where'd you pick that up?
- None of your business.
That's a fine-lookin' mug you picked out
for a brother-in-law.
- You ever take a good look at yourself?
- She's a good girl- Rosa.
How much dough you got?
$826.71.
He's got it, even the 71 cents.
You'll be needin' some furniture.
- I know where I can pick up
a swell set of mission, cheap.
- Never mind.
Where you got the dough?
Court Square Trust Company.
That's a tough bank, all right.
- Isn't my money safe there?
- Too safe.
What do you say, boys?
Is he okay?
- Okay by me.
- Hey, Ritzy, what do you think?
Well, if he’s sap enough to get married,
it's okay, I guess.
Say, when it comes to your sister...
you're not strong for your own mob,
are you, Louis?
Meanin' yourself?
Any objections?
I've seen what's happened to dames
who hook up with guys like you.
Well, it ain't gonna happen to my sister.
Get that?
- Now, look here-
- Louis's right.
Come on, fella.
We'll go see Father McCann.
So long, four eyes.
Say, who are you callin' four eyes?
- Come here.
- Be a good boy.
- Okay.
- He's all right at that, huh?
He's got a little
rooster in him at that.
Come on, beau. So long.
I don't like to be called four eyes.
Okay, Charlie, my boy.
Okay.
- Hello, Louis.
- Hello, Good News. How are you?
What's your hurry?
Shoot. What is it this time, a rap?
Go on into the house, Charlie,
and tell Mom not to worry.
Tell her I'll be out late...
on business.
We're gonna take a little walk.
Hey, tell her I won't
be home at all tonight.
- Hello, Cardigan.
- Hello, Bill.
- Lookin' for a story?
- That's what I get paid for.
That's wrong.
That's what I get underpaid for.
You know about that mob that's been
raising Cain on the Lower East Side?
- Sure.
- Well, I got three of them tonight
in a jewelry robbery.
That's a frame-up.
I work for my livin'.
Yeah? What do you do?
I truck.
Let me look at your hand.
Never done a day's work in his life.
Let me look at yours.
No calluses on that hand either.
Now, you better frisk 'em.
Huh. Take a look at those, Bill.
Draft cards, huh?
- What are you gonna do with 'em, Cardigan?
- Up the river.
Listen, I'm gonna do you a great big favor
and grab a front-page spread for myself.
Yeah? What do you got on your mind?
Spit it out.
Let 'em go to war.
Great story.
Gangs-gunmen, see-
turned loose, given a chance to do their bit.
Patriotism, see?
Safe for democracy.
You're a Democrat,
aren't you? You are.
The primaries are
next month, aren't they?
They are.
"Cardigan for city court judge.
A real patriot."
Get me?
Mm-hmm. Hmm!
I was kinda thinkin'
about that myself.
I knew you were.
I'll quote you.
I'm gonna give you three guys the greatest
opportunity you ever had in your life.
You're tough guys. Gunmen.
You wanna shoot.
Well, I'm gonna give you a gun
and make soldiers out of you...
instead of lettin' you eat your head off
up there at Elmira.
Sort of probation.
I'm gonna keep this evidence in my safe...
for the duration of the war.
After it's all over,
you can come back and report to me.
If you've made good,
we'll tear up the complaints.
If you haven't,
you're gonna take the rap!
You get me?
- Are you kiddin' us, Cardigan?
- That's a great idea, Chief.
Why, fighting's their racket.
You let these three guys go to France...
and the whole East Side
will be proud of them.
Here's your cards.
I envy you men...
this opportunity
of fighting for the right.
- You're better men than I am.
- Gunga Din.
- Okay, Chief.
- Okay, let 'em go.
Wait a minute.
I knew there was
a catch in it somewhere.
- You'll need that to get you up in the army.
Fall in! Hold your heads up!
Throw that butt away!
Put your heels together!
Now, Sergeant,
don't you think it would be more advisable-
Now, just a moment, sir.
Please let us handle this...
or you’ll have it all balled up.
- Hey, what's your line, fella?
- Ballplayer.
Send him to noncom school.
- How about you?
- Lightweight.
- Thug, huh?
- No- iceman.
Garbage detail.
Sergeant, I'm a certified
public accountant.
I hold two degrees in accountancy.
I've done expert work
for some of the biggest firms in the country.
Just now I'm employed by Whiting-Small,
a mail-order house.
Don't know if I can be of any use to you
around here, but if you need a good C.P.A. -
Horseshoer.
What are you?
Irish.
Give him a gun. What do you do, buddy?
I don't do anything.
I go to college.
How about sending him
to noncom school?
Ah, them guys don't know nothin'.
Say, you gotta watch those things, Sarge.
You know?
Hey, what's your line, feller?
Me?
I'm in the jewelry business.
Well, how would you like to dig toils
with the latrine squad?
Well, yes and no.
What do you do?
I'm a burglar.
Hey, Sarge,
that's just the guy you're lookin' for.
Hey, Sarge, just the guy
you're lookin' for!
Hey, Sarge,
he's just the guy you're lookin' for!
Hey, Corporal,
just the guy you're lookin' for.!
Attention.! Attention.!
- All you men, get in line up there!
- Well, Frank, my boy.
- Hey, doc, you got a match?
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
And, uh, don't ever ask any of those officers
with gold bars for a match.
- They'll have you shot.
- Okay, doc.
Frank, my boy...
I came down here looking for you.
Brought your sister with me too.
What is the meaning of this?
Why aren't you at Plattsburg?
Well, I thought I'd do
better in this business as a private.
Oh, think of your family, my boy.
You belong to-
I don't wanna be a hero.
If it's ever curtains for anyone around me...
I don't wanna have
any responsibility.
I'm sorry I can't
have you along with me.
Frank, aren't you going
to speak to me?
Jo! What are you doin' down here, monkey?
Hello, Uncle Jim.
Oh, I want you to meet
my friend Louis Beretti.
Louis and I have decided
that we're gonna be buddies.
How do you do, young man?
How do you do?
Oh- How are you?
Jo, I want you to meet Louis too.
Louis, this is my sister Joan.
She's a great girl, but she's kind of fond
of herself.
Pleased- Pardon me, doc.
- Pleased to meet you.
- How do you do, Mr. Beretti?
I hope Frank can bring you down to see us
whenever they let you off.
So do I.
I'm sure you'll both be captains before
it's over over there.
Well, he's made
a good start already.
- You're right, General.
- Thanks, thanks.
All these men offering
themselves to their country.
They've come from
the highways and the byways...
the machine shop and the store.
They've dropped
the plowshare for the sword.
It's upon the lives
of such men as these...
that our country must rely...
to bare their open, manly breasts...
to the beast that is ravishing
the motherland.
Somebody swiped my watch!
All right, pick up your bags.
Hold up your heads!
Pull in your chins and your bellies!
Squads, right!
Ho!
One, two, three, four.!
I told 'em I was a burglar.
- Look what they give me.
- Hut, two, three, four.
Hut, two, three, four.
- Oh!
- How many times have I told you-
- Hey.!
Hey, you lop-eared,
screw-eyed sons of-
Oh, excuse me, Father.
I didn't know you was the umpire.
Hey, why don't youse guys make home plate
that manure pile and bat the other way?
- Do you wanna kill somebody?
- Aw, go wash your face.!
- Come on!
- Let's beat it!
- What is it, a German?
- Here.
You mule-eared, dog-faced...
son of a pop-eyed-
That general can swear
as good as I can.
Big Shot just sent us over
another bunch of cigarettes from home.
I guess he must've been
robbing a warehouse.
Well, I hope they don't catch him
before the war's over.
Oh, uh...
you heard from your sister lately?
Yeah.
She sent me this.
Nice fit, isn't it?
Yeah. Well, I got a postal card
from her myself.
Hey, you've told me about that postal card
about 50 times.
Why don't you have it
framed or something?
I think maybe I will.
Yeah, and hang it on the fireplace
under your crossed "spoys."
Your spoys.
You know, your spoys.
- Spoys.
- Oh!
- You mean my spoys?
- Yeah, that's it.
I think I'll-Well, well!
Hello, Cheri, old girl.
How are ya?
- Bonjour, monsieur.
- Bonjour.
Hey, Cheri, get a load of that.
Papa!
"Papa, sugar." Say, listen.
I'll tell you what I want you to do.
I want you to get me three or four bottles
of your best grape.
You know, grape.
Grape. Look.
- See?
- Moi?
Flatterer.
Nice girl, full of good, clean fun.
Come on.
Let's have the wine, huh, baby? Come on.
- Come on?
- Yeah, come on. Get it.
Huh? No, look, look.
Wine, wine. Grape.
You know, look.
Mmm!
- She don't need Papa now.
- Marie?
M-Oh!
Hey, I thought you was a sergeant.
Where's your stripes?
Who handed me that bat?
Get a load of that.
See that?
- Ooh!
- There.
Yeah, see?
Now, listen.
You, me-
- Huh?
- For that?
- Yeah.
- Oh, no, no.
- Hey, come, come.
- Come, come.
- Oh.
That's the price in Bar-le-Duc.
Say, wait a minute.
There.
Now, how about that?
No.
- No?
- Non.
Oh, baby, you're tough.
- There.
- Ooh!
Those are Paris prices, baby.
C'est très cher.
Share it with me, little froggie.
Come here, baby.
Oh, Sherman was wrong.
- Come on.! Let's go.!
Louis Beretti reporting, sir.
- Hello, Beretti. How are ya?
- Hello there, O'Brien.
- Glad to see you.
- Judge.
You oughta remember Louis Beretti.
You know, that jewelry job.
You oughta remember what that red,
white and blue whiskey did for you.
Sure. Cut out your kiddin', Bill.
Glad to see you, Beretti.
- Glad to see you, Judge.
- But wasn't there three of you?
- Yeah.
- The red, white and blue.
I'm reporting
for Gibbons and Donley too.
What became of Gibbons?
On the Rhine.
Army of Occupation.
And Donley?
Bumped off in the Argonne.
The spirit of patriotism, Beretti.
The spirit of patriotism.
- When you were standing in the mud of Flanders-
- In the Argonne.
Of the Argonne,
we were beside you...
trudging forward step by step...
while you vanquished a stubborn foe.
Oh!
Were you there too, Judge?
In spirit only.
In spirit.
Anyway, I'm glad you're back
and squared your account...
and I hope you'll
always keep it that way.
Yeah, well, I'm, uh,
I'm goin' into business now myself.
- Jewelry?
- No, no, no. Something respectable.
- Splendid!
- Oh, uh-
Oh, Judge, I, uh-
You-
- Hey, get these guys back, will ya?
- You're all right, Louis.
- Sure.
- Back in your old neighborhood.
- Hello there, Mike.
- How are ya? How's the veterinary?
- Great.
Hello, Joe. How are ya?
How's Big Kate?
Same as ever, and some cook.
- Hey, Judge, you, uh-you know Donley?
- Yes.
Well, uh, you know,
he didn't have no folks, see?
And he was kind of dragged up in
an orphanage and that kind of stuff.
And, well, I was with him
in the hospital...
before, uh- before he bumped off.
He said,
"Louis, give these to Cardigan."
Luigi. Luigi.
- Papa.
- Luigi.
Hey, Ma.
Look, I brought you some flowers.
Oh, by Garibaldi...
what a fine soldier he is, eh?
Look, Mama. Look. See?
What I tell you?
Don't I tell you Luigi win the war?
Hey, wait a minute. Wait a minute, Pop.
I didn't win the whole war.
There was a couple
of other guys fightin'.
Listen to him, Mama.
Just like his papa.
Luigi, a fight, she never stop...
until a Beretti steps in.
Hey, Pop, wait a minute.
Look what I brought you.
- For me, huh?
- Nothin' else.
Oh.
Hey, Ma, where's Rosa?
- Louis.
- Rosina!
Rosina.
Hey, wait'll you see
what I brought you.
Hey, what's the big idea?
You're wearing mourning
'cause I come home again?
That's a fine way
to mee-
Say, Rosa, what's wrong?
What's happened?
Where's Charlie?
Rosa's baby...
got no papa now.
Gee.
Gee, that's tough.
Poor kid.
It's tough to lose your man.
One of the toughest things
in the world, I guess.
Ah, there, there, now.
Don't-
Don't worry, kid.
I'll take care of you,
and I'll take care of the little one too.
Now, now, don't worry.
Don't worry. Poor kid.
What was it?
What happened?
It was a robbery.
Charlie had the payroll
of the-
Killed?
Who did it? Who killed him?
Who did it?
No, no, Louis.
That won't bring Charlie back.
- You know who it was. Now, tell me.
- No, Louis, I don't.
- Come on. You must know who it was.
- No, Louis, no.
- I don't. Even if I did, I wouldn't tell!
- You know who it was. Tell me!
- What was his name?
Oh, no, Louis. No, no.
I know what you'll do.
More killing, more trouble.
Prison.
Oh, I don't wanna lose
anyone else that I love, Louis.
Rosa is right, my dear.
Oh, let us thank God
that you came back safe.
That's all right
about me coming back.
But while I'm away, a rat sneaks into my home
and kills one of my family.
Am I gonna let him
get away with that?
Am I gonna stand for a rat
making a mug out of me?
- Come on, now. You know who it was.
- No, Louis, I can't!
Tell me, you hear me?
I swear it, Louis!
I swear it!
I'll find him.
I swear it.
If it takes me all my life,
I'll find him.
And when I do-
Funny thing.
Sometimes, I got to feelin'
like he was my own brother.
And then for him to get it like that.
A game guy like him.
I think Frank would like to have heard you
call him that-a game kid.
Oh, I never did fall
for that hero bunk.
But there's some guys you'd go the whole way for,
others you wouldn't.
Well, Frank was the kind of a guy
you'd go the limit for.
Just as he-
Just as he was-
Just as he was... leaving...
he told me to tell you...
that he did his best to-
to win his spoys.
Well, if he didn't,
I don't know who did.
- Yeah.
- I'm glad you were there, Louis.
Then he said, uh...
if you ever needed anybody...
you could call on me.
I will.
I'll always remember what Frank called you-
a great guy.
Well, I'm not.
But I've always-
I've always wanted to be
a-a great guy.
You know, Joan...
I could try to be a great guy...
if you could see-
Oh, Dick.
You're just in time to meet Louis Beretti.
Louis, this is Dick Milburn.
I've told you all about Louis.
- He and Frank were chums.
They were together when-
- I know, dear.
- Glad to know you, Beretti.
- Glad to meet you, sir.
You'll stay to dinner with Dick and me?
That is, if you don't mind Dick.
He's going to be my- my husband.
Aren't you?
Thanks, Joan,
but l-I, uh- I can't stay to dinner.
- Yes, you can.
- No, l-I can't. You see, l-
Well, l-I can't.
- Do you mind if I have another cigarette?
- No.
Well, old man, if you really have to beat it,
I'll run you down to the station.
No, thanks.
I'd-I'd rather walk.
You see, I got so used to walking in the army
that I kind of like it.
- Now, Louis Beretti, you're not going-
- Now, now, Joan.
So long. Lots of luck to you.
So long, Joan.
If you ever need anybody,
why, look me up.
Good-bye. So long.
Good luck.
Bye.
Hello, Needle, old boy.
How have you been? Full house.
Lot of important people out there.
They workin' you hard?
I've walked about 10 miles behind this bar today.
Take a peek at them dogs.
- They're swelterin'.
- Dancin' pumps. You know what they oughta-
They oughta get dust boards back there
for you guys to walk on.
Let me have a little shot.
Louis's bottle right behind you there.
- First today.
- Old Taylor, Needle.
Okay.
Everything's on the Old "Taylorino."
That's right, Bill, plenty of water.
- That stuff'll burn your guts out.
- Yep.
Doctor told me that one time. Never drink
it straight. Always put something in it.
Listen, I knew a guy once that went to one
of those temperance lectures uptown.
You know, that tells you about all that booze
does to your insides.
Hobnails on your liver
and "very close" veins.
Well, he went on a buttermilk diet.
And what do you think
happened to him?
In three weeks, the guy is dead.
- No!
- Yes, sir.
Run over by a streetcar.
Hi, Needle, old boy.
How 'bout a shot?
Listen, nix on the booze.
The main gee just called up.
He wants you fellas downtown right away.
So you'd better screw.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yes, sir.
Okay!
What's up, Needle?
The boys are havin'
a little party down there.
The main gee
is goin' to the "cansky" in the morning.
- I heard about it.
- Hello, Needle.
- How are ya?
- How about a brandy and soda?
Nix on the "bransky."
You better get goin' downtown.
The main gee just called up,
and you better hustle.
Hello, Moe.
- Oh, Sir Maurice.
- How do you do, Miss, uh-
Sir Maurice,
may I present some of my friends?
I'd be delighted, I'm sure.
This is Sir Maurice Mos-
...cowitz.
Sir Maurice Moscovich.
Sir Maurice was with me in the taxi
that night when I lost my diamonds.
Oh, yes, very valuable
and beautiful diamonds.
- Oh, but you were so kind and helpful.
- Oh, not at all.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
really, I must push along now.
- May I call sometime?
- Oh, please do. I should be delighted.
- Well, good-bye.
- Good-bye.
- Au revoir.
Charming chap. Very fine family.
Real nobility, you know.
All that sort of thing.
Oh, uh, a slug of gin.
- How are ya?
- Louis Beretti!
Sit down, fellas.
Sit down. It's all right.
I'm so glad I know you, Louis.
It's much easier to get into the social register
than into your place.
Well, there's always a table
for you, Mrs. Milburn.
"Mrs. Milburn."
May I call you Mr. Beretti, Louis?
Sure, Joan.
Oh, this is Louis Beretti, our host.
- Mr. And Mrs. Fairfield.
- How do you do?
- How are you, old man?
- You remember Dick.
- Sure.
- How are you, Beretti?
- Hiya, skipper.
Louis and I are old friends,
although I always have a hard time...
making him ask me to dance.
Well, you see, I've been too busy to dance.
I've almost forgotten how.
- I don't believe that.
Well, uh, would you-
- would you care to have a little drag with me?
- Certainly.
- Hello, Big.
- Hello, Sally.
- Gettin' fat, aren't ya?
- Eatin' regular.
How about your hat?
Is your head cold?
- Never mind.
- Okay.
What's on your mind, Big?
Got to take the rap.
You what-
You didn't beat that case?
Gee.
I never thought they'd put you
behind the bars.
- I'm sorry, Big.
- The appeal was denied.
Yeah. Brophy's case was too tight.
Beats me how he had everything lined up
in court the way he did-
the cars, the witnesses, the fence.
Yeah, witnesses to everything.
- Say, he ain't smart enough-
- Good-night, Louis.
- Night.
- To figure things out for himself...
without somebody rattin'.
You think somebody
turned you in, Big?
Sure, and I think I know who it is.
Yeah?
My bail bond's up tomorrow.
You know, Louis,
I'd like to see your old lady...
before I go away.
Sure, Big. Sure.
Hey, Sally,
bring me my benny and lid.
Come on.
I'll go along with you.
Hey, uh, Pete. Wait here.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Okay.
- How's business?
- Oh, fine. Everything's going okay.
You be in the inspector's office at 9:00
in the morning and tell him what you know.
- Do you understand?
- All right, Good News.
- I'll be there.
- You'd better be.
What's the meeting for?
What's happening tonight?
Big Shot wants to tell us something
before he goes up the river tomorrow.
Well, what's he bothering about?
After tomorrow...
somebody else will be giving orders.
Not meaning yourself, old fellow?
And why not?
Big Shot will be up the river.
I'll be sending him cigarettes.
Thanks, Ritzy.
I might need 'em.
Oh, hello, Big Shot.
I was just talking about you.
How's the uptown joint going, Louis?
Great.
Full up every night.
- Fine. Get me a table, will you?
- Sure.
Call up to my place and have Bugs reserve
a table for Ritzy Reilly.
- Okay.
- I got a date with a little blonde.
One of those young things from upstate.
She thinks I'm going to marry her.
Well, that's good.
Yeah, that's good.
Yeah, table in the corner for Ritzy Reilly.
Yeah, Louis says it's okay.
It's a pip, ain't it?
She's up in her flat now packing.
I just left her at the door a moment ago
while I came up here.
Well, it's too bad we didn't get around
a little sooner.
I always like to take a look at the blondes
you travel around with.
What are you doin',
spillin' your guts to her?
- Shut up, Joe!
- No, Ritzy's too smart for that.
He knows enough not to take her down
to Atlantic City...
after that jam he got in with a little redhead
down there.
How did you beat that rap?
What are you guys doing,
giving me the third degree?
- How did you beat that rap?
- Oh, shut up.
How did you beat that rap?
She swore she was my niece.
That's how I beat it.
Brophy took her down to
the D.A.'s office, and she-
Oh, Brophy took her.
- Yeah.
- So that's how Brophy got ya.
Made you turn stool pigeon...
so you wouldn't have to serve a few months
in the can.
Double-crossed your own mob, huh?
Turned in Big to save
your own rotten hide.
Say, this room ain't big enough for both of us.
This town ain't big enough.
So if you ever bump into me,
you better see me first...
ya dirty, sneakin' rat!
That guy's getting high-hat ever since he got
that new joint uptown.
Scram, you guys!
Well, cheerio, Ritzy old boy.
So long, old fellow.
Well, you never can tell
when a pal's gonna turn you down.
No, you never can.
Give me a cigarette, will you?
No.
Well, that's that.
Wait a minute!
I got something to settle with you
before I go up the river.
Well, make it snappy, will ya?
I've got a date.
- The date'll have to wait.
- Not if I can help it.
Maybe you can't.
You ratted, didn't you?
What if I did?
You're so smart,
aren't you, Mr. Big Shot?
Well, when you'll be doing a stretch,
I'll be running around uptown...
doing plenty good for myself.
I don't need you anymore.
I was all washed up with you anyway.
I ain't goin' away leavin' a rat
runnin' around loose.
Just try and stop me.
And give my regards to the warden.
Go on.
Get in there.
Go on. Get in there,
you guys. Go on!
All right, Big, quick.
You didn't have to do that.
You go in too quick for that stuff.
I told you 20 times
you don't have to croak nobody.
It was comin' to him.
He didn't keep his nose clean.
Aw, I always liked that guy...
ever since we was kids.
- You didn't have to do that.
- I liked him too, Louis.
But you know what's got to happen to a guy
when he doesn't keep his nose clean.
Come on.
Let's go up and see Mama.
- Hello, "mamina." How are you?
- Ooh.!
Look who I brought here to see ya.
Hello, my baby. How are ya?
Look who's here.
- Hiya, Pop.
- Come on. Sit down here by the fire.
How are you?
Sit down, okay?
- Big's leaving town tomorrow for his health.
- Huh?
Your health not good?
The "rheumatiz," huh?
You know what's good for him?
You take the raw potato...
and put him in the back pocket.
In one month,
the rheumatiz, she's gone...
and the potato, she's a rock.
Tell me, Big.
Not the- cough?
Wait a minute.
I got just what you need.
Oh, I'll be all right, Pop.
- Too long I don't see you, "mamina."
- Oh.
Too busy to kissing the hand
of the young girls.
- So you now kissing my hand.
- No, "mamina."
- No.
- What time is it, Ma?
Why, it's...
9:15.
- I thought it was more than that.
- Ah, here it is.
I got just the good thing
for the cough.
Grease of the goose.
I'll be all right, Pop.
"Be all right. All right."
Everybody say "All right."
Then they cough-
Then by and by, the croup come in.
You guys'll be here when I get back?
Sure.
Yeah. That's what I thought.
Didn't I see you two fellas
at the Yale-Princeton game?
No!
I thought I recognized the coats.
Hello, Louis.
- Hello, Good News. How are you?
- Hello.
- Have an apple.
- No, thanks. How are ya, Mrs. Beretti?
- Just dropped in to see the old folks.
- A cigar.
- A cigar, Mr. Brophy.
- Oh, thanks.
- One of Pop's best.
- You don't smoke 'em, do you?
You think I'm crazy?
Well, Good News, what's the big idea?
Oh, just passing by.
Just passing by.
- Good.
- You fellas been here long?
Oh, a half,
three quarters of an hour.
What time did they come in,
Mrs. Beretti?
- A quarter past 9:00.
- A quarter past 9:00?
- Sure.
- Are you sure?
Oh, sure I'm sure.
Didn't Luigi ask me the time,
and didn't I look at the clock?
Sure, I'm sure.
He asked you, did he?
You guys are gettin' to be
a couple of champion clock watchers.
- Well, what's the difference?
- Hello, Rose.
Hello, Mr. Brophy.
Hey, uh, we were just leavin'.
- Goin' our way?
- Yeah, sure.
Good-bye, Rose.
What's the good news
this time, Brophy?
Well, I got a shock for you guys.
Ritzy Reilly was plugged a few minutes ago...
in the back.
No!
Gee.
- He was my pal.
- Bumped off? That's tough.
One of the old mob too.
According to the clock
and Ma Beretti...
you guys were upstairs
when Ritzy was killed.
You know, someday,
you're gonna run out of alibis.
- Well, you don't ever think that I'd-
- You'd do anything.
But you're different, Louis.
Why, you got a great war record.
Your joint uptown,
it's making plenty of dough.
Why don't you shake this mob before they get you
in a jam that'll mean the chair?
I'm all through with that,
Good News.
Except Big. I'll never ditch a guy
I've been pals with all my life...
that I went to school with.
Ritzy went to school with him too, didn't he?
So did I.
You can't beat old John Law,
Louis, all your life.
Think that over.
He'll have plenty of time
to do his thinking...
up the river.
- How's the old lady, Louis? Okay?
Aw, she's great.
Say, we're havin' supper with her tonight.
You know that, don't you? Spaghetti,
plenty of vino.
Hey, now, don't forget.
You just come back from the old country.
Yeah, my granite castle
on the river.
- Tough joint?
- I've been in easier.
But they won't put me in there again.
They'll bump me off first.
- Aw, it's a sucker's game, Big.
You can't beat it.
Now, I'm makin' a lot of dough. Why don't you
come over to my joint and take a cut?
Nah. You stick to your racket, Louis.
I'll stick to mine.
You ain't got a chance, Big.
Good News is on the gang's tail every minute.
- They can't move.
- Brophy'll never lay a finger on 'em again.
What they need is a leader,
and I'm plannin' somethin' big for 'em.
- Very big.
- Okay.
But you're welcome to come in with me
at any time.
- You know that, don't you?
- I know it, Louis.
Thanks.
Tough on the mother, all right.
Yeggs that do a thing like that
oughta be lynched.
Stealin' a kid.
I'm a peaceful man...
but I wouldn't mind
helping string them up myself.
Beacon-4000.
Give me a quick shot, will you, Needle?
- Louis's bottle.
- Okay.
City desk.
O'Brien talking.
Listen, I got a lead on that lost society baby.
Yeah, I trailed a car
down to Jamaica Bay.
You know, those low marshlands.
Oh, sure, you do,
where all those fishing boathouses are.
I tipped off the local cops.
They're spreadin' a net around.
- So long, Louis.
- So long, Big.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Okay.
Nothing will break on it
before morning.
No, this isn't a hunch.
It's a real lead.
I'm gonna stay on it all night.
Well, I'm in a drugstore
in Jamaica right now.
Call me back
if you don't believe me.
Good night.
- Sounds like you got a big story there, Bill.
- I have.
- Seen the duke lately, Louis?
- Say, listen.
If I see that duke again,
I'll punch him in the nose.
There was a dame
around here a little while ago.
Heard she was a duchess.
She was raisin' the dickens.
Hey, boss, your sister is out here...
and she wants to see you right away.
- Rosa?
- Yeah.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
- Wait here for me, Bill.
- Sure.
Louis.!
Hey, what's the matter, Rosa?
What's-
Joan. Hey, what's this all about?
Oh, Louis, it's so terrible.
Poor Mrs. Milburn.
Her baby!
- Nobody but a beast could-
- Now, take it easy, kid. Take it easy.
- What's wrong, Joan?
- Oh, Louis, my baby's gone.
Stolen!
- Your-Your baby?
- Louis, l-
You mean that little-
- So that's what they was talking about.
- Oh, Louis, I'm frantic.
Dick's still in Europe.
The police tell me to wait, wait.
My baby's gone.
How can I wait, Louis?
Once you told me if I ever needed anyone
to help me, to come to you.
Well, Louis, I need you now.
Sure. Sure, Joan.
I'll help you. I'll help you.
I thought you might-
you might know people who could tell you.
I don't care what it costs.
Anything. Anything!
Ah, now, don't worry.
It'll be all right, I tell ya.
- It's gonna be all right.
- Thank you.
- Take her up to my office. Now, don't worry.
- I knew you'd do it.
It's a cinch. It'll be all right.
Sure, sure.
Give me that gat, Joe.
Give me that gat!
Bill, I want you
to take me down to Jamaica.
You know, that place
you tailed that car to.
Wait a minute, Louis.
I didn't tell my city editor everything...
but I'm gonna tell you.
It may make a difference.
You might wanna keep out of this.
Huh?
What do you mean?
That car that I trailed to Jamaica,
I followed it back here...
right out to the front door.
It was Joe’s hack.
Joe was the guy that was driving it.
Stay out of this, Louis.
Don't be a chump and get yourself jammed up.
You're doin' all right now.
Give me an extra clip.
Give me an extra clip!
Come on, Bill.
Hey, Needle, give me a pint of scotch, will ya?
I may need it.
Hurry.
Right off the ship.
Hey, Bill. Wait here.
I'll be right back.
- Watch yourself, Louis.
- Okay.
Stick 'em up!
Louis.
Good mornin', Sir Maurice.
So this is the place you were gonna bring
that dame to, huh?
Your country estate.
Oh, I say, Louis, don't rag a chap.
Look, you know what women are.
What the heck-
Oh, it's just-just-just a doll I've been making
for the nipper.
What are you doin' down here, Louis?
Me? Plenty.
A couple of fine rats
you guys turned out to be.
Stealin' a kid!
Why didn't you come to me
if you was broke...
instead of pullin'
a lousy trick like this?
We couldn't help it, Louis.
I told Big-
Aw, shut up!
Where's the kid now?
- Is she okay?
- Oh, sure. She's asleep.
Go get her.
- Does Big know that you're comin' down here?
- Shut up!
Careful now.
All right.
Take her outside and give her to O'Brien.
- He's waitin' out there.
- Please let me go home. I wanna see Mommy.
Sure, sure, kid.
You're goin' right home to your mama now.
All right,
now I'm gonna let you guys go clear.
But I oughta put a couple of slugs
into both of ya.
So don't try to pull anything.
Get me?
All right, get out.
Look out, Louis, for Joe.
Hey, Bill,
take the kid from these rats.
Okay, Louis.
- Come on out of there, Joe.
I can see it was you
who promoted this lousy trick.
It would take a yellowbelly
like you to think of it.
Well, the kid's gone.
You can't get her back without finishing me...
and you ain't got
the guts to do that.
- I ain't, huh?
- No, you ain't.
Well, I had enough guts to bump off
that four-eyed husband of Rosa's, didn't I?
- You did that?
- Yeah, I did it, and I got
enough guts to bump you off too!
Think you're pretty swell, huh? Givin' up
your own mob because you got a new-
Hello?
Oh, hello, Big.
Sure.
Everything's okay here.
The kid's gone back...
to her mother.
I sent her.
Yeah.
Louis.
Louis Beretti.
So you couldn't keep
your nose clean.
I'll be waiting for you...
at your joint.
- Hello, Joe.
- How are ya?
You're stayin' up
pretty late, ain't ya?
Waitin' for Louis
to take the damper.
No, you'd better
give me some seltzer.
Okay.
Well, I think I'll beat it, Needle.
- Okay?
- Go ahead.
Good night.
- Good night, Big.
- Good night.
Good night.
- Any news in the paper, Joe?
- Lots of news.
- Hello, Louis.
- Hello, Big.
Out kind of early, ain't ya?
Yeah. You too.
Yeah.
What's on your mind, Big?
I guess you know.
Yeah.
How's your old lady, Louis?
It's been a long time
since I seen her.
Too long, I guess.
She's okay.
She always did a guy good.
Yeah.
She's been just like a mother to me.
The only one I ever knew.
Sure.
I remember when
we was kids together.
The time I got
that slug in the shoulder.
All the other kids run away.
Yeah.
It was you who took me
to the hospital.
You used to be a good guy, Louis.
Yeah.
It's tough.
Too bad you couldn't
keep your nose clean.
Yeah.
Too bad.
I'm tired, Louis.
I'm gonna hit the hay.
- So long, Louis.
- Okay.
So long, Big.
- So long, Joe.
Did he get you, Louis, bad?
I'm okay.
You'd better phone Brophy.
- He'll wanna talk to me about this.
- Hello, Louis.
Hello, Bill.
Where's the kid?
Safe and sound,
back with its mother.
What's wrong with you, Louis?
Nothin', nothin'.
You've been plugged.
Who did it?
A guy who-
who didn't think
I kept my nose clean.
But he-
he never knew what it-
what it really meant.
L-
I just found out...
myself.
I think I'll go home.
He'll be all right.
Get him a drink, quick. Hustle!
Get me one too.
Hey, Joe?
Louis's bottle.