Downloaded from
yts.Mx
Official yify movies site:
- Will you brats keep quiet?
How do you expect me to concentrate?
- Well, oliver won't let
me play with my blocks.
- Will you leave stanley
alone and play quietly?
- Certainly, if you must make
a noise, make it quietly.
- Make a noise quietly.
Give me those.
- Ooh!
- Oh!
Now listen, if you don't keep quiet,
You'll have to go to bed.
- Yes, we'll have to go to bed.
- Not we, the kids.
Now keep quiet.
- Let's play hide and seek.
- You're it.
- No, you're it.
- I don't want to be it.
- That's enough, get to bed.
- Yes, get to bed.
- Go ahead.
- You see, if you had been it,
We wouldn't have to go to bed.
- Boys will be boys.
- Blood's thicker than water.
Come on.
- Oh.
- Oh!
- Oliver, will you stop throwing things?
- Oh, oh!
- If you brats don't get to
bed, i'll break your necks.
- Sh, don't talk to 'em like that.
Treat them with kindness,
you'll get more out of them.
Remember the old adage, you
can lead a horse to water,
But a pencil must be led.
- I guess you are right.
Now listen, the first
one undressed and to bed
Gets that nickel.
Goodbye.
- See?
See what a little bit of kindness will do?
- You're right, a little
kindness goes a long way.
- Have a marshmallow?
- Shoot that ball.
- It's my break.
- It's my break, you went in the pocket.
- Let's get him.
- Why don't you do something to help me?
Oh.
- Now, who's making all this noise?
- He hit me.
- I did not.
He hit me.
- Why is it, when your mother's home,
You always go to sleep?
- Mama always sings us to sleep.
- If i'll sing to you,
will you go to sleep?
Now lie down, and i'll sing for you.
- Lay down.
- Will you go to sleep?
- Can i have a drink of water?
- Me too!
- If i give you a drink of
water, will you go to sleep?
Just a moment.
You might spill it.