I Miss Christian!
And well, Miss Christian...
- ... we are waiting
for you, Miss Christian.
-Sorry, I have not
heard the question.
-What? -I have
Not heard the question.
Yes, I see.
-You have not heard the
question, right? -Yes, dad.
-What? -Yes, Mr. Christian.
Very well. Now it seems
that we will get somewhere.
Miss Christian, espéreme in the
hallway, at the end of the class.
Tomorrow we will submit a work,
on the subject "the duties of
The citizen to the government",
the Church, the School, the
parents, the community...
"and the local police."
I feel me angry, Candy. Oh forgive me!
Sure, dad!
You must think I'm a little weird...
and a dad very rare and
plated to the old one.
- Huh?
- Just a little! -Many thanks.
-Dad, I... -No, I have already
understood. You don't have to say anything.
I know what you mean. I don't
need to explain anything.
I know as I called students to my back.
No one says anything about
you behind your back, dad.
That is precisely what I say.
All the other teachers of
the School I nicknames;
But to me just call me Mr. Christian.
Oh, don't take it as well! All
of them landing very well.
- What is the truth?
- Of Course.
Believe that you are a prof very nice.
Thank you, sweetie.
Oh, that makes me feel good!
O my daughter, I'm glad we had this talk!
A girl and her father must be good friends,
- ... like us. -Oh, dad!
What do I do!
-Hello!
- Oh, Excuse Me, Mr. Christian! What happens, Harold?
I just came to tell Candy that is given
in a hurry. You will be late. Come on!
Is a good boy!
Always. And a good student.
-Oh, Dad, I have to leave!
-You see to often, right?
I just want to be sure that you
will not make any madness.
-I have to go. -Very well. Then
we will have a talk from man to man.
-Very well.
- Will you come to my Sociology class of the 5?
-We'll see you there. -Very well.
-But, what's wrong with you?
It Mac Phisto!
What Mac Phisto?
"The life that burns and bleeds,"
"in my triumph days sieved sleep,"
"in that I towered brilliantly,"
in the dream sustained...
"the vision of an eagle...
"that transports us
between the knobbly pores,
"that surround our meat, clean words,
"and that throws its
cry bitter and nameless,
"as a scream for ice cream,"
"shaken with passion by a wind,"
"in which my weariness is rampant,"
"overflowing with this liquid..."
"of my lust."
The poem that I just
recited was composed...
in a hospital in Burma,
in which lay, near death,
after you have been savagely attacked...
by a rampant horde of belgian tourists.
You can find this poem in my
collection of verses entitled:
"Forests of meat".
Here has not been published yet,
but you can find a private edition,
signed personally by
its author, which is me,
$ 3,
cash or by transfer...
Mac-Phisto,
Po Box 2723,
Lemington,
New Jersey.
Mac Phisto, Po Box 2723.
Lemington. New Jersey.
I would like to express my
gratitude to the Rolling Stones,
I say, Rolling...
the Rolling Fields Center,
and the student Council
supervisor of this School
who had the courage...
and, I would say, the intelligence...
invited me here.
As you know, my work has been banned...
and my books burned in 27 countries
are already consolidated...
and 14 emerging nations. -I'd
like to see him at once. Me.
"Why what are you afraid of me?"
should one ask.
Why?
Because exult the virtue,
the beauty, the magic...
and the supreme and ineffable desire...
ecstasy of the human spirit.
Or Dulcis Imperatrix!
()
I mean that's what it is!
My poems have the innocence of
the young and innocent children,
as only children can
understand the freedom...
and the virtue of giving one's
self without restrictions,
without inhibitions and without shame.
And I wonder...
how many people here have the
gift of being able to sacrifice.
I think that perhaps some of you;
Ten or twenty,
three or four.
Perhaps...
only one.
Miss Quimby, who exactly
is that Mac Phisto?
Do not know You, who is Mac Phisto?
I'm surprised You Mr. Christian!
Do not read You poetry?
I don't have time for poetry. I
teach Sociology, not Humanities.
Because it is one of the most celebrated
poets of the TWENTIETH century.
I've devoured mountains;
I eat the Sky and drink the Ocean,
until I have become the Universe.
The Universe I am! Me! Me! Me!
Where are you?
In the Mercedes.
This time leading me. You
will need to use your hands.
I...
I am a Mac Phisto.
Hello! My name is Candy.
Candy Christian.
Oh Candy! A beautiful name with
echoes of the Old Testament.
Thank you.
I would like to that would
allow me to escort her home.
That will be great.
Where do you live?
In the 83571/2 Schweitzer Terrace.
- Zero, can you find the 83...
- 571/2
571/2 Schweitzer Terrace.
-I Received!
Oh that was Zero!
-What driver? -No, my friend.
Some years ago I was
travelling up the Congo.
One day, after having
recited one of my poems...
to an audience of at
least 700 warriors Gonori,
a tribe of cruel, thirsty for poetry,
I could see a clearing in
the forest to a poor indian,
that was being attacked
by a giant python snake.
The man had already been half
devoured when I arrived...
and you grabbed it from the jaws
of that beast that threw foam.
Then, I ended up with the animal with
a single and sharp blow of my...
ballpoint pen.
After sixteen delicate operations
on the feet and the brain,
Zéro was able to walk again.
From then on, we never separate.
I've seen this story
Tuesday night on the Tele.
Then let's say...
I saved Zero of a lynching,
three years ago in Shreveport,
Louisiana, when he already
had the noose around the neck.
And then I began to recite
one of my epic poems:
"The Brotherhood of Man",
first in English and then...
and then... in welsh.
That changed their minds and their lives.
And now there's a system full
of school integration...
in Shreveport, Louisiana and...
Zero and I...
Are they living together since then?
Exactly!
And now...
I want you to tell me things of you.
Tell me about yourself.
What is it that you're looking for?
What do you believe?
I believe in what you told us before.
-Before? -Yes, in College.
When we spoke of all those who felt
free to give. Ah, yes, to give!
Those few,
those few and incredibly
privileged that...
that are free for you to take.
But, what for?
Be one in the same.
Yes, but to whom?
-All that I need. Oh,
yes, they knew and forsaw it!
From the moment I saw you, I knew that you
alone were able to understand my great...
my great...
Yes?
Need. I need! I need! I need!
My huge and gigantic need!
My huge and overwhelming need!
My huge and irresistible need!
I need it!
I need! I need!
I never deny the need! I need! I need!
I need! I need! I need!
I never deny the need!
Do not deny it, only that
I am still not prepared.
Never forget that the need can't wait.
The need is here!
The need is for now!
The need, the need is for now!
Don 83571/2 Schweitzer Terrace, guys!
I get out of here, you're impeding my need!
My need! My huge need!
Oh, no!
Oh, that's not good!
I need! I need!
Oh my god, look at that!
It's disgusting!
Well, that is love!
Is completely drunk and has wet everything.
We must do something.
Help me to take it home!
We will remove the pants, to the dry.
Very well.
Oh, that is not good!
It is necessary to live happily!
That guy has wet his pants!
It is horrible! Is soaked with liquor.
A poet as famous as Mr. Mac Phisto.
Is to be made to think, don't you think?
Oh, that's not good!
This people do very bad things.
Do you think that you can walk, now?
-Not to worry. We will try it. -Are you sure?
- Sure!
What is going on here?
If you go down the stairs
to the games room,
- ... I'll go get the iron.
-Not to worry.
I'll take care of it.
What have you done with my need?
Come on, old man!
Come on! We can do it.
Come on! We have almost arrived.
-O Emmanuel! -Yes, miss.
Please, come in. I want
you to do something.
What Does The Inside?
If you please.
¡Inside, no! I know that Mr
Christian will not like that.
Doesn't matter to me, Emmanuel. I need you.
Do you need to Emmanuel?
Yes, right now.
But is that Emmanuel is a good boy.
-I Want you to go to the kitchen to get the plate.
- Do the ironing?
-Yes, the irons. And I want to be the bring to the basement.
- What in the basement?
Yes, please. I have to
change this dress now.
She wants me to do it!
-Let's go, friend! I'm going to
take off now for the pants. -¡No, go!
How can you dare?
Do you think that a possible candidate...
the Nobel Prize for Literature...
is unable to take off
the pants by himself?
Hey, old man, you told him about it when
you saved me from the slave market...
Maracas?
O Emmanuel, quick, I need the iron!
Please, give me the pants!
Yes, to give!
I give!
-The miracle of giving. -Is the
title of one of his best sonnets.
Emmanuel, leave the ironing board here.
Oh, that is not good!
This is the house of the devil.
You, that have a face of Aztec,
the only survivor of the
massacre of your proud race!
Well said, boy!
It seems like that it is cotton!
What is saying this man?
It is a poem.
It is not a good idea! Use
the language of the devil.
No, No, Emmanuel. Speaking of life, of love
and of giving themselves to each other.
-What Happen? Do you realize what?
-self.
Emmanuel is a good boy.
Since then. You're a good
guy and a great gardener.
-Bring Honor to Mexico.
- Remember that you have a client Latin blood!
Emmanuel is a citizen of the united States.
Remember The Alamo!
-That I do.
-Remember the Revolution.
The Revolution! The Revolution!
The Revolution!
-The Revolution! -But that
is not what I wanted to say.
O Emmanuel, also wants to give now!
O Emmanuel! Don't, please!
-O gives himself!
-oh, Now, not! -Now.
-Oh, not Now, Emmanuel! -Now!
Oh, and she also gives it to him!
¡Viva Zapata!
Let it go-the-go!
My house is your house!
Oh, my God, it's dad!
You are my brother.
Say to me what I have done wrong!
-Let's go, tell me! -Do
you Know, what is your problem?
You can not live only.
You'll see how you'll love New York, Candy!
It is full of young great like you,
who are not afraid to
follow his instincts.
The only thing that I feel
is having to let my dad,
precisely now that you're so angry.
Thou oughtest to give thanks to God to
get out of this town, full of idiots.
What do you think of the scandal?
Just because you were surprised
and to do it with this latino?
It doesn't matter.
Listen, when I was your age,
I had a japanese lover.
We were so ardently
passionate to one another,
that I had to go over cold water.
On the pool table, right?
It is a pity then not to have my Polaroid!
Please, you're talking of my daughter!
I already know. But it is useless to cry
for a little fault, in matters of love.
Well, I'll take you to the airport.
Please do not respond. Must be one
of those nasty anonymous calls.
¡Good! He speaks to the
brothel of the Christian.
Thank you very much.
By the way: Your sister is here, and
it has already earned 200 turkeys.
-Hey, are following us!
-Who do we follow?
A group of bikers we are
following the heels.
Yes, I wish it was me he followed.
Hey, guys!
Isn't that, Emmanuel?
I don't know, sweetheart. You
know him much better than I do.
Oh bitch, stand up!
Stand up!
It seems that you are looking for a fight.
Have you seen the girl
out of the first moto?
It seems out of one of those
magazines that you have.
How "whips and Chains"?
No, the other: "Women of leather".
Yes, you're right. She is.
Maybe you just want to talk with us.
I prefer to talk with the mayor.
I have No doubt that you would.
But I assure you that we
have not come here to talk.
Maybe what you want is to give them
a kind of citizenship Education.
Not funny, Livia. Our situation
is anything but funny.
Down there, there is your plane.
Hey, gringo! Do you have a lot of hurry?
Yes, we are about to catch a plane.
How about to catch a plane?
You must be in a hurry, right?
Do you try to flee from something?
Oh No; Of course not!
Oh listen to me!
My daughter has to go to School
in New York and just try to...
For the blessed God! Why don't you
tell us what you want from us?
We want to pollita!
- What?
- What for? Do La pollita?
What the hell are you talking about?
Give us the pollita!
I Dánosla!
What? In the name of... oh,
hearken to me a moment!
This is not a lost zone of the border,
where you can catch
innocent people and make...
mexicanadas!
Let me me fix this issue!
Oh wait! Oh wait a moment!
I think that we will be able to find a
solution that will leave us all happy.
All can be arranged between friends.
I have this wrist watch
that has a great value.
It is automatic and water resistant.
We don't want your watch!
You can calculate up in
tenths of a second...
We don't want your disgusting watch!
And also the phases of the moon.
Oh wait a minute!
We're going to ease us all!
Do not do harm!
What are you, Emmanuel?
O Emmanuel, come here!
Emmanuel, what is it that is happening?
Do you know him? Do you
know our little brother?
-Well, I... -you've
disgraced our family.
-In the name of God, what are you talking about?
- Oh, Emmanuel, di...
Emmanuel is a good boy.
Emmanuel was a nice guy...
Don Emmanuel was a virgin!
Emmanuel was studying to become a priest.
I did not know.
I tell us who it was that
did those things with you!
I did not do it on purpose!
It is absurd! We are in the TWENTIETH
century and in the united States.
Ladies, a bit of spanking is fine.
But are switching from the stripe!
Don't you dare!
You will have given to him to lose, and
we will do the same thing with you!
Oh for the love of God, ladies!
We are all fellow citizens.
Don't, don't, hurt! This
woman belongs to me.
Click here!
I miss Christian, stay with me!
Oh wait!
Go up, dad!
Oh stay with me!
I need to get up! Attend to a wounded man.
Oh Uncle Jack! You're hurt!
Oh my god! If you are not
in a mission of service...
would crush these
maggots with my own hands.
Has lost the knowledge.
We must do something.
Who were they? I have not
been able to see great thing,
but I'm sure they were just garbage.
How Were Albanians?
No, it was just something personal.
I'm sure they had the face of albanians.
Not only were mexicans.
Mexicans, albanians,
lithuanians. They are all the same.
I was never the first in my class,
but I know recognize all
of these clandestine groups.
Listen up! I think that my brother is
injured. Could you not do something for him?
Okay, let me pass! Let me pass!
Oh and do me a bit of the site!
I watch those hands, Charlie!
Inside, there is still a beating heart.
These cockroaches have not
yet been able to kill us.
Can I do something?
I can hope and pray, young
lady, and You do the same.
They still have not been able to take this!
Everything has been my fault.
I don't doubt it, but I've already
seen in my life many wounded.
This man is in a very bad state.
Let's stick to the facts.
That liquid, which flows
from its head, it is blood!
Oh dad, say something!
No, No,
no tears now.
Soldiers don't cry.
Is there a doctor on board?
To a negative!
Fantastic! What kind of squadron is this?
We fly fast, we attack and
we go back to the base.
Forsake the fallen. That is the
price we pay for democracy.
Just wait! I have friends who are
very influential in Washington.
I have no doubt of it.
Sure are a bunch of leftists.
I would bet that you know many
communists are well located.
Well, let me tell you one thing:
Here these gentlemen don't send anything.
Just wait a moment! I
wasn't trying to say...
Do You, perhaps, a Political
Science professor?
What stock broker?
Can subscriber to the New York Times?
Do you see foreign movies and
even, sometimes, eat caviar?
What does that have to do to eat it or not?
Let me tell you something,
mister, lover of the caviar...
and now the one who speaks
to him is this simple mono!
And why I relate to all of you!
Special order of the Army n° 902783.
All those going to board
this device, are my orders.
To the orders of R. A.
Smight, general of brigade.
Special unit of Paratroopers
on reconnaissance mission.
I am responsible for the
success of this mission,
which consists in flying over continuously,
except when you have to refuel or stock up,
until the General Headquarters,
at any time, we are told to throw...
and to fulfill our work. Understood?
-But that man... -Oh, That man!
"That man!"
I have in my charge, 24 men!
Do you understand it?
- I 24! It numbered!
- 1, 2, 3, 4, 5
&, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12,
13, 14, 15, 16, 17,18
- 19, 20, 2, 22, 23, 24.
- Bingo!
It is impressive, isn't it
I would say that your men can count
up to 24, without being wrong once.
-What's more they know how to make
their guys? -What You like, lady.
Don't tempt him!
Are you ready to do any thing.
Eighteen months of flight,
do not have off - do not turn
off, repeat - his ardour of combat.
Oh look at this!
Oh my god,
if this is not again
proud to be americans,
is that I don't have
blood in your veins!
You have done a great dance number,
but let's be realistic: My
brother-in-law is in a coma.
Yes, you are losing a lot of blood.
You need a transfusion.
-What? -A transfusion.
-Do A transfusion?
-oh, General, please!
I will do whatever!
Whatever
Don Fischer! Chester!
Bring the first aid kit.
Prepare this man for a blood transfusion!
-He loved this jacket.
-Let Donors! We need donors.
Just wait a moment! Don't move!
-That man is your
brother, right? -Yes.
- And what all of You are family to him?
- Of course.
So, tell me in the name of God what is
what you plan. -I do not understand.
What I want to say, my lord, is that...
can not give blood to a
member of your own family.
Why not?
-Why not? -That is what I ask.
Because it is...
is incest.
Am I wrong?
General- ... -Yes.
-Come here for a moment.
-Yes, what happens? What happens?
Let me explain something!
That what You speak happens when...
Do you understand?
"For God's Sake! What
kind of people are you?"
How is that not respect anything?
Oh, please!
Don't worry, little one. We're
not going to let your dad die.
Generates, why their men don't sell
us your blood? We would pay for it.
Our guys can enter in combat at any time...
and need all your strength.
You, the white hat,
That you, a relative of him, come with me!
-¡Moveos, boys! -Yes, sir.
Back, there are a seriously wounded
person who is bleeding from the head.
If you do not want to go to play at the Casino in
Heaven, you must receive blood from a good american.
-What I have understood?
-Yes, sir.
-I command you that ye should go and
you do a blood transfusion. -Yes, sir.
And now, let's go to the grain.
-But, general,
- ... don't think it should go back...
-Let you Rest!
Let's look at the situation as I see it.
A man like me has no time for
speeches or pretty words.
What I have to say, only I'll say it
once and will listen to me carefully.
I never had time to lead an
easy life do you understand Me?
Most of us have not had anything
of "dolce" in our "vita".
And what can I do?
- I would like that...
- Yes.
I Desnúdate!
But, in general, that respects
the range that has...
Let's stop the blather! What
I need now is not respect.
-I Am asking for something more.
-I see that you must feel very alone.
This has nothing to do with the loneliness!
A man can not be only,
when you live surrounded by
24 soldiers, day and night.
I have been in this appliance.
Oh God, six years ago!
Six years moving from one side to the
other, on the belly of this monster,
spent among the enemy,
in search of some big fish.
It six years no movies,
no outings, no shows!
-Oh, Six years without a single woman!
-That is a record!
That's why, now, I ask you,
in the name of the most sacred
that there is in the free world;
In the name of all those,
that support this pernicious
wave of totalitarianism;
On behalf of those of us who are
standing, with your back on the wall...
and his fingers full of grease:
I ask of you,
that if you love your country,
I let you take a look.
It makes Me feel proud to be american!
But, general, You said that
you only wanted to look.
Sometimes, a look is not enough.
Get set!
What is it that you want?
I want to have a son of yours!
I want to have a child!
I will be strong, loyal, and blonde!
It will be like the two of us!
I will take a uniform like his father!
I will show you the manual of the soldier.
Will go to the Military School.
On the way, small! Is on the way!
You will learn what is freedom.
I will teach you to be a man of truth,
not a child's weeping,
or one of those pacifists of the fourth.
It will know be upright,
feet and with the chest lifted!
Oh, it's horrible to see you leave all these
handsome young men with their bayonets!
I retreat strategic!
Don retaliation massive!
It truly, war is hellish!
Where have it gone? Where are they?
Oh my god, they have gone without me!
If you hurry, you can catch them.
I Esperadme, boys!
I can't get in on the action without me!
I wait for dad!
Please, you can call for an
ambulance, when we land!
PRESENTED TO THE DR. A. B. Krankheit.
OPERATING OBLONGOTONOMIA THE PATIENT T.
M. CHRISTIAN
THIS EVENING AT EIGHT AND A HALF.
DEPLETED LOCALITIES.
You can be well proud of, Candy.
What amount of public to view your old!
New yorkers richest, most
respectable and most depraved...
are here, this evening.
Don't worry, sweetheart. If something happened,
provided you could live with your uncle.
Yes, you could teach it all!
What you mean if something happened?
"Well, you have to be realistic!"
Nobody wants to see your father more
than I, Would give my right arm for him.
You're right-handed!
But, going with the grain.
What I'm trying to say is...
that I am sure that
everything will turn out fine.
But, if not,
you know, such is life.
How can you say that?
Well, whatever happens, there is
to go on living... and loving.
Dr. Krankheit is the best surgeon
in the world, in their specialty;
But even he can make mistakes.
To say that da bad luck.
Only to the patient.
The patient suffers from a severe and massive
displacement of its nodes intracorticales.
There is a considerable
risk of lock-glandular.
Hopefully successfully
overcome that risk particular.
But we have to be very careful in
avoiding more serious injuries...
in the phase post-op
because of the lymphococcus.
As you know You, well, that could end up
degenerating in the syndrome of Rathner,
in which case the
patient continues to live,
be able to use almost
completely your muscular system.
But your mental capacity will be reduced...
that you can have a
cretin of middle age.
All of this offers us a range
of interesting possibilities.
A:
We could make the traditional
and classical fusion,
by removing two-thirds of the skull...
and exposing the patient's
brain to a strong level of D. A.
Waste atmospheric.
Two. We could atravesarle
carefully a shoulder blade,
following the technique developed
by Brett Sullivan and John Hawkins,
in their experiments
with monkeys of Papua.
But, let's be realistic:
We will operate a human
being, not a monkey of Papua.
If there is someone here
who is not in agreement,
with this technique, you
get out of here, immediately!
Good!
Let's start!
What are we going to do exactly?
What Dr. Harris?
I would start by making
an incision in the brain.
What is now going to get
to say stupid things?
I just wanted to suggest that...
You'll be in lectures redundant!
It seems to Me that this
operation must be...
You'll be nonsense, Harris!
I'm going to tell you exactly
what we're not going to do.
We're not going to use the old methods
are already very experienced.
Not at all, that's what
we're going to take out...
and throw it!
You have to do it again!
It's a human being...
and not from a method of literacy!
I'm going to give still one
more minute to achieve this.
Oh my blessed, look at what it does!
O you are a surgeon, not a gynecologist!
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
we're going to get to the end!
No, Bullock, not now!
Ladies and gentlemen, the
occlusion has disappeared.
My left index finger...
has managed to slip seven centimeters,
inside the head of the patient.
With a single slight movement, could
erase twenty years of memories,
as easily as you erase a whiteboard.
Only that he now had the hiccups,
could return to the patient is not
only unable to pronounce the letters:
L, R, D, y or F,
but also make you unable
to dial any phone number.
But, that's not going to happen,
because...
I know precisely...
what is there to do.
I carried you to your room!
I forgive you! Do you know where
I could find Dr. Krankheit?
-I Would like to know...?
-Close door!
Could you help me?
-How To Help You? -I'm looking for the Dr. Krankheit.
- What?
Do you know where I might find him?
Be careful!
-Can anyone help me? -Mom!
I'm looking for the Dr. Krankheit.
I want to leave you in peace!
Who?
Dr. Krankheit. Oh precisely, he!
Why?
Because I am his mom.
What is You Ms Krankheit?
-Krankheit, not. Fingolini.
-Let Fingolini!
Abraham Krankheit is
actually Mario Fingolini.
I changed her last name.
Because a doctor rich of New
York may not be an immigrant.
That is why, not to mention
that he is target in trouble
with a girl who is called Christian.
If you again see you here,
sneaking around him,
I will take this brush and...
This hospital is full of very sick people.
What you said?
He said that...
It doesn't matter. You've heard it before.
You said "sick".
But I...
I don't give a damn what you wanted to say.
This people...
also has feelings
like any human being...
and not have to endure
your aires of superiority.
I just wanted to find Dr. Krankheit.
Oh! What for?
-To ask a question. -If,
that is not what I doubt.
But, listen to me, lady
of the eyes so vivid!
I am the personal nurse of Dr. Krankheit.
¡Personal!
Bullock, here Krankheit.
I Want you to come immediately! Come on!
She wants me to go!
Oh Candy, you always manage to maximum fun!
It's the best reception post-operative
that has never attended.
Here it is! It is he of whom I have spoken.
-Not to touch you. -The
doctor has said that we will not touch.
Do not forget that our hands are
full of germs and micro-organisms,
spirochetes and who knows how
many other forms of infection.
-I Just want you to know that I'm here.
- He knows it.
How can you say that?
How can I tell that?
He asks Me how I can say that.
Put those flowers in ice.
He knows because he is a doctor, tontita!
Do you think that will be ok?
Look at it this way:
Your father will live.
Oh, thank God!
-The question is: For how long?
—You mean...
I don't want to say anything!
You should know that,
scientifically speaking,
the only difference
between life and death...
is that death lasts much longer.
Just look this! Don Max
has brought his radio!
- Oh, Yes, let's dance a little!
- I have to find where to plug this.
Do you suffer any pain?
That is an interesting question.
Let me try to contestársela.
The pain is very difficult to measure.
For example...
What have you done?
You have been hurt, right?
- Yes of course.
- How much? -I don't know.
-Do More than a punch? -Yes.
But not as much as being run
over by the wheels of a truck.
Of course not.
Well, that will give you an idea of how
to measure the pain of his father.
-Let Me explain something!
-What is that?
It is one of my personal findings.
A tremendous progress in the
field of neuroencefalografía.
I've called electrodegenerador
subcutaneous Krankheit.
The patient's brain is a
storehouse of energy.
We implemented a small plug
in your cranial cavity.
The plug connects here...
and so we eliminate the
excess of electrical energy.
Without this safety circuit, his father
would have a serious short circuit.
In popular parlance: "you
will melt the leads".
But,
this will not happen.
Oh honey, come and dance with your uncle!
Wait just a moment! Wait just a moment!
What's wrong with you?
Don't you like the party?
I sit here, near your father!
I Muévele a bit!
It is very comfortable,
and family,
lying one next to the other.
So should be always!
I'm so tired!
Ah, I see! Why don't you
take off your shoes?
Yes! Already is.
Perhaps you would be better if
you loose a bit of the dress.
And now we taparemos with this sheet.
Now, you just have to put
your head on my shoulder...
and try to sleep a little.
How much I wish that you were my daughter!
I know how hard that can be sometimes life.
Living with your father must not be easy.
But that will change with
the aunt Livia and me.
We are a people with much less formal.
We treat everything as if
it were something familiar.
What is going on here?
I animals is what these are!
A gang of wild animals!
Come on, if you spend all
your time carving up people!
It is she who organizes all the scandals!
I hope, miss, you have a good reason...
we're caught in the bed of a
patient in a critical state,
with his body half-naked,
wiggling and writhing,
under a passion so foolish as shameful.
I just wanted to sleep
for a while, next to...
I'm at the front of this hospital.
I'm Dr. Calvin Dunlop,
general manager of this establishment.
And I think I should intervene,
when in one of my rooms,
is conducted a shameful
and disgraceful orgy.
Truly I say to you, that
there has been no orgy!
Don't tell me!
I am a doctor and not a
psychologist of people upset...
and I know to recognize
in an orgy, when I see it.
And also what are the
depravity and indecency.
And even more, when you catch
someone "in flagrant delicto".
I don't know what that means.
It means that you must
leave here immediately.
I don't want to see my hospital converted
into a brothel by people degenerate like You.
For me, You are a pelandusca,
a harlot, joins furcia, a...
a young girl.
What are You doing, Dunlop?
Why is it on the floor this girl?
It has been dropped.
Because of Newton's laws, right?
I guess the psychotic abuse
that You usually exercise...
has nothing to do with it.
You don't need to take as well, Krankheit.
Let me remind you, doctor, that
this is a patient of mine...
and this is your room...
and she is the daughter of my patient.
Do you understand it?
It help me to lift it! Come on!
It Bullock!
Try to keep a little order in this room.
Mr. Christian, just You out
of a operation very serious.
I think that you are mistaken Mr.
Christian, miss!
Let me or I hit him a kick on their parts!
Good! Do you any suggestions, doctor?
It seems to be unconscious.
That's a great diagnosis!
And now, how do you propose
You look to this situation?
Can you think of something?
-Is young and apparently
in good health. -Very well.
We are practicing physicians.
Exactly.
I Examinémosla!
Oh Behave, Dunlop!
Why can't we examine it a little?
It not going to know.
He suggests that you return to your office,
take a tranquilizer and
then take a cold water bath.
I have not examined any patient.
Good night, Mr. Manager.
Good night to you, kind Mr. Prevaricador.
I have happy dreams, Mr. Wallet!
And You the same, Mr. Cazamoscas.
Thank You, Mr. Sacadineros.
Nothing, Mr. Bloodsuckers.
There is what, Mr. Gains.
Very well, Mr. Mammon.
I Jódase, Sr. Merdoso!
-I must have fainted. -Yes.
And I have to find the cause of
your fainting. It stand, please!
Fainting is a notice of our
nature that we must control.
I breathe!
Give yourself the back, please!
Yes.
All of this could be the symptom
of a dangerous disease.
-Let's Take off the clothes!
-What?
Oh the clothes! ¡To remove clothing!
Do not understand what I was saying.
I have to examine you.
But if there is nothing wrong with me.
It is not You who has to say it.
You are just a kid that has
not gone even to College...
and your Coefficient of Intelligence,
sure that is not that of a genius.
And, however, dares to
discuss the diagnosis...
of a surgeon renowned with many
titles as for wallpapering the walls.
Well...
Is well.
Of course that is fine!
-When we did the last?
-a month Ago, in College.
I mean to have a medical examination.
Yes.
-What You said that You had
a deviation of the spine? -No.
Then, he was only a charlatan.
Without a proper treatment,
when you turn 42 years old
your body will look
like a bag of clothes.
Now, take the back!
Go bowing slowly!
Because I'll tell you
when you have to say: Oh!
-But, doctor. Are you sure
that, You know...? -Slowly.
-O Slowly! -But, Dr. Krankheit...
Wow, this has to end already!
Let's go, follow pitch! You should
have a little more humanity.
"This is not the patient!"
Of course not, you idiot!
It is his brother.
If not, I would not have lasted so long.
Who has been to the patient?
Don Bullock, many times I have to
tell you not to interrupt my queries!
If you interest...
This query already are ja finish.
Oh my god, she already has done it again!
Oh dear, put a counter
up and we will be rich!
Well, I don't know about you,
but I have much work to do.
Let me pass, Bullock!
Let me pass!
And warn him to stop once
to follow me and spy on me,
whoever you are.
¡Doctor!
¡Espéreme! I have to talk with You.
Don't lie. That's not
going to serve anything,
Why would they lie?
Oh listen to me! We know what you're
looking for and what are your intentions.
Because they all think that...
The doctor is not available, do you
understand? It is not available!
So try to sell your
charms on the other hand,
because the doctor has already
said what he had to say.
And now,
¡come!
You will not notice anything.
I guess you don't care about anything,
but during your medical examination, your sick
father has disappeared in the middle of the night.
Oh dad! Oh dad!
Oh ladies, show your charms!
Hello, my dear!
You will be the next.
I Deténganla!
Oh stop that girl!
It Bullock!
A Coca Cola, please!
I'm afraid that I don't have money.
What?
I can't pay.
Stop!
Thank you. Oh my god,
all for just ten cents!
If you let me your address, I'll pay.
Forget it! The Big Boss wants to see it.
Who is this Big Boss?
Does The Big Boss? All of you know.
It is...
the Great Chief. Come on in!
Well, to me I love to meet new people.
This is the Big Boss.
Delighted to meet you.
-Hey! Be careful. -Let
us know what all you have.
What is this doing?
He has paid me a Coca Cola, but that
does not authorize him to take...
these freedoms.
Did you hear what that says? It freedoms!
I'll show you what is taking liberties.
No! Don't, for a moment! Just
because I'm not from here!
You should try behaving well.
-What? -If not, you
can have a small accident.
We're going to hammer a nail in the foot...
and then we're going to
get burned a little hair.
That is what happens here to the
girls who do not behave well.
Oh my god! And they call
this the City of the Fun?
¡Fantastic! That's it.
It is perfect!
Don't have any photos!
Don't we want photos! Let's go down!
Great! Great!
I just shoot a door in the wall.
And now, I'm going to look
at the door, on the wall.
My eyes are going to see, one by one.
The left eye...
and now the right.
My mouth, my teeth,
my gums, my lips and everything else.
And my throat.
- Oh, Excuse Me!
- And now, you! Just do it!
-Do It! -To do what? -Again!
¡Corten!
What Is G3?
Yes. What does it mean?
I am, G3, G of the cube.
G. G. G. Gian Giovanni Gemini.
What is called You so?
-Does it sounds familiar?
-I have Just come.
-Have you Ever seen my movies?
-Well... Not.
-Wait! I'm going to
shoot your answer. -No.
-Again! -No.
¡Corten!
I have filmed 112 people
saying the word "no".
Why?
Because this is all part of life,
and part of being,
living and understanding.
Have you seen someone film this?
No. 113.
-Have you heard of "Campbell"?
-What? -Campbell.
The I shot last year in both
color and black-and-white.
Two hours of soup,
beans, rice, lentils, and carrots.
The essence and the spirit and
the intimate entity of the soup.
Oh I already got it!
Man going through a door.
And now I'm going to take
care of You Come on in!
-Where are we going?
-I have an idea.
I don't understand what it
is that you want it to do.
I want you to be you! (TOILET)
Listen! I want you to become part
of the great human experience.
I baths, crowds, trombones, rubbish!
Oh listen to me!
I was looking for. You're
going to be my next film.
Stay with me and you'll
be just as famous as...
How is it called?
-What About Elizabeth Taylor?
-Who? Oh, no!
And now, let's start. -Action!
But it is that I know
nothing of interpretation.
And the Grand Canyon either
and, however, all go to see it.
Don't move!
Fantastic!
Girl sitting on the throne.
And now I want to see all
the pores of your skin. So!
That's it. Good!
And now; Now I want to see your pupils.
Where are they?
Where are you, cretin?
Beware! This with a type that has a camera.
Just perfect! Just perfect!
Now shot your arms and your legs!
It is everything that I needed. And now...
How beautiful!
And your sex!
I would say that they are doing
something forbidden. What do we do?
And now your face. Look at the front!
-Don't move! -Do
something that is haraam or not?
The door is closed!
Get ready to intervene!
Whatever you are doing, stop!
-In the name of the law!
-oh, The thighs!
Oh show me your thighs!
-Is something forbidden. How
we broke down the door? -Yes.
Perfect, two cops! Control immorality.
I come near! I come near!
"This is going to be your last plane, man!"
What crime we accuse?
Filming without authorization.
Illegal employment in public toilets...
and flooding is not controlled.
Where is gone girl?
Do you know that has happened
with the girl in the blue dress?
Who is that movie?
Man fainting.
-Do you Have money?
-No, I'm sorry.
I'll play if you give me something.
But it is that I do not
have anything to give her.
-O give me your ropopompón!
-What?
See. We will win some money
and then ropopompón.
-Don't you want to ropopompón?
-I Would like to put on a dress dry.
I will give it and then ropopompón.
Did not you come?
I don't know.
-What Is this? -No, not really.
It is always for this!
Oh poor man! Should not think that.
Is it here where you live?
I'm sure that the music
is one of your hobbies.
-Could you play something
for me, while I dry? -Yes.
Are you sure that you
know what you are doing?
You have an exquisite taste.
-Who is she? -Where are you?
-Where is the Boss?
-What is going on here?
-What kind of guardian are you?
-What is your mission?
Hello, chief! We bring it all.
Have reached their friends.
I can not understand you.
What do you want?
It shouldn't bite people,
is very ugly!
And now, ropopompón!
Don't you think...
Do you not want to?
I appreciate your hospitality, but...
What is this?
-No, that has nothing to do with it.
-Yes.
-What Is this?
-oh, No, No, really!
Why? It is not nothing. It's
like having torticolis.
It's always so!
Oh, poor boy, you must not think that!
What is this?
I don't know that to do here,
but they seem to some panties.
Oh my god, is a 507!
Let us go to make
adjustment to the accounts!
Let no one move!
And what does this who it is?
We have won the lottery!
Is the visiting card of the little man.
-What little man? -The hunchback
most dangerous criminals of today.
You have three seconds to drop your
weapons and get out of that Steinway!
That is one of the old
tricks of the crosses-walls.
-We'll catch him! -Yes.
I had not told you how it was called.
Go! If what I see, I hope
to be able to recognize it.
Let's see if I calmáis back there
or I'm going to give you a beating!
What do they do?
I don't know. But whatever
it is, should be illegal.
-Can I look at? -Not!
' Shut up and drive!
Are we going to the police Station? No.
I find me a nice site!
I want to get rid of these
nasties and get some pleasure!
But if we have not done anything wrong.
Listen, I don't know what is your game,
or to engage You and your gang,
but I'm going to teach them
to re-tuck in my district!
But, if I had not seen nape
of the neck to that people!
Everything you say may be used against you.
-But if I don't... -against you.
I understand!
I would not mind to be against it.
You, watch where you're going!
Do you carry hidden weapons?
Of course not!
What drug? What pills?
-What About Amphetamines?
What marijuana? -Not!
Oh, that's not going to
serve you, small slut!
Put the hands in the back!
What are you going to make me?
We're going to register for, miss,
as you've never been before.
I record it, sergeant!
I score it!
And now we present, for your amusement,
newcomer to any site, Ahmed,
the magician!
Let us run over!
¡Gross polis!
O murderers of children!
¡Let's get out of here!
This is a nest of queers!
¡Fire at will!
¡Monster fascist!
¿Bromeas? I'm irish.
Why not fighting like a man?
Do you want even more?
Yes, yes, hit me more,
putón of blue eyes!
Oh sergeant!
I've broken the heel!
What I can bring?
Stop! You have to take your shoes off!
Oh, I'm sorry! I thought that maybe...
This sanctuary is well above this
material world. It is a sacred place.
The light, the walls, the water, and
these hands; Everything is sacred.
I've already seen!
-Oh, keep your shoes materials in the sacred water!
- And what do I do?
I throw them to the material world!
But if you are the only ones that I have!
I pull them!
Wait!
Give me that material corruption!
Out! Out!
Don't need them, or anything
else that is material!
You must strip yourself of everything
that is material. And let's go!
-What's your name? -Candy.
What Candy? How do you write?
C-A-N-D-AND
Be careful! O tell me the truth!
Of Course, so I call. Wait!
Wait, don't repeat it! It is a sacred name.
A name that can not say.
I don't understand.
Listen!
C-A-N-D-Y. Five letters.
Five, the magic number.
Five, the pentagram is sacred.
The first letter of your name is C.
C is the sign of the sierra
eagle, the sign of masculinity.
The last letter of your name is the Y.
The sign of the Yoni,
the dispenser of all good.
And in the middle AND (and).
C and Y.
Do you understand, now?
I'm not sure. I...
Wait, don't talk! Don't move!
I have more evidence.
Oh, my God!
-I Thought... -what better,
you thought that hung in the air.
So it would seem.
It is a plastic seat.
Appearances are always deceptive.
To float in the air is a trick very easy.
In my country, all this is only
used as a public entertainment.
Disappear by the end of a
rope, walk on hot coals,
play with poisonous snakes.
Are games only for children.
How can You do all of that?
My dear and innocent girl,
when I was nine years...
he could do things that are
incomprehensible to the western mentality.
He lifted huge weights
only with the tongue.
I could see, through seven layers of zinc.
And, it is not by vanagloriarme,
but,
until, until I could
speak with the vegetables.
Oh, that is wonderful!
No, that is not nothing.
Only a grain of sand, compared with the
mountains created by the gods in the past;
Compared to what you and I
are going to do together here.
Do together?
Yes, of course.
Together we will find the path of
selfishness; I say not-selfishness;
Beyond the valley of
the material concerns...
and the cliffs of the negative feelings,
clambering and fighting...
until we reach... the vacuum.
The vacuum!
Beyond time and space,
beyond one's self,
the vacuum,
pure energy and light.
God!
What god?
God has nothing to do Come!
Where do I start?
-First, I'm going to teach you to breathe.
- What?
As a typical american, you must believe
that you already know breathing.
But, let me tell you this. Only
know one mode of breathing.
-Inspire and breathe.
Do you deny it? -No.
But the truth is that there are
other thousand ways of breathing.
Forward and back; Up and down,
breathing like a camel
or like the grass.
Do you want to say, as the photosynthesis?
- What?
- Do you know, when the carbon...?
No, No. Forget about all that
and take it off of your mind.
Leaving aside the science,
that it is something corrupt.
I forget everything they
taught you in School!
I forget the formulae and theorems,
of prefabricated houses
and of the gum of rubber,
of the lacquer to the hair,
credit cards, Wall Street and...!
It cast!
What does it say?
It cast! We're going to start breathing.
-Oh, that is gorgeous! -Oh Cast!
Just wait a moment!
When I arrived a little while
ago it was day and now...
It's midnight!
What I have done?
To you, nothing. But at the time, a lot.
Now we have to find the
appropriate site. It cast!
-What we call the centre of all breathing.
- Are my lungs?
No, it is not so simple.
Is the site in which it is to be immutable.
We must seek it.
Let see! Will it be here?
No, I don't think so.
Maybe, you should be here!
No, I've gone back to being wrong!
Here?
No!
-Or here? -No, I'm
sure that here is not.
I think yes.
What we have found very fast.
It must be a good sign.
-I Am sorry to take you the opposite, but...
- oh, throw yourself!
Who is the guru, here, you or me?
-Do More breathing? -No,
this is just the first level.
You must move forward, now.
How many levels we have to take?
Seven. The first is to be able to
feel the rhythm of the cosmos.
I hear you, a moment!
Don't talk! We can't wait.
Oh my buttons!
Your buttons, as you call them,
are not more than the reflection of
that self that you must leave behind you.
Don't mean anything and
are somewhat corrupt.
Without those buttons, you're
going to move on to levels 2, 3,
4, 5 and 6 and, finally...
to the last level. Good!
And now, let's get ready to
address the second level:
The body has no value.
It's not worth anything!
It or this!
It or this! And now we
will pass to the level...
-To... -Do Two?
Two!
Don't think I could breathe
so much more time.
So keep patience! The road is
hard, but worth the effort.
The escolopendra, in my country, it has
thousands of legs, but can't dance tap dancing.
I don't see that has to do that.
Well, you always lose
something when translated.
I wonder where we can be.
That does not matter.
The space is just an illusion.
It is curved in on itself
like an artichoke.
Oh, an artichoke, I would be very good!
I'm dying of hunger.
What is that you can only think about it?
What in your body and in your poor desires?
I can not help it. I'm hungry.
We are traveling beyond
the thirst and hunger.
It's like the legend of
the pig and the flower.
What is the legend of
the pig and the flower?
Is a legend that my people sing and dance.
A pig comes up to some bushes.
In the scrub sees a large
flower of violet color.
It is the only one in the surrounding area.
Then, the pig falls in
love with the flower.
The pig confesses his love
to the flower and she says:
"You're a pig and you're very
dirty, even to be a pig".
Then the pig starts to cry...
and the flower is pity, the
dirty animal, and he says:
"I'll love you, when you get to be clean."
The radiant heart of joy, the pig
drops to wash herself at the river.
It gets in the water...
and is devoured by a crocodile.
What is the meaning of this story?
I have No idea.
What level are we now?
-In the third! -How is it called?
The level of positive non-being.
I can not grasp the difference
between one level and another.
It will be better for us to stop.
Look, snow!
If you don't mind, I would like
to now take a little rest.
Look like stars floating in it.
-Look! Oh listen to me! -Is
There anything not going well?
It is not only that...
Depart!
You're going to resfriarte!
That is impossible.
The flesh does not mean anything
in the way of the realization.
-We Live in the vortex.
-what is The vortex?
It is the fifth level.
What has happened to the fourth level?
-I've jumped. -Can You do that?
Do not follow every one of the
levels in the way everlasting?
Yes, but I am a mystic reformed.
Listen!
This can be something serious.
Do you not have a thermometer?
It seems that you have not learned
anything. Our bodies do not exist.
We are on the threshold of the last level.
The injection of the universal spirit.
But if that is the level 6!
What happens in the ♪ 7?
And what about the vacuum?
I don't I can carry to
the edge of the void.
A teacher wiser than I...
will lead to the end of the trip.
How will I recognize you?
By the sacred bird.
What is the holy bird?
-No matter what.
-Hey, the door is open!
The police!
Take a look back; I'm going
to talk with the driver.
-Do you take fruits, flowers,
plants, weapons, or alcohol? -A guru.
What?
A guru. Is that a fruit or a plant?
Hey, George! What is prohibited to
import of gurus frozen in California?
Oh Charlie, get me out of here!
Do you want to?
-Oh, Charlie!
- You're well? -I've lost all my pocket change.
Let me out of in here!
The sacred bird!
Is it You who will lead me to the vacuum?
Have we arrived already?
Say that You are able to...
give me the answer?
I don't understand...
which means all of this!
The statue is coming towards us!
What has happened?
What are we going to do now?
Are you not going to tell me your name?
Oh my god!
It is dad!
Oh dad!
Vtg