Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Madagascar.
For centuries
the bloodiest cockpit of all the seas.
Where
the infamous Brotherhood of the damned.
The weight of the plunder.
The treasure laden galleons
from India and Cathay.
Then returned drunk with slaughter
for their pirate stronghold of last hope.
Most ruthless of all
was Captain William Kidd.
He encountered the great London galleon,
the 12 Apostles, commanded by Admiral Lord
Blaine, and approaching unsuspected
in the guise of a peaceful merchantman.
By a sudden touch of a salad bowl,
he was just turned to a burning hulk.
When night fell,
the 12 Apostles was only a blazing
funeral pyre
on the surface of a Madagascar lagoon.
Stop me!
There's a pretty side.
Reproduce during the fire.
Reaches the magazine.
Put it all.
Lots of stout seamen among them.
And with us a long time we can.
None of us live forever, Mr. Boyle.
Dead men don't talk man your own.
We got this job to build before high tide.
There and dig past the tide.
Catch his head or save the king's hangman.
Some rope.
Hell, yeah.
Deep enough to bury him at it.
Give us a happy
all ready, captain.
And she goes.
What are you waiting for, little captain?
That just been in cabin the longest time.
And we all thought is how it wouldn't
do no harm to open up that chest,
make sure that what was in it,
then, isn't it? Now?
I suppose you remember what was in it.
I remember an emerald necklace
that came off the Portuguese ship of anger
and all those pearls that we took from
the big ship, the Virgin Queen.
I remember a diamond medallion we got from
that Moorish canyon of Madagascar.
And could we ever forget
that silver casket with the arms of Lord
Blaine that you claimed yourself
after the taking of the 12 apostles, sir,
your necklace
stretched as long as your memory.
One of these days.
And. Satisfied.
Gallows meat.
Put them back.
Long away.
No matter.
The laminate. Cat and mouse. You forgot.
What are you.
What now? We've got half an hour
of all the tide trap.
That just may be, sir.
We're all equal in this,
I take it. Equal shares.
Yes, well, I key then what you put back in
your belt that goes down with a chest.
Thus we starts all clear.
No favors.
Some of us don't get back.
It'll be that much easier. Open for them
has done.
Question me on it again, would you?
I'll rip you from Belgian Chine.
Always such
callous rascals
that we leave a dead comrade
without commending
his soul to his new master.
Here lieth
one who, through treachery and avarice,
would have placed in jeopardy
the lives of honest men.
And here may he live forever.
And the sands of Madagascar.
Rest in peace.
It's time to be out of that.
It's time to be away.
From.
If a gentleman is a gentleman, he's
a gentleman.
That's all there is to it, sir.
I want a native gentleman,
but I need polish.
My good man, if I'm to improve myself.
Gentleman employs
the terminology, my good men,
only when addressing lower servants.
Or is inferior, sir.
You see, that's why I need you.
My upbringing,
gentlemen. Never such as tea, sir.
Many a man's social career
has been ruined by lesson.
You seem to know your business.
I want the best man and I can pay for it.
Hundred quid a yet
an infallible mark
of the person of quality is his reluctance
to pay his domestics
high wages that say so many
an idiosyncrasy of good breeding, sir.
£60 here,
then you realize I've never been on board
a ship before, sir.
I don't let that frighten you
to the contrary.
In fact, since I was a nipper,
I've had rather an adventurous inclination
toward life on the bound in Maine,
which had been quite educational. Sir.
You learn a lot, no doubt.
Is it a bargain, then?
But it was.
I had my hand on it.
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Then it is your proposal,
my lord Belmont, the Captain Kidd
sailed to meet our ambassador
Lord forthwith and give him a safe
conveyance with a parrot.
What is of Madagascar?
May I please, Your Majesty? Yes.
That needs a bold and adventurous man.
Bring in this, Captain Kidd. Why?
We take the measure of him.
And William Kidd.
Your Royal Majesty
and I will, Lord.
Belmont.
Is this your roaring killer of Spanish
buccaneers?
Me. Me, lad,
I am only a peaceful ship master.
Who must you trade with other ships
without inquiring too closely
about that business.
And it was so.
I fell into the hands of the 12 apostles,
a king ship
turned pirate in Madagascar waters.
I have never been in Madagascar.
What is your Grace?
It was off the southern tip of Africa.
What?
I had gone to trade in elephants teeth.
Who commanded her?
One of your admirals, your Majesty.
You name of Lord Blaine?
He did.
Had pirate been sufficiently lad
to put fear in honest traders like myself.
And if you are successful in
this voyage, captain,
what reward do you expect made?
Please,
Your Majesty, having forfeited me to him
that I was supposed
to strike me to a pirate, I want no reward
but to regain it
in the service of Your Majesty.
Unless it be.
Or is it to that Lord Blaine's
lands are restricted and his titles
forfeit?
Yes, all.
All I ask is that if I lay this
renegade nobleman by the heels.
Is that you honor
the humble self with his castle
and his lands.
Is that all you want, Captain Kidd?
Not a pardon more, Your Majesty, whom
the fellow treats of a title so lightly.
He must be bursting with noble blood,
though I confess he keeps it well hidden.
I say,
you can no more judge of a man
by his appearance, than you can judge
the extent of a nobleman's brains
by the expansiveness of his wit.
Am I to suppose
that the captain of the king's
God would deign to fence
with me?
Come, captain.
Is your courage less than your wit nicer?
I know nothing of fence.
You must come at me
quickly, as though you'd kill me.
Very well, then.
I ask pardon, sir.
I have a hot head.
When roused, I only meant to demonstrate,
and to good purpose.
Captain.
Your Majesty is satisfied
with the captain of our choosing.
I can think of none better.
I thank you, sir.
And now, captain,
the main mission of your cruise
will be to meet a great ship,
a merchant, which is sailing from India
with vast treasures
and to give us safe conduct in my name,
past the pirate waters of Madagascar.
But, Your Majesty, will her commander
accept my letter of sufficient authority
to. You? Shall have a letter to what?
Ambassador
Lord Portsmouth was returning home.
But he is to accept
your protection
and to submit to all matters
pertaining to the safety of the ship
and her treasures.
I oh,
and now, sire may crew your crew.
Captain Kidd wishes to recruit a crew
from the Pirates, now under capital
sentence in Newgate and the Marshal, sea
a crew of condemned pirates.
I sir
this none would be so loyal,
nor quite so desperate
as cutthroats under sentence of death,
if they knew that at the end of the voyage
a royal pardon would be in their pockets.
But I shall hold you accountable for that
good conduct between their conduct
and mine, your Majesty,
there will be little to choose.
And now, goodbye.
And Godspeed you.
I am but his unworthy sparrow.
And every
few and rather ether bills
come from an African slaver.
Adam, don't let that temper
get you the lash again.
If I must hang, I'll hang.
But I'll go to the gallows
with clean guts, at least.
Hey, you!
What kind of stinking
maggots meat is this?
What is it?
There's a dainty crumb. Mercy.
Complaining about the taste of the king's
bounty again.
Watch it.
Basie, fight me.
I the king's allowances trumpets
a day for food, not muck from the soil.
Is the white chapel making trouble again?
I ain't mercy, I'm asking only
what a man's legally entitled to hear.
Smell this.
Delicious.
I don't want anything I can
hear your guv'nor.
What sort of a kingdom is this?
Well, a man's condemned before
he's heard and style before they hang him.
Who was that
quarrelsome fella? At a mercy.
He was taken in a pirate ship
by His Majesty's frigate wasp.
He's always escaping.
So that's why we keep him in chains.
He's got a lacing of tiger's blood in him.
Who isn't exactly a flower.
God knows it.
Oh, forgive me, governor.
These are two of me officers.
Mr. Boyle, governor Landers, Mr.
Lorenzo, governor Landers.
Spanish blood.
A pretty lot of sinners could be done.
Do you think that he's.
Anyone down there knows us?
I hope not, I've no doubt you'll be good
enough to tell him what we're here for.
Give heed, you, you vermin.
Here's news to get advantage
as the hangman that day.
Oh, to that then, Jack.
Nasty face.
Is that that your mother's turned
into an honest woman?
Silence your mutinous dog.
If another man speaks, I'll trace him up
by the Thames and play him raw.
Governor,
is that the way to win the love of these
unfortunate gentlemen?
Now, then, me bullies, would you rather do
the gallows dance and hang in chains.
Till the crows
pick your eyes from your rotting skulls?
Oh, would you feel a roll of a stout ship
beneath your feet again?
I I'm a vessel.
The adventure galley
and the king's commissioned a sailor.
And for those who shall a loyal
and a stout heart.
That are royal pardon in the offing.
Have I.
Which of you knows the waters
off Madagascar?
Are you?
Would you have him unlocked the.
Water.
Unlock him.
Look you.
Then I want men with iron in their blood
and stealing their sinews.
And the first up here is the first
enlisted governor of your waters already.
Would you be good enough
to have them lower the ropes, Lord.
Away!
Own. Oh!
Yeah.
They come back where they land.
Where your hands are
that I'll make you free. Man.
Go on now.
Next.
Month.
Name it a shot.
Need either shout.
Regardless of the fact
that I'm your captain,
you will always address
a gentleman who serves scum.
I say make your mark.
On board.
Name that of my sister.
Oh, so it's you.
Mercy!
That's a comical handle
for a blade of fortune.
Mercy?
It's also something
the world needs more violent death.
A philosopher. You speak cultured.
Well, are you by any chance
stable boy to a noble house?
Perhaps.
I was also a master gunner to a buccaneer.
You may have heard of Captain Avery,
Avery's master gunner.
We've made him a master, Mr.
Boyle.
And from what I've heard,
Avery was a shrewd hand at picking him.
The berths?
Yours for as long as you can handle it.
I can handle it.
Swivel gunner. Long time.
I've offered a guinea for every mess
for which your neck.
If you miss while you're on my ship,
I come up.
And you can write.
We'll give you a nice bath.
You'll draw a uniform
befitting the master gunner on board.
Next man.
Name Bartholomew Blevins.
salamu.
Livings
make him up.
Down below.
Oh. Like it?
Every day.
I don't want any other.
I don't want anything.
No more war.
You know, Vanessa.
Thanks, man.
That's all.
Sir, compliments for.
Oh, me?
I thought you.
Yes, you thought I was dead.
Well.
I can hardly believe my eyes.
I mean, you don't want to believe I.
Come, come, Mr. Pogue, is that kind of.
Is that fair?
As fair as what you did that day.
You abandoned me out of a hammer.
If you please, Mr.
Pope,
it is not the time to talk about that.
Oh, it's the time. All right.
Unless you want me to go. No.
In which case your present voyage is over
before it's begun.
No, no, no, no. Povey.
Mr. Boyle, would you take over, please?
Mr. Lorenzo, take the deck. Watch.
Come to my cabin.
My heart bleeds
when I think of one of your delicate
constitution.
Having to fend for yourself
on a coral reef.
Mr. Boat, come off it, captain.
I know why I'm alone. Me?
So there'll be only three
a good a share instead of four.
It's true.
A hostile wind
did blow us away from your reef.
Between friends, we might have sailed back
at exactly what you would have done, Mr.
Povey.
So no more of your sentimental nonsense.
Please.
Know that we are for again.
What then?
We're not for
with two.
Boylan.
Lorenzo.
Joe loves
20,000 pounds.
A piece in their hands
would only be spent in sinful ways.
And you propose to remove them
from the path of temptation?
Oh, a knife in the dark.
I'm not a violent man, Mr.
Povey, I detest violence.
People have such an awkward habit
of getting in my way.
I am an ambitious man, Mr.
Povey.
An ambitious man, if he be bold
enough, can carve himself a kingdom.
I let to be a lord, my friend.
And that for a commoner
like myself takes a deal of money.
And that's why
that could be too less to share
before we raise old England game.
You cold got sha?
Flatterer.
Oh, get your back a game, Mr.
Povey.
You've no idea how gratifying it is
to have a congenial soul
to confide in.
Thank you.
Oh, there's something I want to tell you.
I have left with a clemency letter
containing an exact and complete
account of certain previous happenings,
only to be opened in case.
Just in case, of course,
you should happen to return to England
without me.
Of course, my dear fellow,
very sensible of you.
Now I know you will have a happy voyage.
I shall too.
I look up in the corners.
We are two of the luckiest man alive.
Just think.
We are sailing from Madagascar waters.
Don't pick up the stranger
where we left off.
Every office on board has a servant.
I request the captain assign you to me.
Then we can be together.
Yes. I've spent
a good many years of my life.
See that I do.
But I doubt if any woman minds.
Is there some sort?
Even an opinion of the realm?
But myself.
Now milady will join me in.
And then you, my lady sir,
not me, lady flask. Me.
Shadwell, there's one gentleman
creep up on another without a cough
or a spit or something to warn him.
I'm not a gentleman, sir.
I'm a gentleman's gentleman.
Give you back the hat.
I suppose you've tried everything.
There's grease.
Prenatal influence.
Perhaps.
Dinner says
thank you, Shadwell.
Pardon, sir.
I'll show you that you play.
What's all this mummery?
You can forget your bilge water manners
for the time, Mr.
Boyle.
You are now officers on a cruise ship.
So a man must stop while his manners.
Madam.
I know, I know.
And in the king's ship
it is customary for the officers to rise.
When the captain enters.
That's better.
Gentlemen, be seated.
Oh! Well, well, well,
what have we here?
Well, I'm.
Of course, but don't press.
Come, Mr.
Murphy, tell us something about yourself.
You already know what I was
of consequence. I'm
well under every.
I was taken by kingship
and brought to London.
I was tried for a parrot and condemned.
You were innocent. Of course.
No, sir.
I was guilty.
You speak above your station.
How came you go on the account?
Call it the love of adventure.
Cost in love, a scandal
and perhaps the mixing of all three.
And you've seen something of the world.
Enough.
Say to dislike what I've seen.
And to know that small old. The.
Perhaps you prefer the next world, Mr.
Mercy.
You were close enough to it
when you were in the condemned
hold of Newgate.
But I'm keeping you from your dinner.
I don't know.
Oh. oh,
And now, gentlemen,
a toast to the King.
And since proposing it
is the privilege of the youngest present,
the honor falls to Mr.
Bessie.
Mr. Mercer, we are waiting.
No. So,
since I have little love for the king.
Oh, now that proposes health,
I'll drink it.
Nevertheless, you are on a kingship.
Kingship of the devils.
It's all the same to me.
So I owe him nothing.
You owe him your neck, Mr. Mercy.
If it were not for his bounty, you'd be
dancing daintily on air at Wapping.
I owe my reprieve to you, captain.
So do you. I'll drink, and gladly.
But not to. William.
You stand up and drink to his Majesty's
health as I King's office.
I should all by fire and flame.
I'll have you shipped back to new.
Been on the first vessel we speak.
Gentlemen.
The king.
They can't go about him.
That's one reason.
It's curious.
Do you suppose His Majesty
put him on board to spy us out?
We found him chained to a pillar.
A new Newgate
wouldn't be too hard for the king
to plant him there.
Yes, but why would he speak
so openly against the king?
Your wits. An even taller than usual, Mr.
Lorenzo,
have you never heard of the serpent
that takes the color of its background?
The better to strike
Shadwell?
Yes. I can.
You have a knowledge of highborn people
and those of the called shadow.
What? Have you ever seen Mr. Mercy before?
Not before this voyage.
He's as high of spirit
as a gentleman of quality.
I'm like you.
Would you find out who he is,
where he comes from?
As you wish. Thank you. Though.
Oh. Foggy night.
Good evening. Shadwell.
Excuse me, sir, but you seafaring men
always seem to be looking at something
that I never can see.
You're looking for something
just over the horizon.
You know, I recognized you for gentlemen
the moment I saw you.
What are you doing at sea?
The captain employed me to make him
socially acceptable. Sir.
I'm afraid
we are too far out for me to swim back
if I can be of service to use it.
Did the captain send you here?
Yes. Why?
He wants to know who or what you are.
Ought.
Who do they think I am?
Most of this tide
placed on board by His Majesty.
They seemed uneasy to him.
This,
This Captain Kidd.
How long have you known him?
Have you sail with him before?
Oh, knows.
All I know is he's,
Well, among other things,
a merchant captain spy.
That's strange.
Why should they be afraid to be spied on?
Good night sir.
Who is he?
Where is he from? He's a nobody, sir.
He was employed by persons of quality.
But he learned his speech in his manners.
It's a matter of judgment.
If you fire on the uproar,
the shot will go ablaze.
Yea, but if you wait for the down roll.
The enemy is coming up.
Now watch.
Get ready.
Oh! Oh!
For these men.
Then you do as well with a 70
for throwing grape and canister at you.
I've done it, sir.
Be reload and secure
and pick up your practice on the lob.
And quite a swivel gun, Mr. Massey.
You sailed with Avery.
You must know they brought us fairly here.
If we needed to carry them,
take on stores.
Where would you recommend poverty?
Basically, we draw too much water.
You remember Camden?
Can't remember what I know.
The Spanish man.
These are Madagascar waters.
Poverty Bay. I say.
Thank you, Mr. Madison. Come along.
Let's go.
I'm doing a.
Your presence is becoming
increasingly irks.
You will.
Now let's get down
to the business of this voyage.
I made a chart to boil.
The coffee down.
I have been thinking every day
and every night.
What about that?
The arrow that we buried in the cave.
What good is it
there? Let's get it and get it back.
Where are we going to spend it?
That stays where it is for a while. Why?
We've got a better prize
sailing right into our pockets. Now,
here's our present position
is Madagascar is Calicut.
In June, the great galleon, the cuy,
the merchant sails.
Calicut to England.
We should meet, about here.
She's stuffed from keel to gunners
with treasure to the value of half
1 million pounds.
and we ought to give her safe passage
through the pirate seas
by, safe passage,
you mean where to take her, captain?
No, no, no, don't be greedy, Mr. Poe.
They are granted, most of what's in there
may find its way into our pockets.
But let's be fair.
The king.
Poor gentlemen will expect something.
But however we do it, it must be done.
Eagle like and on his stick.
Two ways you're familiar with.
Well, straddle bill and I can be as honest
as any man if I have the incentive.
Oh, yes. May Lord blame
Lord blind.
His name is not to be mentioned
among us, Mr.
Povey. He's dead.
So's his crew and so's ours.
And there's none outside this cabin
that knows what they came of them.
And if you all enjoy living,
you will remember that well,
here's to our meeting with the Queen's
a merchant,
with a merchant, and general merchant.
let's, listen for your love.
Indigo. And.
Winn.
Fresh from West. Northwest side.
Quest. Noise by night. Dog. But clear.
Very well.
Mr. Mercy.
Norris.
Peace.
Now he's facing.
The door with Mr.
Bow and the hangman.
And. No.
Oh, no!
He's dead.
I find the man
that's responsible for this.
I'll hang him.
Fish the yard and reset it.
What do you suppose happened?
Someone's been tampering with these lines.
We all gather
together to bid farewell
to a gallant seaman
and a stout comrade.
Here was a man.
Shipmates whose heart
the flinty mountains could not match.
Who always took better than he gave.
Whose benevolence was such
the orphan's might.
And the rich man's gold alike
found refuge in his pocket.
A jealous providence has removed him
from us,
and I esteem it a privilege
to commit his body to the deep.
We shall all mourn him.
I we shall mourn him.
But take comfort, my friends.
We shall never see his like again.
Rest in peace.
Pop him over.
The day, Mr.
Mercy, a great pity,
but the ship's work must go on.
Move your gear into poor Mr.
Boyle's cabin.
You will take his
place as master, as master?
I see
I shed.
Don't tell me.
After all this time at sea, I in revolt
is not from the movement of the vessel.
Was occasioned by the company idea
that matters.
I say nothing of sir,
but I'm a such a man.
And when I find a common ship
master has the presumption to copy himself
the coat of arms of one of our best
all sorts of families.
Can you wonder if I'm physically upset?
Whose crest was he copying?
Credited or not, sir? The plane crashed.
What are you saying?
Thank you sir,
of course is honoring his desk.
Pardon me sir, I must join.
The captain is inspecting.
Cost me with Mr.
Lorenzo.
Well, Mr.
Massey.
Do your new duties
include rubbing my desk?
Shoot me, captain,
and your head goes with it.
I'm here with the king's orders.
So he did want you on board.
Do you think he would let a man sail
with a crew of Newgate cutthroats
and not keep tabs on him?
And with good reason, if anything, of a
reeked of piracy, this does.
And murder, captain
Boyle's death was no accident.
By the way.
what ship was sunk here?
The 12 apostles.
Why the 12 apostles, Mr.
Massey?
Has Blaine's ring.
His name is on it.
He commanded the 12 apostles.
That'll make interesting
telling in London when we get back.
Captain, if you get back when I get back.
For if I don't.
On the other hand.
On the other hand. What?
Since the man doesn't exactly grow
rich in the king's pay.
crooked rogue.
So you have your price.
How much? An equal share.
And what's buried
here? Share that with you.
I'll be hanged if I do.
You'll be hanged if you don't have all the
I key.
Blackguard.
And if you do share Mr.
King's informer, what guarantee is that?
That you won't still turn evidence
for the Crown?
If I go in with you, I am equally guilty.
And if we are caught, we hang together.
But I can keep you from being caught.
What more could you ask?
You know, Mr.
Mercy, I've wondered sometimes
if ever I'd meet
a more unscrupulous blackguard
than myself,
and I have.
Well, let's be sensible about this.
Who knows?
We might be useful to each other one day,
in one way or another.
To forgotten something wearing.
So I have.
Listening carefully.
Because I want you to tell in London
if anything happens to me.
Kidd caught me in his cabin
robbing his desk.
I lied to him.
Told him I was a king's informer.
Good. Yes,
but he didn't believe me. Nothing. Wait.
He just pretended to.
Oh. Why didn't you shoot him?
Then? He will give us no more trouble.
That's a pleasure.
I'm reserving for later.
He proves the latter, I think.
Him King's men.
Oh, no.
He betrayed an uncommon interest
in the 12 apostles.
I didn't like him. Still around seven.
I mean to find out why. Why?
You could have charged him with robbery
and turn him over the yardarm.
All legal and shipshape.
I would have been rid of him once
and for all.
Let's not be impetuous, Mr. Poliakoff.
Leave us as he swims.
Would be
rather amusing to find out what he does.
Do you rest easy.
Leave.
Must have mercy on me. You.
Will.
Stay at home.
Oh. Have the boat and pipe to Curtis.
Pipe to put up.
The queendom much?
And sure enough.
And you make her out.
Captain Russell, who?
She hasn't
the cut of a buccaneer, your Excellency.
Much too tidy for that.
More like the kingship that she has.
The lines of a merchantman.
Have the longboat ready and, man,
don't put him up.
Stand by to put a shot across her bows.
Mr. mercy, I, sir.
Number four gun crews,
stand by for action.
She's flying the English colors.
Perhaps she's. Our escort ship.
Was about here.
We were to meet, wasn't it?
We make it certain just the same.
It's a hit.
You see
that? All hands are at the station.
Very good. Sir.
Ready?
Fire!
Place Mr.
Massey on top. It.
I discovered this garbage is sir.
You will come across.
This is the Longboat Key.
Convey my compliments to all officers
who will dress
as befitting a kingship. I.
Captain William Kidd of His Majesty's
privateer.
Adventure. At your service, sir.
Mr. Povey.
miss. Surgeon.
Mr. mercy, me, master.
Mr. Lorenzo, my navigator.
Welcome aboard,
gentlemen, I'm Captain Russell,
I'm Lord postman, His Majesty's ambassador
to the court of the ground.
Mock up your obedience, sir.
I've been sent to give you a convoy.
And we'd better make haste
with our business.
These are unhealthy waters for ships
to be hoped to.
As I discovered a day or so ago.
You mean
you cited some of the Pirate Brotherhood?
More than that, sir,
we beat up two of them.
Hey, Brown color for that of last hope.
Some kind of leaks out of here.
Oh, stuff down there for God.
Could you spare us some powder and ball?
We use more than was safe
during the action.
Why all that?
You need, sir, and welcome Mr.
Lorenzo here. Could attend to that.
We stay here.
You take Mr. Lorenzo below
and see that he gets what he wants.
I said captain of the.
Sense of the master.
He'll take care of all your needs. And?
Wish.
Mr. Lorenzo
and me.
Thank these powder and put it in the long
balls. I.
Gentlemen made on the navy and
Captain Kidd and his
Mr. Mercy.
Haven't we met before?
I think not when me.
You remind me of someone I've seen.
I think it impossible
that we could have ever met.
That.
How do we proceed now, captain?
Well, I'm instructed
to give you a protection past Madagascar,
and you'll be safe
as long as we sail in company.
But Avery will be a wolf at your heels.
And if we are separated in darkness.
Oh, storm.
And, what would you advise then, sir?
Well,
I suppose we could take Lord Paul's
with lady and,
board the adventure to Madagascar instead.
And then if we are separated
and this vessel should be taken.
What about the treasure on board?
One silver chest alone.
A present to His Majesty
from the Grand Mogo contains
precious gems
valued at more than 1 million pounds.
May I suggest, Your Excellency now?
Why not transfer the treasure chest
with yourself and Lady Anne on board
the adventure? And to.
We are out of danger.
She's a kingship
that is a great responsibility.
And although my instructions are that
you are to trust me
in all matters,
I don't know if I could go so far as.
What else can we do?
Three of them against
this will even two, sir.
We'd be hopeless. It's the wisest course.
I defer to Your Excellency.
Now, could we inspect the chests?
We could have them slung into our boats
along with the gear of Lord Paul's
with them, lady. And I said to me.
Come this up.
No trouble at all.
Hoist away!
Mr. Hervey,
I send for the manifest, captain.
You may check it
against the contents of this chest.
And give me your receipt, if you will.
Gladly, gladly. Oh, there you are, Mr.
Renzo, have you, completed your business?
Almost.
Your people have been most kind
to be done, Russell.
There is only one detail left.
It will not take a minute.
Finished up.
Then we must be gone within the hour.
Yes. Copy. Done.
Oh, manifest.
Would you attend to that, Mr. Perry?
Thank you very much, captain.
Mr. Lorenzo, you've seen a lovely lady
before.
This.
A tribute to your beauty, ma'am.
did you finish your business below?
Yes, captain.
Then we'd better be underway.
Mr. Mercy, you will see Lord
Paul's with the lady and the boat.
I see.
You walking?
They plan for the long run.
You will look after the lounging.
Mr. Lorenzo.
I apologize,
but I did try poor accommodations.
But we've had a chat.
Well, we'll see the show made comfortable.
It's a pleasure
to have Your Ladyship aboard.
If you'll follow.
Why hasn't it happened?
She's blown up.
Someone must have touched over
the magazine.
Send out your boats at one son.
You can't ask me to risk men there.
That show.
Let me go,
captain. No!
No. Excuse me.
Milady.
Your father.
May I say sorry? I am.
The captain is requested that you take
your meals in the main cabin.
Oh, no.
Shadwell, I can't bear to face those men.
I can't, I quite understand, milady.
But the captain's orders are orders.
Shadwell, you must help me.
There's no one else I can trust.
What can I do, milady?
I'm only a servant.
Oh, where can I turn?
I I'm so confused and frightened. I.
Think of my father and the others
lost back there.
And on the ship,
wherever I go, those horrible staring
men had Lorenzo,
who was always standing behind me,
beside me.
Last night there was a tapping on the door
when I opened it.
There he was there, that
evil, smiling face of his
where he might
better belong with those pirates
you found a few days ago.
The pirates.
Merlin.
We fought no pirates,
my father said.
Captain Kidd told.
Shad.
Well, what manner of ship is this?
My father was killed
deliberately, I'm sure of it, sir.
That's
why I got back to face your captain.
I accuse him.
That is a man on board, milady.
A gentleman whom I know you can trust,
Mr. Mercy.
Yes, milady.
Shadwell,
I know I've never seen him before.
No matter how he denies it.
His name is mercy.
Who is he?
All I really know is milady.
He's now a friend of the captain's.
Perhaps if I ask him.
Who shall I call?
Yes, will you please?
Yes, milady.
I am asking you again.
Very nice, my dear.
Be done.
Oh! Fancy manners.
You're not impressed me, Mr. Lorenzo.
When do we divide the gold in London?
Not before. I'm
there. Look, are we done?
I would make a bargain with you.
A thug in.
Everybody wants to bargain with me.
You and messy foreign thought.
What do you think
I am, a stinking sausage merchant?
What kind of a bargain?
The girl.
All my life
I have dreamed of a beautiful woman
like that.
Give me half of my denaro now
and you can split the rest between you,
if you will let me have her
fie on him.
He's met with love again.
I want her, and I am going to take her
whether I like it or not.
With all this treasure on board,
the crew is like a barrel of hot
gunpowder.
All that is needed
is a word in the right ears.
Do you mean look at me.
You're a witness.
He's inciting the crew to mutiny.
I know nothing like that.
Done. I was only joking.
You have a very nasty way of joking, Mr.
Lorenzo.
As for the girl,
I have my own plans for her.
They do not include you.
Get out. To.
Who is it?
Adam, listen.
You see, I'm.
Thank you for coming, Mr.
Murcia. I don't names Adam Bloom,
son of Lord black.
I knew it, I know
well, what are you doing on this ship?
My father was killed
and accused of piracy.
Few people believe.
Don't blame the king did.
That's why I went to sing and turned
pirate three years ago.
That's why I'm on this ship.
I knew that
some day I'd come upon the truth
that you have.
It was Captain Kidd
who killed your father.
Wasn't.
Adam.
Wonderful.
He did the same thing to my father,
the butcher
taken me three years to track him down.
Three years of degradation.
Now I can cut him away.
I want him, and he knows it.
You mean he knows what you are?
He knows something.
That's why you didn't admit to me
who you are.
Why are you avoiding me?
If Kidd knows we shared this, he could
kill you with a little compunction.
As he means to kill me if I let him.
What can I do to help?
It must be something.
Forget
everything you've seen on this ship.
Play up time. Be friendly.
That way you'll be safe
now when you get back to London.
No matter what has happened to me.
Go to the Lords of the Admiralty
and the King.
You'll be doing me
a great service as well as yourself.
I will add him, I promise.
You're going to have trouble with Lorenzo.
A meeting of the lambs. Exciting!
The tiger is blood
is getting too rich for him.
He'd be the better for bleeding.
Things are getting a bit complicated,
milord.
The King
may accept the elimination of the queen.
The Virgin next.
Maybe
even the sudden demise of Lord Bosworth.
But what about the lady
who said you had plans for?
Do they include Mr. Povey?
The little dears is safe with me
as if she was my daughter.
My passion is power and gold.
Since she suspects nothing,
I deliver her to His Majesty,
along with his share
of the Queen of merchants goods.
Oh! Weep appropriately over
the untimely demise of her.
received the grateful thanks of me.
Sovereign and a peerage is mine,
Lord love, if you will.
But that's what ought to have another man.
No devil shall stop me.
Shadwell, Senorita.
Milady, do not be alarmed.
Now that she knows
who I am, the kind of a ship
she's on,
I think we can count on to keep her here.
You stay here till I come off.
Watch.
Shadwell.
Lose your head.
Least luck's with us tonight.
Whichever either of them
would you like to see survive?
Mr. mercy, you did well to protect her.
Well.
You all right, sir?
Yes, I'm all right.
Look at the lady at.
Arms!
Let my medallion.
It's gone.
Has the plane crest on it?
Plane?
Perhaps I can find it.
Please. No.
It must have come off
just before Lorenzo went through the port.
Chad will take away the end to a cabin.
Oh, please. Adam,
I can't go in there. You must.
And this is serious.
It involves you. Remember?
No matter what Trixie tries,
you've never seen me before.
And you don't know who I am. Shadwell,
I think.
Oh, don't worry about me, Jeanette.
He never could get anything out of me.
And you never will.
It's the only way you'll be safe.
Shadwell.
Watch out for you.
What about you, Adam? What would he do?
The same thing he's done with the others.
If he gets a chance.
What? Don't worry.
I at least know what to expect. Go.
Shadwell, if anything does
happen, remember you the stand by lady
and see that you get safely to London.
I'll stick my life on it. I know you will.
Be careful, Adam.
Please be careful.
Come.
The lady.
Oh! He's no king's head.
Who is it, then?
Tomorrow
he put it into the lagoon for water.
And while the crew's getting it on board,
you and me and Mr.
Mercer, he's going to the cave.
You're going to take him in there?
I have a peculiar humor to watch my clever
young friends face when we dig out ship.
Sweet dreams.
Come.
They pass, Mr.
mercy, you haven't got forever.
Who might this be?
But perhaps a man
that has too many questions.
Gently.
Now, Mr. Mercy, you've come on. Something.
So it was the 12 apostles.
They. Captain?
Yes, it was Mr.
Mercy.
You open it up.
Blames.
He was a brave seaman, but foolish.
Did you happen to know him, Mr. mercy?
I heard of him.
I thought perhaps you had.
This.
Is yours,
Mr.. I,
traded a ring for it.
One of Avery's men?
Yes.
When I encountered Lord flying at sea,
I did my simple duty as a loyal subject.
A pity
he turned pirate and traitor to his king.
Liar!
Was. He's made for the sharks now, Mr.
Appleby, the tide comes in at this place
in half an hour.
We've nothing more to fear.
Yeah, sure. I haven't come it. Yeah.
It's a long voyage.
Helpless to poke at anything might happen.
Naturally, her ladyship
is still very distressed
in the midst of life.
We are in death, Shadwell.
And though my heart may my heart bleeds.
Confound you, Shadwell.
You drove
the thought right out of the head,
and it was an uncommon pretty one,
I'm sure of that.
It got all at once to tell us
she can't mourn forever.
Nigel, I expect you to take our meals
in the main cabin with the rest of us.
Very well.
Well, that
we turned just in time to see him
go over the edge.
Such for now.
It never came up.
Well,
here's to him,
wherever it is.
You feeling ill?
Yes, sir.
I'll go to my cabin.
With your permission, if you wish.
It's been quite a trying voyage,
what with one little thing and another.
But bear up. You'll soon be home again.
I warned Adam not to come.
No one could have stopped you.
It was cold blooded. Plan delivered.
The same will happen to Her ladyship.
Unless we can.
Read them.
How did you find you on board, sir?
I've come back for lady. Oh,
thank you sir.
I've been hanging on the rudder chains and
stock waiting for the turn of the watch.
The jolly boat's motor stayed.
I waited alongside.
It's secured right down at this point
where I'd get in it
and drift aft under the main cabin.
Well, now, get me some dry clothes.
Where's the captain?
In his own cabin, with Mr.
Purvis on examining the silver chest
they brought back on board
my father's chest.
Chadwick Kidd doesn't suspect you.
Tell me the end
to get some things together.
And when the coast is clear,
you come back for me? Yes, sir.
I, sir,
I felt
rather hot by watching the daybreak.
Well, weighing on the morning tide,
I thought.
Kidd doesn't suspect Shadwell.
He's staying on board.
He'll be evidence for us in London.
Watching the small boat,
the water staying.
We're all ashore.
Then we're at home.
Two days journey.
Overland is the pirate town of last Hope.
It's the most lawless place on Earth.
But I have friends there.
Somehow
they'll find us a ship for England.
England?
Now come on.
Get down on the boat!
Goodbye.
The lady climbed aboard. Got.
A scene in England.
I know who's in that book now.
Come on.
Where?
Thank you.
May Lord.
Where?
Is the London?
Why? But.
Hold on to me.
Take.
Why? Me.
He's dead as a mackerel.
He's gone through
all right.
I guess I've never met captain.
I'm good. Reckless.
Back to the ship, boy.
If you're thinking what I think
you're thinking, my friend, forget it.
As a little measure of a letter
I left in London.
Spoilsport.
Well.
From. I'm.
When.
Captain William Kidd.
Greetings, captain.
What news have you brought me from the
Indian seas for your leave, Your Majesty.
Both good and ill, but mostly
very good indeed.
I return
by way of the American colonies. So?
So I understood
with the main points of your voyage.
I am familiar.
I wonder if you can enlighten me
about the affair of the Queen's godchild.
Lady and Dunstan and your ship, master Mr.
Mercy.
Oh, that poor, impetuous fellows here
inveigle that badge of innocence
he did into running away with him
and catching him red handed in defense.
The very life I was forced to dispatch
him both rest in peace.
Tell me, captain, about the treasure
and the merchant.
Unfortunate, sire.
Most unfortunate.
We ship.
But that chest, when she blew
and all souls went heavenward.
Rest in peace to them.
Ditto.
I see
now about the 12 apostles and Lord Blaine.
You encounter any trace naysayer.
I can only hope that the weight
of his sins sank both him and the ship.
I see
then how do you explain this?
Whose might that be, your Majesty?
My officers found it on your ship
at Plymouth after you left for London.
It bears the Blaine crest,
which I believe you are not unfamiliar.
I've always felt that, Mr.
Pope. A message in a very while.
A fellow indeed
was hiding something from me
or hiding it in a secret laceration.
You are Kevin, captain.
I hope it has a proper explanation, sire.
Mr. Pope, he was killed three days ago.
Defending it with his dying oath.
He swore it was not his prep. Shadwell.
Mere ballot slip to the board might not
have come to my Madagascar cave, captain.
Something dreadful clear about all this.
Isn't that what the allies look?
Nightmare.
A pity you overlooked last hope, captain.
We stood on the headland with my friend
Avery and watched you sail by.
May I please, your Majesty,
I accuse this man of piracy and murder.
Was ever a gentleman.
So Misfortunate lock him up in
Newgate is to be held for the next session
of the Court of Orient.
Time and I
that have been tried for his life.
I'm sorry.
You cannot.
Oh, I don't wish to the credit.
I'm for the honor and glory of England.
So he is may bequest to them.
What hunch would I have heard?
And to their sons, hands
down,
through the endless corridors of time.
Greed that spawns murder.
Hatred
that corrodes the soul.
Ambition.
The foulest trumpet of all.
Hey, Jack.
Jack ketch,
send me that note for sixpence yet.
Save you my name, lads.
You can have it all for nothing.
If you'd only step up here and wear it.
I need it,
can't wait forever.
Captain Kidd is dead, milord Lane.
His account is closed.
Now I want manikin.
I have turned for the injustice.
I wept upon your father.
I'll put you up.
See, Lord, what do you suggest?
We have a fine frigate of 50 guns
commissioned for American waters, sire.
That we thought of naming the lady and
it should be a wedding gift to you
from the Crown.
Your loyalty
and service to King and country.