Attention! Attention!
The Langford express
now arriving
The Langford Express
now arriving track 6.
All right boys, let's go.
One two three
Come on fellows.
What do you say Joe?
You're sure seeing
Europe the hard way.
Ah, it's better than dodging
those sheriffs in Kentucky.
Besides we might do
pretty good here.
Hi lover, did you miss me?
Miss you! I couldn't
sleep, couldn't eat
- couldn't think
- Yeah, ah hah,
You couldn't even write
you muscle bound ape.
Come on, hurry it up,
get in line.
You've got the only good looking
pair of legs in the show.
Come on.
Ah!
Straight from Hawaii.
Come on over to the
carnival grounds tonight.
Come on out tonight and
see a great show.
Let your eyes gaze upon the
wonders of all wonders.
All right, hold it,
hold it, hold it!
Now pat attention everybody.
The cook outs are
straight ahead.
Living quarters over here.
We go on tonight.
I'll meet you in the cook outs
at 6:30 and give you the
rest of the low down. Okay.
All right everybody,
quiet, quiet.
Quiet! Just a moment.
Now you all know why
we're here in Europe.
Back home we didn't do so good.
As a matter of fact,
we didn't do anything.
They won't look at you freaks
anymore even if we paid them.
The only one who came
around was a sheriff.
Now this is the first
American carnival
that ever played Germany.
Nobody knows whether they're
going to go for us or not.
But I figure this way,
we might turn into a freak
novelty if we give them
straight America mud show corn.
So, forget where you are.
Play it straight to
the hillbillies.
Now you talkers, you'll
have to work in German.
I've had translations made
of all the ballyhoos.
So you read them right out.
And if we can't talk them in...
Pray them in.
The lady with acres of charm.
The one and only Miss Daisy May
Captain Snyder
Sword swallower extraordinaire
The human flamethrower.
This is giant Vice Groppo.
He was worshiped as a God.
Uh, animist God.
By the Dayak tribe of
central Borneo.
Where he was captured
after a terrific battle.
Uh... kampf.
Here we show him as a gesture
And in American Friendship
to all the people in the world.
(Speaking German)
All of these remarkable
little ladies here
(Speaking German)
to the Gods of their fathers.
Watch the perfect control.
Control
Of the 200 separate and
distinct muscles of the, uh...
of the belly.
Yeah.
All right, 50 cents. 50 cents.
Only 50 pennies.
Come on, only 50 pennies boys
and inside works warmer, they
don't wear so many clothes.
There, who's next? You are.
Yes sir, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Step up sucker.
(Speaking German)
Come back in half an hour.
A cola, honey.
(Speaking German)
Thank you.
Hey you!
(Speaking German)
Oh!
- I'm hungry.
- Hungry?
You're hungry for what? Blood?
Suck the wound,
it may be poisonous.
If you're hungry, why don't
you go ahead and eat it.
Thank you very much.
You speak pretty good English.
How come?
Of course I do
A hangover from the time
You're a pretty
good looking girl.
So...
You know what might
be good for you.
A little time in jail for
picking pockets.
Some honest work.
Can you get me work?
Might get you a job
here in the carnival.
I can do anything.
I'm very strong.
You mean it?
Yeah.
Come on.
Let's go see.
- What's your name?
- Willie.
- Villie?
Oh, Willie.
It's not my real name.
Someone called me that
one time and it stuck.
My name's Joe.
Joe Hammond.
Hi Willie.
Alright.
Joe!
What's the matter?
I've got some
information for you.
You did not count your money.
I think this must be yours.
Thanks.
Willie, remember this,
anytime you ever catch a thief
be sure and search
him very thoroughly.
Charley!
Charley.
Well, uh, looks like we're
doing all right now, huh?
Yeah. They're really going
for that Tennessee Dutch.
Oh, uh, this is Willie.
Willie? From here
it looks like a girl.
I think she is.
She'd like to join up
with us Charley.
Oh now listen Joe,
I can't put everybody
you pick up on the payroll.
No, no, look.
This is an exception.
She's going to, uh... She's
going to teach me German.
You know, to help
out with the spiel.
What else can she do?
Now this is serious.
You can put her to
work in the cook house.
- Washing dishes.
- I will do anything Mr. Grayson
Even a few days
work will help me.
Okay. Sleep her with the
hula dancers, I guess.
You show up at the cook
house at 6:30 in the morning.
Thank you, Mr. Grayson.
Ahh.
Oh don't worry about him.
He's harmless.
I had him released from
the asylum in Alabama.
- He's
- No No No No No.
No he's just a little stupid.
And he's a dummy.
You know. He can't talk.
Go back to your tent Groppo.
Go back to your tent!
- Kids.
- Get out of here ya Tom.
- Shut that flap.
- Oh shut up a minute.
Come on. Come on!
This is Willie. She's
gonna stay with you a while.
Well baby this is your new home.
What's the matter?
- Um
- What's the matter?
Look uh, I've been traveling.
I'm unclean.
I'd be ashamed for
them to see me.
Is there some place where
I could take a bath?
Sure.
Hey uh. I guess the only clothes
you own are the ones you got on
Yes.
Well. I think we can find
something for you.
Come on.
Which one do I pull?
- What do you want hot or cold?
- I want hot.
Then pull the one on the right.
Huh! Ahh! Oh! Oh it's cold!
- It takes a little while.
- Ah! Oh No!
Ahh! Umm!
Ahhh.
You wet all over?
Um. All over.
Let go of the chain
and soap yourself.
Oh.
Soap is expensive you know.
Oh it feels so good.
You all soaped all over?
Every bit of me.
I'm all smothered in bubbles.
I'm all slippery in
soap and it's wet.
Then go ahead and rinse off.
Oh. Oh I hate to do it.
How do you feel now?
Uh. Clean.
You look clean.
- Umm. You smell clean.
- Ha ha.
- I bet you taste clean too.
- No, no. Please don't.
What's the matter? What's this.
You've been kissed before.
What difference does that make?
I've been married before.
Would that make you
want to marry me?
I've been hurt before. Would
that make you want to hurt me?
Uh-huh. I don't
want to hurt you.
No. Please, please.
What's the matter?
You said I'd been kissed before.
Yes I have. Many times.
But.
But what?
I'll tell you only this.
For me you're different.
Don't take from me.
Let me give.
Oh? When.
When, when I've had
time to think a little.
Hi!
- Hi!
What's for supper tonight?
Meatloaf!
You're the new girl in
the cook tent aren't you?
How did you guess?
What are you doing up there?
Testing the gi wire.
Oh.
Say. I used to pay the
other girl a little extra
to bring a pot of coffee to
my tent just after the act.
That be ok with you?
Be glad to. You have
sugar and cream?
Black.
Ladies and gentlemen
The amazing act from
the Colloni wonder show
From the height of 110 feet
Uh, I mean Uh
(attempting German)
Still trying to speak German.
Which is only six feet deep.
Uh, (attempting German)
Ladies and gentlemen
the great Colloni.
- Here's the coffee.
- Fine just put it on the chair.
Now that's real service.
How do you say thanks in German?
Danke schoen.
- Danke schoen.
- And you deserve it.
I saw your dive.
Like it?
Well you're very brave but it
frightened me.
Ha. It would probably scare me
too if I saw it from the ground.
Ooh. I've got a headache.
You get them often?
- Once in a while.
Depends how I hit.
Will you let me rub your neck?
I used to be good at it.
Alright.
Um.
You've got strong hands.
- Hard work makes strong hands.
- They always do hard work?
Not always.
Who are you?
Where you from?
That's not important.
Ah. It's wonderful.
My headache feels
better already.
Thank you.
It was a very quick cure.
Would you mind walking
across the room please?
Why?
I want to see how you move.
How you carry yourself.
Very well.
You mind taking off your dress?
At some times there are phrases
in English I do not understand.
Did you ask me to
take my dress off?
Afraid of me?
I'm not afraid of anyone.
Well?
You know what I was thinking?
Probably.
You're wrong.
I've been thinking lately
the act might go better
if I had a partner.
That's all. Just an idea.
- A lady partner?
- That's right. Can you swim?
Yes but you were thinking of me.
Why not? You've got good legs,
good shoulders, strong hands
That's important when
you're coming up.
You move well have good balance.
Yes but why do you ask me?
There are many who move well.
Well if you don't
want to just say so.
I... I don't really mean that I
don't want to it's just that
I'm scared to death
just thinking about it.
I know. I used to
be that way myself.
But I found you can do anything
you make up your mind to do.
Here. For the coffee.
Oh. Thanks.
Why don't you think
about it for a while.
I'll be able to earn a great
deal of money wouldn't I?
A lot more than you're
making in that cook tent.
- A lot more?
- Uh huh.
Think it over.
I will.
- Goodnight.
Joe.
- Oh. Hi Willie.
- Hello.
What's this? Bedside
service for the great Colloni?
Yeah. And uh he said
something tonight
I want to ask you about.
Oh, what?
He wants me to be his partner.
In the diving business.
He said he would teach me.
Well.
Maybe uh, maybe he's
on the make for you.
Oh no. He's very serious.
He said I'd be able to
earn a lot of money.
What did you tell him?
I said I'd need a little
time to think about it.
I thought I better
ask you first.
Ask me? Why?
See if you minded or not.
Mind it.
Baby you've been
overdue for a good break.
You think I'd stand in your way?
No, no, no. I know you wouldn't.
It's very dangerous you know.
Ahh!
I'm afraid.
Don't people. People get killed
everyday in the bath tub.
Anything's dangerous.
You really think I could do it?
I know you can do it.
But listen you.
I don't want that
Wisconsin cheese eater
moving in on my girl.
I'm glad you're jealous.
Sure I'm jealous.
I um, I gotta go check with
Charlie about the receipts.
See you later.
Night.
Goodnight.
Oh even ten feet
looks high from here.
It is.
Ahh!
Lesson number 1. Never look up.
Not even when you're climbing.
- Yeah.
- Never look up.
Now try it.
No matter how high you are
take one look down at the tank.
Just one.
Then look straight ahead.
Shouldn't I watch you
do it once or twice?
Nope. This is the way to do it.
Now look. You watch me.
Turn around.
Soon as your head touches water.
The very instant you feel water
Bring your back full up like
this and reach for air.
You do that you
won't touch bottom.
You ever do touch bottom
from real height you're gone.
Got it?
Alright. I'll try it.
Alright you go on out to the end
and do exactly what I tell you
when I tell you
Alright. Look down just once.
Look straight ahead.
Up on your toes.
Deep breath.
Now fall forward.
You got splattered.
Yes. I know.
But how was the rest of it?
Terrible. Now go on up
there and do a good one.
More gravy darling.
Oh yeah. Thank you.
Hi.
- What's to eat honey?
- Meatloaf.
Honey, my cup's dirty.
So is your face my dear.
But we can get a new cup.
- Don't you dare grin.
- Who's grinning?
These dishes need washing.
Hurry up with it.
- Well get with it.
- You get with it.
You'd feel sorry for
everything that wears skirts.
Come on. It's only 25 feet.
I'll mark you up for good.
Cut it out!
You want to fight
take it to the alley.
Break it up!
Go on Tami. You'll find
him on top of some fence.
Don't whistle for me.
- Been in a fight?
- Yes. You guess with whom.
I don't like it.
Whistling for me.
That's for a dog.
You never let me
know ahead of time.
You never take me out.
You just call for me as
if I were your servant.
Baby what kind of a beef is
this? You know I'm busy.
I don't know when
I'm going to be free.
Well, from now on
you have to find out.
You must treat me like a
person who has feelings.
- Instead of..
- Instead of what?
Instead of what you think I am.
Baby I think you're mine too.
Anything wrong with that?
You shouldn't be so certain.
I can't help it if I'm certain.
Come on. Lets take a walk. Huh?
- No.
What do you mean no?
I think you are fond
of the that high diver.
I'm not falling for anybody.
You're falling for somebody.
Alright now I want you to
arch your back more and
you get to the surface
faster. You understand?
Ok. Otherwise
you're doing alright.
Come on. It's only 75 feet.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Now lets see you do
a really good one.
- How was it?
- Pretty good.
Deserves a little present.
You go get dried off.
Come over to the tent I
got something for you.
Oh but it's wonderful.
Oh it's so beautiful.
You're going to wear it tonight.
Tonight?
Sure. You're going
off the top tonight.
Oh.
Shouldn't I try it just once?
You only hit the top once
in your whole life Willie.
After that it's never the same.
There's only one way to
hit the top the first time.
Right out there where the music
is playing and everybody
in the whole world is watching.
- Yes but...
- Here. Take this.
Go ahead.
Just one.
Go on take it.
It'll relax you.
There.
You go on to your
tent and lie down.
I'll wake you when it's time.
- But what if..
- Go on Willie.
That stuff hits you fast.
Willie.
You go on in six minutes.
Time to get dressed.
Six minutes.
- Frank I'm frightened.
- Well I should hope so.
If you aren't I'd think
you were crazy.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the show.
(speaking German)
The great Colloni.
I should have said
the great Collonis.
Look at the town Willie.
Enjoy this feeling.
Look at those lights.
See other cities other towns
shining like that tonight.
Be way up here.
Cool and far away and high.
Looking down on them.
Never letting them touch you.
The moment I've
been waiting for.
I love you very much.
I wanted to tell you up here.
On your first night.
I love you Willie.
I want you to marry me.
You can tell me later.
Now. You're on your own.
Music's over. The act is on.
Hey. What's the trouble?
Something happened tonight.
Which makes me very unhappy.
- Frank asked me to marry him.
- What?
The cheese eater
wants to marry you?
Well what do you know.
Why should you be unhappy?
Because he's in love with me and
I don't love him.
Well uh
Maybe you should
learn to love him.
What do you mean by that?
That Wisconsin
hillbilly should have
a good wad stashed away by now.
You could do a lot worse.
But Joe, I...what uh..
You mean about us?
Look.
We're not going to
let a little thing like
you being married
come between us.
If you ever touch me again.
I'll kill you.
Alright all you
beggars and thieves.
Like the man said, ahh
there's good news today.
The show's a big hit and
we got a brand new star.
And here she is the
other half of the team
of the Great Collonis.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
This is the happiest
day of my life.
Not only because
I really feel a part
of the show now
But because
From now on the Collonis are
not just going to be a team
They're going to be
Mr. and Mrs. too.
Music! Music! Music!
Everybody dance.
Frank.
Hey Frank.
Bill. Bill Vines.
What are you doing here?
I'm here on an assignment
for Life Magazine.
- Wonderful.
- Uh
aren't you forgetting something?
Oh excuse me.
Willie this is Bill Vines.
He was combat photographer
assigned to our regiment when
I was peeling spuds
for company K.
- She's my new partner.
- Hello Willie.
I uh didn't know Frank had
such a good eye for partners.
Come on everybody
kiss the bride.
Alright. Stand in line
and take your turn.
Alright next.
I'm not going to
miss out on this.
You're getting a swell guy.
All the luck in the world.
Thank you. No, Groppo,
Groppo. You too.
Come on. Come on
and kiss the bride.
Ahhh.
Lift her up so we
can all see it Groppo.
What do you want?
Uh, nothing I guess.
Just thought I'd drop over
and see how you're doing.
How things are going.
They go very well and
you shouldn't be here.
Yes you're right, but
Baby
I never see you alone anymore.
You saw me alone.
You'll see me alone for
the rest of your life.
You didn't want us this way.
I know.
I made a mistake.
I'm made it but
it doesn't mean I
have to like it this way.
No. But there's nothing
I can do about it now.
I guess not.
Oh there is
There's one thing you
could do for me.
Uh.
You see I uh, I got
myself in a jam and
I need a couple hundred bucks.
I thought maybe you could let
me have it for a few days...
I haven't got it.
What do you mean
you haven't got it?
Frank takes care of our money.
I haven't got it.
Well.
Thanks anyway.
Baby.
Something else I need.
You've got it.
No Joe.
Maybe I can get the money quick.
Soon as I can. Maybe
tonight maybe tomorrow.
You've got to go.
Alright. I'll see you tonight.
Meet me at the uh carousel.
Better make it about 12:00.
He'll be asleep by then.
Ahh. You're crazy.
Frank finds you here I don't
know what he'll do to you.
I'll take that chance.
See you tonight.
- Hello Mrs. Colloni.
- Hello.
I saw him come out of
here you dirty little cheat.
- And if you ever do it again..
- Be quiet.
- Well hello, Frank.
- Hi ya, Peggy.
See you later doll.
So long.
What was she doing here?
Borrowing thread.
I don't like these
Sunday afternoon shows. I
I like the lights when I dive.
Wanna get dressed?
We go on in 20 minutes.
Ladies and gentlemen. I want you
to meet the wonder of our show.
The fire eater extraordinary.
Captain Schnieder he heats
the swords in the fire.
Ladies and gentlemen. Welcome
to our show. I now present the
Great Collonis.
You waited a little too long
after you looked at the tank.
- That's dangerous.
- I know.
Nothing bothering you is there?
No I just made a mistake. Why
should anything be bothering me?
Come inside so
no one can see us.
Look Joe I haven't
got the money.
I couldn't think of way of
asking him without it
seeming strange.
- Don't you know where it is?
- No. I never asked.
What kind of dame are you
you don't know where your
husband keeps his money.
Look. I'll find some other
way to get the money.
I've got to go back.
- No baby I don't want you to..
- No get away from me.
Ok.
I told you I'd kill
you and I will.
What's the matter with you?
What are you talking
about, you'll kill me.
If I knocked you
down and kicked you
you wouldn't do
anything about it.
Couldn't cause
you're in love with me.
Couldn't help yourself.
Joe, you hurt me.
Baby, nobody else is ever gonna
come close to you except me.
Nobody ever.
You're going back there and
you're gonna get that money
and you're gonna bring it to me.
We're gonna leave together.
You and me.
Oooh Rat!
Aah!
Oh Joe.
I fight and I fight but it
doesn't do any good.
Until I met you. I never
knew how rotten I was.
If you're rotten.
We're both rotten.
Two of a kind.
We belong together.
Don't fight it.
Come here Willie.
Frank!
- Frank!
- Get.
No Frank!
Frank!
No! Stop it! Stop!
Go to your tent.
Go to your tent!
He's leaving the show
Charlie. Tonight.
I ever see you again I'll
really finish the job.
I don't want no trouble
in my show Joe.
You better pack your things.
Come by my tent I'll
give you your money.
Better start packing. We're
leaving the show tomorrow.
What are we going to do?
I'll tell you what
we're going to do.
We're going to the States
and buy a farm and live on it.
And work on it with
our own hands.
When you're so tired you won't
have ideas of playing around.
I won't go.
You'll go where ever I tell ya.
Do you think you can move
me around like some varmint?
Your cat. I'm not an
animal I'm a human being.
- You don't act like one.
- I won't go.
I don't love you.
I won't go with you.
I hate you. I hate every
man in the world and I
hate you most of all.
I don't belong to you. I don't
belong to you or anyone else.
And I want my money.
I earned it.
You have no right
to keep it from us.
I'm not keeping it for
myself. I'm saving it for you.
Where is it? Why don't
you show it to me?
You must think. You
must think I'm very stupid.
Oh! I've got to get
my mind right.
All I want is my money.
I'm all through with you
and I want my money.
Shut up and go to bed.
Frank.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
I'm really not much good Frank.
But if you want me
I'll try to be a decent wife.
And the U.S.
and that is where
you want to farm
or anywhere else.
Then it might just
as well be here.
I guess that's what comes
with being a bachelor so long
I've done everything myself.
My own way.
Sometimes I forget that
I'm not alone anymore.
I'll try to be a good
husband for you Willie.
- Ready?
- Sure. Come on.
When will the pictures be
published?
Maybe never. I haven't got an
order for the assignment yet
but the, I think
they'll like them.
Uh, especially if you'll
uh open the cape a little.
Ooh. I hope this shows
up in the picture.
Frank gave it to me today.
Real diamonds.
Beautiful.
Any special occasion?
A birthday or something?
No. No birthday.
But uh, a very special occasion.
Nolan my assistant and I will be
popping up all over the place.
But it will all be this
flash stuff so just
play like we're not alive. OK?
- Bye.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The biggest act of the show.
We present The Great Collonis!
I hope that didn't disrupt you.
- No. Not at all Bill.
Aaaaah!!!
Stand back! Give us
room will you please.
No don't look.
Please.
- Is there, anything else?
- No, no, no.
Thank you very much.
You've been very nice.
I wish there were something I
could really do for you. I mean.
Really do.
I think all I need now
is a little rest.
It was a real nice
funeral Willie.
Nobody could ask for any better.
Yes. I'm sure Frank would have
thought it was a lovely funeral.
You get some rest.
You'll feel better in
2 or 3 days.
Charlie.
Why did everyone act so
strange at the funeral?
No one came near me.
On one spoke to me.
It's been that way
ever since he died.
Why worry about them.
They're nothing but a bunch
of characters anyway.
It's as if they think
I killed him.
Oh. You ought to know
better than that.
Gab, gab, gab.
That's all they ever do.
There was an investigation. It
was an accident and that's that.
Besides if they didn't
have this to talk about
they'd find something else.
It's possible.
Uh Willie.
I've got a little business I'd
like to talk over with you.
Frank's will.
He made it out the
day after the wedding.
You get everything Willie.
I think it's a little more
than you'd expect.
Five thousand dollars
cash money.
- Five thousand?
- Been saving for years
for that little farm.
Says you'll find it in the top
of the trunk back of the mirror.
Cause I'm sorta responsible.
I'd like to have you look
to see it's all there.
-Yeah?
- Alright.
Think we better count it
and see if it checks out?
No.
Frank said there was
5 thousand dollars.
That's what there is.
My whole life I dreamed of
having money.
I was much more modest
in my dreams.
Five thousand Marks
was all I wanted.
Now I have 5 thousand dollars.
And I don't want it.
Of course you don't.
I understand honey.
But Frank wanted
you to be happy.
Why don't you look
at it that way.
Charlie. I really have
to get some rest.
I'll go.
These pictures will
sell a lot of tickets.
I'll show 'em to the gang.
Poor Frank.
Even when he's dead he
makes money for Charlie.
Made money for me too.
I got an awful big check
for that layout Willie.
You see. People
like those pictures.
They dramatize death. Gives them
a thrill even in the photograph
to see Frank falling.
Ah perhaps.
Do you know why
they'll come now?
Cause they'll be
waiting for you to fall.
They'll want to be sure not
to miss it when you do.
Did it ever occur to you Bill
that people might
like to see diving just
because they like diving?
Not a dive like you make They're
waiting for you to make a slip.
They want to see you dead.
I want to see you alive.
Tell me about Frank and you.
Not much to tell.
We met. Fell in love.
Just like that.
Then we weren't alone anymore.
We did everything
together because
we couldn't stand
to be separated
even for a single minute.
That's why we became partners.
We were very happy.
Well at least he had that.
No.
He hadn't
I'll tell you what he had.
Really had.
He picked me up
out of the cook tent.
He taught me how
to earn a living.
He made a performer out of me.
He loved me and he married me.
By way of thanks I betrayed him.
I broke his heart.
And in one way or another
I killed him.
Did you love this other guy?
This heal?
- Will you take me home please?
- Sure.
No please.
Don't get out.
I feel like being alone.
Thank you so much.
Goodnight.
Hello Willie.
I uh.
I didn't want to come
around any earlier.
I was real sorry to
hear about Frank.
Were you?
Of course.
I mean like
somebody we know.
I heard you were
terrific your first dive.
After it happened.
I had a good teacher.
Yeah.
How's Peggy?
Peggy? Uh
She left.
I don't know.
Well I, I guess
I better be going.
Where are you going?
Haven't made up my mind yet.
Doesn't much matter.
If you wanted it I,
I think I could get Charlie
to give your old job back.
No baby.
You're doing alright
now and I want you to
I'm no good for you.
Joe.
Harry.
Hi Willie.
Will you get Charlie to come to
my tent as soon as he can?
- And it's very important.
- Sure.
- Right away.
- Thanks.
Wanna see me?
Sit down.
There's uh something
we haven't talked about.
Yeah?
What's that?
My new salary.
You were paying Frank
2 hundred and me 125.
That's 325 for the
whole act right?
Yeah well you see I..
From now on the act
only costs you 300.
I was thinking around 200 and
then maybe a little later...
It's 300 Charlie
or I don't go on.
And I'm not joking.
No, I don't believe you are.
Then it's settled?
Yeah.
By the way.
You haven't seen Joe around
this morning have you?
Joe? No why?
I didn't even know he was back.
He was.
Is there anything wrong Willie?
Not a thing. Why?
I was just wondering
the way you held me up for
that 300 dollars just now.
That wasn't like you Willie.
It's going to be like
me from now on.
I'm turning smart.
Very smart.
You don't have to convince me.
The Great Colloni.
You can tell them tonight
that I'll dive like Frank did.
I'll do the summersault dive.
Gee that's great kid but do
you know what you're doing?
Improving the act Charlie.
That's what I'm doing.
And after the dive
you come to my tent
and we'll talk about money.
More money to be exact.
MS. Colloni tonight will
attempt a summersault dive.
(speaking German)
Aaah!
Come here will you?
Willie! Come on Willie.
Ok. Ok. Take her arm.
The doctor says
you're going to be great.
It'll take a little while but
your going to be alright.
How did you get that
scar on your cheek?
Oh that that. I got a
nick during the war.
I was a photographer
at that headquarters
I was snapping a
photograph of some VIP
75 miles behind the
front one day when a
flashbulb exploded in my face.
I always felt they should have
given me the purple heart for it
I like it.
Gives you sort of a sporty look
You like?
I like very much.
Willie. I want to
ask you a question.
That's why I brought
you here. It's a very
- important question and I..
- Bill I, I can't.
I just can't.
I might even want
to but I can't.
You're throwing away
an awful lot of years
that might be good for us both.
I know.
I'll probably be sorry
for the rest of my life.
I've never brought good
fortune to anybody.
Least of all to myself.
Are you sure it isn't Joe?
Do you still love him?
I don't know what love is.
I think you love me.
Stop, with all those
people watching
Excuse me but you have a
phone call from Frankfurt.
Thank you.
I'll be right back.
Uhm. How much.
5 Marks.
Yes who's calling?
Charlie.
Oh how are things going?
Ah not so good Willie.
I thought we'd do better
here in Frankfurt.
The most important thing
is how are you?
I'm fine. The doctors
say they're going
to throw me out of
here the end of the week.
She's getting out
of here alright
but she's not coming
to Frankfurt.
She quit see, she's through.
You can take that diving tower
and you can sell it
to junk dealers.
But to tell you the
truth Charlie
I probably won't be coming back.
I think I have other plans.
Nice plans.
Uh. Just a minute.
There's somebody here
wants to talk to you.
Just a minute.
Hi ya Willie.
Yes.
Yes I'm much better.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
Your attention please.
The passengers of flight 418
from Munich to Frankfurt will
enter through gate number 2.
- Willie.
- Willie. Hello.
- I'm glad to see you.
How do you feel Willie?
How do you feel?
Ah I knew you'd come back.
This show is really
nothing without you.
Come on.
I'll show you your tent.
Where's Joe?
Oh he's in town trying to
drum up some business.
For me?
Oh Groppo.
We're very much alike you and I.
We have good things in us.
Lots of good things.
They're trapped there.
They can't come out.
Thank you.
Hi Willie.
Hello Joe.
I uh.
Oh yeah.
I uh guess I've got a
little explaining to do.
No. Everything's alright Joe.
Let's just forget it.
Willie.
Uh.
Willie I, I don't
want to forget it.
I want to talk to you.
Could I come back to
your tent after the show?
Sure Joe. I'd like to see you.
Ladies and gentlemen.
The star of our show.
The great Colloni.
Willie.
Why did you have to follow me?
If I were right for you I
would have come back.
Joe's here. Did you come
to Frankfurt to see him?
Yes. Yes I did.
Please believe me.
I'm not running after you.
I just want to be around
if you need me.
Look. I have to
be alone now Bill.
Don't follow me please.
You were terrific.
You're great.
That took a lot of guts.
I couldn't have done that.
I mean go back up there
after what happened.
Thank you.
Uh. Willie.
I know what I did was a,
was a real lousy thing to do
and I'm sorry.
The only thing I can say is I
want to make it up to you.
You want to give me
back the money?
Why sure baby. Sure.
But I want to do more than that.
Look. Without you this show
wouldn't be worth a penny.
You know that. And what's
Charlie paying you? Peanuts.
I can show you how to
make some real doe.
You know what you
should be getting?
A piece of this outfit.
And I mean a big piece.
And I'm going to see
that you get it.
That will be fine Joe.
Is that all you're
interested in?
Baby.
You know better than that.
It doesn't work Joe.
It doesn't work anymore.
What's the matter with you?
You nuts?
What are you talking about.
I'm free of you.
I didn't think I ever would be.
But I am.
Look baby. I don't blame you
for being sore about the money.
The money.
No Joe.
I'm only sorry it couldn't have
been put to some decent use.
Instead of being carried off to
the sewers by filth like you.
Now just a minute. Just hold it.
You can be sore.
But you or no other dame is
going to talk to me like that.
Now let's stop this nonsense.
Come here.
I won't.
- You'll do as I tell you to do.
- Not anymore Joe.
That's all over.
If you were starving to death
and howling for food
I wouldn't throw
you a rotten bone.
Ah!
Now.
I know what you're trying
to prove but knock it off.
It won't work.
You're stuck with me
baby and you know it.
Whatever I am. We're
both made of the same stuff.
We are not!
I'm not dirty like you.
When I saw your money
I was hungry.
Whatever I've done
wrong shames me.
But you
You love to wallow in the mud.
You've been paid in full.
Now get out of here.
Get out of here?
Get out.
You could stand just like that
and tell me to get out?
You think after what I did
Do you think I fixed that
bar on Franks ladder
for you to tell me to
get out of here?
Yeah. I did that.
I did it because I couldn't
stand to be without you.
I did it for us.
Because we belong together.
- You killed Frank?
- No. No. Not me.
We did it. The two of us.
The both of us.
Yeah.
That's what everybody will think.
Yeah. And I'll
let them think it.
Yeah.
Now.
Now tell me to get out of here.
Get Out!!
Ah. Uh.
Groppo!
Groppo. No! No! Come down!
No! No! Don't Shoot.
Come down Groppo.
They won't hurt you.
Please come down Groppo.
It's alright Groppo.
They won't harm you.
I know you did it for me.
And I'll tell them so.
You must go with them now.
No. He will not need those.
He will go with you now.
Poor Groppo.