Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
♪
Stay right were you are.
Don't move. Stay there now.
Steady.
Now sit up. Sit up, sit up you.
Up you fool up.
[Meow]
Sit up I said. Sit up.
[Hiss]
[Crash]
- Really Mr Livington.
- Oh I'm sorry. Please let me
help you.
Oh here.
[Hiss]
Buzz! Oh Buzz!
What's the matter?
- Buzz.
Take it easy what's the
matter?
- Look.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
- Take it away.
- Not here.
- Now wait a minute there. Take
it easy Stanley.
This is a
harmless little kitten.
Buzz I'm scared to death. Why
the look on his face.
I can't understand why you have
this terrible fear of animals
in you. What is it?
- When I was a little baby I was scared by my piggy bank.
- That's nonsense.
- You want to hear something worse?
- What?
I was 15 years old before I ate
my first animal cracker.
Come on, stores about to open
up.
Fix up your counters. Now get
to work. Come on, go on.
And how. Yes sir. That's the
truth.
- How do you do? May I help you?
- Do you happen to have a copy
of Dark Safari by Cuddleferd?
I'll find out.
Hey Bub.
How do you do gentleman.
We like to speak to salesman pal.
- Well I'm the salesman Stanley
Livington.
I'm the clerk in charge of all
jungle books. And at 11 o'clock
I'm giving a lecture.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. You got a book by the name of ...
- Dark Safari by Cuddleferd.
Dark Safari by Cuddleferd. We
did have it but we got rid of
it sometime ago.
I want to tell you gentlemen I
read that book. I had
nightmares for 9 months.
How well do you remember that
book?
- Why?
- Do you remember a map then?
- A map in that book?
Of course
I remember it.
- Could you draw it?
- Could I draw it?
- For a $1000.
Draw that map in that book for
$1000? Ha ha, for $1000 I could
draw that map in oil.
OK then meet us in the ally
tonight at 7:30.
And we'll take you to somebody
who will give $1000 the minute
you lay down the pencil.
- Is it a deal?
- Shake. Oh!
- OK pal see you in the ally tonight at 7:30.
- And be there chum, get me.
$1000 to draw that map. Ha ha.
- I'm sorry but that book is out of print. In fact we sold the last one some time ago.p- Oh dear I was afraid of that.
I've been to every bookstore in
the city. There is a map in
that book that I would give
$2500 for.
Will you give me that again
please?
I said there was a map in
that book that I would give
$2500 for.
$2500. Excuse me I'll be right
back.
What are you doing?
Hey Buzz this you'll never
believe there were two guys in
here....
I understand. Look Stanley how
well do you remember that book
you read about Dark Safari?
That's what I'm trying to
tell you. There was two guys in
the...
Look you remember there was a
map in it.
You too. Now go away, go away.
- What are you doing there?
- I'm drawing that map now.
- Oh no you don't.
- What a minute.
- Oh you...
Buzz Don't tear that up. I
got a chance to...
Wait quite, quite. Come on
follow me now. Oh take it easy,
take it easy.
Madam you are the luckiest
person in New York this
morning.
- Allow me to introduce Stanley Livington. One of
the world's greatest wild
game hunters.
Well how exciting. Why game
hunters are my weakness. This
is really a thrill Mr Livington.
So nice meeting you to but I'm
really not...
It might interest you to know
that when Mr Cuddleferd wrote
Dark Safari Mr Livington was
right there.
- Oh.
- Wonderful.
Well then you must
be very familiar with the map
that is in that book?
- Map.
- Yes.
- Our sure.
That's one map that I can draw
in a darkroom even without a
pencil.
You see your troubles are all
over.
I could make arrangements to
bring him over to your home
this evening.
Oh Marvelous I think it's a
wonderful idea.
- My name is Emerson, Diana Emerson.
- How do you do Ms Emerson. But
no I have a date in the ally.
- She'll have to wait.
- She'll have to wait oh.
Here's my address. See you
tonight then.
- Goodbye.
That's the kind of girl I dream about. But you should see the ones I get.
[Whistles]
I tell you boss the guy said he
knew the map backwards. So we
make a date to meet him.
Bring
him in and have him draw it.
Yeah and the little muzzler
never shows up. After us
offering him a grand.
- Well you can relax I found somebody myself this morning.p- You did boss? Where?
- In Kloppers Department Store.
- That's where we found our guy.
Wait a minute. Was he a silly
looking little fat guy?
- That's him.
- Why that two timer.
You offer him $1000 and he holds out forpa higher price.
- The minute he puts his foot through the door I'll break every bone in his head.
- You'll do no such thing.
- When he leaves you boys can meet him outside and get my money back.
- We get you boss.
Now go out the side entrance.
I'm closing a deal with the man
who is going to lead the safari.
Won't you come in Mr Beatty.
This is the place. Now don't
forget she thinks you are a big
game hunter.
Buzz why do you keep getting me
in the middle? I wish you
hadn't.
Why you ingrate. Here I am
giving you a chance to make me
$2500.
Is that the way you want to
repay me for all the things I
could have done for you?
Come on.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh come on.
Stanley will you come on?
- I'm shutting off the water.
Well turn it off and come on.
- I stopped it.
- Good come on up here.
May I see you a minute please?
- Now what's the matter.
- My fingers stuck.
- Leave it there and come on.
- Ok.
- What's the matter. Let me see
this.
Not that one, not that. Not
that one! That one!
- Don't holler.
- Don't pull out that one.
- Wait a minute.
- Harry did you answer the door?
- No do I have to?
- Answer the door.
- Oh all right.
I do everything around here. I
have to be a cook and a butler.
One of these days I'll just..
Well.. That's all I'll just...
do it.
[Knock, knock]
Yes.
- Mr Johnson and Mr Livington to see Ms Emerson.p- Well come in.
[Knock, knock]
Well who is knocking? Well come
in!
Ms Emerson is busy for the
moment will you step in the
living room please.
- Hats.
- Thank you.
Ow that hurts.
- That belongs on outside.
- Yeah I can't get it off.
- Help me get it off.
- Will you keep your hand...
- Not so hard your..
- Get your hand out of the way
now.
Get your hand out of the
way.
Well get your hand out of the
way I'll get it off.
Naturally I haven't publicized
the expedition cause I could
easily become the victim of
unscrupulous people.
If that map is one of the few
in existence.
The owner would
practically have you in the
palm of his hand.
This man coming tonight is the
gullible type but fairly
intelligent.
If he could remember the map
accurately we will proceed at
once.
- That would be fine with me Ms Emerson.p- Now regarding your fee.
Suppose we say $5,000 in
advance and $15,000 on
completion.
- That's very liberal.
- On the contrary.
Money is no
object as long as I get what
I'm after.
- Come on will ya.
- Ha ha there it is.
- Oh not that hand this one.
Well put this hand in your
pocket. Ow get your hand out of
there.
Ow sometimes if.. Oh.
Stanley I just found out that
map is worth more than $2,500
to that woman.
- I can't get over it, all I did was go like this and the water came out.
- Are you listening?
Come on.
Come on!
You go in the living room and
wait. I'm going to snoop around
here and find out more about
this deal. Go ahead.
- Who was at the door Harry?
- Mr Livington and Mr Johnson.
- Good where are they?
- There in the living room.
- I'll see them in a minute and
have coffee in the library.
- Harry I'm phoning Gunner to come over. Please leave the door open.p- Yes Mam.
Excuse me. I didn't know anyone
was in the room.I'm awfully
sorry.
Say hold it right where you
are. You know you standing in
front of this here picture
reminds me of my last
expedition in Africa.
- Is that so?
- Yes indeed. Yes indeed.
And it was my most dangerous
expedition.
- We were after cats, big cats. You know what cats are?
- Lions I imagine.
Oh there is no imagining about
it my friend. Lions are lions,
here or anyplace they are lions.
You can't imagine the lions. Oh
no indeed. I want to tell you
something.
My first afternoon out I bagged
64 lions.
- Gad what a hunt.
- Really?
- Oh yes.
- Then I ran into an old friend of mine Clyde Beatty.
- No.
- And was he irked. He didn't bag a lion for 2 weeks ha ha.
- Really?
I bagged them all he couldn't
get one of them.
Of course when it comes to
hankering lions he don't know
from nothing.
I am the boy
right over here.
I want to tell you something
else too between you and I.
Clyde Beatty is a phony.
On the side a pretty nice
fella. But between you and I a
phony.
Something else I want to tell
you friend.
Who do you think
tames the lions that he has
inside the cages?
- Me Stanley Livington the world's greatest hunter.
- No kidding.
- Yes sir, well one of the greatest. By the way what's your name?
- Clyde Beatty.
Clyde Beatty. Clyde it's nice
knowing you. I want you to
stick around,
cause I want to tell you how I
used to go in myself and tame
those lions.
Now when it comes to taming the
animals Clyde. Clyde! Clyde!
Aw good evening I see you've
met Mr Livington our big wild
game hunter eh?
- Yes indeed.
- Swell.
He's juts been telling me
about some of his exploits.
Oh swell, swell that's fine.
Tell him about the time you and
Clyde Beatty went tiger hunting
in India.
- Yes I'd like to here about it.
- Stanley tells me that he out
shot Beatty 5 to 1.
- By the way I don't you introduced me to this gentleman.
- Clyde Beatty.
Clyde Be... Clyde Beatty. I'll
be seeing you around.
Mr Beatty I'm sorry for what I
said about Mr Beatty. Excuse me.
Why Mr Johnson and Mr
Livington please forgive me for
keeping you waiting.
You met Mr Beatty?
- It seems Mr Livington and I are old hunting pals.
- Won't you gentlemen have tea.
And after coffee we'll have Mr
Livington draw the map.
I'm terribly sorry but Mr
Livington will not be able to
draw the map.
But he's got to. The whole
success of my trip depends on
it.
You mean you intend to take a
trip to Africa?
- Very definitely I'm planning a safari.p- I wonder if I may be excused.
I know you folks would rather
talk business in private.
If you don't mind I think it
would be better. Mr Beatty's
hat Harry. Excuse me gentlemen.
Goodnight old friend.
Quick Grappler and Boots are
outside waiting to slug Johnson
Livington.
Tell them the plans
have changed and to lay off.
Yes Mam.
Look Buzz let me draw the map
we'll get $2,500 and get out of
here.
Certainly not. Now if I play
your cards right we'll get more
than $2,500.
- Listen you heard her she is organizing a safari.
- I wish I was there.
- Where?
On the Hoboken safari right now.
- Uh..Uh.. Stanley you are
absolutely right.
- As you surmised, to be frank with you, I don't blame you for having the desire.
- The desire to what?
- Of course I'll have to explain everything to the lady.p- Explain it to me.
Uh Mr Livington insists on
joining your safari to Africa.
- I insist.
- There you are, you heard it
from his own lips.
Just a hold... How do you do?
You see with Mr Livington in
Africa he'd feel right at home
and it would be very simple for
him to draw the map without any
difficulties.
- I think it's an excellent idea.
- Surely.
Once we are there he can lead
us to the east fork of the
Talabongo and Okavangy river.
- Lead you to the fork?
- Yes surely of course it will
be the regular $5,000 fee in
advance and $15,000 on
completion.
- Of course that includes my services.P- Why splendid.p- That's fine.
- And for your safety I am going to assign you my best follow upper.p- Follow upper?
Yes he is the man who follows
you in the jungle. And if you
miss a shot at a charging
animal he shoots and saves your
life.
[Crash]
- Oh that's him now. Excuse me.
- Surely.
- Hey listen Buzz. I'm not going over there. You got no right to out me in a thing like that.
- All this kind of money?
- You're always putting me right in the middle..p- Don't tell me...
I don't care what kind of
money it is.
- Don't you give me that..
- Now Listen..
- Aw no arguments...
- I'm not going to go over there with all those lions roar!
- You'll do as I tell you.
- Roar. I'm going to...
- You'll do as I tell you no
arguments.
Oh no I'm not. I wont.
- Gunner I'd like to have you meet Mr Johnson and Mr Livington. Gunner Jenson.p- Hi.
I don't want to seem
inquisitive but just what are
going to Africa for?
Why we are going after an
Orangutan Gargantua.
- An Orangutan Gargantua.
- Excuse me please.
- Pardon me.
- May I see you.
What's Orangutan Gargantua?
- It's a big ape.
- Big ape.
- Yeah stop worrying.
- Big ape. Excuse me, excuse me.
- Pardon me.
- Big ape?
- Yeah.
- You mean like the thing that I see in the circus like the father to the monkey.
- Yeah it's only bigger, bigger.
- Ping. And he's going to protect me?
- Um huh.
Gunner show them how you can
shoot the winchester.
You missed the lion. I raise
the gun to my shoulder and look
threw the peep sight and I....
I look threw the peep sight,
put my finger on the trigger,
grab for the pump slide and
I..I...
Huh no pump slide.
Stanley come here. Stanley. Now
where did he go? Stanley.
[Clock bell]
♪
[Monkeys screeching]
[Elephant trumpeting]
[Lions roar]
♪
[Crocodile growls]
The Cong River. You know
Stanley suppose a north wind
should come up, what would you
do?
- I'd throw out an anchor.
- If a west wind came up what
would you do?
I'd throw out another anchor.
- And a south wind came up what would you do then?p- I'd throw out another anchor.
- And an east wind blew up what would you do?
- I'd throw out another anchor.
- Where are you getting all the anchors?P- The sam place you're gettinpall the wind.
You keep quite.
Come on row your boat. You've
been a very bad boy the last
couple of days.
I want you to change. I'm
warning you. I don't like it a
bit.
- All you do is snap at me.
- Me snap at you.
- Oh ain't that a laugh me snapping at him.
- Why should you laugh?
- Ho ho ho ho.
Don't splash.
[Yawn]
[Crocidle growls]
What are you doing?
[Motor boat sound]
♪
- Hey you.
- What's the matter?
Oh Gunner look not me the
post.
- Oh.
Always complaining.
- Hello.
- The camps coming along fine Ms Emerson. And in the morning we will start for the interior.p- Very good.
Well we've looked the whole
place over. You want to know
something boss?
This don't look
like a place to find diamonds.
You fool. Don't you ever
mention the word diamonds.
We're supposed to be after an
Orangutan.
And another thing boss I'm
getting awfully sick of these
two guys you're depending on.
They're always fouling us up.
Just be patient it won't be
long now before the map is in
my hands.
Stanley. Stanley! Drop everything.
- Huh.
- Drop everything.
Come here Stanley. Get up, get
out from under there. Hurry up,
come here. Come on Stanley.
- Oh Buzz just when I had the tent up.P- Never mind the tent. Comepover here and draw that map.
- The map.
If I draw it will you let me
go home?
- Why do you want to go home?
- I forgot something.
- What did you forget?
- I forgot to stay there.
- Draw the map come on.
Boy oh boy can you picture me
as a tycoon. Ho ho ho.
Buildings, yachts, railroads. I
don't know I might even buy an
airline according to how I feel.
Winters in Maine, summers in
Florida. Oh it's unbelievable.
- Get him he could even get his laundry up.
- Have you got it ready yet?
Come on!
You got? That a boy. Oh this
paper here is worth a million
dollars.
A million dollars? Well I mean
I did it give me something. I
got to have something for it.
- Oh sure, sure. I intended to. Here, here's a nickel.p- Thank you.
- That a boy.
- Oh a nickel.
- Hello Diana.
- Harry some tea for Mr Johnson.
- And plenty of sugar.
- Wonderful day we're having. You are looking marvelous yourself.
- Your in fine spirits.
I have all the reasons in the
world to be. I finally
persuaded Stanley to draw the
map.
- Oh well may I see it?
- Eh I also made some very
interesting discoveries.
Aside from the Orangutan there
are far more important things
to be found in that particular
territory.
- Really.
- Yes and due to the facts I
personally think I'm entitled
to new deal.
- What kind of a deal did you have in mind?
- Well I'd say 20% of the
safaris profits would be fair.
- Very liberal. In view of your generosity may I see the map?
- Oh yes surely, surely.
Now this map will take you
right to eh...
Um.
There seems to be something
lacking here.
I'll see Stanley. There's some detail work....
He hasn't really completed the
map.
- I'll be right back.
- Here's your tea and I put
plenty of sugar in it.
Oh drink it yourself.
- Oh drink it yourself, drink it yourself.P- Harry I want to see Boots andpGrappler immediately.
- Come here. Wise alec huh.
- Now what's the matter with
you.
Thought you were putting
something over on me.
This is not the map that was in
Cuddleferd's book.
- Oh yes it is.
- This, this thing tells you
how to get to Kloppers
Department Store.
Well that's the map. I used to
keep that map in Cuddleferd's
book.
Listen you nit-witted numb
skull. These people want a map
of Bangy Territory.
- Bangy Territory. Bangy Territory!
- Yes.
I was wondering why they want
to pay all that kind of money
just to find the directions on
how I get to Kloppers
Department Store.
That I couldn't understand.
Just a minute. Do you realize
that we are in the most
dangerous spot we've ever been
in our lives?
- Dangerous spot.
- Dangerous spot!
- Buzz.
- What.
- Is is worse than the time
when Skinny Marink knocked the
chip off my shoulder?
- Ah certainly.
- Worse than that?
- I should say it is.
- And the time I drew the line like that?
- Far more.
Yeah but that time he came over
the line. It's worser than that?
Never mind that, it's worse
than that.
- Oh are we in trouble.
- Wait a minute we got to do
something.
- I have it. We've got to get out.
- Sure.
Come on hurry up. Grab a hold
of that will ya.
- Look I'm scared....
- What ya doing boys?
Going somewhere fellas?
We were juts going to take
these little trunk inside the
tent.
- Get moving.
- Hey, hey.
- Go ahead knock the chip off my shoulder.p- Not that.
Your heads liable
to go with it.
Oh.
Go on get moving.
Um. I'm getting sick and tired
of being pushed around by you
guys.
Do you hear me? Getting
sick and tired of it.
Hey. Come on back, come on back.
[Whistles]
Hey come on back. Hey come on
back.
Hey! he....
[Whispers]
Hey, come on back.
Step on that side of the line.
Come on. Hm hm.
- Stanley, Stanley, no.
- Don't bother me.
Stanley your not going to
kill anyone.
- Don't hold me back.
- Don't so that.
Somebodies got to get it. And
when I get this mad somebodies
got to get it.
Fine friend you are. You bring
me way out here in the heart of
the jungle why?
Because you
told me you could draw the map.
You can't draw it can you? You
knew you couldn't.
Why did you bring me way out
here? Now what am I going to do?
What am I going to do with the
boats I was going to buy?
The buildings I was going to
buy, the railroads I was going
to buy.
Put that down. That's a fine
how do you do. Nice goings on
from a pal, from a friend.
And I never... I never expected
it from you. I'll have to go
into bankruptcy that's all.
That's all that's left for me
to do Then what will my friends
say?
To think that you my bosom
friend...
- Hey look where are you going with the water?p- Oh my tents on fire.
Well what do you have to say
for yourself?
♪
[Jungle noises]
[Yelling] Hold it, hold it.
Stop. Go no further.
- What are you stopping here for, its early yet?P- Well this is where Cuddleferdpstopped.
Now uh, on the bottom of page
389, according to Cuddleferd.
He wrote that he had a very
uneventful day.
Therefore he
made camp on a bank of the
Crocodile River.
Now over there is a crocodile river.
Eh Uh.
- Over here.
- [Scoffs] Uh, you'll have to
forgive him.
- You see, Stanley is actually living the book.
- That's not all.
At night Cuddleferd, he posted
a double guard because he was
nearing the Bangy Country.
Which was full of ferocious
animals and cannibals.
Stanley is right, this is
pretty dangerous territory.
- I suggest we pitch camp on this side tonight.
- That means we will lose an
entire half day.
- Well if you cross over your gonna lose 2 days anyway.
- Why?
Well according to Cuddlefer,
when he crossed the river he
was brought down by Jungle
Fever.
And he was that way for 36
hours.
Ms Emerson, I think we should
look for a location to pitch
camp.
- All right Mr Beatty.
- Stanley come here.
You got use a little more tack
when you talk to Ms Emerson.
You know shes libel to send us
back to the States.
- Good, good.
- Good, good. You...whats the
matter?
Ah, my goodness are you
worrying about that? That's
just a little baby lion.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I'll get a hold of him.
- [Laughs] Can you imagine that.
- Buzz don't. Buzz, don't.
Here, look here.
- Remember what happened in Kloppers Department Store, don't do it.
- Now don't get excited.
- This little cat was raised on milk.
- So was I, but I eat meat now.
Take it away, let it go back to
it's mother.
- Touch it, touch it. Now go ahead touch it. Their you are.
- [Screams]
- You see, their you are. Now go ahead, go ahead. There he is, look how kitty runs.
- Look at that, hey.
- Hey, I got my finger back.
- What do you mean you got your
finger... you touched him
didn't you.
- I...I...I touched a real lion.
- That's all their is to it.
- A... a real lion I... Brave!
- Well that's it.
- Just like that.
That will take that fear out
of you.
[Laughs] I'm gonna catch that
little baby lion and I am gonna
bring it back to Diana.
Hey wait a minute. That's a
good idea.
That will put us in good with
her. Go ahead kid I'll see you
at camp.
[Makes bugle noise]
Here kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here kitty.
Come on kitty. Ha ha kitty,
kitty.
- [Lion roars]
- [Screams]
Hey, Buzz!
Buzz come on.
[Lion roars]
Well Buzz I guess we lost that
pussy cat. Oh Buzz.
[Crashing noise]
Oh, no.
Hey, Buzz. Uh, Buzz.
Hey it's dark down their, I
can't see a thing. How did you
ever fall into a trap any way,
you clumsy boy?
I'm gonna throw you some rope
down. Can't see a thing so grab
for it.
That a boy.
[Grunts]
[Gorilla growls]
That a boy. Now, Buzz you
better go on a diet because you
are getting awful fat and awful
heavy.
Give me the other end of the
rope. Thank you. Now leave it
here for who ever it belongs to.
[Gorilla grunts]
[Gorilla growls]
Oh.
[Sighs] Thank you.
Oh, get out of the way fast.
[In distance] Hey Buzz.
We better go over and check on
that trap.
Stanley? Stanley?
All right boys, you've done a
good job now. Take them back to
the truck.
Come on boys, back to the truck.
Stanley? Stanley?
Stanley?
- Look out there fellow, their is a trap right in front of youp- A trap! Thanks stranger.
My name is Buzz Johnson. I'm
look for a little chubby guy by
the name of Stanley Livington.
- Have you seen him?
- No I haven't. My name is
Frank Buck.
- Frank Buck, well I'm certainly glad to know you.P- And glad to see you. I'plooking for a great big guy
called Orangutan Gargantua.
Have you seen him?
- Oh no.
- Well it just built this trap
for him.
Come on you better get
away from this trap.
I think we better.
- Hey Mr Buck?
- Yeah.
- Is their really such a animal
as an Orangutan Gargantua?
- Of course their is.
- Their is.
Theirs one right around this
district now.
- Great big fellow, about 20 feet high.
- [Whistles]
Face almost human. Matter of
fact I've got traps all around
here set for him.
Un huh.
[Yelling] Hey Buzz!
Mr Buck, I... [Chuckles]
I wonder if you would help me
find my camp.
Why I would be very glad to...
[Crashing noise]
A trap, a trap. Come over here.
[Men yelling]
We got one!
It's only a baby thou, but we
got him. Boy bring the net
around there, come on now.
Now get him in the neat there,
bring him up. Pull him up.
Mr Johnson, that's the first of
the species ever captured by a
human being.
You two take the bullseye. Drop
the net.
Come on Bobo, come on get...
get him up there. Get him up,
hoist him up.
- Take the slack out of the rope.
- Careful boy.
- Is he ferocious?
- We don't know.
- Don't know.
Ah, ah hey. Hey!
[Men scream]
It's Stanley! Stanley, where
have you been?
- I've searched this jungle all night long for you.
- Last night I want to take
that, ah ah ah ah...
- This is not time for clowning!
- Clowning!
Now listen what are you
trying to do.
- Make a monkey out of yourself?
- That's it!
Look at all the extra work
you did for my men.
- Are you the man who dug this whole here?p- Yeah.
The least you could have done
was put a red
lantern in. I'm gonna report
you to the African League For
Better Road Improvement. I
certainly am.
- Now take it easy, take it easy.
- What are you trying to build
anyway a trap?
Yes a trap.
- Your doing it all wrong.
- What do you mean I'm doing it
all wrong?
This guy don't know for
nothing about a trap.
- I showed Frank Buck how to build all his traps, everyone of them.
- Oh, yeah.
He listens to me, I'm one of
the biggest game hunters in the
whole world. That's why I'm
over here.
Will you wait a minute.
- You've got the whole thing... it's longer... will you keep quite!
- Will you listen.
It's longer over here... will
you keep quite. After what I
saw last night I'm the boss. I
know what I'm talking about.
- Its, its, its, its one... who's this character?
- Frank Buck!
- Ha, ha.
- Frank Buck. How do you do?
- Yeah.
- I'll see you later Mr Buck.
Yeah, well get on with the
truck and stand over there.
Boys hit the trap again, now
get it all ready.
Mr Buck the boys have finished
resetting the traps.
Alright go down the other way
and set the other ones.
- I'm sorry I feel in your trap.
- Oh that's alright.
But last night, I saw something
like I have never saw before in
my life.
Not even in a nightmare, I've
never saw anything like this.
- I'm gonna tell ya. He had a head like that.
- Alright go ahead.
- I am not lying about that.
[Gorilla breathing]
Hes...
Eat your food, come on.
I'm mm...
[Gorilla grunts]
[Staggered breathing]
A little sugar.
[In audible words]
[Coughs]
[Gorilla growls]
[Blows raspberry]
[Coughs]
[Gorilla grunting]
[Exhales sharply]
What makes you so nervous?
Don't play with it, eat it!
[Harshly] Buzz, Buzz, Buzz,
Buzz.
- Buzz, there.
- What's that matter with you,
huh.
- He must be tiered.
- Mmm mmm.
- Buzz, Buzz.
- Whats the matter?
- Do you see a thing over there?
- Certainly not.
- Then I got Jungle Fever.
- I've better get him back to our camp.
- I think you better too.
- Now just follow the trail exactly as I told you.p- Yeah.
And you won't miss it, and
look out for my traps.
Now wait I think you better
take a gun along with you.
By george I think we can use
one.
- Yeah.
- Thanks a lot, so long Mr Buck.
- So long.
- So long, bye bye.
- Come on, come on. Take it
easy, take it easy.
♪
- What a business for a guy to be in.
- Crocodiles and lions bring a
lot a dough back in the States.
- He can have it.
[Crocodile growls]
Ok boys your finished. Lets go
back to the compound.
[Crocodile growls]
Well Buzz.
- After this swim I'll feel like a diamond in the rough.p- Yeah, diamond.
- That's right.
- Stanley, I think Diana is
trying to put something over on
us.
Doesn't it seam funny to you,
that as soon as Clyde Beatty
goes out to bag lions.
She's lets us come down here to
take a swim in the river.
- Oh tush, tush.
- Never mind the tush, tush.
- I can use it, I can use it.
Just a minute. We may be in the
diamond territory.
- Maybe she knows where the diamonds are.
- Buzz.
- Maybe she has the diamonds.
- Buzz you got to take it easy. You need more sleep at night kid.
- I don't know.
- Now forget about diamonds.
- I'm a little worried.
- Don't get worried. Hold that.
- I know.
- Hold that.
Lets go in and take a bath. A
bath or something, and we will
swim nicely.
Alright put it down, put it
down.
- Come on, lets go.
- Well.
- The last one is a old maid.
- Wait, wait a minute. Where are you going.
- I'm gonna dive in.
- In there!
Of course in there, I'm not
gonna dive in there. You'll
hurt your head over there.
- Did you read this sign?
- What?
Do you know what that sign
says?
- Who's walking on the grass?
- Wait a minute you can't dive
in there,
theirs nothing but
crocodiles in there.
- Ahhh. What!
- Crocodiles. Don't get
excited, don't get excited.
- You see over here, theirs nothing but nets.
- I dive inside the nets.
- The crocodiles can get in the nets.
- That's good.
That's swell, go ahead right
in. Enjoy yourself.
- Ok.
- Can you make it? Oh, come on
that's warm.
- It's cute.
- Sure. That a boy. Wow boy,
where you going.
[Water splashes]
What a belly flop.
- Hey Buzz.
- Watch my impersonation.
- Oh you do impersonations?
- Yeah watch. My first one, a seal.
- A seal.
- Here I go.
[Making seal noises]
[Man laughing] Ahhh.
- Pretty good, huh?
- It's a lion.
- Hey, watch this.
- What's this?
- A whale.
- A whale!
[Spits water]
- Ah, shucks...
- Ha ha ha ha.
- That's a whale.
- Yeah. Hey watch this one Buzz.
- What's that.
- A alligator.
- Look I want to go in there to
you know.
Wait till I do the alligator.
- Let me go...
- Here I go!
[Crocodile growls]
Argh. Buzz? Buzz?
How do you like that the guy
could not wait he had to dive
in.
Uh oh, uh oh. Ha ha ha ha.
Hey Buzz?
Buzz, stop tickling. Ha ha ha ha.
[Yelling] Stop!
Stop tickling Buzz!
He a playful little son of a
gun. Buzz will you come on...
Buzz come up where ever you are...
[Laughing] Wow oh oh oh oh.
Buzz will you...
Buzz? Buzz?
Will you cut it out!
Buzz will you stop I don't want
to play anymore.
Buzz no more. Now will you come
up no matter where ever you are.
- Oh, Buzz in gonna...
- [Crocodile hisses]
[Talking nonsense] Nivin gar,
nivin
- [Crocodile growls]
- Oh!
[Lion roars]
[Bangs on crate]
[Lion continues to roar]
[Cracking whip]
[Lion roars]
I don't understand why he has
to try those cats out before he
sends them back to the States.
It worries me.
It doesn't worry me half as
much as those two knot heads
you brought along with us.
Relax.
[Cracks whip]
[Lion roars]
- Buzz please don't make me do this.
- Your going to do it.
- I don't wanna.
- Your making a coward out of me.
- Oh I'm not making a coward
out of you.
The gossip that's going
around this camp.
"Stanley's a coward, Stanley's
a coward." Afraid of a little
tiney winey alligator like that.
- It was a big alligator...
- Oh stop it. Are you afraid of
that?
I think so.
- Oh stop it. It's only a skin.
Feel it, feel it. Don't be
afraid of it.
- That enough.
- Now look I'm gonna make a
hero out of you. Whether you
like it or not.
I'm going down that path. You
know where the water bag is?
- Yeah.
- You meet me there. I'll be in
this skin.
Un huh.
And make sure you bring Diana
with you.
Oh you me to get Diana and
bring her over by the path, by
the water bags?
- Don't over think it.
- Your gonna have the lion skin
and then... Ha ha.
- That's it.
- Just act like Clyde Beatty.
- Ok Buzz.
- That a boy.
- I'm going over and have a chit chat with Diana.
- That a boy...
I'm gonna show her I'm a pretty brave
kid.
- And I don't like this kind of talk going around.p- Now your talking.
Down by the path by the
water bags.
I'll be there.
[Lion roars]
Well boys, in a little while we
can say good by to Mr Beatty
and his lions and crocodiles
and cages.
Tag this one for shipping back
to the States, he's a good one.
And get the other 3 ready for
the training cage. I'll be back
later then to work them out.
[Humming]
- Diana?
- Yes Stanley?
I would like chit chat with
if you don't mind?
- Of course.
- Excuse us fellows.
- Now, uh, a few things I want to get straightened out. I uh...
- Yes?
I'm gonna tell you over here.
Diana their is some talk going
around this camp, and I don't
like it.
I don't like it no how. I am getting plenty peeved about it, and I have a right to.
Have a drink.
People are going around saying
I'm afraid of lions. Well
that's not true that's a lie.
I'm one of finest big game
hunters in the world!
No one surpasses Stanley
Livington!
You think the lions that Clyde Beatty catches are big ones?
Ha, ha.
Their nothing but kittens, little bitty kittens.p[Whistles]
Why, I want to tell you
something. I'm going on a big
game hunt myself.
I'm going to catch a lion just
for you, to show you how big I
can catch em.
- Ha. You afraid of lions?
- No.
- Good, take a look.
[Screams]
Stanley? Stanley, what's the
matter with you?
- She scared me.
- Oh, never mind. Listen, I'm
going into the cage and you
behave yourself.
I can't understand why he gets
so scared.
[Lion roars]
Stand back, have no fear fare
lady of that wild beast.
I Stanley Livington will
protect thee, and you's two.
- Get back Stanley, I'll plug him for you.P- Why not let the lion chew ophim for a while.
- The lions gonna spoil my fun.
- Let him alone Grap.
- Nice work Buzz.
Look! He's heading him towards
the cage.
- Well, I'll be.
- Come on, come on. Get in the
cage now!
I'll show you who's the boss.
Come on, come on.
Ha ha ha.
The key! I need it now more.
Diana watch. I'm not afraid of
lions.
And the gun, that's only for Clyde Beatty.pHa oh!
Oh me oh my. He, he.
Don't get scared, I've got him
under control.
Boy, that stupid little idiot
showing off like that.
[Whispers] Come on Buzz, get up
on the box. Move it bub. Come
on stop stalling get up there.
Come on get up there will you,
that a boy. Hey Buzz this I got
to tell you.
You walk on your knees like a real lion. You even hopped around like a real lion.
[Sniffing]
You want to know something
else. You even smell like a
real lion.
And that's the part I don't
understand. Stop breathing down
my neck too, I don't like that.
How do you do.
- Oh this is gonna be horrible.
- Hey, you come awful close.
Now cut it out or I'll hit you
right in the puss with a chair.
[Lion roars]
I'm not afraid of nothing.
How do you do? I don't care
about kittens I don't care how
big the kittens are.
How we doing Buzz?
[Lion roars]
Hey Buzz, get those nails filed
they hurt.
[Crunching noise]
[Lion screams]
- Serves you right.
[Lion roars]
- I've seen enough.
Stanley! Stan... Stanley!
Stanley, come out of there.
Ha ha ha ha ha. Hey Buzz, did
we fool them.
I wish you could have got the look on their faces when they saw you in here.p[Laughing]
- Stanley come out.
- I can't I locked the door
over here.
- Well, throw the key out.
- [Laughing] I threw the key
out long ago.
- Where?
- Over there.
- [Laughing]
- Stanley.
- Hey look, hey, hey...
I loosened them up. Now go away
before you queer it.
- What are you talking...
- They don't know your inside
the lion skin.
Ohhh.
- Well, I'll look for the key.
- [Laughing]
Oh, the big guy. What a look on
his face.
[Laughing]
Buzz, I tell you should have
saw that big guys face.
[Lion roars]
[Laughing]
He didn't know you was inside
the lions skin.
[Lion roars]
I know that your inside...
[Laughing]
[Lion roars]
[Crying]
Oh, ho Buzz. I don't know...
Get, get...
Stand up...
Help I'm paralyzed.
[Lion roars]
Stop.
Hey, Stanley I found the key.
Everythings alright you got
nothing to worry about...
St.. Stanley?
[Lion roars]
Oh no. No.
Oh, no.
Stanley? Stan.
- What, what did you do with my buddy?p- [Lion roars]
All my fault. I should have
never let him do it.
My bosom pall.
[Lion roars]
- Why is this cat in here?
And who locked this gate?
[Lion roaring]
Alright let the rest of them in.
[Multiple lions roaring]
[Whip cracks]
Come on.
[Whip cracking]
[Lions roar]
Eh!
[Lion roars]
Good boy, that's it.
[Bangs whip against box]
Up.
[Cracks whip]
Up, up!
[Lion roars]
Eh.
[Cracks whip]
[Fires pistol]
Get up now. Up, up, up.
[Continues to crack whip while
lions roar]
Alright boys let the others in.
[Even more lions roar]
[Screams] Ah!
Oh this is terrible. Stanley,
Stanley its all my fault.
Don't blame anyone else but me.
Stanley how was I to know that
a real lion would go into the
cage.
Oh this is terrible Stanley.
How can I... Oh stop I just
lost the best friend I ever had.
Oh if he was only here. The kid
never done a bit of harm to
anyone...
- He was a nice boy.
- What a man he was but I never
appreciated him until now.
- No you didn't, you was mean to him all...
- No its late its all over he's
gone.
- Yes, you...
- [Crying] The way I use to
trick him and send him to do
things. It was all wrong.
I wouldn't send my worse enemy
out to do the things, I taught
him to do.
- And the way I use to cheat him in poker.P- You use to slap that poor kidpall, all over the face.
- Oh, I use to cheat him and...
- That kid never did nothing to
nobody.
If he was only here, I
would...
- He was a nice, a nice boy that kid.
- I would give him every dollar
of his back.
Oh, I feel like jumping off a cliff.
[Crying]
- That's what I should do.
- Poor Stanley.
But no, no. I haven't got the
nerve. If only he was here to
tell me what to do.
Stanley, what should I do
Stanley? Oh.
I know what I'll do. It's that
lion. That lion!
- The one that got him.
- I'm...
- I'll spend the rest of my days
- Right here in this forest. I'll get that lion.p- No you don't have...
I'll get that lion if its the
last thing I do.
- I'll spend my life here in this forest.
- He's a brave man...
- Don't tell me what to do.
- I... I...
- You don't have to get the...
Hello Buzz. How are you?
- Stanley?
- What's the matter?
- Stanley its really you.
- Sure Buzz.
- Wait a minute, are you all
there?
- The lion didn't hurt you.
- No, no...
- It's really you Stanley.
- What do you think I am a
mirage or something?
- Your no mirage.
- I'm no mirage.
- Your real.
- Sure.
- You double crosser. You dirty
double crosser.
Ah, Agh.
- Oh, oh.
- What's the matter with you?
What's the matter.
Oh.
How do you like that I was
sitting on a piece of broken
milk bottle.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute. That's a diamond.
- I'm gonna throw it away, I
don't...
- No! That's a real diamond.
- That's a real diamond.
That's what I've been looking
for.
No, don't touch. Don't get
hoggish.
- It's mine I found em. I found a diamond.P- Diamond, that's a piece opbroken milk bottle.
- Don't tell me what it is.
- Theirs another piece over
there. I've been looking at
that one for a long time.
- Wait a minute, Stanley. It's another diamond. A real diamond.
- Hoot, ho ho.
Stanley look here. Come here,
follow me. Here's another one,
this is unbelievable.
You... Come on, come on Stanley.
Look another one. I'm rich, I'm
wealthy Stanley.
Can you imagine... Look
Stanley, come here look at here.
Look Stanley. Another one, I
can buy buildings.
I can buy polo ponies. I can
buy yachts. I can buy
everything that my heart
desires. I...
Stanley do my eyes deceive me?
Look Stanley another one.
Stanley, look at that. Look at
the size of that diamond.
Well don't stand there. Think
of something I can buy for
myself. Think of something.
I... Put that away. Can you...
Stanley look at here, look at
here. Stanley two of them.
Hold these, hold these Stanely.
Hold em, don't drop them
Stanley. What your eyes see
your heart must believe. two of
them, real.
- What are you doing with my diamonds, trying to steal em?p- Yeah that's right.
Look at the size of them.
Stanley do you realize. I...
Hurry up Stanley. It's another
diamond.
- Buzz.
- We are on the right trail.
Stanley... Look Stanley come
here.
Stanley my back is broken pick
that up.
- Hurry up put it on here.
- You want to know something?
- What?
- There's another one.
- Well pick it up. Put it on
here.
- I'm watching you.
- Come on.
- Look!
- Another on. Come on put it on
here. Boy oh, boy.
- Another one.
- Can you imagine nothing but
diamonds.
Oh, no.
[Humming]
[Cannibals speaking foreign
language]
[Water bubbling]
[Grunts]
[Laughs]
Um, ga'wa.
[Water bubbling]
Fine mess you got us into. All
on account of your lust for
money.
Me?
Oh, Buzz.
Now, I know what they mean when
the say "Boy are you in hot
water."
Never though it was going to be
anything like this though.
[Whispers] Buzz.
Buzz, how... how did you get
yourself untied?
Quiet, quiet.
Your smart Buzz. I take back
everything I've ever said about
you.
Good work. Tell me what to do
Buzz.
I'm gonna stay like this.
Don't make a move until I make
a move, until I make break for
it.
I can see them. Get back
over there, make like your tied.
[Cannibal language]
Get ready, their turning away.
Come on!
Come on, Buzz.
- Come here.
- Buzz come on will you.
- How can I, I'm still tied.
- Your not tied. I... You untied me.
- I did nothing of the kind.
You untied yourself.
- I did not.
- Well then untie me. Come on.
- Are you kidding.
- No he ain't.
- Come on hurry up. Get these
off.
Get these off hurry up.
[Cannibal language]
- Here they come.
- Well come on.
- Doh, dah. Oh, eh.
[Cannibals yelling]
[Screams]
Ohh. Get.
[Thuds]
[Gibberish]
Ahh.
Yeh, yeh, yeh.
Ohh. Hey... How the... eh...
[Laughs]
[Humming]
[Making fighting noises]
[Screams like gorilla]
What else is on your mind?
- You know Diana, I never did go for that talk of yours about a 20 foot monkey. p- Really?
Nah, and uh, as for bringing
Clyde Beatty out here to
capture wild animals.
- You didn't fool me for a minute.
- Well, just why did I come to
Africa Mr Johnson?
Diamonds!
- And I know just where they are.
- And you can lead us to these
diamonds?
That I can, but first we'll
talk business.
You and I will cut this pie
right down the center.
- Isn't that robbery...
- Now no bickering, take it or
leave it.
- I don't seem to have any alternative.
- That you haven't. So when you
make up your mind just give
Buzz a buzz, huh.
Here big boy, hold on to that.
Boss, about splitting that pie
down the center?
I'll handle this my own way.
Get ready to break up camp,
while I give Mr Beatty his
walking papers.
Hey boy, boy come here.
Now, gather up my belongings
that are scattered around here.
I might be moving to better
quarters. Ah, by the way...
Leave these things right here
in case that little fat boy.
You know, little fat boy, eh?
If he does show up this is good
enough for him. Go.
[Speaking foreign language]
[Cannibal language]
- chief wants see head man.
- Yes sir.
So I have decided theirs no
such thing as a Orangutan
Gargantua.
And now that we have enough
animals to have made the
expedition worth while.
I suggest that you and your men
prepare to leave for the coast.
That's alright with me Ms
Emerson.
- I will go an tell my men.
- Alright Mr Beatty.
Ms Emerson, Ms Emerson. Theirs
some fellows out there want to
see ya.
They want to hold a
conference.
- I think you better hurry.
- Alright Harry.
- chief want talk.
- We'll talk in the hut.
[Cannibal language]
chief say, many white men come
to Land of Bangys for diamonds.
- Many white men die.
- Why does the chief want to see
me?
chief want to be your friend.
chief want to make deal.
chief want to trade these,
diamonds.
What does the chief want for the
diamonds?
- chief have sweet tooth for little fat man.p- Him?
- Oh no.
- Oh, not him. Little fat man.
Mm, mm, mm. Strong, strong.
Little fat man. Friend of tall
thin man.
Oh, Stanley.
- Tell the chief he's made a deal.
- [Cannibal language]
- chief say, deal good.
- Excellent.
[Whispers] She's gonna sell him
on the hoof.
- Hey Gunner, Gunner.
- Who is it?
- It's me Buzz.
Have you seen Stanley?
Well if you see him tell him to
hide until he sees me.
- If I see him I'll tell him.
- Yeah.
But so far I haven't even
seen Africa.
- How is it?
- Oh Gunner.
Hey.
I'll tell him later.
Diana, theirs something I want
to tell you. We're in very
dangerous territory.
Last night Buzz and I were
captured by the cannibals.
Man eating cannibals. And you
know what they did,
they tied us up to the stakes.
And one guy looked at me and
went, mm mm mm mm, like this.
And I know that was for no
good. And I want tell you
something else,
I escaped. And
then I untied Buzz and he
escaped.
And there they were all these
cannibals, and I was starting
to fight them.
And I hit one
with a right and another with a
right.
And I... I... I hit one with a
fancy upper cut, I went like
this.
Boom! And I hit another
with a right.
And I... and I... I kept hit...
one guy looked just like him.
He had a hat on like that, too.
And this guy who had a hat on
like this, I hit him such a
belt.
I went, Whoop! Ha, ha. Right on
the side of the head over here,
I hit the guy.
Oh, he's got the bump there it is.
[Screams] Oh.
[Cannibals shouting]
- Quick after Stanley.
- Yeah.
[Cannibals yelling]
Oh, oh.
Diamonds, diamonds! Dropped in
my lap by some kind fate.
[Spits]
[Screams]
Wow!
- [Cannibals shouting]
- The diamonds. Diamonds!
Can't let Stanley know about
these.
- Their all my mine I wont share them with no one. I won't...
- [Gorilla growls]
[Shouting in distance] Hey
Buzz! Buzz!
Buzz, come on quick. Get up
will ya. Come on.
- Hey what is this?
- My diamonds.
- Little fat man got em.
- Oh you snitch.
[Cannibals shouting]
Can you see them Stanley?
Stanley what am I going to do?
My diamonds, my diamonds.
That's what their after my
diamonds.
Oh, no they can't take my
diamonds. It would ruin all my
dreams.
What would happen to my boats,
my buildings? Give me, give me
diamonds.
I know what I will do, I'll
hide em. They'll never find em.
- I can always come back and get em Stanley. Yeah, here is a good place right here.
- [Whistles]
- Now I'll mark the tree.
- [Cannibals shouting]
- Come on boys, load the truck.
- The men have finished setting
the traps Mr Buck.
- We have this area pretty well covered.p- Well I hope we bag some bigPones...
[Cage crashes]
Look the cage, come on.
- Get me out of here. Someone get me of here.
- Alright, alright, alright.
Come on raise it, get her out
here.
Have you seen a short fat man
and a tall thin man running
through the jungle?
- No and I don't want to either.
- Now I will never catch up
with them.
Where are you going, wait a
minute.
- Where are you going?
- I've got to find them.
Your not going to run around
this jungle alone.
- Stay right here with me.
- [Cannibals shouting]
Come on Stanley.
[Cannibals yelling]
Stanley, Stanley I'm going back
for the diamonds, you keep
running.
How can I keep running, you
got a hold of me.
Go ahead keep going.
[Cannibals shouting]
Oh we got him, that's Stanley.
Keep him covered Gunner.
Not me, him.
I'll go get help. Oh your such
a nuisance.
- Don't give no trouble Stanley. I shot and shot to kill.
- I know you do Gunner.
I wont give you any trouble.
You... you wont even know I'm
here.
- Don't press in so hard.
- Oh, oh scared eh.
Look at your face, its getting
green and green inch by inch.
And your getting spots on you
kisser.
Stanley, don't force me to pull
this trigger. I got a itchy
finger.
Ah here it is. My diamonds.
Where are my diamonds? I put em
here.
My diamonds.
Who's that? Is that you Harry?
- It's me Harry.
- He's scared stiff, he didn't
budge an inch.
- He didn't?
- No. Did you find Boots and
Grappler?
No I didn't. I'll tell you
what to do,
- keep Stanley covered.
- I got him.
- Keep him covered.
- Got him.
- Well bring him back to camp.
- Okay.
- He's... he's, he's a pretty dangers kid this Stanley. You did a good there kid.
- Ah, ah ah.
- Not a squawk out of him.
- Okay.
Keep walking. Hands high keep
walking.
My diamonds! They have got to
be around here some place.
Yeah, that's the mark.
Why should this happen to me.
I... I planted them right here.
Me who's been so good to his
friends.They gotta be here, the
must be here.
- My diamonds where are they.
- Keep walking, keep walking.
How did you ever get into this
mess?
I don't understand. Go on, keep
on there. Their you are, keep
going.
I got my eye on you. What are
you trying to do make a monkey
out of me?
- I see ya.
- [Laughs]
- Huh, huh, huh.
- Come on, come on.
Come on.
[Bugle sound]
[Monkeys screeching response]
[Gorilla growling]
[Cannibal's shouting]
[Monkey noises]
[Monkey screams]
[Monkey laughing]
Why don't you watch you clumsy
ox.
- Me?
- Yes you.
Why you tripped me with those
big feet of yours.
I did not such thing.
- What are you kicking me for?
- Whose kicking who?
- You kicked me.
I didn't even touch ya.
Look I told ya to lay off of
me. I didn't trip ya and I
didn't kick ya.
- So now leave me alone.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah!
- I'll leave ya alone.
- Look I'll hit ya harder then
Louis ever did.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah.
[Thuds]
[Monkeys screaming]
[Loud thud]
[Another loud thud]
[Monkey noises]
My diamonds. No, no.
[Crys]
Oh, I can't understand it.
I had an empire in the palm of
my hands.
It just slipped through my
fingers. I can't understand it.
I can't understand it.
[Cannibals yelling]
[Yelling stops]
[Screaming]
[Gorilla growls]
[Screams]
Get home...
[Thud]
[Monkeys screeching]
[Gorilla growls]
Oh, uh uh.
[Screams] Oh! Ah, ah, get away.
Can't understand it.
My big buildings, my airplanes,
my railroads.
My yachts.
Could be on one of my yachts
right now, huh. Look at that
guy.
A raft, can't understand it.
Buzz! Buzz, Buzz where are you
going?
- I'm going home.
- Well wait for me take me with
you...
No you don't I've had enough
of you.
- Pull that raft over here, so I can get on...p- Pull nothing over there.
You nothing but a little jinx,
you've always been jinx to me.
- I don't understand it.
- You don't understand. I don't
understand.
Go on get yourself lost.
But I...
- Hey Buzz, I'm coming on that raft!
- [Crocodile growls]
Ah, oh. So long Buzz.
Oh, ah oh oh.
Now I'm all alone, whats gonna
happen to me now.
Buzz.
♪
[Door slams]
- Morning Sir.
- Good morning Mr Livington.
- Polish every one of the letters, their important you know.p- Yes sir.
- Good morning Matilda.
- Have you my paper.
- Yes sir.
- Thank you.
[Humming]
- Good morning Mr Livington.
- Good morning Mr Mercer.
How do we stand in the gin
rummy game?
- Oh you owe me about 22 cents.
- See you at 2.
- Yes sir.
- Don't forget.
Can't understand it.
[Loud crash]
- Sunday driver.
- I'm sorry sir.
Ah, Mr Livington, what about
that raise I've been asking you
about?
- I'll talk to my partner, if he's in.p- Thank you sir.
[Whistles]
[Gorilla growls]
He's in.
[Mouths words] My partner.
♪