Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Charlie Chaplin in City Lights
C
CI
CIT
To the people of this city
we donate this monument;
Peace and Prosperity
Afternoon
DANGER!
Did you pick it up, sir?
Wait for your change, sir
Evening
Grandma
Night
Tomorrow the birds will sing
Be brave! Face life!
No, I'll end it all!
I'm cured. You're my friend for life
We'll go home and get warmed up
Any news?
‫Only that your wife sent for her baggage, sir
Good!
Here's to our friendship...
No, I'll live!
James - the Rolls-Royce.
We'll burn up the town!
Early morning; homeward bound.
Be careful how you're driving
Am I driving?
‫I like your car
Then keep it, it's yours
Where's my friend?
‫! Let him in, he's my guest
Let's buy some flowers
Here's ten dollars
I haven't any change, sir
James!
Take these inside; I'll be right back
‫Thank you for your kindness, sir
May I see you home again?
Whenever you wish, sir
‫The sober dawn awakens a different man
I'm out to everybody!
‫! Whoever he is, get rid of him
and then he brought me home in his car
He must be wealthy
‫Yes, but he's more than that
That afternoon
My friend!
‫Come on home, I'll give you a swell party
‫The party
‫The past in the United States
was whistling to stop a taxi
‫The morning after
‫Destination: Europe
I'm sailing at noon, so hurry!
She has a fever and needs careful attention
Determined to help the girl, he found work
‫Grandma, he's coming today
‫? Grandma, what's wrong
Grandma, I wish you'd meet him;
you're never here when he calls
‫Lunch time
Have you seen the soap?
Be back on time!
‫To play the part of a gentleman without the
millionaire was difficult, but he did his best
‫VIENNA DOCTOR HAS CURE FOR BLINDNESS
‫Thousands journey from all parts of the world
‫FREE OPERATION FOR POOR
Miraculous Work Of Surgeon
Astounds Medical Profession
Wonderful! Then I'll be able to see you
For me? Read it please
‫Now don't worry, I'll pay it
the first thing in the morning
‫Late
‫! You're late for the last time
‫Boxers' entry point
Get out!
Do you want to make some easy money?
That night
‫;Remember, we split fifty-fifty
and you promise you won't hurt me
Be careful, the boss might hear us
I've got to beat it; boss!
‫, Do you want to fight for a fifty dollar purse
Winner take all?
You'll fight him!
That's my lucky rabbit's foot
Let's take it easy and we'll split fifty-fifty
Winner take all!
Still hoping to get money for the girl,
he wandered the city
Back from Europe
‫Now don't worry about
the girl, I'll take care of her
Will a thousand dollars be enough?
Police! Help!
He has been robbed, search that man!
Where did you get this money?
Tell him you gave me that money
Who is this man?
This is for the rent
And this is for your eyes
I must be going
How can I ever thank you?
You're not going away?
For awhile
But you're coming back!
‫Autumn
I'd like to order some flowers
Why, what's the matter, child?
Nothing, only I thought he had returned
I've made a conquest!
You?
You can see now?
Yes, I can see now
THE END
High leverage crypto trading community
Trade with us! www.FilthyRichFutures.com