Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext
Hey, you got to admit, it's a
pretty swell-looking layout.
- I'll buy.
- Yeah?
But I can't do nothing
until the big fella gets here.
Here he comes now. He's the boss, you know.
Hello, Big Fella. How's tricks?
- Well, how about it?
- Sold.
But you're lucky you're getting paid for it.
You ain't got no right on this
side of the river anyway.
No hard feelings.
No, sure not.
- I'm moving my mob in tomorrow.
- Ok, tomorrow.
No hard feelings.
Nobody can hit nothing
with this piece of tin.
- Now what do you want Poppa to hit?
- You ain't hit anything yet.
Try the ceiling, aim straight up.
Hey, look out. What do
you think you're doing?
- I guess I know what I'm aiming at.
- You may be, but not with your head.
I'm aiming at that little duck
over in the corner.
By the way you're shooting Mister,
I'd rather you aimed at me.
You can't hit anything with that.
You do it for me. Come on, show me.
Showing off again.
Shooting all my profits away.
Every cent I make.
That's what you do every time I turn my back.
Why, you'll pay for every one
of them out of your salary.
And the next time you are
caught shooting, you are fired.
- Where you going?
- Supper.
Alright...
but see that you're back in half an hour.
Alright boys, see how good you can shoot.
Would he really fire you?
No, he's just like an old bull
we used to had back on the ranch.
He stamps around a lot,
but he hasn't got any horns.
- Hi, Nelly.
- Hi there Kid.
I almost wish he would fire you.
How's that?
Then you could get into a
regular act, something good.
You're in your usual number again?
You think you're pretty tall
and smart, don't you?
Come here.
That's what you really look like.
Yeah? Take a look at yourself.
I don't look like that. Let me go.
- Aren't you going to get any supper?
- I'd not hunger.
Well, I am, I'm starved.
- Want a weenie?
- May help.
- How many?
- Two.
Well, I can't eat two.
I didn't think you do.
- Elephant.
- You again?
Say, listen Kid, I've had about
enough of you round here.
This ain't even for a person anyway.
Didn't I tell you about that guy before?
You oughtn't be wasting your
dough in these joints.
- I won something, didn't I?
- Another elephant.
- Don't you want it?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- That's alright.
Gosh, is great.
It sure is.
I love it when is really rough...
And the big ones come tearing in.
I remember summers, it is a mile high.
And when they hit...
Boy.
I got all soaked.
- Gee, was swell.
- Yeah, I know.
I used to want to be a sailor before I
made up my mind about the circus.
You sure go for jobs with no dough.
There is plenty of money in the circus.
I can shoot and throw a
rope and do trick-riding.
I used to ride some pretty tough
broncs back on the ranch.
Yeah, you'll probably get stranded
again the way you did with the rodeo.
Only next time maybe you won't
even land with a Top-gun joint.
Money isn't everything.
People use it sometimes to get married on.
Don't you worry, I'm going to make
plenty of money for both of us.
Oh Kid, why won't you let me talk to Pop?
He could put you in right.
Doing what?
Beer.
I wouldn't like that kind of work.
It isn't work...
You just go round and
collect from saps that do.
That's all Pop does.
And he's always got a big roll.
Gee, you could be smarter than him.
We could've cars and servants and everything.
I wish you weren't in that racket.
You'd have different ideas about things.
Where your ideas got you?
We can't even afford to get married.
If you love me you'd marry me anyway.
Yeah and live in a tent.
Why not?
I don't like tents.
It isn't the tents.
It's me.
You don't really love me.
Don't be a sap.
I want to see you make something of yourself.
A racketeer like that stepfather of yours.
What's the matter with racketeers?
Anyway, they're smart.
They're not dumb...
like somebody I know.
Yeah?
Well then, why don't
you get yourself a racketeer.
Well, maybe I will.
Go ahead, you big dummy.
Wait a minute.
- That's yours.
- Thanks.
- Oh Kid Kid I'm sorry, I didn't mean it.
- Yes you did.
- Why, I didn't Kid, honest I didn't.
- Yes, you did. You think I'm a sap.
Of course I do Kid, but
I love you on the level.
No you don't.
- Yes I do, I do.
- I don't believe you.
I do.
- I do love you.
- I don't believe you.
- No you don't.
- I do.
I love you, love you.
Gee...
I got to get back.
Gosh, your late too. Happened before.
- Meet me when the shooting gallery closes?
- Yeah.
Pop got to go out, but
I'll be back at 22 o'clock.
- Hello.
- Come here.
Come here.
Where you've been?
Where you been?
I said where you've been.
Out with that shooting gallery mug again?
Answer me.
Come on. Spill it.
Good kid.
You'll never tell nobody nothing.
Here...
for keeping your trap shut.
A good kid.
Yeah, I got to go over to Blackie.
Stick around, till I get back.
Lay off.
Is mine.
You picked yourself a big-shot alright.
Go ahead, laugh.
He may not be a big-shot but he can
shoot better than anybody in this mob.
Yeah?
I saw him shoot a cigar
out of a guy's mouth, once...
when the guy got fresh.
Cigar? You don't say.
Jackie ain't sung a tune all day.
I'm worried about it.
Well, goodnight, Blackie.
- Get in there, you.
- Ah, don't get sore, Blackie.
It was just a good-night kiss.
A goodbye kiss, you mean.
Oh, you don't scare me.
Just because you're running this Mob,
don't mean you can pull anything like that.
Forget it.
It didn't mean nothing.
No hard feelings.
No...
not as long as you stay away from my girl.
Hello, Big Fella. How tricks?
Hey Pop...
If anything happened to Blackie, do you
think you could hold his mob together?
Sure.
It'd suit me better.
You've a nice sunny disposition.
I'd be willing to do business with you...
if anything happened to Blackie.
Thanks for the confidence in me, Big Fella.
Hello, Blackie, how things?
Hello, Aggie. How is trick?
- What's been keeping you?
- Me? Nothing. Why?
- Ready to go?
- Yeah.
I'll be with you in a minute.
You little bum, you.
Use your phone?
Say, listen, Babe.
Blackie and me is just going over to Joe's.
Meet me around the
corner from there in 25 minutes
if you have to break your arm to get there.
I said...
Yeah.
Anything wrong, sweetheart?
He better stop slapping me around
or he's going to get his some day.
Suppose he don't live that long?
It'd be alright with you, wouldn't it?
I don't hear you saying no.
You know, it's tough
keeping the ash on a cigar...
If you don't keep smoking them, they go out.
And the ash drops off.
- Ready?
- Hey...
You didn't happen to run into the
big fella on your way in, did you?
No.
See you soon, Aggie.
- I think I'll carry your rod for tonight.
- Ah?
What's up?
- Have I done anything?
- No, not yet.
Come on, get it out.
What kind of a bodyguard does that make me?
Well, Come on.
- I ain't going in there.
- Eh? Why not?
What's the good of me without a rod?
I ain't taking any chances tonight.
Now, listen Blackie...
you know the big fella wouldn't try
to put the fix on you through me.
- No?
- No.
Not him, nor nobody else.
They know what I think of you.
- Alright.
- Thanks.
Everything Ok?
- I guess so.
- No hard feelings.
No.
What's the idea.
Let go of my hand. Let go of my hand.
What's happening?
In the river.
Hey, you.
What do you know about this murder?
What murder?
Well, a fellow got bumped off back there.
And the guy passed his gun to a girl.
Oh, I saw a girl running down the street.
Oh, you did? Which way did she go?
She went down that street.
Oh?
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Why, Blackie and me was pals.
I'd like to get the guy who did it, myself.
You ain't figuring on suicide, are you?
Oh, lay off.
- Why Pop and Blackie was just like that.
- Yeah?
- Just like that when you give it to him.
- Me?
Why he went out before I got here.
I've just been sitting here playing
checkers with Aggie and...
- smoking.
- That's right.
Yeah?
- For how long?
- Oh...
Half an hour.
- Why don't you get wise Sister?
- We're your friends.
Everybody knows you didn't kill him.
So why not spill who did?
The Inspector would still give you a break.
We're just trying
to give you the right steer.
Well, how about it?
Decided to come through
with who gave you that gun?
No?
Ok...
possession of the gun makes you
an accessory-after-the-fact anyway.
Listen sweetheart, why
get left with an empty sack.
Why take the rap for Cooley?
You want to do a couple
of years up the river for him?
He turn you in.
It was Cooley, wasn't it?
Told you Pop isn't in this.
Well...
Maybe not.
- Bring Cooley in.
- Yes sir.
Well, Cooley, I guess
this is once you'll come clear.
She says you're out of it,
so I'm letting you go.
But I'm holding her unless
she'll spill who gave her that gun.
Don't hold out on the Inspector, Babe.
I'll leave you two alone.
Maybe you can make
her see what's good for her.
Sure, she'll listen to Pop.
Won't you, Babe?
Listen Pop, I was...
The Inspector is right, Babe.
Think it over.
You should tell him all you know about this.
Never hold anything out
on the Inspector, Babe.
Probably a plant, dictograph.
Safer to talk this way.
Play ball with them babe,
they let you take a plea.
Sit tight, keep your trap shut.
I'll get you out of this.
- The mob will stick by you.
- Pop, I was to meet The Kid at 22 o'clock.
You go to him, tell him.
So you won't even answer me, eh?
You'll never do a day's time.
Trust Pop.
You play ball and the mob won't let you down.
Gee Pop, supposing they do send me up...
I won't see The Kid maybe
for an awful long time.
Forget it. Don't squawk.
Nobody in the beer racket
ever welshed out on a pal yet.
What you doing traveling around
with that West Side mob, anyhow?
Pop, he might get troubled
being in a spot like this.
Tell him I love him Pop.
No matter what happens.
Be sure and tell him, I love him.
Sure, but don't you spill nothing to
that cop, I don't care what he promises.
Keep your shirt on. I won't.
Well, how about it?
Just drool.
Open now Babe, tell the Inspector...
Nice view you got from here, Inspector.
Glad you like it.
You'll probably see it plenty more times.
Why, you act as if I
wasn't trying to do you a favor.
Could I help it if she won't talk?
You know how kids are nowadays, they ain't
got no respect for parents or the law or...
Alright, alright, clear out a here.
But don't kid yourself I want to let you go.
There's a shyster with a writ for you
downstairs, so I've got to do it.
The law don't look so good when
it works both ways, eh Inspector?
Goodbye Pop.
- Goodbye, Babe. See you soon.
- Maybe not so soon as you think.
What you worried about
the time for, sweetheart?
Where you're going,
you'll have plenty to spare.
Hello Kid. Still open?
- Where's Nan?
- I don't know.
Try one Mac.
Get that cigarette over there.
Say...
they tell me you shoot
pretty good, is that right?
I shoot some.
Well, go ahead and show us what you can do.
Oh boy.
- Ah, what's funny?
- That you couldn't even hit it.
I can hit you.
Your initial?
Hey, give me that.
Right over the bump.
Say, you...
Say, listen Kid...
Why don't you get out
of this dime-a-throw racket?
I can use a guy that can shoot like you.
- Beer?
- Yeah.
- No.
- Why?
A man tried to sell me that number,
too, but it was no sale...
I'd just as soon be a cop, as that.
Oh, you would.
What would say if I told you
the cops framed Nan?
What do you mean?
They got her down at Headquarters.
- What for?
- Nothing.
A guy gets bumped off and
they plant the gun on her.
- The police did?
- Yeah.
That's cops for you.
But let's go up there.
- I got to see her.
- Not a chance.
They wouldn't let you see her.
Besides, she wants you to keep out of this.
But somebody is got to do something.
- Get her out.
- Not so easy.
Takes money.
Lots of it.
Big lawyers and expenses.
Have you got any?
Me?
No.
Well, I'm willing to do
all I can but it ain't enough.
Don't you want to help?
Yeah, but...
I haven't got any money.
Now, listen...
Why not play along with me?
You can make a lot of dough
in the beer business.
We can work together to get Nan out, see.
Well, what will I have to do?
Just pack around with me, I'll show you.
Here, take this and keep it on you.
What do you afraid of?
You won't have to shoot anybody.
Don't you want to help Nan?
Yeah...
But...
Alright.
Good boy.
Nan will be tickled to death.
When they open those gates and let me out.
Johnnie is going to be
sitting there waiting for me.
- He promised.
- Yeah.
Pop promised I wouldn't do a day in stir.
I'm doing it, ain't I?
Oh, well, you got a dirty deal.
Johnnie never pull a thing like that.
Look up and see me laughing
when you don't find him there.
And If I wave my handkerchief you're wrong.
I won't be.
They all leave you holding the bag.
Oh, I know the line they gave you.
Play ball with us Babe and
the mob will stick by you.
They never welsh
out on you in the beer racket.
I know, believe me.
They can all kiss my foot when I get out.
Well, I rather have a guy
in the beer racket...
- than a circus act.
- That's what I thought.
I thought the mob stuck
by you if you didn't squawk.
Now I'm glad The Kid
ain't mixed up with them.
With mugs like that.
- What's that?
- I don't see anything.
What's that car doing there?
Hijackers.
I better stop before they give it to us.
No, turn your lights off. Keep rolling.
Step on it.
Keep on rolling.
- I've come for Esther March.
- Alright.
A party for Esther March.
- Well, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
She's waving. Johnnie alright.
Long may she wave.
Oh Johnnie. Johnnie,
Johnnie, what's the matter?
Talk to me Johnnie. Better get the...
I thought there was something funny about it.
Poor Johnnie.
That's being Johnnie-on-the-spot alright.
They all get it, sooner or later.
Your lucky your boyfriend isn't
mixed up in the booze racket.
Don't know I know it.
4753.
It's no use the rest of you
people waiting, it's nearly 4 now.
I've been waiting so long.
Well, I'm sorry, it isn't my fault if
we've had such a crowded day.
Better hurry, you only have a minute.
- Is swell seeing you.
- Well, is great seeing you.
- Boy, you're good to see.
- And you too, Babe.
Yet...
I wish...
What?
I wish I could just touch you.
Babe...
Oh Kid...
See...
I thought you might never come.
I had to tell them that we're married
or they wouldn't let me see you.
- Did you? Did you say that?
- And how.
- Have you missed me?
- I'll say I have.
Kid...
What have you done to yourself?
Do you like my get-up?
- The circus is in town?
- Not much.
Say...
Oh, gee, you must be come up in the world.
- I'll say I have.
- Doing what?
Beer.
Beer?
I'm working with Pop.
Pop?
Oh Kid.
You had it right, Babe.
It's great, I love it.
Oh, don't kid me please.
I'm not. What's the matter with you?
- No, no, no, it can't be true, it mustn't.
- Why, I thought you'd be tickled to death.
- Oh Kid Kid...
- Time is up.
Sorry, but you came late.
- Just a minute please.
- No, I'm sorry.
Goodbye Nan.
I'll be waiting outside for you
when you come out.
- Come along, come along.
- Goodbye Kid.
Goodbye.
You must've come up in the world.
I certainly have.
Doing what?
Beer.
Beer?
- I'm working with Pop.
- Oh Kid.
No, no.
Is great.
- I love it.
- Oh, no Kid. No.
Time is up.
- You certainly had it right, Babe.
- Time is up.
It's great.
- I love it.
- No Kid, no.
Come along, come along.
Lucky your boyfriend isn't
mixed up in the booze racket.
Beer.
I love it.
That's being Johnnie-on-the-spot alright.
- Beer.
- Johnnie-on-the-spot.
It can't be true, can't.
You had it right.
- A party for Nan Cooley.
- Alright Nan.
- How do you like it?
- Swell.
- Hello, you must be Nan.
- Yeah, to my friends.
- Then it is to me.
- You know the big fella, don't you?
OH, no, she doesn't.
But she will. I'm glad to see you out.
You know, you're a lucky mug Kid.
Hot stuff, eh Chief?
Red hot.
- See, what did I tell you?
- Yeah?
It's a swell joint alright.
Nan baby you're looking Ok.
- I'm alright.
- Well, what's eating you?
You ain't sore? Not at Pop.
Can the Pop stuff. Sell it
to somebody who wants it.
Now, is that any way to talk,
and me so glad to see you?
Yeah.
What did you do to get me out?
He did everything he could, I know he did.
Sure. Oh Pansy...
Pansy.
She's your new Mom.
Oh, I'm glad to meet the family.
- Be yourself, I'm dieting.
- Don't let Nan get your goat.
Oh, I don't blame her.
Going up the river is no picnic.
I thought you'd gone.
- Hey, I have an idea.
- They must be giving them away.
I'm giving a party for Nan.
Tomorrow night at the Club Villa,
so the mob can meet her.
- Coming-out party?
- That's right.
- What do you say?
- I'm tired.
It do you good.
Thanks Chief, we'll be there.
Mighty nice of you to do that for Nan.
I'll do a lot more for you too.
How do you spell it?
T - W - O?
Well, I'll see you tomorrow night. Goodbye.
Oh Nan, we got a lot
of swell dresses for you.
Pansy picked them out herself.
Come on Pop, you and me got a date.
What for?
- To buy a new dress for the party.
- But you got lots of new dresses.
Oh Pop. Don't be mean to Pansy.
Ain't she clever to speak of answers?
Why don't you like
the big fella? He's a great guy.
Yeah? Well, I know better.
Oh Kid, let's not go to that party tomorrow.
Let's drop this mob, before anything happens.
I thought we settled all that out in the car.
If you call not listening
to me, settling anything.
- Kiss me.
- Let's both beat it tonight.
Kiss me.
Kid, there's going to be trouble, I know it.
Let's be sensible.
That's what I am being.
Mighty sensible.
Get a load of the big fella.
He's all steamed up.
Yes, he sure is.
And is it a burn-up for The Kid. Oh boy.
That brat of yours is certainly a queer one.
She's got The big fella out
on his feet and don't like it.
She'll learn.
Oh, stop worrying about The Kid, Baby.
I just don't want to dance
with you all the time.
Can't you give The Kid a break?
At least let me sit with him for a while.
I will give him all the break he needs.
Hey Baldy, Come on, sit down.
Sorry old man, but this is my chair here.
No, it isn't.
But this is my lady's wrap here.
Well, you can have that, we don't need it.
Pick that up.
Pick that up, I said.
Let's have another dance.
- No, thank you, but if you don't mind...
- Oh, no excuses. Come on.
Really I don't...
And if you start anything, you'll
get more than a fork in your hand.
He must know about us.
We're going to get married.
That's more of a reason...
He wants to show you where you get off.
You're getting too big in this mob.
- I thought, I thought you and him were...
- Yeah.
Were...
Until he got a look at her.
She better lay off him or...
I can make you very happy, Baby.
You could have everything.
A car of your own...
Chauffeur and all the clothes you can buy.
No thanks, not tonight, or any otter night.
Oh, think it over.
I'll leave the offer open.
You think I'll change my mind, don't you?
Others have.
It's about my turn, isn't it?
Oh Kid, I thought
you were never going to ask.
Hey Pop...
- That kid of yours made a big hit with me.
- Yeah, so I've noticed.
- Any objections?
- No, sure not.
- But...
- But what?
Well you know how it is with The Kid.
- He's pretty handy with that gat of his.
- Yeah?
- I take care of him.
- So could we Chief.
- The rest of this is mine.
- What's the idea?
We just started and I've been
dancing with you all evening.
- But I want this one too.
- No you don't.
Oh, who do you think you're talking to?
Come on, Baby.
Wait a minute.
Hey, trying to get tough?
Nobody takes my girl
away from me, not even you.
Get that?
Ok.
No hard feelings.
Get off the floor,
what's the matter with you?
Don't get excited, buddy.
Kid, you shouldn't have done that.
There'll be trouble.
- I can take care of myself.
- Blackie didn't do any more than you did.
Nobody is taking you away
from me, Blackie or no Blackie.
Well, forget it.
What's the matter?
- Take me home, will you Kid?
- Home, why?
I'm tired.
Let's get out of here.
How about those two guys from Detroit?
We don't owe them.
Alright, that will be fine..
What do you suppose
we want guys from out of town for?
They're gone.
He's taken her home. Pop's house.
Now listen, make it fast.
Here is the address.
Listen Kid, I know what I'm talking about.
What about Blackie?
Nan baby, you're seeing ghosts.
Things won't look so tough in the morning.
You're not going back to the party?
- No. Home.
- Promise?
Sure, the party is no fun without you.
Goodnight Nan.
No more nightmare, see?
Excuse me sir, there's
a man outside to see you.
- Who is it?
- I don't know sir.
Don't go Kid.
- Didn't he say what he wanted?
- No Sir.
Just that it was important.
Alright.
Do go out Kid, It's a plant, sure.
That's what I want to find out.
Don't Kid, don't.
Don't worry.
I know what I'm doing.
No Kid.
Kid, don't, don't be foolish.
- Kid please don't go.
- I'm alright. You stay here.
Here?
Kid Kid, don't go.
Kid, come back here.
- Looking for me?
- Who are you?
You ought to know
who I am, if it's so important.
Drop those.
Kick them out.
Now go home and tell your mommas
you've been born again tonight.
Step on it.
What I tell you?
I'll take you upstairs to your room.
We got to beat it
tonight, catch a train, go now.
No. You're going right to bed.
Good night.
Where you going?
Back to have a little
session with the big fella.
Please Kid please don't go.
If you love me, they'll get you sure.
They're not getting me now nor anytime.
Kid please don't go.
Please, if you love me, don't go.
I won't let you.
- What you want me to do, crawl?
- This is no crawling.
Listen Nan,
I've got to handle this my own way.
I'm having a showdown with
them tonight and that's flat.
Oh, no Kid, no.
Kid please please don't go.
Please, if you love me.
Kid, don't...
Kid, come back.
Come back, you fool.
Fool.
Hello...
Club Villa?
Mr Maskal please.
Tell him to hurry. It's very important.
Big Fella?
It's Nan.
Well...
Does that offer of yours still hold?
I'll say it does.
Tonight?
Great.
I'm leaving for home right now.
I'll give you 5 minutes
to pack up and get out.
You think you're a fast worker, don't you?
Throw me out, grab the kid's girl,
knock him off. All before morning.
But, you're not giving this
baby the air. I'm not leaving.
No?
Look who's here.
Hello, pal.
- Where's the big fella?
- He's gone home.
- Why?
- Nothing.
Where's Nan? Did she
fall without being pushed?
- Listen big fella, have a heart.
- Oh, no, it's top stuff.
- Get out and step on it.
- In a hurry, ain't you?
What's the matter? You expecting company?
You know your way out.
- Well hello Baby.
- Hello.
Is nice of you to come.
Oh, let me help you to take off your clothes.
Oh, heavy, isn't it?
What you carrying, gold?
Haven't said.
Now, is that nice?
I always carry it with me.
You won't need it here.
No.
Oh now, is that living up
to your side of the bargain?
- I told you it was COD.
- Oh, Ok baby.
Don't get so fussed about it.
I'll call McCoy now and tell him
to lay off, if that's all you want.
I'll do more than that for you, Baby.
Hello? Club Villa?
This is Maskal, get me McCoy.
Only with Kid out of the mob.
Run him out of the rackets, that's the deal.
When you come through, I will, not before.
Alright baby, have it your own way.
You'll see, I'll treat you square.
Oh darling.
I'm crazy about you.
And you'll see how happy I'll
make you, you can have everything.
Car, clothes, everything.
- What about Agnes?
- OH, who cares about Agnes?
Hello Mac...
Say Mac, forget it that about The Kid.
Yeah, I want you to lay off him.
Baby, you sure have me on the run.
Yeah, you heard me, forget it.
And don't you worry about Agnes.
I am through with her for good.
Yes, I want you to lay off him, yes.
But listen Chief, he just took a sock at me.
Hello hello...
Let me in. Big Fella. Open the door.
Help. Help.
A shot. I heard it and the door is locked.
Open the door.
Open the door or we'll kick it in.
Come on boys, hurry up.
Big fella, speak to me.
Speak to me. Oh, he's dead.
- You'll get plenty for this.
- I didn't do it, I tell you.
- I didn't do it.
- Then who did?
- What's going on here?
- The big fella, look.
Kid Kid, they think I did it, but I didn't.
I just heard 2 shots and somebody
threw the gun in and locked the door.
- That's true Kid, honest.
- Honest?
- Why, you killed him, you...
- I didn't do that, swear I didn't.
Of course you didn't.
Now, wait a minute.
- You believe me, don't you Kid?
- Sure, I believe you.
But what was you doing
here? Why did you come?
That's my business.
It wasn't because you thought you
could get me out of a tough spot, eh?
- No.
- Well, I know better.
- Now, get out of here.
- Say...
- Who's going? What right have you got to...
- Beat it.
Well, I like that.
Look here Kid.
- We ought to wait till McCoy gets here.
- I'm running this show.
Good night.
Maybe Mac will have
something to say about this.
Maybe he will.
I'll just stick around and see.
Well, what's the good of all this arguing?
It's a cinch, sure.
If Nan didn't do it, who did?
- Yeah, who?
- That's what I'd like to know.
How should I know?
Plenty of people would've
been glad to knock him off.
Who, for instance?
- Agnes, for one.
- Me? How do you get that way?
Why should I?
The big fella told Nan
that he'd given you the air.
Ah, that's just about of lucky as that
little rubbish that yarn of hers.
Me and the boys think it was Nan.
We want to know who's
running this mob now, anyhow.
- I am.
- Who says so?
I say so, for one.
He's right boys.
It's alright, the Kid.
- Sure.
- That's right.
And when you talk to me take
that toothpick out of your mouth.
Ah, you dumb egg.
Are you going to let him get
away with a thing like this?
If he's running this mob, what you're
going to do about the big fella?
He was knocked off, wasn't he?
Yeah, what do you going to do about it?
The payoff is up to you.
- Sure.
- It's up to you Kid.
- Are you going to let her get away with it?
- Not much.
Don't worry.
Whoever it is, will get what's coming to him.
To her you mean.
If it wasn't her, what's that gun
doing here? It's hers.
She said it was. And the door locked.
- That's right Kid.
- Say...
Are you trying to kid us?
- Trying to give us the run-around.
- What's your idea?
Well, what about it?
- Who said it was her gun?
- She did.
That's right, she said so herself.
- The door...
- The door was locked.
- If she didn't do it, who did?
- He knows what he is doing.
Don't be a sap.
Well, what do you going to do about it?
Leave it to me.
Don't bother, big fella.
We'll handle this.
We'll take him for a buggy-ride.
I'm running this show,
and I'm driving that buggy.
Hello Nan? Listen, meet me outside
your house in 5 minutes, will you?
No, I can't explain now.
No, everything is alright.
So far, so good.
But be sure that you go through with it.
I said I would, didn't I?
And don't try to pull any fast ones.
Or we'll pay double. You get me?
You wouldn't try to frighten me,
would you mister?
Wait a minute.
Don't be in such a hurry Chief.
We're going your way.
He thinks he can put one over.
We'll let the both of them have it.
Suits me.
- Kid?
- Yeah, Come on.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing, nothing. Get in.
- What for? Where we going?
- Get in, get in. It's alright.
What's the matter, Aggie?
Why are you in such a sweat?
Me?
I'm alright.
I thought you said the big fella
hadn't given you the air?
Sure.
You heard me.
Where were you going with this?
What you're hiding it
back of the curtain for?
Hey, what you trying to do?
- Can't you see that train?
- Slow down. Are you crazy?
Stop.
Pull up.
Slow down.
Hey, what's the idea?
Hey, are you crazy? Slow down.
Put on those brakes or I'll...
- Well, why don't you go ahead and shoot?
- Go ahead, give it to him.
At this speed? Don't be a fool.
- Feed it to her, That will stop him.
- Yeah.
You put a slug in her
and you'll get the clip.
That help you make up your mind.
Cover them.
Now shoot or tip your hardware overboard.
Thanks boys. We're slowing up here.
This way out.
Maybe the walk back home
will clear your heads.
And you can figure out for yourselves,
that it was Agnes that got the big fella.
And get out.
And you can kiss a beer barrel
goodbye for me, forever.
Oh?
Hey...
No hard feelings.
Watch Movies, TV Series and Live Sports
Signup Here -> WWW.ADMITME.APP