[dramatic music]
[music continues]
(male narrator)
The most improbable event
of the 20th century
occurred in Havana, Cuba.
The revolutionary victors
marched in
and the national complexion
changed completely.
They had been liberated.
The survivors of the old regime
escaped as best they could.
Taking with them only
a few meager effects
such as the Cuban treasure
and other art objects.
It wasn't always easy to
smuggle a loot out of Cuba
and so secret meetings were
being held all over the island.
This story of robbery,
double-cross, and murder
begins with
just such a meeting.
[car engine whirring]
[dramatic music]
Are you Renzo Capetto?
I am. Who are you?
Never mind who I am,
it's the mission that counts.
Let's get on with it.
As an American gambler
and gangster
you're above suspicion.
Of course you know that our
government has been overthrown.
- You know, I heard that.
- Shut up.
But not for long.
We'll be back.
And if you think you have seen
executions, now...oh, boy!
- Bravo!
- Bravissimo!
Shut up.
But of course in order to
finance a great revolution..
...it has been necessary
for us to, uh
steal the Cuban treasure.
- Rob?
- Shut up.
[siren wailing]
Let us proceed.
You're going
to lose your casino.
so you will
be leaving Cuba anyway.
You have a big yacht and you can
leave any time you wish.
Such as immediately.
Therefore I'm going to entrust
you a solemn trust.
Here we have one-fourth
of the Cuban treasure.
Your group, General Tostada,
Colonel Cabeza Grande
and a squad of men will proceed
to Ciudad Trujillo.
There you'll wait for us to
relieve you of the money.
One-fifth of which will be paid
to you, do you understand?
I get the whole picture.
Now, you do the rest.
Senores.
General Tostada, Colonel Cabeza
Grande, Senor Renzo Capetto..
My name's Happy Jack Monahan,
glad to meet you, gen.
[speaking in foreign language]
And now, the gold.
[chattering in foreign language]
[whistling]
You two better get
into the car.
General doesn't know any
English, Senor Capetto.
I'll be his translator
for you.
[speaking in foreign language]
Now, it's time to go.
- Adios.
I'll see you later, huh?
[dramatic music]
[indistinct chattering]
[gunshots]
The first move and the great
conspiracy had been made.
The Cuban treasury was now
in the general hands
of Renzo Capetto.
The most trustworthy man ever
to be deported from Sicily.
They thought they were smart.
But little
did they know that I
Sparks Moran,
was an American agent.
Luckily I had been able to work
my way into the crew by posing
as a notorious gun machine
burglar from Chicago.
My real name is XK150.
Hey, you, come on down here
and help with this.
(female #1)
'How'd it go, boopsie?'
We had a harried little chase,
but we got the stuff.
Crazy.
Hey, Colonel Grande,
you can bring your men aboard.
What happens
with all that mob?
I don't know.
I expected
an officer or two
but it looks like we're gonna
a little difficulty.
And you'll think of a way to
remove them and grab that loot..
...cause you're my big,
strong, swingin' brain.
You're sweet, baby.
Hi, sis.
Hi, baby doll.
- Did they scare you?
- Ah, just a little.
- Awww.
- Alright, boys.
Get ready to go.
Pete, take the wheel.
Jack, you and, uh, Clarks, uh,
Sparks, get ready to cast-off.
[motorboat revving]
Well, well, this is a beautiful
night for sailing.
(Sparks)
And so we left Cuba forever.
Sailing into
the most astounding adventure
to be inflicted upon man.
And what a group we were.
The big cheese
was Renzo Capetto.
Alias Capo Rozetto,
alias Ratto Pazetti
alias Zeppo Sticcato
alias Shirley Lamour.
At 15, he served his first
stretch for rolling a drunk
in the lobby of the Waldorf
Astoria, new year's eve, 1934.
In 1940, he was involved in an
unsuccessful attempt
to nominate Benito Mussolini
for the Republican ticket.
During the war, he was rejected
by the navy, marines
and the SS.
Now, deported, he's retained
his contacts with the syndicate
and is still regarded as a
dangerous character.
[comical music]
Mary-Belle Monahan,
alias Mary-Monahan Belle
alias Belle-Mary Monahan,
alias Monahan-Mary Belle.
They say she was a gun moll
just because Lucky Luciano
gave her a Rolls Royce
every Christmas
and they can't really prove
that she sneaked
into the Hollywood Bowl
with a tommy gun
and rubbed off the convention
of police chiefs in 1956.
All I know that she got nailed
when she was pushing heroin
in the laundry room
at the boys town.
But I'm willing to give anyone
the benefit of the doubt.
Especially when she's as crazy
looking as Mary-Belle.
This is Happy Jack Monahan.
So called because he developed
a muscle spasm in his cheeks
from watching too many
Humphrey Bogart pictures.
Happy Jack's record is brief.
His only crimes having been
committed after his sister
Mary-Belle talked Renzo into
giving him a job.
Up until that time, Happy Jack
had been a tennis bum.
Sleeping under the bleaches
at forest hills
and mooching nickels
in the BMT subway.
Since taking up with Renzo
he's become a well known dice
loader and murderer.
The most obscure member of the
dark quartet
is Pete Peterson Jr.
Son of Pete Peterson Sr.
Famed Wardville bird mimic.
Pete Jr. inherited his father's
talent for animal imitations
but unfortunately, blew
his brain out of whack
while imitating
a whooping crane
at the Elks convention picnic
in Osh Kosh in 1942.
Since then, anyone's been able
to convince Pete of anything.
Renzo found him struggling
along as a pickpocket
at Jones Beach and took him
with him in his exile.
Since then, he's been
Renzo's faithful servant.
Shining his shoes
and rubbing out his enemies.
In return, Renzo permits him
to imitate any animal
that comes into his head.
[animal cry]
That, for instance,
was the mating call
of a Himalayan yak.
There they are, my shipmates.
I didn't know where
they were taking those
unsuspecting Cubans,
but I knew they were taking.
And so with grim faces,
we set our helm
against their perilous future.
[singing]
Okay, now before I begin,
has anyone anything to say?
Pete.
[mooing]
How about you, Jack?
What do you think we should do?
- Give up?
- Oh, now, honey.
Is that any way for
Mary-Belle's big man to talk?
Now, look, we've got to get rid
of at least half of these Cubans
without making the rest
of them suspicious.
There used to be
a Cuban fisherman
by the name of Hemmingway.
He got hooked on a sea monster..
...in these waters
a couple of years ago.
And he was dragged for miles.
Got a lot of publicity.
We're gonna show these boys
the greatest sea monster
they ever saw in their lives.
'Jack, in my trunk,
there are some garden rakes'
'used for weeding tomatoes.'
'You get them. and,
and sharpen them like scalpels.'
Pete, you mix up a mess
of olive oil and green ink
'and snag some seaweed
from over the side.'
And, Jack,
what are you gonna do?
- Sharpen up the garden rakes.
- Good boy.
Pete, how about you?
[barking]
Does he have to do that?
Alright, Jack, beat it.
[singing]
We've had a good life together,
haven't we, baby?
Um, you know it, boops.
Winters in Tijuana.
Summers in Cicero.
Remember that wonderful trip
we took to Monte Carlo?
You mean the time we heisted
all those $100 chips?
Sure.
(Sparks)
I'll admit I couldn't really
hear anything through that door
but I was sure
they were up to no good.
I knew it was up to me
to stop them.
Now we are off again
to parts unknown.
It's like a second honeymoon.
You know something?
We ought to get married.
Now, don't be a drag, baby.
[chuckles]
How much jack do you think
is in that strongbox?
I don't know. There's plenty
of Cuban sugar though.
What are we gonna do
with all of it?
I don't know.
I always wanted to open up
a home for the aged hoodlums.
Baby, you got a heart
as big as all our dollars.
[instrumental music]
(Sparks)
Our government agent lives
in constant peril.
I devised my undetectable
radio set
using simulated hotdogs
for knobs..
...and tubes
inside of dill pickles
while watching
a number of sewer workmen
during lunch hour.
It comes in mighty handy,
believe you me.
One little slip and I could be
headed for Davy Jones' locker.
Hello, Havana.
This is Agent XK150.
I'm making my first
official report.
So far, not too much
has happened.
But I'm anticipating.
Friends of Capetto and his gang
are on board as suspected.
I am with them.
I will call you again
soon one of these days.
This is Agent XK150
signing off.
Hey, what's happening?
Just having a bite.
[munching]
Gee, that looks good.
Do you mind if I join you?
[munching]
Come to mama.
Great.
Six is the point.
[speaking in foreign language]
The general says,
"Good mornin'
you gorgeous,
beautiful creature."
Would you ask the general to
remove himself from my presence?
Um..
[speaking in foreign language]
The general says
you are, um, you are a..
...golden angel flower singin'.
Would you tell the general that
I feel that he'd be most at home
barbecuing slowly
over a hock spit.
Uh..
[speaking in foreign language]
You must be a glutton
for punishment.
[coughing]
Oh, now, what do you want?
You're too good for this life.
You're young and you're
innocent. You should get out.
Probably get a..
Are you unwell?
The gettin' is great.
You're a victim of circumstance.
I try. I do try.
You're a crazy mixed-up kid.
I'm perfectly adjusted
to my life of crime.
Now, what is your story?
Oh, well, you see,
I'm beyond help, but you're not.
You could find a clean,
young man to marry and..
I haven't got the time.
But I can help you, Mary-Belle.
You can turn blue.
Don't worry, Mary-Belle.
I'll save ya...or die.
That's a comforting alternative.
(Sparks)
A secret agent
should never sleep.
But there I was,
dreaming of mom's apple pie.
While up on deck, Renzo
and his cut-throats were taking
their first step.
Killing an innocent Cuban.
And pretending
some imaginary monster did it
just so they would be panicked
into changing course.
So that Renzo could steer them
to his own picked destination.
[dramatic music]
[snoring]
[choking]
Pete, wait one minute.
Then give the alarm.
(Sparks)
But what none of us knew
was that the monster
invented by Renzo
had already been invented
by somebody else.
By a couple of other monsters,
I guess.
[growling]
[screaming]
[continues growling]
Help, p-p-police, mayor.
Uh, the-the-there's a monster!
[speaking in foreign language]
What did he say?
The general says,
"What happened?"
Now, in my stated opinion,
those soldiers were attacked
by some weird creature
from the sea.
It came in, did your boys in
and vanished again.
[laughing]
What's so funny?
A creature. How silly.
Did you really think it..
[continues laughing]
[speaking in foreign language]
In few words, colonel.
Well, uh, the general says, uh
"You're right.
It is a monster."
[speaking in foreign language]
The general says, "These waters
are very dangerous.
So, we must plan a new course."
[speaking in foreign language]
Catch that?
Our brave General Tostada,
didn't miss an excuse
to blow the trip
and change course.
Do you think he's got
a glint in his eye?
Pure gold.
Maybe we won't have to
knock them all off.
Oh!
You boys are getting careless.
I told you to kill one.
Not two. Was it hard
to get your count?
Okay, Pete. Now, take the wheel.
But, gee, I-I thought
it was only one.
Well, I can't figure this out.
(Sparks)
So we were going
somewhere I didn't know.
Washington didn't know.
Renzo didn't know.
We all had to find out.
Ah, gentlemen, I think we ought
to make our decision.
[growling]
Thank you, Pete.
- Now, has anybody got an idea?
- About what?
About where we're going.
I thought it was to
Ciudad Trujillo we were going.
Oh, no, no.
That's been changed.
Well, General Tostado thinks
we ought to change course
in order to escape the monster.
[speaking in foreign language]
Oh, no, no,
I think we ought to go--
Let's go to India. I've always
wanted to see the sacred cow.
I think we ought
to go to Cannes.
Nice this time
of the year.
Now, will you listen?
So strange, my friends.
I always had a secret desire.
I always wanted to go to Bali.
- You know.
- Bali?
(both)
Bali?
(all)
'Bali.'
[dramatic music]
(Mary-Belle)
'Now you say no.'
We are not going to Bali.
[general speaking
in foreign language]
No, please tell the general
that I am convinced
we ought to go to San Juan,
Puerto Rico.
[speaking in foreign language]
This is Agent XK150
calling Agent XK120.
Via 1 Nadia S.L.
Come in, Havana.
Now, the first thing
we've got to think
about is to escape
this finky monster.
Now if you take a look
at the charts, you'll notice
there's a lot of deep water,
just north of Puerto Rico.
'Too deep for the monster
to live in.'
Well, how do you know
he can't live in deep water?
Because of his feet.
He's a walker and he's got
to stay at the bottom.
- 'Alright, stupid?'
- Yeah, it's stupid..
Now, when we get to Puerto Rico
we'll take
the strongbox ashore.
Now as an American,
I won't be noticed.
I'll take a plane
up to Ciudad Trujillo.
Take the box with me.
I can say unequivocally, without
the slightest qualm of doubt
that this gang is...
heading for Bali.
I think the government
should watch for us
at the Panama Canal.
Over.
[speaking in foreign language]
The general says, "It's alright.
We may go to Puerto Rico.
But he won't keep this
trunk box out of his sight."
Okay, it's a deal.
I think I smell land.
Are we almost there?
Oh, about six or eight hours.
Another lucky shoot up.
Four's the point.
- You're ravishing.
- You're sick.
Listen, I have a plan.
As soon as we get there,
we'll wait for night.
And when Renzo isn't looking,
we'll jump off and swim ashore.
Through shark infested waters,
so no one will follow us.
Then we'll steal the sailing
dinghy and head for Brazil.
How do you like that?
I think it's grand,
you ought to do it.
Well, I meant you too.
Honey, I wouldn't ride
on the same bus with you.
Now, Pete, I want you
to listen carefully.
Now, on the North coast
of the big island
there's a teeny speck of land
called "Isla del Borracho."
Named after one of
Columbus's lieutenants.
It should be deserted by now.
We ought to be
able to land there, huh?
[imitating bird]
Good. Now, there's a reef
around the island
and a very narrow opening
which we have to go through.
I'm going to run
this yacht on the rocks
right at the entrance.
Now, during the panic,
we'll take the strongbox
load it on a skiff
and head for shore.
Now, Pete, when we get over
30 feet of water
I'll give you a signal. And then
I want you to capsize the boat.
You understand?
Later, Pete, we'll come back
and dive for it.
You understand everything?
Sure.
Uh, we-we hit the rocks and then
we put the box in the skiff
and then we dump it
over 30 feet of water.
So we can come back and get it.
And that's because
it's filled with nitroglycerin.
That shouldn't be
onboard anyway.
Isla del Borracho.
Look at the reefs.
Reefs dead ahead.
We're starting through.
[indistinct chatter]
[roaring]
[intense music]
[crashing]
I'll save you.
- No.
- Come on, Marry-Belle.
Remove your hands, sir.
Very well. I won't leave you,
I'll never leave you.
- We'll drown together.
- You've been--
My life jacket.
My, what a short memory.
[speaking in foreign language]
[indistinct]
You two go down and get
the strongbox out. Go on.
It's alright.
Be calm, everybody.
The boat's insured.
[creaking]
[bickering]
(Sparks)
Everything went
according to plan.
For Renzo
and the monsters.
[dramatic music]
♪ Row, row, row your boat
♪ Gently up the creek
♪ Merrily, merrily,
merrily, merrily ♪
♪ I'm going to be sick ♪
You know this reminds me
of one time on Lake Minnetonka.
Louie Schmidt
and I were paddling along.
When what do you think
happened?
[intense music]
General says
you'll have your orders
as soon as he can
estimate the situation.
Well, you can tell old General..
Tell him he's through
giving orders around here.
Now, look. You men have
no money and you have no guns
and you're on US soil.
That's alright.
I'm on your side.
Pete, I want you to
search the island.
See if anybody lives here.
Jack, you take one of
the life boats and rode ashore.
Go to San Juan
and rent us a fishing boat
and plenty of diving gear.
[cawing]
Ah-huh. Come on, boy, let's go.
Oh, Colonel.
You see if you can get your men
to build us a Lean-To
or something
to keep the rain off.
[speaking in foreign language]
You look just great.
Could stay here forever.
That won't be necessary, baby.
Why?
Well, the way
I've figured, these Cubans
aren't very much at diving.
But Jack, Pete and I are all
pretty good spear fisherman.
We'll go down,
find the strongbox
and hide it in the hole
in the reef.
After that we'll tell
the Cubans that it's no use.
Give up.
It'll be safe there
for months.
Even years. Until we're ready
to come back and get it.
You like it?
Boopsie..
...some times you're so smart,
you make me sick.
[roaring]
[cawing]
[crowing]
[clucking]
[grunting]
[indistinct chatter]
Eat. Eat. It's good.
It's good.
Where'd you find her, Pete?
Pete, aren't you gonna
introduce me to the lady?
Isn't she beautiful, Renzo?
Very lovely.
Where did you meet?
[trumpeting]
Oh, no!
That must mean
they're in love.
I wish you many happy
returns of the day.
Oh, isn't that a ring
you're wearing, Miss, uh..
Rosina Perez.
It's a wedding ring.
Hop along, baby doll.
Aloha.
About 20 bottles, ten regulars,
mask, spear guns that works.
Overdid it as usual.
Well, okay, we're gonna
start diving this afternoon.
I brought something else
along with me too.
[speaking in foreign language]
Carmelita, I'd like you
to meet Renzo Capetto
my sister Mary-Belle,
Mr. Pete Peterson and..
Well, I don't know who
the large woman with him is.
Rosina Perez.
Hi.
Hello, everybody.
You found this woman
in San Juan?
She was livin' in a sorority
house down by the docks.
She's awful friendly.
Why don't you come
over with me, honey.
I'll show you
our sorority house.
Senor Capetto. I have the honor
to report that my men
will be ready in one hour.
Ready for what?
To dive
to the strongbox.
You mean,
your men are divers?
Yes. They're Cuban army
front men.
Ole!
I have a situation
well in hand.
Mary-Belle was weakening
as I'm sure you've noticed.
Then she came into my life.
I didn't see her coming, but
somehow I sensed her presence
and knew that my life
was changed forever.
[indistinct]
Hello. Who are you?
Carmelita Rodriguez.
Sparks Moran.
As a trained espionage agent,
I could tell
that she was attracted to me.
But I wanted Mary-Belle.
And Mary-Belle wanted Renzo.
And Renzo wanted to go.
[screaming]
Sparks. Sparks, I'll kill you.
Just keep this thing firm.
- You alright?
- Oh, yeah.
Alright, we're ready.
Where's the Cuban army?
I don't know.
But I'm ready.
[speaking in foreign language]
No!
No..
[yelling]
[trumpeting]
Goodbye.
Good luck, boopsie.
[intense music]
[music continues]
The search for
the strongbox had begun.
But the sea was
cladded up with Cubans.
Dispersed by General Tostada
to search independently.
All those Cubans,
alone in the deep.
This was a chance for Renzo to
again become the sea monster.
A lonely Cuban had found one of
the many wrecks on the bottom.
And Renzo had
found the lonely Cuban.
[intense music]
Their attack was
cleanly executed.
The victim was dead.
The killers delighted.
But not satisfied.
Renzo must have another
quart of Latin blood.
We waited.
Sensing the dangers below.
While the unholy three
sought new prey.
[intense music]
It didn't take them
long to find it.
[indistinct]
What happened to them?
Was this shark?
- No, it was a monster.
- What do you mean a monster?
A real, live,
honest to goodness monster
with claws and everything.
Oh, you're nuts.
The way they say.
Carmelita, it's too
dangerous for you here.
Let's run away
and live a little.
No, I'm in love
with Sparks.
- Sparks Moran?
- Si.
How can you be in love with him?
He's an idiot.
- You should love me.
- No. I'm in love with him.
And I don't care
if I never see you again.
If I had only paid my
life insurance premium
I'd kill myself.
Oh! No, no, no!
- Don't kill yourself.
- Why not?
No, you come with me.
I'll show you.
Come with me to the jungle.
You've seen one jungle,
you've seen them all.
You come with me,
you see and you like.
Hello, colonel.
Senor, I'm very much afraid
of this monster.
Well, then, just
pick up and go home.
No! I am an officer.
We will not stop
until we have the strongbox.
From now on we'll dive
with spear guns.
Crazy.
Mango.
Senor Happy Jack. This girl is
my daughter. Her name is Mango.
- Mango?
- Si.
[speaking in foreign language]
I was telling her what that
Carmelita do to you.
I was telling her
to cheer you up.
Oh, gee, thanks, Rosina.
But it really
wasn't necessary.
Oh. Do you not like Mango?
Oh, yeah.
I like her.
[speaking in foreign language]
She must speak
good English, senor.
Oh, I don't think
that's gonna matter at all.
Okay. I'm going back now.
Mr. Pete Peterson Jr.
He is waiting for me now.
- Adios, Rosina.
- Adios.
[soft instrumental music]
[speaking in foreign language]
[imitating lion roar]
[intense music]
- Are you alright, Rosina?
- Oh, I'm alright, my hero.
Hey. Where's Happy Jack?
Oh, come on.
I take you to them.
- Them?
- Yes.
[speaking in foreign language]
Oh, I don't know
what you said, Mango.
But it sure was wonderful.
[speaking in foreign language]
I feel the same way, Mango.
Why, I never felt like this
in my whole life before.
[speaking in foreign language]
Oh, I know, Mango.
I know.
Why, here come
Pete and Rosina.
[speaking in foreign language]
Hi, Jack. Who's your friend?
Oh, this is Mango Perez.
Rosina's daughter.
Gee, she is almost
as pretty as her mother.
Yeah, she is wonderful.
Yeah, but can't she do
imitation?
Well, I don't know.
And I don't care.
'Cause I love her.
- Gosh! You're gonna marry her?
- Yeah, well, why not?
Why not? If you marry Mango
and I marry Rosina.
I'll be your father.
What kind of a
call was that?
Oh, we cannot talk here.
We cannot talk.
My monsieur..
He make big trouble.
Yeah. I just had
a fight with him.
You know, Pete.
I'm getting tired
of all this runnin' around.
You know what
I'd like to do?
I'd like to marry Mango
and settle down here.
Why, I could start
a tennis club.
They don't have clubs.
They have rackets.
Say, why don't we
rub the mole out?
And this way, we can keep
the strongbox for ourselves.
Oh, yes. Even Marry-Belle?
Well, gee,
I don't know about her.
Well, she is my sister.
'We could keep her around
to do the housekeepin'.
Sure?
And she will get over
losing Renzo.
- Sure.
- Is it a deal?
Besides, they've been cheatin'
on their income tax, anyway.
[speaking in foreign language]
Mango, she want go swimming.
- Alright.
- Let's go.
Sparks, where's Pete
and the boys?
They know we should be
diving this afternoon.
I think they're
somewhere in the jungle.
[speaking in foreign language]
What's this?
Well, what is this?
This man's wife is playin'
around with Mr. Pete.
He is very angry.
That's tough.
[speaking in foreign language]
This man wants to sell you his
wife for $50 and a case of rum.
Tell him he's nuts.
[speaking in foreign language]
Carmelita, will you talk to him?
We're busy.
Oh, sure. I would tell him to
cut down to 20 and gin.
Gin nothing.
Who wants to buy
his improbable wife?
Come on, Gen. Tostada.
Let's get going.
[speaking in foreign language]
Alright, baby.
Listen, you hold on to these.
I can't use them without
Pete or Jack to help me.
I'll keep 'em warm for you.
[dramatic music]
[hysterical laughter]
[indistinct chatter]
[music continues]
(Sparks)
Renzo Capetto had
at last found the strongbox.
And the unknown partner
had found Renzo Capetto.
[music continues]
[indistinct chatter]
[intense music]
[laughing]
Mango?
Please find my daughter.
Please.
Mango?
Why'd you have to do it, Renzo?
- Why'd I have to do what?
- Don't play games.
Why'd you kill her?
- I swear, I had nothing to do--
- I said don't play games.
We all saw the...the same five
incisions and the ground marks
in that stupid coral plunger.
Ask Marry-Belle.
I gave her the rakes
before I went under.
That won't play. You had
two more in your trunk.
Just in case,
you said, remember?
Yeah, I remember,
but they're still there.
I can't convince him.
Honey, maybe you can.
Sorry, honey. But I'm afraid
I'm gonna have to
go along with Jack.
You think I did it?
Well, what else
can I think?
You made that monster
out of thin air.
Now don't try to
tell me it's real.
I'm not that stupid.
Well, I am. I always
believed in it.
But it's gotta be real.
Either that or the Cubans
are tryin' to kill us all.
- I can't buy that.
- I don't care what you buy.
From now on
we're gonna dive with spears
like the rest of them.
We've got to get rid of those
Cubans as quickly as possible.
Now, we'll start
tomorrow morning with Tostada.
Jack?
Pete.
[dramatic music]
(Sparks)
Possible death notwithstanding,
the courageous general
and two of his men dove once
more into the deadly sea.
But as usual,
they were not alone.
Renzo waited
for them to separate.
[music continues]
One pulled away
and then there were two.
Tostada went out alone
into the forbidding void.
With the killers closing in.
The giant observer
stood watching
over a pathetic bit of cloth.
All that remained of Mango.
At last, Tostada had found his
gold in his own watery grave.
[intense music]
[indistinct]
The general died
as old general should.
His greedy murderers
let his body drift away
while they
congratulate each other.
Happy Jack found
a scrap of a dress
and knew what had happened
to his beloved.
Suddenly.
[music intensifies]
- Don't touch me.
- Oh, honey.
Go ahead, try to
talk yourself out of it.
Tryin' to talk yourself
cool this time.
- Baby.
- Tell me the Cubans did it.
Only they were onboard.
Now, who was
down there with Jack?
No, baby.
You gotta believe--
I don't want to
look at you again.
Oh, Renz.
O-oh!
Marry-Belle,
I saw what he did to you.
They told your brother and now
you've gotta leave, Marry-Belle
and there's no one
to help you, but me.
Oh, Marry-Belle, I love you
so much, I could split.
Just get on..
What do you do to my man?
Oh, shut up!
I'll save you.
(Sparks)
It was dusk.
I could tell, because
the sun was going down.
You were right, senor.
All my army is finished.
I knew when the general died.
I don't care about the box.
Let the monster keep it.
I don't want him
to kill anymore of my men.
Neither do I, colonel.
Think we must go to
Ciudad Trujillo in the morning?
You can go anywhere you like.
I am going home.
To America?
America?
No. I can't go back
there anymore.
Sicily.
Oh.
I've got an uncle there who's
been after me for years
to help him stamp grapes.
It's beginning
to appeal to me.
Mary-Belle hates me.
I know.
But I love you.
It's kind of nice
having somebody love you.
Why don't you
try to love me?
You might like it.
I guess I can try.
(Sparks)
She pressed her hot,
Latin lips against mine.
And I forgot everything
but Carmelita.
But our silent partner was
not going to let me forget.
This was it.
There was but one thing
a responsible, trusted
representative
of the United States Government
could do at a time like this.
Get out of there.
Mary-Belle.
Yes.
I..
I just like one more
chance to explain.
'Please?'
It's alright, boopsie.
(Mary-Belle)
'Doesn't really matter.'
No matter where you go
or what you do or..
...whom you kill..
...I'll love you
till the day I die.
[growling]
[Mary-Belle screaming]
[speaking in foreign language]
[dramatic music]
[gunshots]
[grunting]
[music continues]
Renzo loved Mary-Belle,
but he was the skipper
and decided to go down
ahead of the ship.
[dramatic music]
Help!
[growling]
[instrumental music]
Carmelita, I've never known
a girl like you.
You ever spend your whole life
in a months time?
Carmelita, I love you
and I wanna marry you
and take you away
from all this.
Hmm, that I would like it,
I think.
Of course we'd have to live
on the salary of an American spy
which is $41.50 a week.
I don't care.
You're so strong,
so intelligent.
You see, how you solve
the whole case.
You're the smartest
torpedo in the whole world.
I'm not really as smart
as I look, Carmelita.
You see, I-I have
to admit that..
...all that time I thought
Renzo and the Cubans
were trying to steal that
strongbox.
But I was wrong.
The real killer was the monster.
So what?
You are beautiful.
So I got the girl.
And guess who got the gold?
[dramatic music]