If something doesn't
happen pretty soon, I'll die.
Alright.
I'll fix that.
One moment, everybody.
Bonnie's going to dance.
Now make it hot.
Done.
I wish I were in his shoes.
A little number
sis picked up in Biarritz.
Making rather an open play
for Bob, isn't she?
I'm betting on her to win.
You Jordans don't exactly hate
yourselves, do you?
Certainly not.
Why, we're just crazy about us.
Yes.
That's right.
Cha-cha-cha.
Bob, behave yourself there,
buddy.
Whoo!
Ha ha!
There we are.
Oh, let's have a little...
Mmm.
Whew.
Thank you.
$900.
Not so good.
- Marvin.
- Yes?
Young people seem
to be enjoying themselves.
Well,
you're only young once.
I don't want my children
to have the hard time I had.
Spare the rod
and spoil the child.
Well, it's a good alibi.
- Alibi?
- Yeah.
For running up
Consolidated Air 200 points.
Well, we must take advantage
of the present market, D.L.
Haven't seen
anything like it in,
well, not in my experience.
I've been playing the market
all my life.
I withstood
the panic of 1906
the slump after the war,
and here I am once again
sitting on top of the world.
Well, I'm printing
a story tomorrow
that may bring you down
a peg or two.
Oh, Blair.
Blair, you and your Herald.
You're the worst calamity teller
in town.
Just the same,
the market's crazy.
Stocks aren't worth
that much.
You've been saying that
for the past six months.
- Yeah.
- Stocks are still going up.
Oh, everybody's dying.
Come on.
Let's get the party going.
- Do something, will you?
- Alright.
Listen, everybody.
How about
a little moonlight bathing?
Cool the fevered brow, huh?
I've always wanted to
go swimming at night.
Ooh, I hope it isn't cold.
Well, I hope it is
after 97 all day in the shade.
But, Bob, we won't have enough
suits to go around.
Wait.
Allen, lights out.
Alright. Stand by, everybody,
and off with your clothes.
Come on.
Yeah. Why not?
Hey, Bonnie!
Where's Bonnie?
Dive for her, Bob.
This isn't funny.
What is it, Rod?
What is it?
It's Bonnie.
She hasn't come up yet.
Somebody ought to do something.
Bob? Bob, why don't you do
something for her?
Dive, boy! Dive!
Oh!
Gee, you certainly had us
worried.
Oh, you little minx!
Sometimes I'm sorry
you're too old to spank.
Oh, I know.
If I ever say anything,
I'm old-fashioned.
Whew!
Staged that pretty well,
didn't she?
Gee, what a girl. If I were
Bob Townsend and she loved me...
I don't see
her fascination.
No? Well, uh...
You know I'm very much in love
with you, don't you?
Are you?
I'm crazy about you,
and you know it.
I didn't know.
Well, you know it now.
What about it?
That's it. What?
Going to make me
stand on ceremony?
You think
I'm so old-fashioned?
I hope not.
You're right.
I'm not.
I believe in...
in trying love out.
On approval?
Yes.
On approval.
Good morning, Dad.
Hmm.
I was just wondering if you
were going to sleep all day.
- Where's your brother?
- I don't know.
You know, the only thing
I demand of you children is
that you...
Speak of the devil.
Ah, seltzer, Greg.
Everybody's so sociable
in this house at breakfast.
I never could see the idea
of dragging us out of bed
in the middle of the night —
Shh!
Rodney, Halsey tells me
you're drinking too much.
I'll push that old fool's face
in for him
if he starts blabbing.
- Better cut it down.
- Sure.
Must you smoke
before breakfast?
Well, I must
if I want to keep thin, darling.
What's the matter, Daddy?
Isn't the market behaving?
The market's rather unsteady.
Oh, by the way,
have you seen Dr. Reed lately?
Maybe you're teething.
Yes, I saw him last Friday.
I haven't had time since.
International Copper
dropped ten points
while he was making
a metabolism test.
And your blood pressure
skyrocketed.
Oh.
A gentleman
to see Mr. Rodney.
Me?
Oh, it's Wally.
Excuse me.
- Hello, Wally.
- Hello, Rod.
Say, I've got
to have some good stuff.
There's a buffet luncheon
at Connie King's today
and I've been asked to pour.
Oh, I see.
Gonna tote your own?
I don't trust
their bootlegger.
Well, what do you want,
rye or Scotch?
Same as the last.
Want to settle for it now?
The head man's
sort of shot this morning.
You'd better let it ride.
Well, that's okay with me.
- Two suitcases, imported.
- Fine.
Okay, Rod.
It will be there.
- So long.
- So long, Wally.
Sell 10,000 and a quarter!
Sell 5,000 Jordan Chemical
at 220!
Ten thousand call of
a quarter and an eighth!
Five thousand Jordan Chemical
at 200.
Look.
Monty Jordan's on the floor.
That looks bad,
doesn't it?
Hey, Mont, you fool.
Get back in your office.
- How late is this tape?
- About an hour and a half.
Look, get off the floor,
for the love of...
You're tipping off
your hand.
Offer!
20,000 Jordan Chemical!
What's bid,
Jordan Chemical?
Yes, what is the bid?
I haven't a bid at any price.
That's a quarter.
No bid?
Monty!
Come on, you fellas,
give me a hand here.
Mr. Selby is calling.
Shall I show him in?
Would you please, Albert?
It's probably something
about Dad's will.
Yes, no doubt.
Bonnie.
I'm very sorry for you,
my dear.
I was fond of your father.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
- Hello, Rodney.
- How do you do, sir?
Well?
I regret intruding so soon
on your sorrow.
But I've been worrying
about you two.
Wondering if you've made
any plans for the future.
If you knew
how things stand.
No, not exactly.
Well, I know Dad was hit
pretty hard in the crash.
I thought while things
are being adjusted
I'd take a little flying trip
to Florida.
Bonnie might go abroad.
You know, change of scene.
It's a pretty good idea,
isn't it?
I'm afraid you don't
quite realize the situation.
Your father
was wiped out completely.
You mean there's
nothing left for us?
You're quite penniless.
But there must be some money
somewhere, there must be.
Hadn't Daddy
any life insurance?
His heart.
You know he wasn't a good risk.
But what's going
to become of us?
- How are we going to live?
- I don't know.
Unless you do as a
great many others have done
in these circumstances —
Go to work.
Work? Ha!
Rod...
You see, Mr. Selby,
it's all happened
so suddenly that,
well, it's quite difficult
to realize.
I know.
But you're young, my dear,
and very pretty.
Surely there's — there's
some nice, young man who...
Who might want to marry me?
I don't know.
Rodney, there's Andrew Cowan
of First National.
He was a friend
of your father's.
He might give you a start.
Yeah, as a teller
in one of his banks.
I should stand behind a cage
and dole out dollar bills.
Well, you'll have
to start somewhere, my boy.
Your father
started at the bottom.
Look at the fortune
he made.
Yes, look at it.
Where is it?
He might have kept something
to leave his children.
We're not prepared to work.
We didn't even finish school.
Rod, he wanted us to finish
school, but we wouldn't.
Don't start blaming him.
It isn't fair.
Alright.
It's our own fault, then.
But does that
make it any easier?
Oh, Roddy.
We mustn't bother Mr. Selby
with our troubles.
I wish there was something
I could do to help.
But I-I took a pretty stiff
licking myself on the market
and have to pay for my folly
with the rest of the fools.
Good bye.
Goodbye and thank you.
Two men who say they're from
the auctioneer, Miss Jordan.
They've come to price
the furniture.
Yes, I was expecting them.
And, Albert...
I'm sorry, but we shan't
need you any longer.
Would you tell the cook
and Pearl and the others?
Very good, miss.
Ah! Here comes your erstwhile
devoted Mr. Townsend.
Bob.
You won't need this.
I'm leaving you
to your golden opportunity, sis.
Remember, wealthy bachelors
don't grow on every rosebush.
- Hello, Rod.
- Hello, Bob.
Nice of you to come.
What can I say, Bonnie?
It's enough that you came.
I haven't had you off my mind
since it happened.
The appraisers, miss.
Would you ask them to work
in some other part of the house,
please, Albert?
Very good, miss.
Appraisers?
Getting ready
for the auction.
Auction?
We're cleaned out.
Sounds like a bad dream,
doesn't it?
Why, the...
the whole works?
House, yacht, furniture,
everything.
Nothing left
but my reputation.
Sit down, won't you?
Aw, gee.
Why didn't you let me know,
Bonnie?
- Why?
- Well, I...
Sort of a jam, isn't it?
Sort of.
Well, you know
you can count on me.
I'll do the right thing,
Bonnie.
The right thing?
I'll marry you, of course.
That is, if you...
That's funny.
- Funny?
- Yes.
What's funny?
Your thinking
you ought to marry me.
It's the least I can do,
isn't it?
Kiss me, Bob.
Don't be silly, darling.
You don't have to be a martyr
to the cause.
Everything's 50-50.
You know that.
You mean that?
Fifty-fifty.
Absolutely no obligation
on anybody's part.
So, cheer up.
No wedding bells for us.
You're not being heroic?
I'm quite myself,
I assure you.
I like my freedom
just as much as you do, Bob,
and I intend to keep it.
Well!
Spoken like a gentlewoman.
Oh, good scald, Bonnie.
Gee, I might have known it.
Relieved?
Well, I — I hadn't
exactly figured
on walking down the aisle,
not this winter.
Oh, but give me credit.
I was willing.
Noble Bacchus.
Spoken like a gentleman.
- Smoke?
- Sure.
- No?
- No.
Bob, would —
would you mind going now?
- I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
And if there's anything
I can do, Bonnie,
I hope you'll let me know.
Nice of you to call.
You know, I'd like to have
these drapes.
Can you imagine
Bonnie Jordan poor?
It must be
an awful letdown.
Serves her right.
Imagined every man was crazy
about her, even Bob.
Well, this will take her
down a peg or two.
I wonder if they're selling
all the furniture.
I hope so.
I'm gonna make a bid for that
little spinet desk of hers.
I've had my eye on it
for ages.
You'll find seats
right over here.
The next we have to offer
is this genuine
Chippendale settee.
Speak right up now.
What are my bids?
One hundred dollars? Thank you.
Start at $100.
Now $100.
100. Who will make it 125?
125. 125. Do I hear 150?
Do I hear 150?
Good morning.
Good?
That's rich.
With the house
being sold over our heads?
I know.
The auction's in full swing.
Going, going, gone.
It's a tough break,
being left stranded like this.
Why, we're paupers.
Well, there's no use
crying about it.
Buck up.
Put on your spurs and gauntlets
and give the world a battle.
Swat 'em in the eye.
Yeah? Just how?
Go to work.
I'm not afraid.
You?
Why, what could you do?
Open up a tea shoppie?
"Bonnie Jordan's
orange pekoe blend."
Go to it.
No. No tea shoppies
for Bonnie Jordan.
Well, what, then?
Model for a living?
Parade in front of all
our sympathetic friends?
Two to the right.
Two to the left.
Pose and smile sweetly.
Oh, I'm not gonna do
any of those
stupid, silly,
conventional things.
You'd be surprised
what a young girl can earn
when she sets her mind
to it.
I'm no dud.
You've got the looks, kid.
Trade on them.
Open up a beauty parlor.
"Bonnie Jordan's face cream.
Works while you sleep."
You get the works,
and they get the sleep.
That's your idea of me, huh?
Beautiful but dumb.
Alright.
I'll show you.
I'm going out to get myself
a man-sized job.
You can do
exactly as you please.
Alright.
I'll get drunk.
Oh, Rod,
what good will that do?
A lot of good.
At least for the time being.
- And then?
- The hangover.
Darling, if you'd only
pull yourself together.
I'll stick to you through thick
and thin. See if I don't.
Let's not get emotional
about it.
- Oh, but, darling —
- Don't mollycoddle me.
I'll pull out of it
someday.
Maybe.
Boy?
Hello! When did she come
on the paper?
Last week.
Swell kid, too.
Yeah? Well, how did she get
into this racket?
Friend of the managing editor.
He's giving her a try.
Yeah? What for?
To rest his eyes?
What's this?
The Jackson Park
Poultry Show.
Mr. Boole has a photograph
of the prize rooster.
Copyboy?
Is this all of it?
Yes, sir.
But I could write some more.
There's your story
in the first three paragraphs.
You can have the rest of it.
Great story
about the poultry show, boys.
Give it a box
on the front page.
Oh.
Thank you.
Cut it down to 50 words.
Home and garden section.
All through?
Yes. I've done my one good deed
for the day.
Yeah?
Could have saved myself
a lot of trouble.
You'll learn, kid.
Clearness, condensation.
Where, what, when, and why?
That's the idea.
Say, don't let those guys
over on the copydesk bother you.
They're just a lot of butchers
at heart.
Why, you know what they'd do
if they got a chance?
What?
They'd cut the Lord's Prayer
down to a one-line squib.
You know,
"Now I lay me down to sleep."
I like you.
Oh, yeah?
Come on.
Give a little girl a hand.
Sure.
Just for that, lady,
I'll see you to your limousine.
- Tally?
- Ho.
- Live far?
- Unh-unh.
- Boarding?
- No.
Gee, I'd hate to have to get
a story out of you.
Say, you must come up sometime
and try my cooking.
I will.
- I love homemade cooking.
- Yeah?
Say, do you know what your next
assignment's going to be?
No, but, gee, I'd like to get
a chance at some real news once.
Oh, you'll get along.
All cubs have to start out
the same way.
Yeah.
You know a story
I'd like to see written?
No, what?
"Society girl turns reporter."
Well, I'm afraid that's one
story that never will be wrote.
Yeah?
Said she stepping grandly
upon the omnibus.
Thanks for the buggy ride.
Hey, what do you think this is,
a sightseeing bus?
Roddy?
- Hello, kid.
- Hello.
- How's the little newshound?
- Well...
Hey, Bon, what's become
of my blue-polka-dot tie?
Blue polka dot.
Oh, you mean the one
with the lifesavers on it?
Yeah, the nautical number.
I'll get it.
Here you are.
- Oh, that's great.
- Look at it.
It's all mended with
my little thread and needle.
Fine.
How's that
for a mark of devotion?
You're all there, honey.
I appreciate you,
even if The Star doesn't.
- Oh, guess what.
- What?
I was graduated
to the poultry show today.
- Yeah? That's fine.
- Mm-hmm.
You know, I used to think
that Plymouth Rock
was a place
where the Pilgrims landed.
- We all learn.
- Yeah, we do.
Oh, Roddy, coffee with
your dinner tonight?
Don't cook anything for me
tonight, sis.
I've got to see a man
on business.
Gee,
any prospects of a job?
All the earmarks
of a paid proposition.
Oh, Roddy!
Gee, I'm glad.
Honey, you don't know
the thrill
of trying to make good
on your own.
Not just trading on your name
and running around
to parties all the time.
Suited me alright.
And I'll have you
out of this dump pretty soon,
running with the old crowd
where you belong.
You know, Roddy,
I'm not so sure
that I'd like to run around
with the old crowd again.
Why?
I used to think anything I did
was alright.
I was Bonnie Jordan
in society.
Society.
What is it
but a lot of people
who are for you when you're
on the up-and-up and...
what would one of them
do for you
when it came to a showdown?
Nothing, except grab your
pet belongings at an auction.
The gang have sort of let us
down since we lost out.
Oh, I'm not fooled
about why we were in society.
It was because father
had a lot of money.
But was that any credit to us?
We didn't make it.
You know,
it isn't who you are, Roddy.
It's what you are that counts.
You're willing
to sign that article?
"By Bonnie Jordan."
What's the new job?
Mmm, selling.
- Selling what?
- Well, stock.
Uh, in a big industrial concern.
Well, I've got to be there, sis.
It's getting late.
- Good bye.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Step on it, kid.
We're late already.
Now, when you get upstairs,
remember, no talking.
The boss hates a guy
that shoots his mouth off.
You answer questions.
"Yes, sir. No, sir."
Get me?
Yes.
And don't forget the "sir."
- No, sir.
- Right.
- Hello, Wally.
- Hello, Del.
Who's your friend?
Oh, this is Mr. Jordan.
He's a great little guy.
He looks like a nice kid.
Hello, Jake.
Here we are.
This is the kid
I was telling you about.
Your name's Jordan?
Yes.
Uh, yes, sir.
Wally says you've got a wide
acquaintance in this town.
I know everybody of any...
Yes, sir, I have.
- Do you talk much?
- Not when it's inconvenient.
- Drink?
- A little.
- Blab when you're soused?
- No. Pass out.
How long
have you known him?
Ever since I've been working
the north side.
He's an old customer of mine
down on his luck.
His father lost his pile in the
crash and kicked the bucket.
Now, listen, this kid knows
all the big shots in town.
All the heavy drinkers.
And he can put enough business
in our way
to make himself
a lot of dough.
To say nothing of the 700
I owe you, Wally —
which of course
he's never mentioned.
A lot of those blue bloods
are buying from Ollansky now.
If you can get 'em to switch
to Wally
we'll write the 700
off the books.
Sure I can.
Uh, Wally says
all I have to do —
Yeah. Sit down.
Yes, sir.
Now, listen, kid.
Money talks.
But, remember,
in this business
it's the only thing
that talks.
Now, we don't make a practice
of going outside the gang
to sell a little red eye.
But I'm laying
for this guy Ollansky.
And I'll do anything to cut in
on his trade.
Well, I — I...
If we take you on
there's certain rules
of the game you've got to learn.
Keeping your mouth shut's
one of them — the first one.
No matter what happens,
don't talk.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Wes?
This is Rod Jordan speaking.
I've got bright news
for you, Wes.
You need any liquid refreshment
up at your house?
I find I can spare a little
from my own private stock
just to a few close friends.
Well, not too close.
Sure.
Absolutely okay.
I've had it analyzed.
Okay, Wes. Two cases.
F-O-B your house.
Alright, Wes.
So long.
That's the way
to hook 'em, kid.
Only take a poke at Ollansky
every now and then.
I wish I knew of some legitimate
business that was this easy.
What? This is
a legitimate business.
Only, we make our own laws.
We don't let any small-town
senator make them for us.
That's the only difference.
I never thought I'd come
to bootlegging for a living.
What's the matter
with bootlegging?
What's the difference
whether you buy or sell?
You're equally as guilty
in the eyes of the law.
Only, here you make the dough
instead of spending it.
That's where you're wise.
Yeah. Say,
how do you spell Schneider?
S-H, S-C-H, or S-N-I?
Battle that out for yourself.
I've got a call to make.
Don't forget what I told you
about Ollansky.
He's selling poison.
Okay. Goodbye.
So long.
Come in.
- Hello, Bob.
- Hello, Rod.
I was going to call you.
You're looking fine.
Yeah?
Well, I don't feel it.
Got a touch of jaundice
or something.
Spring fever.
I don't know what.
Have a drink.
No, no, thanks.
Not for me.
Gee, I wanted you to try this.
It's great stuff.
Say, what's become
of Bonnie?
I know you two
don't go out much,
but why doesn't she
let me hear from her?
What's she doing
with herself?
Well, you know us
"woiking goils."
Oh, Bonnie?
Working?
Yep.
Bonnie's got a job.
Doing what? Where?
She doesn't want anyone
to know.
Oh, Rod.
I want to see Bonnie.
I've missed her.
Everywhere I go,
the party's dead.
I don't believe I'd look her up
if I were you.
Just between ourselves,
Bonnie is sort of off the bunch.
- Well, why?
- I don't know.
She thinks
they rather let her down.
Bonnie's got a lot of pride,
you know?
Oh.
Well, if you won't tell me
where she is
I'll find out some other way.
Oh, tell her I was asking
about her, will you?
Sure.
But what's your hurry?
I have a little favor
I was just about to do for you.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Say, how's your liquor
holding out?
I find I can spare a little
of my own private stock
just to accommodate
a few close friends.
Well...
Who you been buying from?
Ollansky?
Lay off that guy.
He's selling poison.
Baxter's the only one
to buy from.
His stuff's not cut.
You ought to try it.
If you're sure
you can spare a little.
I can use a dozen quarts
of Scotch.
Fine. I'll have Wally
call you up.
Alright, fine.
You'll come again,
won't you, Bob?
I'm living alone here
at the club,
and I'll be glad
to see you anytime.
Sure, I'll be around.
- So long, Bob.
- Bye.
Just to a few close friends,
Schneider.
Well, not too close.
Sure, absolutely okay.
I've had it analyzed.
- Bert...
- Boy?
Yeah?
How many L's
in "parallel"?
Six or seven.
You should get yourself
a headache.
That's what those dumb eggs
on the copydesk are for.
What the "ell"?
Oh, stop.
What have they pinned on you
now, sister?
Oh, gang stuff.
Holy gee.
So, you're doing
the racket, too.
Woman,
I takes off me hat to ya.
- Where is it?
- There it is.
The crack still goes.
Where's the other 12 pages?
All boiled down to one.
You wouldn't kid me,
would you, mister?
I would if I could, lady.
Parker talking.
Make it snappy.
That right?
Seven shot down
in a garage, eh?
Good stuff!
Hold the line.
Hey, Tom, Smith,
Scranton, Curtis!
Just a minute.
Hudson's on the wire.
Hot gang-war story.
- Go get it, Curtis.
- Okay.
Curtis is on the way.
Tom, get over to that garage
and get some pictures.
Smith, get everything
we have in our morgue
on the Ollansky gang.
Dig up all the pictures
you can find.
Scranton, greatest
gang-war story in months.
Seven of the Ollansky gang lined
up against the wall in a garage
and mowed down
with machine guns.
Nice work, eh?
Sounds like
some of Luva's work.
You know,
Ollansky's been cutting in
on his pet territory lately.
Breeze down on the street
and see what you can pick up.
- This ought to be hot stuff.
- Alright.
I'll take a run
down to his joint.
I'll nose around
a little bit.
You know, I'm getting to be
quite a schnozzler.
Can I do something?
You'll have to cover the morgue
for me, Miss Jordan.
Some of the dead men's
wives and sweeties
may drop in
to see the mangled remains.
- The morgue?
- I mean the real morgue.
Yeah, I heard you.
Parker talking.
Make it snappy.
Clinton talking.
Statement from the chief
on the Ollansky slaughter.
Quote, "This wholesale,
cold-blooded murder
of seven of the Ollansky gang
is undoubtedly the work
of rival gangsters."
Yeah, ain't that smart?
Quote, "We have
a definite suspicion
as to the guilty party
and arrests..."
Huh?
Well, who says
we've got to be original?
What?
Well, the same to you.
And then we lined 'em up,
face against a wall.
Nobody says nothin'.
And one of the guys,
Wilkinson, calls out,
"For jeez sake,
give us a break, will ya?"
Whitey here says, "Yeah.
We'll give you a break."
And we turns on the hose,
and they go down like a row
of ducks in a shooting gallery.
Clean getaway?
Clean as a snowbird.
Except one of these nibs over
there took sick at the wheel
and I had to change places
and drive.
Sick, eh?
What did you go along for?
I didn't know what it was.
I thought we were
just going on a hijacking.
I didn't know
there was going to be... gunplay.
I was driving,
and Whitey said
"Turn into this garage,
and keep the motor running."
I sat at the wheel
and saw the whole thing.
I didn't realize what was
happening till it was all over.
Then I got sick.
I couldn't help it.
I'll be alright now.
I'll be alright.
All I need
is a couple of drinks.
That's all I need.
Just a little something
in my stomach.
It's a great joint, ain't it?
Sure, great.
Hey, do you know Luva?
What's it to ya?
Oh, nothing.
I was just wondering.
I'm Eddie Burke.
Outside man for Luva.
Oh.
You're new to this racket.
- I ain't seen you before.
- Who said I was?
Oh, boy,
wasn't that a hot session
down at that garage
this evening?
Shh.
There's no dicks
in the joint.
If there was,
I'd tip you off.
I was lookout man
across the street
and I heard the spray.
You know,
the people on the street
didn't seem to pay
any attention to it.
They thought it was a motorcycle
just starting up.
But I knew what it was.
When the car came out,
I beat it.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
What part of the job
did you handle, kid?
I was driving.
Oh.
You were going so fast
I couldn't recognize you.
But I thought
I saw Whitey Lucas.
Who else was along?
- I'll be right back.
- Okay, kid.
- What do I owe ya, Oscar?
- One dollar.
- Okay. See ya later.
- Yes, sir.
Hello, newshound.
How's it coming?
Hello, Whitey.
How's the racket?
- Fine, how's yours?
- Oh, same old grind.
Say, I got a great story
tonight, though.
Somebody shot up
that Ollansky gang.
Oh, yeah.
I heard about it.
- Yeah.
- Have a drink.
No, I got to get
back to the office.
Wait a minute.
What's your hurry?
I think
you better have one.
Well, okay, but just one.
- Same thing.
- Yeah. Make it two.
What I said
didn't mean anything.
He didn't notice.
I didn't mean
to do anything wrong.
- I didn't know.
- Talk, will ya?
What did I tell you
about that?
I didn't know who he was,
I tell you.
He said he was Eddie Burke,
your outside man.
He said he was in the street
by the garage.
You...
Scranton still there?
He's at the bar
with Whitey.
I know that guy.
He'll go straight to his paper
with the story
and send it to the cops.
If he gets to his office,
it's a blow off.
That's easy.
He don't get to his office.
We can't let him have it here,
and he's too wise to frame.
He'll walk to the subway
at the corner, and...
And you'll meet him there,
Jordan.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
- W-What for?
- Slim, give the kid your rod.
No. No!
I'm not...
I can't.
Take that gun!
Now, listen close,
because I don't repeat myself.
You got us into this jam,
and you're going to get us out.
You're going to meet this bird
at the subway entrance
and you're going
to let him have it.
I can't. I can't!
You guys scatter
along the block.
Slim, you and Emilio
take Jordan in the car
and stall near the subway.
If Jordan lets Scranton take one
step down that subway entrance,
give them both the works.
Get me?
- Alright, boss.
- Okay.
You understand this deal,
don't you?
Listen, I —
Slim will be ready
at the wheel.
When you give Scranton
the works,
jump in the car,
and you're off.
It's murder.
It's murder!
If you don't come through,
there will be a double murder.
Oh, I can't, I tell you.
I can't!
Stand on your feet.
Now get going.
Well, I got to blow.
See you later, Whitey.
Wait a minute.
Have just
another little one.
I'll finish this one.
Sure you won't have
any more, huh?
I'm late now.
I got to be stepping.
So long, Bert.
See you some more.
So long, Whitey.
- Hello, Scranton.
- Hiya, Lefty.
- Howdy, boy.
- Okay by me, kid.
Hiya, Bert.
Hi, Scranton.
Hello, kid.
Hi, Jack.
Swell night for a walk,
huh, Bert?
Yeah.
Hi, newshound.
Hiya, Wally.
How's everything?
- Okay.
- Same here.
Why, hello, kid.
He's killed! He's shot!
Somebody shot him!
Boy?
You're holding three
of Luva's men?
Who are they?
Wally Baxter.
What's that?
Righty?
Oh, Whitey.
Who's the other one?
The chief says they all claim
they can furnish alibis.
Well, Blair's offering $25,000
for the capture of the man
that fired the shot.
Now go to it.
The police
are a big help.
It's up to us, boys.
They haven't got a clue.
Of course, Jake Luva's
back of this, but prove it.
Well, I'm willing
to risk my neck
to run down the mucker
that did the shooting.
I'd join the police force
or anything.
But what's the use?
We're too well known.
They'd spot us,
the newspapermen, in a minute.
Yes, that's just the trouble.
Now, we've got to
get Luva sometime,
and now's the time
to do it.
I know!
That Jordan girl.
- Bonnie Jordan?
- Sure.
Nobody knows
she's working on the paper.
And they'd never suspect
a girl.
Go get her.
By George,
I think I've hit on it.
Now, remember, we never saw
this girl before, any of us.
- Get that?
- Right.
You tip the others off and then
go back to the police station.
Bring in anything you can,
but make it snappy.
Come on, boys, let's get
back to headquarters.
Okay.
- Hello, Bonnie.
- Hello.
Sit down.
I've been hearing very
complimentary things of you.
Thank you.
Miss Jordan,
how's your nerve?
Haven't any.
Why?
I want to find out
who killed Bert Scranton.
And I'll do it
if I have to break the paper.
You want to tackle it?
- I'm aching to.
- Good.
Now, listen, we think
Jake Luva's back of this.
Luva pulled the
Ollansky killings. Must have.
Now, Bert was on the trail.
Possibly had a hot tip,
and they knew it.
Now, if Luva's back
of the Ollansky killing
then he's back
of Scranton's murder.
- Logical, isn't it?
- Of course.
Listen, you're not
Bonnie Jordan. You never were.
You're Mary Smith,
a tough girl from Missouri.
You never saw a newspaper.
You're a cheap mow
in the underworld.
You hang around nightclubs,
especially Luva's.
You get to know him.
You drink with him.
Use any weapon you've got.
Only, get to know this man
and know him well.
Alright.
Nothing I wouldn't do
to find out who killed Bert.
It's a dangerous game,
Bonnie.
No child's play,
you know.
I'm not afraid.
Then you find out
who killed my best reporter.
And if you come in
with the story...
you can have the paper.
We'll give it to you.
I see where
The Star's offering
40 grand for the
capture of...
well, whoever killed
their best reporter.
Yeah.
Can you beat it?
As if there ain't enough
reporters in the world already.
They offer any more
for that young punk's skin,
I'll be tempted
to turn him over.
Remember now, Jordan should
stay away from this joint
fill all this hullabaloo
dies down.
- You hear me?
- Yeah. I told him.
He's laying low
like a scared rabbit.
He's afraid to show his face
in the light.
Oh, uh, you sure
none of the boys broke
when they grilled them
at the station?
Certainly not.
We're all out, ain't we?
All but Wally.
That will take a little fixing.
But I'll have him out tonight.
- Slide over, will you?
- No. I'll scram.
I'll see you later.
- Hello, Della.
- Hello, Whitey.
- Oh, is that an encore?
- No, sit down.
That's my new cabaret number.
Your new number, huh?
Oh, so, that's what's become
of Bonnie.
Oh, Sylvia!
Phew!
That will be all, Alice.
You can go home now.
Slim.
- Buy Della a drink, will ya?
- Why, sure.
Let go of my arm!
- Gee, you're a cute kid.
- Yeah?
How'd the number go over
tonight?
- Couldn't be better.
- Good.
- You got me going, sister.
- Can I depend on it?
In a big way.
You know,
this is my joint.
I feel terribly proud.
You should.
You got a big hand.
I mean
to be dancing with you.
Why, you're the owner
of this nightclub.
Ah. I own more
than this little joint, I hope.
You do?
You're going to have
a little supper with me tonight.
Upstairs in my room.
We've got to get
better acquainted.
I'd love it.
I'll go and dress now.
- Okay.
- Oh'
Who is it?
It's Bob.
I want to see you.
What's the idea
behind all this, Bonnie?
I don't see how that could
possibly concern you.
Did you have to come to this?
Yes, I did.
Why didn't you let me know?
And what would you have done
for me if I had?
- Well, I...
- That's just what I thought.
Would you mind handing me
that cloak over there, please?
What's the matter?
You've kissed me before,
haven't you?
Yes, but that wasn't
a permanent arrangement, was it?
Aren't you being clever?
And aren't you being vague,
as usual?
Alright,
if that's what you want
I'll set you up in a real
establishment anytime you like.
You don't have to make
your living off Jake Luva
dancing in his nightclub.
I can do much better for you
than that.
Now, is that less vague?
That's very clear.
Now we understand
each other.
I'm a cheap little dancer
in a nightclub
and you thought you could
have me on your own terms.
Well, you're mistaken.
I can still pick my own men,
Mr. Townsend.
And right now,
it's Jake Luva.
Bonnie...
You had your day,
and what did I get out of it?
I offered to marry you.
And what a grand and
condescending gesture that was.
You were willing
to do the right thing.
What a perfect gentleman.
And what a fool I was.
I loved you, Bob.
And I thought you loved me.
No, don't touch me.
That's all over.
Nice of you to offer
to be so generous,
but I must be going.
I have a heavy date tonight.
I'm hitting the pace now,
and I like it.
There's your "Moonlight Sonata,"
only not as it was written.
I like it better.
Pretty, isn't it?
Like it?
I love it.
You know, it's hard to believe
that a girl like you
ever came from Missouri.
Go on!
Missouri's a famous state.
For what?
Lindbergh, Ozark Mountains,
muddy rivers,
pretzels, mules —
And pretty girls.
How'd you happen to hit Chicago
and this racket?
Well, you see,
my father died and...
and a certain young man
I was in love with
wasn't exactly
the marrying kind.
I had to paddle for myself,
so...
I paddled to Chicago.
You know, I liked you the minute
you walked in my office.
I liked you when you said
your name was Mary Smith.
Of course, I knew
that wasn't your real name.
I took you
for a clever little girl
that could pull one over
when she wanted to.
Say, I've heard of Luva's
nightclub even in St. Joe.
Believe me,
you're well known.
I've read all about you.
In the papers.
Yes, I get my share
of publicity
more than I care about.
Well,
why don't you sue them?
They haven't got a thing
on me.
No?
They seem to think they have,
the way they're playing up
this Scranton case.
Yeah?
Well, they're barking up
the wrong tree this time.
They got to climb to find
the bird that pulled that job.
So don't you worry about me,
Mary.
Like me?
What do you think?
Gonna be nice to me?
I'll answer.
Hello?
Is Mr. Luva there?
I want to talk to him.
Oh.
What's the matter?
Somebody's terribly excited.
It startled me.
Yes?
I told you
to stay where you are
until you heard
from Baxter.
Alright, then do it.
What is it?
I just
felt a little faint.
Would you mind telling me
if that's some of your own?
You don't think
I'd drink bootleg, do you?
Oh, I need some lipstick.
My makeup's all worn off.
You left your purse
in there.
Thanks.
Roddy.
Who is it?
Roddy, let me in.
Well, sis,
what are you doing here?
Well...
I had to see you.
I-I hadn't seen you for days.
I told you I was working.
Yes, working.
Making a lot of money.
Sure.
I've been doing fine.
Roddy.
Look at me.
You've never lied to me before
in all your life.
What do you mean?
I mean that I was
in Luva's apartment tonight
when you telephoned.
You?
Roddy, what was it?
What did you want
to talk to him about?
I-I just wanted a little
something to drink, that's all.
Oh, Roddy,
why do you lie to me?
Well, what were you doing
in Luva's apartment?
I've been dancing
in his nightclub,
working for the paper.
Trying to find out who —
who killed Bert Scranton.
Roddy.
Roddy, why did you do it?
- Why did you do it?
- I had to.
They trained their guns on me,
Bonnie.
I talked.
Scranton had the goods on us.
Oh, I wish I'd died first.
I can't sleep.
I'm going crazy.
All night long,
I keep seeing that man's face
the way he smiled
and spoke to me before I...
Oh, Bonnie.
don't look at me that way.
Don't, Bonnie!
Where are you going?
What does it matter now?
You're not going
to give me up, Bon.
Bon, you wouldn't.
Listen, Bon,
don't give me up.
I didn't mean to do it.
You mustn't let them take me.
I can't stand it.
I can't go to jail.
They'll hang me.
I don't want to die.
Don't be afraid, Roddy.
You'll be alright.
We'll think of something.
Sure. Sure.
Take it easy now,
and don't make a sound.
Thought you'd get away with it,
didn't you, Miss Jordan?
Yes.
How do, Miss Jordan?
Too bad I happened to be driving
into that alley
when you slid off
of that fire escape.
Yeah, just too bad.
Fond of adventure,
aren't you, Miss Jordan?
A clever little girl
who could put one over
when she tried.
Almost.
You've read about me
in the papers.
Write for 'em, too,
don't you?
- Yes, I do.
- Not anymore you don't.
We're gonna take you
for a pleasant little ride.
And that brother of yours
who also likes to yap so well.
He's gonna get his too.
You've made
a murderer out of him.
Aren't you satisfied?
Get going, Wally.
Wait for me.
I won't be a minute.
You're gonna walk out
of this room and get in my car.
If you turn your head
or try to speak to anybody,
well, you know
what you're walking with.
- Brave, aren't you?
- Yeah.
It's the kid.
Bonnie? Bonnie?
Bonnie?
- Stick 'em up!
- What's the idea?
Couple of
newspaper framers, eh?
We haven't been
doing anything.
And you won't.
Thought you'd take it
on the run, eh?
Trying to slip out of town,
I guess.
Now, look here, Jake —
There's nothing you can say
that I want to hear.
Now, listen, Jordan,
head for that door.
Keep your arms down
and walk straight ahead
with that sister of yours.
Get him, Rod!
Get him!
Roddy.
Roddy, darling, listen.
Roddy, speak to me.
Roddy, look at me.
Look at me, Roddy.
It's alright now,
Bonnie.
Roddy.
No, no.
Roddy, no.
Roddy!
Oh, Roddy,
don't leave me.
Please don't leave me.
Come on, you'll have to
clear out of here.
Come on, get back! Back up!
Come on! Back up.
- Get the coroner.
- Alright, I will.
Luva.
By golly, they got him.
Who are you?
Do you know this boy?
Yes.
Don't touch that gun.
Don't touch anything.
Yes, sir.
Hey, what are you doing?
You know.
Area 400.
Parker talking.
Make it snappy.
This is
Bonnie Jordan speaking.
I-I found out who...
killed Bert Scranton.
It was Rodney Jordan,
my brother.
What's that?
Your brother?
Wait a minute.
Come on, boys.
We got the Scranton-Luva
murder story.
Just a minute, Jordan.
Take this down, boys.
Alright. Give me some more.
Make it snappy now.
I got a job
in Luva's nightclub as a dancer.
While I was
in his apartment tonight,
the phone rang,
and I answered it.
And...
And it was my brother.
Hey!
Special gangland killing!
High-society boy
gangland killing, extry!
Hey! Bert Scranton's murderer
found, extry!
Hey! Extry, extry!
Hey!
Special gangland killing, extry!
High-society boy
in gangland...
Bonnie, I don't see
why you should leave us.
There's no disgrace
attached to you, you know.
It isn't that.
But I just feel like I want
to get away from everything.
I kind of hate to see
you leave that desk of yours.
You did a mighty fine thing
in spilling that story
to the paper.
We know
that you didn't have to do it.
You know,
I meant every word I said
in this little yarn
I wrote about you.
It's the first time
I've banged out a story since
well, since I used to
leg it around for news myself.
You've all been
awfully kind to me.
We've been great friends,
and I...
Goodbye, Mr. Parker.
Goodbye.
And good luck.
Goodbye, Mr. Blair.
Goodbye, Bonnie.
Let's hear from you.
You know, we really feel
as if you belong to us.
Thank you.
- Goodbye, Bonnie.
- Goodbye.
Good bye.
Bonnie.
I've been here a dozen times
asking for you.
Can't I talk to you
a minute?
Let me walk home with you.
I'm not going home.
I'm, uh — I'm going away.
Then I'm going with you.
I am, Bonnie, no matter
what you have to say about it.
Won't you let me help you
forget everything?
That's all I've been doing.
Trying to forget
the way I've acted toward you.
I love you, Bonnie.
I've always loved you.
I know that now.
I want you to marry me.
Kiss me, Bob.
Hey, cut that down
to 50 words, will ya?
And make it snappy!