Oh, jeez!
- Oh, no, no, no! No!
- Shit!
- Back up, goddammit!
- I'm on it, I'm on it!
What happened, Shaun-boy?
Sorry, Bull, it was a pothole.
I didn't see it.
Clean it up, for Chrissake!
Come on, move it!
Move!
And lock it this time.
Now you drive.
We have to move, Bull!
Let's go!
Shit. How much further?
Here. Sawbridge.
We're nearly there.
- Look out!
- Shit!
Shit!
No, no, no, no, no.
Agh! It's jammed! It's jammed!
- What do we do?
- Just shut up!
Let me think, let me think!
- Christ!
- Just get out!
Oh, shit!
Fuck!
Get 'em out of there.
Talk fast, Dwightie.
What could I do?
It was standing in
the middle of the bloody road!
So?
You're supposed to go
through 'em, not around them!
I didn't have time to think,
Bull. I just...
I'm sorry.
We can get it
out of there, I swear we can.
No one's gonna find it
at least. It's safe for now.
Oh, yeah, it's safe. Hmm?
It's safe...
for all fucking eternity!
I will get it out of there, Bull.
I swear on my mother's life, I will.
Okay.
It's alright, Dwightie. Alright?
I'll do it myself, yeah?
What's the plan?
I'm working on it.
Cranes.
Don't they have cranes
for this type of thing?
No cranes.
We'd draw too much attention.
Now, what we need is divers.
- Divers?
- Yeah.
You know, with the big helmets
and the rubber togs?
- Find me some fuckin' divers.
- Got it, Bull.
- How'd you go?
- No good.
That valve's gonna need
a bigger spring.
Dammit. I was hoping
third time would be a charm.
We've never been that lucky.
No. But if anyone can do it,
Jimmy, it's you.
Where's Ernie?
Is he still not awake?
He's gonna sleep the whole day away.
Was he on the sauce again?
All night.
What was it this time?
He wouldn't say.
Oh! Ohh...
Oh...
What time is it?
Almost midday.
Shit!
By the way,
that new hose you ordered
finally arrived.
I paid with a check. Is that alright?
Will be. Till it bounces.
Ooh, and Jimmy will have the valve
on helmet two repaired today.
Which means we're all set
and ready to go.
Tell him there's no rush.
We didn't get the bridge contract.
Why not? I thought it was settled.
They changed their minds.
They went with the Alberts.
But we can do it better,
and at a better price...
Not anymore.
Not without our own boat.
But how will we afford one
if we keep losing
all of these big contracts?
Yeah, it means I won't be able
to pay ya for last month.
You or Jimmy.
I'm sorry, kiddo.
Everything's just gone
to hell in a hand basket.
Hey...
We'll survive.
We always do.
Somehow.
And, look, if the Alberts are
busy for the next three months,
that leave everything for us, right?
Sure.
If there's anything else.
Always the optimist.
Right. Come on. Get dressed.
Go and help Jimmy with that valve.
I-I've got to weld
that damn winch on the truck.
- It's come loose again.
- Leave that to me.
I'm not the one trying to sober up.
Eh, uh... Just be careful.
Oh!
Hello. How can I help?
Who is boss here?
Oh, well, um... that's Ernie.
But, um...
he's a little busy right now.
Is there anything I can help with?
No. We need to speak to him.
Right.
Alright, well, give me a minute.
Ernie. There's two gentlemen outside.
They want to speak
to the man in charge.
You the boss?
Yes. Ernie Morgan. Owner/operator.
- Dylan Maddock.
- Mr Maddock.
I hear that you're the bloke
to see about a special job.
Of course!
It's just this way.
Take a seat.
Excuse the mess.
You caught us at a good time.
So you were in the service, I see.
Royal Navy during the Great War.
Four years. You?
'41 to '42.
Infantry. We were in North Africa.
Oh! Heard that was a helluva fight.
That it was.
So you, uh,
you been a diver ever since?
Yes. Worked in pearl
and abalone farms.
In the north, mostly.
Ah, there wouldn't be much call
for that round here, surely.
Oh, we do whatever's needed.
Underwater salvage, repairs,
maintenance, piping.
Your crew... Are they good?
They're the best.
I run a three-man team,
unless the job requires more.
So what's this, uh, special job?
It's like this.
Friend of mine,
stupid fucking idiot he is,
he drove into a river
about 40 miles north of here.
Oh.
Now, inside that car were
some things that belong to me.
The job's simple. Find the car
and bring them back.
What's in the car?
Confidential.
Truth is, Ernie, in my line of work,
I don't like a lot of questions.
What's your line of work?
So, what's this gonna cost me?
Ten quid a day, plus expenses.
But not knowing what we're
salvaging... could be more.
We pay two fifty, up front.
Plus another two fifty
when the job's done.
But I want no questions, Ernie.
Not from you or your men.
And this job stays off the books.
That's the deal. Plain and simple.
Take it or leave it.
What was that all about?
That is our next meal ticket, kiddos.
Well, I don't like it.
We should at least know
who it is we're working for.
This is our first paid job
in over four months.
You should be happy as Larry.
They said no questions,
and that's fine by me.
Yes, but that's what bothers me.
What are they hiding?
Who are we even working for?
Listen, kiddo.
If we don't take this job,
we won't last the year.
I'll have to sell up
to pay off my debts.
I don't want to send Jimmy home
with nothing but
the clothes on his back.
And what about you?
You think Rod Albert's
gonna hire you?
He doesn't believe women should
even be in the workforce.
Hmm?
Ah.
- What's this?
- That...
is what they're paying us.
- Two fifty.
- Really?
Plus an extra two fifty
when the job's done.
But this means we can buy a boat.
We can buy a boat!
- Yes!
- Oh! Okay, Clara...
- Okay, okay, okay...
- I'm sorry. I can't believe it.
Well, believe it.
That's enough for a boat,
a motorized air pump,
a dive platform,
the whole kit and kaboodle.
We can finally do that deep-sea dive
you've been pestering me about.
- Are you serious?
- It's a promise.
But only if you stop
giving me the third degree
about this job.
Deal.
Now I'm happy as Larry.
Good... Good!
Hello again.
Follow me.
Okay.
You got here fast. I'm impressed.
Come and meet my crew.
- You've meet Clara.
- Hello again.
And this is Jimmy.
Hey, you said you had
a three-man team.
Alright? Not a skirt and a darkie.
I'm paying you good money, Ernie.
- For that, I expect the best.
- They are the best.
What's he best at, huh?
Chuckin' spears?
Listen, Jimmy's one of
the best divers in the country.
You're lucky to have him.
Is that so?
So, what makes you the best?
- Jimmy's been on...
- Let the native speak.
Been diving since I was a kid.
Been under water half my life.
And what about you, sweetheart?
It's a bit early for nicknames,
isn't it?
Now, now.
I'm just trying to be pleasant.
Well, I've been
a licensed diver for a year.
Been with the Sea Dogs
for six months.
During the war, I was in the
Australian Women's Land Army.
Doing what, huh? Feeding the chooks?
I worked the shipyards, factories.
I was cleaning engines.
Before that,
I was a research assistant
at the University of Sydney.
Wow. You're a real smart cookie.
Mmm. Smarter than some.
Well, well, boys...
Despite appearances,
looks like we have Captain Nemo
and his finest on the job.
Let's see what they can do.
Okay. Let's get you two in the water.
Well, don't you want me up top?
I don't want to go fumbling
around in that muck.
I figured you would.
Well, you figured right.
Great. Let's go.
When should we tell them
what's in the boxes?
They'll figure it out soon enough.
Besides...
once it's done, they're dead anyway.
Mm.
Here we go, gentlemen.
Hearing me, kiddos?
Roger. Loud and clear.
Hearing you, boss.
Visibility is poor.
Can't see more than
a foot or two ahead.
Wait till it gets deep.
Working in a river
is like working in a cave.
There's lots of fallen trees.
Don't snag your line, Jimmy.
Yep. Copy that.
Coming up to a hundred feet.
You must be getting close.
What's your depth?
My guess is 15, 18 feet at most?
Roger that.
Whoa. Did you feel that?
What was it?
Couldn't tell, but pretty big.
Found it!
Jimmy, over here.
Found the van.
Excellent.
Ernie, it's landed on its side.
There's no way we can
winch it out without a crane.
Look, we don't care about
the van - only what's inside.
Clara, can you open it up?
No problem.
Tying off the guideline now.
Guideline attached.
Copy that. Good job.
Clara, look at this.
What have they got in there?
A lot of boxes.
Boxes of what?
Let's find out.
Locked.
Maybe the key's
still be in the ignition.
Do you reckon you could reach it?
Maybe.
The keys are here.
There are labels on the boxes.
I can't quite make them out.
Clara, what happened?
What's goin' on down there?
Something knocked me over.
What was it?
I didn't see.
It just came out of nowhere.
Clara!
Clara, talk to me! Can you hear me?
Jesus!
Shit! Her air line's come out!
Can you hear me? Clara!
Christ! Jimmy, you gotta find
her before she runs out of air!
I'm tracking her.
Jimmy! What's going on?
Clara!
Ernie, I found her!
- Good! Okay.
- Clara! Clara!
She's passed out.
I'm gonna do a blow up.
- Roger that.
- Get ready to pull us in.
- Hey... crank the wheel!
- Go on.
Here we come.
Faster, come on!
Clara, hold on. Hold on.
Oh, kiddo.
God...
Oh, God.
Hey. Hey.
Okay, kiddo.
Okay. Alright.
Hey, hey!
Come on. Come on, wake up.
You can do it.
That's it. Slow. Slow.
Oh, that's it. That's it.
Shhh. That's it.
Look there.
Okay, okay...
Are you okay, kid?
- Wamba?
- Wamba.
You're kidding me.
A fucking shark in the river?
It's a bull shark.
It lives in fresh and salt water.
But what the hell's it doing up here?
It's 50 miles from the coast.
Bull sharks swim up rivers.
Hundreds of miles.
Have babies, then swim back out.
The ones that remain upriver
are usually juveniles.
But, judging by its size,
this one's an adult female.
The females are always bigger.
Alright, so how big
are we talking here?
Ah, 12, 15 feet. Nose to tail.
Big deal. That's not so big.
Well, most bull sharks
are only eight feet.
They're also the most aggressive.
Oh, well, that's just great.
Isn't this what you divers
deal with every other week?
What, you're telling me
you shit yourself
every time a shark turns up, huh?
Get a load of this, guys.
Professional divers.
Scared of a fuckin' fish!
A bull shark is not just any fish.
Certainly not one
that's fearless enough
to attack a diver.
I don't care
if it's Moby Dick in there.
You got a job to do.
Get back to work.
My team's not going back in
until that shark's dealt with.
So you want me to catch it for you?
I don't care who catches it.
But until someone does...
we don't dive.
Jesus Christ.
You want this thing caught -
it comes out of your purse.
Saddle up, boys.
Let's go find ourselves a fisherman.
One with a set of balls.
I know where to go.
Hey.
You did good today.
You saved her life. I'm proud of you.
By the way, did you see
what was inside the van?
Couldn't tell. Just wooden boxes.
What do you think it is?
I don't know.
But next dive, find out, okay?
Oh, Jimmy! Keep it quiet.
Knock, knock?
Come in.
Ah, feeling better, kiddo?
Yeah, I'm getting there.
Well, first sign of any
sore joints or headaches,
you let me know, right?
Yes. No, I, um...
- I think I'm okay. Yep.
- Mm.
Um...
Okay.
You wanna stay up top
from here on, that's fine.
I feel like I let you down.
Let you all down.
Hey. You didn't let anyone down.
Could've been any one of us.
You're alive. Jimmy's alive.
That's all that matters.
I reckon you could use a drink.
I reckon we all could.
Any luck?
We found a local fisherman in town.
He'll be here first thing tomorrow.
Claims to be an expert
catching sharks in this river.
Lucky for you, he works cheap.
That's great.
Helluva first day, hey, lads?
So, how's the drowned rat?
I'm alright. Thanks for asking.
You're welcome.
Are you boys staying here tonight?
Hell no. Got a hotel back in town.
It's a shit-hole, but...
better than being out here
with the flies and these bugs.
Oh, not afraid of a few bugs,
are you?
Not a drinker, Jimmy-boy?
Oh, that's right - it's not
legal for you lot, is it?
That's a shame.
Why is it illegal?
Because the blacks like
getting on the piss too much.
Not as much as you whities.
Yeah.
Now, he does make
a good point there, Ernie.
That he does.
Man enough to fight and die
for his country they say,
but not man enough to buy a beer.
He was in the service?
Yeah, fought
the Japanese. New Guinea.
Ah...
Well, well, well.
Have you ever been
attacked by a shark?
Oh, yeah. Plenty of times.
Mostly little ones.
They come over,
trying to take a bite.
Is that where your scar came from?
No. This was from the war.
But my uncle was swimming
one day and lost an arm.
From here, down... Gone.
Big, big wamba.
My grandfather was
a great hunter of wamba.
I get my tribal name from him.
Barriakada.
Barri-akad-a?
- Barriakada.
- Barri...
He crossed all over my country
with his long spear.
And he cross every river, hunting,
but wamba, it's hard to catch.
But if we catch him,
it's good eating.
That's if he doesn't eat you first.
Very lucky she let you go.
Very lucky you found me.
Trick is,
get straight back in the water.
Mmm. Straight back
on the horse, right?
That's good advice.
Jeez, your boss - he sure can
put 'em away, can't he?
Unfortunately, yes.
I'll deal with him.
Thank you.
It's the local lang...
Do you want some?
Yeah, good.
Yes, why not?
- Come on.
- Hey!
- That's enough.
- Huh?
I think you've had enough. Come on...
Where the hell'd your
boss find that kid anyway?
Ernie was working on the pearl
farms a few years ago,
when his hose got disconnected.
It was Jimmy that found him
lying unconscious on the seabed.
Saved his life.
What about you?
How does a pretty little skirt
get herself
into professional diving?
Same way the boys do.
Don't seem like much fun,
freezing your arse off
in those rubber togs.
I daresay my idea of fun
differs greatly from yours.
So why do it?
The ocean.
It's the last frontier on Earth.
So few people get to see it.
You know, I was fortunate that
Ernie gave me the opportunity.
Nobody else would.
He your boyfriend?
He's my boss.
Hey, just making conversation.
Mm.
If you want to know details
about my life,
why don't you tell me
something about yours?
Like what?
Like... what business
are you in, exactly?
Men's grooming.
And those boxes, they're filled with?
Grooming products.
Right.
We've got an early start. Goodnight.
Oh...
- Ernie?
- Mmm.
I'm telling you
there is something wrong here.
I don't trust him.
Same. He scares the shit outta me.
Exactly.
Look, we don't know
what's in those boxes,
but it can't be good.
Let's just pack up and go. Tonight.
We'll give them their money back.
No! We finish the job.
Ernie. There will be other jobs.
We can manage without this one.
There are no other jobs!
We're not leaving.
That's the end of it.
Leave me alone.
Right.
- Morning.
Ernie.
Good morning.
Sergeant.
Hey.
Well, that's some interesting
equipment you've got there.
Yes.
Uh, we're helping these gentlemen
recover a car from the river.
Oh. I had no report on that.
Was anyone hurt?
Y... you'll have to talk to them.
So... why didn't you
report the accident?
I didn't know I had to.
Was anyone else involved?
Nope. It was just me.
But I got out in time.
Luck of the Irish.
Quite.
Well, if you're thinking of
venturing into the river
you ought to be careful.
There are sharks in there.
Yes, we know. We had a nasty
brush with one yesterday.
We're waiting on
a shark catcher. Bob Drummond.
Oh. I know Bob. He's a good man.
Well, he'll sort you out.
Thanks for dropping by, officer.
Good luck.
Yep.
Ma'am.
Oi! He's here.
"Out of the boat," they say...
He can't be serious.
Hey, young fella... here you go.
Ah, good morning, gentlemen!
Bob.
Big fella.
So...
who wants to go fishing, then, eh?
We'll leave that to the expert.
But you bring this baby
back by lunch,
there'll be a fifty quid bonus.
Mmm. You got yourself a deal there.
Righto.
Right, so,
I guess you all heard about
the Great White caught
off Bondi a few months ago?
It was all in the papers.
That was me.
Right, I caught more sharks
than I can remember.
That's not saying much, but...
All along this stretch
of the river here. Righto?
This was the biggest
bull shark I've ever seen.
Female. They're always bigger.
She could be pregnant. Might
be why she's so aggressive.
Yep. More than likely.
And your, uh,
little diving expedition here
is in her neck of the woods,
and she don't like it none.
What are the fuckin' odds?
Don't fret.
If she's still down there,
I'll catch her.
Alright?
Now, I need two volunteers.
Who's coming with me?
Ah-ah! Sorry, missy. Bad luck
to have a woman on board.
If she's as big as you say she is,
we need all the muscle
we can get, don't we?
And not you, brawny -
you fart, you'll tip us!
- Who else?
- I'll go.
Ah, good lad. Come on.
Bet you've caught a fish or two
in your life, have ya?
Good. Ya know how
to work a motor, son?
- Yep.
- Jump on in.
Sure beats a bark canoe,
doesn't it, eh?
- Righto, who else?
- Shaun-boy.
You just volunteered.
Are you kidding me?
I'm not gettin' in that boat.
What did you just say?
Look, I'm not gettin' in that
boat. Make one of them do it.
Two choices.
You get your ass in that boat,
or my boot in your ass.
Alright.
Are we good to go?
Righto, this here's for the big ones.
They don't like getting caught none.
A little bit of incentive,
alright? Show her who's boss.
You do know that bullets slow
down when they hit the water?
Well, I'll shoot her when
she's out of the water, then,
won't I, missy?
Righto, can ya handle that, son?
Is the Pope Catholic?
Got a helluva kick.
Watch her, alright?
Righto, good to go. Wish us luck!
Mate, uh, give us a shove out,
will ya?
Sure.
Alright, jump up front.
Righto, Jingo!
No, Jingo.
Don't embarrass me now, Jingo,
come on.
You know what to do.
There's people watching here...
Let's go.
There we go!
Let's go fishing! You beauty!
Beautiful day...
I like the feel
of this spot here, boys.
Cutting engine.
Chuck us that rod first.
Just throw that anchor out.
Careful.
Yes. This is the spot.
Righto.
Just throw a little bit
of this beautiful stuff out.
There's nothing more
these sharks love
than the smell of blood in the water.
Drives the buggers crazy.
Whips 'em into a frenzy.
Sometimes they even start
eating 'emselves.
It's a helluva sight, I tell ya!
Yep.
Alright, here we go.
Let's get in the water.
Ahh.
Right on, righto.
So, what now?
Well, now...
we wait.
Right.
Here we go, boys.
Come on, take a big bite.
Okay...
Gimme a hand!
No!
- Oh, shit.
- Bloody hell.
Give me that tacklebox, Jimmy.
- What happened?
- Ah, she got lucky, is all.
So did you. You almost went in.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, mate.
Boys, she's comin' back!
If you can plug her, plug her.
Plug it!
Ah, shit...
Here!
Ernie?
Are you seeing this?
Keep it.
Christ...
- Take a shot!
- Shoot it!
Come on!
Gimme the fuckin' harpoon.
- What?
- Gimme the harpoon!
Come on!
Good.
Where are you?
Yes. Come on.
I can't get up!
Move around and hold it steady.
Hurry, up!
- Get in the boat!
- Goddammit! Agh!
Come on!
No... No!
Jesus Christ.
We are in deep bloody shit!
Get us outta here! Come on! Come on!
Jimmy!
- Are you alright? You okay?
- I'm okay.
- Yeah?
Ah, I see you've been
swimming again, Shaun-boy.
I guess old Bob wasn't
all he was cracked up to be.
You think this is funny?
A man is dead!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Where do you think
you're goin', Ernie?
Gotta report it to the police.
You ain't reportin' nothing.
Why not?
- You got a job to do.
- And what exactly is our job?
Put a fuckin' muzzle on her,
Ernie, before I do.
This job's over.
Clara, Jimmy,
let's pack up the truck.
- Ernie!
- Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh!
Nothing is over until I say it is.
I will personally feed you,
the skirt and the darkie
to that fucking fish.
One juicy chunk at a time. Got that?
What's in the boxes?
What was the deal, Ernie?
No questions.
I swear to God, no one keeps
their fuckin' word anymore.
Shark or no shark,
you're going back in that river.
You tell us what's in there,
or we take a look ourselves.
Gold bullion.
And before you ask, yeah, I stole it.
You realize how long
that's gonna take to bring up?
That's your problem, Ernie.
That's why I pay you the big bucks.
You'll figure it out. And fast.
And what happens then?
To us. When it's done.
Well, you get paid and you go home.
Everyone's happy.
You speak English,
or you don't speak.
The hell is this? A raft?
It's a sled.
We walk it out, load it up,
then winch it back to shore.
Provided it doesn't snag.
There's fallen trees
everywhere down there.
We'll make a path best we can.
We should also set up
a decoy down river.
Some meat on a rope and hook.
Might keep the shark
distracted long enough
to give us a chance.
See? Just like I said...
People are never more creative
than when they got
a gun to their head.
So, what are we waiting for?
Right, watch closely.
You see it being taken,
that's our cue.
Ernie?
Let me go back down there.
You haven't been in a suit in months.
You're not going in that river.
Besides, you're good on the
wheels. You're better than me.
I got us into this mess,
when I should've walked away.
This one's on me.
Let's get it done,
and then we can go home.
Right.
Okay.
Ready?
It's taken the bait!
Ernie, the shark's taken the decoy.
You should be all clear.
Thanks, Clara. Jimmy, stay alert.
You feed out the lines.
Christ...
I can't see a damn thing down here!
Watch out for snags.
You should be at the van
in a couple of minutes.
Ernie, how's it going down there?
Decoy won't last forever.
Going as fast as we can.
There. I see it - right ahead.
Okay, Jimmy, let's get it opened up.
Door's open.
We're in business.
Bloody hell.
What is it?
There must be
two dozen boxes down here.
There's no way we can
take this in in one haul.
We're gonna need two trips.
You'll be lucky to survive one.
No choice - the winch
can only handle so much.
Come on. No time to lose.
I'll start loading, Jimmy.
- You get the work lamp up.
- Copy that.
It's done.
Good work.
Now jump in and start passing
those boxes through.
I'm on it.
Better tell them to watch it,
the decoy is gone.
Ernie, Jim, decoy's gone.
Be careful down there.
The shark could be anywhere.
We're almost done anyway.
The sled can't take much more.
Okay, Jimmy, last one.
Here you go.
Help me strap 'em on.
I can handle the rest.
You keep an eye out
for that shark. Okay?
On it.
Clara, start the winch.
Let's see if she'll take it.
Roger that. Retract the winch - now!
It's jammed!
No good - it's too heavy.
Roger that. We'll lighten the load.
Ernie, how's it going down there?
Almost done.
Boss?
Oh, shit.
Ernie, I think she's back.
Try now.
Try it again.
It's working.
Slow, but it's on its way back.
Roger that.
Ernie!
It's onto us, alright.
Stay in the van.
Once we've got the sled
back up, we'll haul you in.
Roger that.
That was close.
It's snagged on something.
It's not moving.
Ernie, it's snagged.
Come on, Jimmy. Let's go.
What about the shark?
We'll have to take our chances.
Stay close to me, Jimmy.
Hey, Clara, we found it.
Great.
- Shit.
- What?
It's jammed against a log.
Oh, no.
Alright, you take that side.
Come on.
Put your shoulder into it.
Go.
Push.
It's too heavy.
Jimmy... let's try over here.
Give me some slack on the cable.
Back off the winch!
Christ!
It's too damn heavy.
Clara, when I say, start that winch.
Okay.
When that winch starts, Jimmy,
push the sled out
and around that tree.
Hit it, Clara!
It's free! It's on its way!
Yes! It's working!
Stand by, we're coming back.
Roger that.
- Ernie?
- Christ!
- Ernie!
Jimmy, tell me
what's going on down there.
Clara, I'm gonna cut
his weights. You haul him in.
Roger that.
I'm walkin' back. Hold onto
this, you might need it.
Haul him in, quickly!
Now! Haul him in!
Chrissake... Haul him in.
Hold on, Ernie. Hold on.
Pull it faster! Pull!
Oh, my God!
Ernie, it's heading straight for you!
Pull faster! Pull!
No!
Clara! What's goin' on?
Come on.
One down, one to go.
No, Ernie.
No...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no...
- Ernie...
- Clara...
Hold still, Ernie. We're gonna
get you out of here.
We're gonna get you out of here.
We have to stop the bleeding.
Ernie, we have to get you
out of this suit.
We have to get you out of here.
We have to cut it off.
Clara...
You got to... get out of here...
Ernie, we are not going anywhere.
Run. Run...
Ernie, no, just please, just...
Just hang on.
We have to get him
to a hospital! Please!
Please!
You bastards!
- Ernie?
- No, no, no...
Ernie?
Ernie!
Ernie, please, please, please.
Just hang on, just hang on, please.
Please, please... Oh, God...
Oh, God! Oh, God!
No...
No!
Jimmy.
Look out!
You want to kill us, boy?
Let's see you try, huh?
Jimmy. No.
- Put it down.
- No, no. Let him have a go.
I'll make it fair for you.
Come on, boy.
What are you waiting for, huh?
What are you waiting for? Come on.
Come on, Jimmy.
Let's see what you're made of!
- Jimmy... No.
- Huh?
Come on, boy, come on!
Do your worst! Come on!
Fucking black bastard!
No!
You kill him,
there's no getting back
the rest of your gold.
I still have you.
Are you gonna man the pumps?
You gonna suit me up?
That was a nice shot, Jimmy.
Stop!
Stop.
Now, we're still ten boxes short.
So, tomorrow,
you and your boyfriend are
gonna go and get 'em for me.
Okay?
Jimmy?
Jimmy...
Jimmy.
Come on. Get up.
Ow!
Shut up.
Morning.
Big day ahead.
So, who's going swimming?
I will.
No. I'll go.
No.
I think little missy here
should have the honours.
See if she's got what it takes.
Come on. Now's your one big chance.
Make old Ernie proud.
Go and get his body.
It'll make a good decoy.
Keep the big fish occupied.
You touch him, I'll bloody kill you.
Ah, suit yourself, mate.
It's your girlfriend in there.
You're going to kill me now?
The rest of the boxes
should all fit on the sled.
Just make sure
you lash them on tight.
Got it.
Today you must become
stronger than the wamba.
Stronger than the wamba.
She's going in there,
she needs the knife.
Shaun-boy, get her the knife.
Now, you're gonna stay down there
until every one of those boxes
is accounted for.
The faster you get it done,
the sooner you get to go home.
Will you, though? Let us go home?
That's the deal.
You try anything stupid,
I will blow the darkie's
head off, cut your air
and leave you down there for
the shark and all her babies.
You got that?
That a girl.
How you doing, Clara?
No sign of her yet.
Okay, I'm here.
Copy that.
Be careful.
Right, that's all of them.
Ten boxes and they're strapped down.
- Start that winch, Jimmy.
- Roger that.
It's on its way.
Shit. She knows I'm here.
It's okay.
Find somewhere to hide
until she loses interest.
Do you copy, Clara?
Clara!
Yes, I copy that.
I'll hide.
Clara, are you okay?
Yes. Yes, I'm inside the van.
I'll wait for her to lose interest.
Good idea. Stay put.
Okay.
It's working.
Okay, good.
Clara!
Talk to me, Clara!
Clara, are you safe?
I'm okay. She's trapped inside.
I'm gonna try and jam the door.
Roger that.
She's trapped inside the van.
Good. Now get back fast.
Jimmy. In my belt, quick.
Hide it.
We're home free, boys. Well done.
Can we finally kill them now?
We're gonna take 'em
out to the river,
strap those heavy boots on 'em
and dump 'em over the side.
The three of us will be
out of here before you know it.
Shaun-boy, get this loaded
into the truck.
On it.
Well done, missy.
You made it back in one piece.
We kept our end of the deal.
Now keep yours.
Oh, I'm sorry, sweetheart.
That's not gonna happen.
We can't have you running off
to the coppers now, can we?
But that was the agreement.
You know your gullibility is sweet,
you know that?
It's stupid, but it's sweet.
Now go get your boss
and put him in the boat.
What for?
We're giving him a sea burial.
Same as we're gonna give you.
Move.
What is going on here?
Just a spot of fishing, officer.
And you need guns for that, do ya?
Drop it.
Kick it away.
Now, all of you,
keep your hands where I can see 'em.
- Sergeant...
- Quiet!
And what about you, big fella? Hmm?
I said hand over the gun.
There we go.
Now kick it away.
- And what about you two?
- We're hostages.
- Hostages?
- Yes, we're hostages.
Freeze!
Jimmy! Get in the water!
No-o-o!
You're dead!
Both of ya!
Come on.
You can't stay down there forever.
You can hide from me,
but that shark
won't stay trapped forever!
I got you, you little bastard.
Aghh!
You bitch!
No...!
Clara! Get outta there!
Wamba!
Get outta there!
Come on, Clara.
What are you gonna do
with that, sweetheart?
Call me that again. I dare you.
What are ya gonna do?
You gonna shoot me?
Come on, sweetheart.
What are you waitin' for?
Not one step closer.
You're down to your last shot.
You think you can get me
with one shot?
I'm a farmer's daughter,
and a better shot than he was.
That don't make you a killer.
Are you a killer?
Are ya?
No.
But she is.
Keep the pressure on it.
That true, you a farmer's daughter?
No.
He was a lawyer.
You had me fooled.
Sorry I'm late.
Had to pick up a few things.
Whose car is that out front?
Said they wanted to speak to us.
Been waiting almost an hour.
Oh, God.
No more police
or damned journalists. Please.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I'm so sorry to have kept you
both waiting. I'm Clara.
Paul Whitemore.
First National Bank of Sydney.
Frank Sturgess.
Benchley & Shaw Solicitors.
I represent Ernie's estate.
Now, Ernie had no family to speak of,
and, quite bluntly, everything
he owned is in this shed.
But what he did do was,
some time ago, write a will.
And in that will, he left
everything to you, Jimmy.
The Sea Dog Diving Company
is all yours. Congratulations.
Thank you.
Uh, on top of that,
it seems you were unaware,
the bank was offering a reward
of twenty five hundred pound
for any information which led
to the successful recovery
of the bullion.
Now, thanks to you two,
it was recovered in full.
So...
the reward is yours.
Er...
Thank you.
I... I don't really know
what else what to say.
'Thank you' will do fine.
If you do need anything
in the future,
please don't hesitate
to contact me personally.
- Of course.
- Good luck to you both.
Bye.
- Give me the keys.
- Where are we going?
To buy ourselves a boat.