[sci-fi sounds]
[dog barking]
[cat screeching]
[gasping and struggling]
Only Chairman Mao has
the key to that lock.
All we can do is to warn
the rest of the world.
How much time is there?
Less than 72 hours.
I have all I need.
All right.
Follow me.
FEMALE PERSONNEL: 55 is
suspended several miles
below the control unit.
We are certain the
force of this detonation
will rupture the faults
of the Earth's surface
and set off a chain
reaction of explosions
when the Earth's
tension is broken.
There only 51 hours left.
We better notify the president.
MAN [ON PA]: No go on
pressure parity here.
Two, check your output lodging
at uniform alpha double zulu.
Unit niner, alpha two.
We have a slight
hold at T minus 120.
This is a fuel
pressure parity check.
Repeat.
Hold at T minus 120.
Gentlemen, it is T minus 120.
So we'll have to
make this very brief.
You all know Colonel Price, life
commander of our Project Astra.
[applause]
MAN: Colonel, why
this trip to Venus?
I understand it's over
160 million miles away.
It'll take you four
months to get there,
and you'll be gone
for two years.
Gentlemen, we've come a
long way in spaceflight
in the last 10 years.
Since 1965, our fixed
satellites, our space stations,
our lunar landing, and base
established there several years
ago, our probes of the outer
solar system, all these efforts
have helped prepare us for
the payoff of phase one,
putting man on Venus.
MAN [ON PA]:
Attention, countdown
has resumed from T minus 120.
Repeat, countdown is
resuming from T minus 120.
Gentlemen, any more questions?
Yes, why the astronauts
take the long way
to get to a planet?
Instead of hopping
straight across to it?
MAN [ON PA]: Will Dr. Haines
contact operator five?
Repeat.
Will Dr. Haines
contact operator five?
Urgent.
Operator.
Get me a ground control
then base security.
And operator, keep
this line open.
Actually, we take
the shortest route.
I'll show you.
This is the inner
solar system-- Mars,
Earth, Venus, and Mercury.
Note Venus is the next
closest planet to the Sun.
Your question is,
why don't we drop
right down here to
Venus, taking advantage
of the sun's gravitation?
Venus wouldn't be there
when we got there.
It travels along its own orbit.
You'll make a
rendezvous with it?
Exactly.
Colonel, make this brief.
COLONEL PRICE: This is our
starting point and Venus
at our point of rendezvous.
Unit to orbit around the Earth
as a launching point in space.
Then taking advantage
of the Earth's speed
along its own orbit, we
take off into deep space
on a ballistic course
that ends here.
Now we drop into a Venus
orbit and prepare to land.
And it's as simple as that?
Nothing's that simple.
How long will the journey take?
Barring unusual circumstances,
four months to reach Venus.
But counting the return trip
and planned explorations,
we'll be gone two years.
Well, what do you consider
unusual circumstances?
Anything we're not prepared
for-- excessive radiation,
meteors, unknown factors.
MAN [ON PA]: The time
is T minus 117 minutes.
All unauthorized
personnel are instructed
to clear the launch area.
Second stage fueling
will now begin.
Flight crew stand by.
Repeat.
Flight crew, stand by.
That includes me, gentleman.
WOMAN: Well, one
last thing, please.
Yes?
What about your family,
your wife, sweetheart?
That's the most difficult
part of the whole trip.
Two years alone?
Gentlemen, thank you.
Tech confirmed, Dr. Haines.
Right from the top.
Right, like this is it.
We'll speed it up.
Right.
This is ground
control operation.
Urgent.
Unauthorized personnel
clear the area.
Repeat, unauthorized
personnel clear the area.
You still think an old
warhorse like me can't take it?
Doesn't matter what
I think, doctor.
Your technical knowledge gives
you an override on the computer
to the contrary.
I hope you make it.
Frankly, so do I.
Anyhow, it'll be worth it.
You know, I've dreamt
of this adventure
ever since I was a kid.
That's tellin' them, doc.
It's the only way to go.
I can think of other ways.
Especially for you.
What's the matter, a navigator
got the countdown jitters?
$10 billion worth of
taxpayers' money and we
gotta put up with clowns.
Come on, you two, cut it out.
I just hope we're something
more than Guinea pigs
for our brain trust out there.
MAN [ON PA]:
Attention t-minus 98.
Stage one fueling
detail, stand by.
Repeat.
Stage one fueling
detail, stand by.
Hey, stage one.
That's the coal stuff, deluxe.
What's happening?
They're speeding it up.
Eh, it must be the weather.
We're tied to those
tracking cameras.
Who cares about pictures?
Doctor, get those Pentagon
pen pushers off their lard
and behind their computers.
Our lives depend on
ballistics not pictures.
MAN [ON PA]: Attention, all
base security personnel.
Attention, all base
security personnel.
This is a class 1 alert.
Condition red.
Alpha phase is in effect.
All civilians not
actually engaged
in the Astra countdown report
to security headquarters
for reclassification.
Been an alert?
They must be kidding.
Cruise ship went
up with miniskirts.
This is 1975.
Even if you kept up
with your comic books,
you outta know what China's
been fooling around with.
Give me control.
MAN [ON PA]: Attention,
all Sac personnel,
report to duty
stations immediately.
All leaves are cancelled.
Base now operating
under martial law.
What is this?
Where's the colonel?
MAN [ON PA]: Astra
Control Center will amend
countdown to accelerate launch.
All minor system check
outs are cancelled.
Reset all timers from T
minus 90 to T minus 50.
Flight crew, prepare
to board at T minus 30.
Those check outs
can't be bypassed.
It's a red alert, Mason.
The ICBMs are flying.
It's fairly simple.
This base is a strategic target.
They want us airborne.
What do you say, doc?
Relax, Danny.
We'll know soon enough.
Sir, what is it?
We've got to suit
up, [inaudible],
take off T minus 30.
Colonel, we can't let them
bypass those check outs.
We've got to check
with security.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
Are we under attack?
COLONEL PRICE: All
I know, gentlemen,
is that we're in some
kind of military crisis.
It may or may not
be the big rumble,
but you know the routine.
All bases scramble,
and that includes
our big bird out there.
Colonel, what about
those secondary checks?
You and Doc Perry
get together and see
if you can live with your
pet fixes as they are.
It's go for anything
short of a fuel leak.
What's the use of launching
if we're gonna blow it?
You know as well as I do
without a full check out,
anything can happen.
And we're gonna be
out there two years.
Anything can happen
while we're standing here.
Colonel Price?
COLONEL PRICE: Yes.
I'm from the Central
Intelligence Agency.
We have top priority for
replacement on this flight.
Replacements?
Colonel, I'm Donahue.
This is Colonel Mathis.
Hello.
We have special orders
to you from the president.
Gentlemen, what
is the situation?
Red alert, that is
all we can say now.
Russia has advised us that--
MAN [ON PA]: T minus 45 minutes.
General, there's no
time for that now.
You are to replace
three of your crew
with three other officers.
Women?
Now I've heard everything.
Colonel, this is ridiculous.
It's absolutely insane.
Gentlemen, I don't understand.
You will, colonel, but
there's no time to argue.
What's this?
Special sealed cargo.
It's to go on board.
I can't take extra weight.
You know that.
The weights have been
calculated, colonel.
We three women weigh less
than the men we're replacing.
Oh, and, uh, just who do
you have in mind replacing?
They're in your
orders, colonel.
Dr. Brown, flight surgeon.
Well, that's me.
Lieutenant [inaudible]
tech and assistant navigator
and Major Williams, copilot
and systems engineer.
Yes, sir.
MAN [ON PA]: T minus 44 minutes.
Pardon me, sir.
You or the Joint
Chiefs or the president
can order what you wish.
But personally, I think
you're out of your minds.
Colonel Price, it's not
in your province to judge.
Isn't it?
COLONEL MATHIS: No.
What about the
emotional stability
of a mixed crew in deep
space for over two years?
Colonel, we're quite stable.
We have no special
accommodations on that ship.
There's no privacy at all.
Nor are we asking for any
special privileges, sir.
Colonel, this is
Dr. Marion Turner,
flight surgeon, microbiologist.
[whistles]
Where do we put
on our suits, sir.
There goes my stability.
What's the story, general?
What's going on, general?
Let us in on it.
Let us in and take some shots.
Let us in.
Lieutenant Carlson, computer
[inaudible] and meteorologist.
Hi.
Major Bronski, copilot,
survival specialist.
Bronski, the Russian?
First woman on the moon.
That is right.
Fortunately, I was
at the International
Space Conference in Washington
when this emergency arose.
I'm happy to say
that my government
has authorized me to join you.
Emergency?
You haven't said
anything yet, doc.
What can you say, colonel?
It's a presidential order.
There must be worst
fates, colonel.
Gentlemen, I'd like
to consult our project
director, Dr. Haines.
I'm sure he--
CIA PERSONNEL: You don't
have time, colonel.
Please get these
women ready at once.
MAN [ON PA]: T minus 43 minutes.
Attention, Astra flight
crew, stand by for man
pick up at T minus 30.
I'm sorry, men.
Three years of preparation.
Well, at least my wife will
appreciate these replacements.
Good luck, sir.
Thank you.
Ladies?
I don't believe it.
I don't believe it!
You know, there must be a
practical side to having women.
You mean, like having
your socks washed.
Everything OK?
A OK.
MAN [ON PA]: T minus 10,
9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Ground control to Astra.
Everything is A-OK from here.
All systems are going.
You have a good climbing angle.
Your velocity is 3250
at T plus two minutes.
Confirm time sync and
prepare for booster cut off.
Astra to GC.
A-OK.
All go here.
Time sync.
T plus two minutes, 15 seconds.
Cut off T plus three.
Read you loud and clear.
Confirm BECO, at T plus three.
We don't like Dr.
Perry's pulse here.
You'll have it made.
We can only take a second
stage into Earth orbit.
Astra to GC, read you.
30 seconds to cut off.
Colonel Price,
this is Dr. Turner.
Clear the air, Dr. Turner.
How much time do we have
before second stage cut in?
Clear the air.
Doctor, you would ha
several minutes at low G
before the second booster
takes us into Earth's orbit.
The ship's gravity
control is on.
Ground to Astra.
Dr. Turner has a point.
Before second stage cut in--
MAN [ON PA]: We are at T
plus two and 45 seconds.
Kurt, sequence your check outs.
You've got two
minutes before cut in.
Give me a half G on the
gravity neutralizer.
You've got it.
Colonel, what about Dr. Perry?
He'll have to chance.
Dr. Perry must have pure
oxygen. Now ask [inaudible]
medical for his reading.
Control to Astra, your
flight attitude is fair.
Roll sequence is programming
in, changing [inaudible]
to 75 degrees northeast.
Do you read?
Astra to GC, roger.
Take sequence 2-1 as follows.
Cabin temperature
90, air pressure 5.5,
relative humidity 36 degrees.
Sequence 2-5 next.
Danny, read off.
It's 11-3 tracking
at green here,
a little hash from shielding.
Colonel, I warned you not to
bypass those subsystem checks.
Take it, Kurt.
Auto guidance is sluggish.
Manual override seems OK.
[inaudible] this is
following computer control.
Two degrees per second, over.
Ground control to Astra.
Dr. Turner, the arrow med
readings on Dr. Perry--
Dr. Turner, you must
let me run this ship.
Astra to ground, come in.
MAN [ON PA]: You have one minute
before firing second stage.
Where is your prior fire data?
Repeat, where is your
fire commit data?
That's Perry's sequence.
COLONEL PRICE: Major
Bronski, get into your seat.
We fire in less than a minute.
Major Bronski!
MAN [ON PA]: Capcom to
Astra, for heat exchanges
and pressurization,
give status on sequencer
units before program commit.
Astra to Capcom.
We are T plus 4
minutes and 10 seconds.
What is your attitude
for orbital entry?
Are we hitting the slot?
MAN [ON PA]: Capcom to Astra.
We can't bring up your nose.
Hit your overrides
and fly by wire.
You need four degrees
vertical pitch.
Throw the automatic
tanks on manual.
Bring us up.
I'm on wire.
[breathing heavily]
That's it.
15 seconds to
second stage cut in.
Major Bronski,
Danny, 15 seconds!
[breathing heavily]
Commit the sequencers
on the gas generators.
Committed.
Everybody grab tight.
MAN [ON PA]: Capcom to
Astra, all lights are green.
4, 3, 2, 1, 0.
Good boy, Colonel.
You're in the slot.
Earth orbit established.
Prepare for Venus
launch at T plus 1100.
Venus launch, T plus 1100.
Plus 11?
They're moving us ahead again.
DR. PERRY: Combustion
sequence in.
First valve's green.
Gas generator's full pressure.
You're A-OK.
You know, Dr.
Perry might've lost
his life if you hadn't, uh--
We're thinking of one life.
The colonel was
thinking of all of us.
Escape velocity reducing
to ballistic course speed.
Dropping to 18,000
miles per hour.
Cabin pressure up
to a 0.9 atmospheres.
Set control to AGCS and
secure final flight mod.
And here we are.
The old girl
didn't pop a rivet.
Venus, open your arms.
They sure pushed us
out of Earth orbit fast.
I've got a feeling
there's something
more than a war involved.
You'll have plenty
of time to ask them.
Everybody get unplugged.
Does she know why we're here?
No.
Are you going to tell her?
I hope she never
has to find out.
Yes.
What'd you read on
the Doppler scope?
It's been throwing
out a good spectrum.
Hmm.
The shift is declining.
[static]
Velocity 17,500.
I'd say we're 40,000 miles out.
Put it in the ship's computer
and see what we get, doc.
Right.
And let's get these
wires off, huh?
Yeah.
What's her name, uh, Turner,
she's a doctor, isn't she?
Mhm.
Can't wait to take
inventory, huh, Kurt?
I happen to think she knows
more about this cruise ship
that she's letting on.
Danny, give me a Aster control.
I want to talk to Dr. Haynes.
Right.
Hey, they've got us.
Don't think about
Russia and the US.
Chinese are at it again.
That's news?
Picking up a bomb of static,
must be the Van Allen belt.
Or China with her nuclear toys.
What does that mean, doc?
Well, it's possible that new
device they came up with--
Well, that's why
the big rumble.
Well, that's my guess.
Their principle could
start an uncontrolled chain
reaction, that is if they're
mad enough to try it.
Doc, you better
get your check up.
Oh I'm much better,
thanks, much better.
You know, for a while there,
I thought I'd never make it.
If it weren't for
you, I'd probably--
Me?
Thank Major Bronski and Danny.
I don't know if they make
'em like that anymore.
Come on, Kurt.
They have to bury
these probes so deeply.
It's less than a bee sting.
[gasp]
You could knock, Colonel Price.
I thought the
proprieties were out.
What's in?
At least let us get
familiar with the routine.
True, doctor, we do have
a long time ahead of us.
And with only three personnel
modules on this ship,
we should get quite
familiar with the routine.
Why is this,
sophisticated Americans
suffering from false modesty?
In Russia, we are more mature.
Shall we proceed, doc?
When you're through
in here, doctor.
Coming, Kurt?
Oh.
Nice, huh?
Katie, this isn't a hay ride.
We're here for a
serious purpose.
What could be more
serious than a hay ride?
I don't think she realizes
how serious this is.
What are you two talking about?
There you go, major.
I can't get over it.
Putting females together
with the male animal
in a cage like this.
What are we supposed to
do for the next two years?
Breed?
How about some
check outs while, uh,
communications clear?
You know something?
Kurt could have a point here.
What do you mean?
Well, those Pentagon
computers are pretty sharp.
Sending us three women?
Well, supposing China
did destroy the world,
could be nothing left
for us to come back to.
Come on, doc,
you're space happy.
You've been reading
the pulps again.
Doomsday.
[chuckles] Get him.
Well, I mean, you guys aren't
taking him seriously, are you?
Those chopstick jockeys couldn't
come off with a planet buster,
could they?
Look, it doesn't have
to be the Chinese.
Accidents could
happen on any sign.
For the love of--
increase the gravity.
Right.
Ham sandwich?
With mustard.
This is the first time I've
seen the Earth and the moon
together from space.
Of course, the Russian
probes have photographed
most of the solar system.
Of course.
I speak the simple
truth, comrade Mason.
So do I. And don't
call me comrade.
First into space, first to
set the record for manned
orbital flight, first to--
The question isn't
what you did but how.
What do you mean?
I saw one of your
unannounced tries in Earth
orbit, a ruptured hulk with
a corpse for a passenger.
How many more are there?
Perhaps, Captain Mason, we
are more dedicated to science.
To science?
Ha.
Hey, Kurt, lay off, will you?
I can take care of
myself, lieutenant.
I'm sure you can, major.
But if you ever need the
reserves, just whistle.
I'll be on the lower
deck if I'm needed.
He's not really a fink.
He just asks like one.
A what?
Never mind.
Hello.
Enjoy your shower?
Mm.
Love your homemade water.
We do travel first class.
Where's that music coming from?
Our latter day Marconi seems to
have broken through the static.
Who?
Oh, Danny.
I think he's cute.
If you like boys.
Say, I've been wondering,
uh, do you got a specialty?
Uh-huh.
Oh?
Meteorology.
Oh.
Would you care to join
me on a tour of the ship,
see what makes it tick?
I know what it makes it tick.
You do?
Uh-huh.
You're divorced.
Colonel Price is separated
from his wife at present.
And Danny, sweet,
merit badge for him.
You do get around.
You, uh, forgot grandpa.
Dr. Perry's age will
protect me there.
I wouldn't bank on it.
Let's cut out the games, huh?
You know what's ahead of us.
We're all gonna be cozy
together for a nice, long time.
Now why don't you
relax and enjoy it.
You're very
forceful, aren't you?
Do I, uh, need force?
I was talking about vibration.
Oh.
How are yours doing?
What do they say?
I'm not sure, but I like 'em.
And they like you-- in time.
Oh, you startled me.
I'm, uh, finding a high
DNA distortion rate
due to, uh, hard radiation.
Probably the Van Allen
belt or solar flares.
Speaking of flares,
I, uh, wonder what
happened to the
fireworks back home.
Well, I just thank God that
any destruction was averted.
COLONEL PRICE: I could've
told them they were crazy.
This whole mess was unnecessary.
I mean, bringing
you women along.
Some stargazer panicked
and thought the world
was going to end, didn't he?
It was a joint
recommendation of a National
Security Committee and the
Scientific Advisory Board.
The president had to act
before the Astra was launched.
So in case the
world did end, they
figured a few people
like you and me could
do a rerun on Adam and Eve?
Yes.
Something like that.
Look, colonel, we're only doing
what we were ordered to do.
And if it doesn't suit
you, well, I'm very sorry.
You know, without your glasses,
you're a very pretty doctor.
Oh, sorry.
I came to see about supper.
Uh, it's the altitude.
It works up the appetite.
--[clears throat]
I'll help you, Katie.
But doctor, Captain Mason has
not, uh, got to me, as you say.
Ah, there we are folks,
fresh off the space farm.
I must confess, your
country is certainly
first in the culinary
art of space cooking.
Ah, it now delicious, Danny.
Thank you.
By they way, major, remember
those Russian ghost ships
that Kurt mentioned?
I'd like to ask you--
I know of no ghost ships.
Well, there was an early Venus
probe, the, uh, Izvestia II,
I believe.
Yes, the Izvestia II.
That was lost in space.
Well, it's maneuvers were
much too sophisticated
for it to be unmanned.
Izvestia II was a robot ship.
There were no men aboard.
I see.
Then it was purely coincidental
that a certain Igor
Nikonov just
happened to disappear
just about that same time?
Colonel Nikonov did
not die in space.
They would have told us.
I knew him very well.
He was my instructor in
astronautical science and--
Yes, he was also a very
important party man.
We do not mix
politics with science.
MAN [ON RADIO]: We interrupt--
He was cut off.
What's happening?
Why did the delay?
A million miles out, it takes
a few seconds for transmission
to return.
What do you see, Kurt?
Nothing unusual.
Still there.
What is it?
MAJOR MASON: My god!
They did it.
It's happened.
Pure war.
Come on, everybody.
What's all the big
surprise about?
Two years from now
when we get back-- when
we get back-- if we get back.
No, no.
[SCREAMS] No!
[explosions]
It's the one thing we feared,
nuclear chain reaction.
[explosions]
It can't be.
Yes, it is.
How?
No.
That static.
It's radiation.
Oh!
Ah.
Get me the filters.
Bring it in close.
[explosions]
It's gone.
Hold on.
[cries]
Would you shut up?
Mason!
-Will you shut up?
-[screams]
Shut up!
That should quiet her.
What about you?
You gonna be all right?
Yeah.
I'm just so cold.
So am I. Radiation.
Yes, and it's rising.
But that's not all,
Don, Earth fragments,
great broken masses
of land hurdling
toward us at meteoric speed.
Earth fragments,
that's right, meteors.
We'll have to change
if they get any closer.
You and Kurt get the
radiation shielding up.
Right.
We're gonna make it.
Well, I hope so.
I-- I want to live.
[SCREAMS] I want to live!
Come on, Kurt, get
a hold of yourself.
We all want to live.
Danny, Danny, do you hear me?
He's just been
sitting there like.
He reminds me of my
little brother years
ago when he fell from
the roof of the barn.
He's gonna be all right.
Danny.
Danny!
What happened?
He's all right.
I'll be out if you need me.
I'm some astronaut.
There's nothing to be
ashamed of, lieutenant.
We're all very shaken up.
You seem very calm.
My years of training.
Say, what made you
become an astronaut?
You ask because I have a woman?
Yeah.
In my country, women follow
the same professions as men.
I excelled in science
in the university.
It was only natural
that I should become
a part of the space program.
Were you interested in it?
It never occurred
to me to question.
I followed the advice
of my superiors.
I was proud to be the only
woman in a class with six men.
Oh?
Well, uh, don't you
miss being a woman?
I mean--
I know what you mean.
You know something, Danny?
I like you.
You do?
Yes, Danny, I do.
That's a lot better.
That curtain cuts the
radiation to about 5%.
Flight crew, secure.
Get into your seats.
Meteors.
Repeat, secure.
Meteors, meteors.
Come on, Mason.
You OK?
Yes, sir.
Come on, then.
Our suits!
There's no time.
Hold the cabin pressure
at 0.9 atmospheres.
Let's do it!
What if we catch
a-- hole in the hull?
We've got emergency patches.
Without suits, we'd never
get a chance to use them.
Here we go.
[incessant beeping]
Would you cut
that damned alarm?
It's driving me nuts!
It's 15 degrees
elevation, fast.
We're-- we're not plotted.
We'll get lost.
15 degrees.
15 degrees!
Doc, how much reserve
fuel can I use?
We've go the whole
return booster.
We're not going home, so
shoot the works, skipper.
Why don't you shut up?
Mason.
We're clear.
Drop us back 15.
Cut the engines.
Save the fuel.
I will when you level out.
Oh.
COLONEL PRICE: Way off course,
but until this meteor traffic
bends, we've got
no other choice.
How much fuel did
we use, Skipper?
We've used 20% of
the third stage tanks.
And it'll take that much again
to get us back on course.
Mason, relax.
It's only fuel we would've
used on the return trip.
Doc?
We need a new course.
What we need is time to collect
what brains we have left.
What are we gonna do?
What's gonna happen to us?
How do you feel?
Lousy.
All right.
Let's run a play back on this
whole thing from the beginning.
So fortunately for us,
they saw the end coming
and reshuffled our crew.
In other words,
we've been paired
off on a latter day Noah's ark.
Well, there's nothing like
facing the facts, is there?
I've got myself railroaded
into a stud poker game.
Hey!
Not bad, eh, kid?
Who'd a thought of it?
Katie Carlson, the
girl who thought she
had everything going for her.
Now the future
mother of a nation.
Katie!
May, uh, an older
man offer something?
The past is gone.
Every second brings us closer
to a new, untouched world,
our world.
We're the lucky ones.
At least we have a tomorrow.
Doc, he got us back
on course again.
All we have to do is slide
down your orbit, four months of
free falling, and we're home.
Don, can I talk to you alone?
Sure, doc.
Kurt?
Uh-uh.
Rank has no privileges
anymore and no secrets.
It's all right, doc, go ahead.
All right.
We can't afford four months.
We've got to get there
in less than two.
Two?
Impossible.
We'd drain the fuel.
We wouldn't have enough
to make the Venus entry.
The Earth's
explosion has tripled
the radiation out there.
And it's non-directional.
We just can't shield it out.
Ah, it's mostly soft
stuff, alphas and betas.
The gamma concentration
isn't critical.
Yes, I know but for
months' exposure to it
will mean just one
thing-- sterilization.
[chuckles]
In hell do you find amusing?
Procreation.
[chuckles] The only thing
our damn machines can't do,
and we're gonna lose.
[laughs]
At most, doc, we-- we
can't land without fuel.
A few could by
stripping the ship,
dropping the booster shelf.
Oh, I know it sounds ridiculous
to say that the weight
of a few people could affect
the safety of a 50-ton ship,
but I've checked and
rechecked it on the computer,
and-- and there's
no other answer.
Our fuel?
But-- yes, Georgianna?
I just came in to
open the ISPM switches.
Danny and Katie are
doing maintenance
on the digital units.
Yes I asked him to check
the stellar beam registers.
We can't get a
good fix on Sirius.
I see.
How long was she standing there?
I don't know.
Georgianna?
What is it?
Well, that should do it.
Hey.
Hey, those are tears.
Something else you wanted?
Mhm.
Don't.
Don't your vibrations ever stop?
You know it has to
be sooner or later.
Why don't we make it sooner?
[screams]
For god sakes, cool it, Mason.
What are you trying to do?
As if I couldn't guess.
Take your hands off her.
It's too damn crowded in this
sardine can to be playing tag.
I said take your hands off her.
Break it up!
Mason, I've had it with you.
Either you straighten
up or spend the next two
months locked below.
Come on forward.
Dr. Perry has something
to say to all of us.
So you see, the omnipresence
of all this radiation
leaves us no option.
We have to protect the three
people who'll survived.
Three?
Yes, three.
So four of us will
have to [inaudible].
Fuel and weight factors
leave us no other choice.
It's beyond despairing.
Why should you despair?
In a fire, the mares are
always saved, aren't they?
Nothing ever changes
in space or people.
OK who decides what?
We have everyone's XL file.
A computer will be programmed.
Ha.
Sex and the machine.
Well, who does the programming?
Dr. Perry.
Any objections?
COLONEL PRICE:
We'll be there soon.
It'll remind you
of home, I hope.
How close are we?
Less than a million miles.
Only a few days now, and we'll
be entering into orbit around.
Only three of us.
Only three.
I hope you're one of them.
I hope you are.
Start of this trip, I had a
whole world to choose from.
Now--
Now there's just me, huh?
Just you and me.
What's the answer?
Huh?
You're out of order, captain.
Pretty fancy programming, doc.
That information is
for Colonel Price.
Why?
We're all in the same mess.
You're gonna love this.
I know, Katie.
You must be bitterly
disappointed.
No, not at all.
It's almost Biblical.
A patriarch Adam,
fatherly, kindly.
I think it's a fine choice.
Amazing.
The wisdom of an
unemotional machine.
That man represents a
million years of knowledge
for tomorrow's generation.
You really buy it, huh?
I don't care what the
damn computer says.
There's only going to be one
decision, and I've made it.
You with me, baby?
You and me.
I've waited long enough for you.
You're mine.
[gasps]
No one else is going to
get their hands on you.
[shouts]
Colonel Price!
You're crazy, Kurt,
you know that?
You're crazy!
You don't want me.
You and Perry-- it's disgusting.
Come here.
Come here!
You asked for an
impersonal decision,
we must see the logic.
Georgianne, I just
don't know what to say.
I'm happy for you and Katie.
Besides, I'm the oldest.
And that's it?
And?
The computer was programmed.
It doesn't make errors.
DANNY: It's manmade,
so it can make errors.
We've become
machine worshippers.
Don't you see it?
We're so used to
flying on instruments,
we don't know solid ground
when we're standing on it.
What are you trying to say?
He's trying to say that you and
Marion are very much in love.
You're young and vital,
essential ingredients
for an infant humanity.
You're an animal!
That's right, baby, an animal.
We're all animals!
No rules.
No more [inaudible].
Survival! [inaudible].
Look out!
[screaming]
Kurt, Katie, would you
come up forward, please?
[ON PA] Captain Mason,
Katie, do you hear me?
My god!
Katie.
Kurt.
Ohh.
No, not that.
What is it?
Five year supply of
food concentrates.
They've thought of
everything, didn't they?
Well, it's enough
for this load, anyway.
OK.
Those are earth fragments.
Entry should begin at once.
Doc, we didn't reject
the computer's decision.
Why should you?
Well, I consider it settled.
You and Marion and Major Bronski
will carry on, right, Danny?
Right.
Suppose I had stayed at home.
At least this way I get
a chance to wave goodbye.
I've gotta get my gear.
It'll be all right,
because it has to be.
COLONEL PRICE: Danny, hold it.
Nobody leaves this ship.
It's all of us or nobody.
What?
You heard me.
But that's suicide.
The extra weight.
We're going to chat.
But colonel--
Hit the booster commit.
That's an order.
All right.
Committed.
OK.
In less than 10 minutes, the
last stage will blast free,
and we'll begin deceleration.
Everybody secure.
Look, the board!
We never got my
subsystem check out.
The circuit's been shorted
There's a misalignment
in the booster connector.
Let me get it, skipper.
He will be all right, won't he?
If the booster blasts free,
he could use it as a raft.
We're committed.
We can't stop a sequence.
You mean he can't
get back to the ship?
We'd be gone.
Fasten your straps.
Are you getting a green light?
Yes.
It's not holding.
You've got four
minutes, Colonel.
Don?
Dr. Perry?
We're Georgianna?
She's gone!
COLONEL PRICE: What's
the problem, Danny?
I'm trying, skipper,
but I haven't
got enough mass to swing it.
It's really jammed.
Keep trying, Danny.
Keep trying.
That's it, Danny.
You got it.
We made it.
Oh thank god.
Amen to that.
100 million miles from
home, and we ran out of gas.
Georgie, why did you do it?
You needed help, didn't you?
I guess so.
This is like sitting in Central
Park on a warm summer's night.
Have you ever been
to Central Park?
No, Danny, I have never
been in Central Park.
It was a beautiful place.
It started at 59th
Street and-- hey, look!
They're just meteorites.
No, no, over there!
It's a miracle, a
beautiful, floating miracle.
Come on!
How's the fuel?
A-OK.
We're gonna make it.
DANNY: Georgie, it's Russian.
She's got solar cells.
That means we've
got electricity.
MAJOR BRONSKI: [inaudible]
is [inaudible] too.
DANNY: I don't care if
it's the Flying Dutchman.
Let's go inside to
repair the ring.
Come on.
We've got some excess baggage.
MAJOR BRONSKI: What is it?
DANNY: Looks like a
countryman of yours.
Well, at least we've
got some oxygen
and emergency power from the
batteries, what's left of them.
There's no main power.
That means-- Hey,
we've got juice.
We're on the air.
Oh, Danny.
I knew such a miracle
couldn't be wasted.
We're going to live!
How's that for
long shots, honey?
Somebody's betting on us.
We've got to win.
Those systems ought to
come on now like crazy.
But first, let's see if
we've got a home to go to.
I think I can milk 108 megs out
of this rig, even in Russian.
Hello, Astra, this is the
Izvestia II calling Astra.
Do you read me, Astra?
Over.
I don't believe it.
Danny!
Where are you?
This is Astra calling.
Izvestia II?
Don't give up, Danny.
Keep trying.
Izvestia II to Astra.
Come in, please.
Over.
Hello, Astra.
Are you there?
Come in, Astra.
Answer me.
Anybody, please.
Izvestia II calling
Astra, come in, please.
Come in, Danny!
Come in you wonderful,
crazy-- do you hear me, over?
DANNY [ON RADIO] :
Our craft is operable.
We need guidance for entry.
We read your signal, Astra.
It's faint, but we
can beam in on it.
Keep it coming.
We're on our way.
I'm switching to manual control.
What?
COLONEL PRICE [ON RADIO]:
Danny, where are you?
Georgie, activate
the view screen.
I want to see where
I'm going if I'm
taking this baby in by hand.
I'm activating the
image stabilizer systems.
We're set on wide scan.
Should be able to get
reception from Venus shortly.
DANNY [ON RADIO] : Hello, Astra.
All our systems are go.
I'm reading your
signal, but I'm not
getting any audio transmission.
Astra, I know you can read us.
In two seconds, we're going
to boost our reception.
Stand by to confirm
you're holding
us on beam for all our entry.
Do you read?
Over.
Astra, Astra, what's happened?
Where are you?
We're picking up no
signals from you.
No, it's OK.
We've got their signal.
Or do we?
Astra, where are you?
Astra.
DISEMBODIED VOICE:
Last of man, listen.
The craft you are attempting
to communicate with no longer
exists.
Your sister craft
no longer exists.
The signal you are
following is a warning.
Had you been able to
decipher its meaning,
you would not have attempted
to trespass on our world.
Your world?
Who are you?
DISEMBODIED VOICE: We all the
collective minds of the world
your craft now orbits.
Easy enough for you to
know that during the span
of our evolution
our civilization
has witnessed the birth and
death of worlds and suns
untold.
But enough.
Your time is short.
You may not enter our world.
We have witnessed the
self-destructive powers of
the green planet you can earth.
We have no malice toward you.
You have destroyed your
place in the universe.
Last of man, listen of
this we will tell you.
Your journey will continue.
Something very
strange and very great
awaits you beyond the
rim of the universe.
And now, last of man,
your journey will begin.
[explosion]
[music playing]