"Near Bistritz,
"the road turns towards
the heart of the Carpathians,
"one of the most barren and
least known places in Europe.”
Allow me.
Thank you very much,
What was that, Sara?
"One of the most barren and
least known places in Europe."
Keep reading.
"Crumbling castles are scattered
among the rugged summits.
"They belong to
a remote era..."
Coachman, you should go
a little slower!
No! No! We must get to the inn
before nightfall.
Why?
Today is Walpurgisnacht,
a night of evil.
Nosferatu...
The dead come out
from their tombs
and suck the blood
of the living.
Nonsense!
You would not laugh
if you lived here.
Tonight, all doors
will be locked
and we shall pray to the Virgin,
How was the trip?
Very good, thank you.
I'm glad to hear it.
Lad, don't take my luggage down.
I must continue
on to Borgo Pass.
I must warn you that
today is St. Walpurga's day,
which is considered
a bad omen around here.
And the coachman,
who is a good man,
wishes to know whether
you wouldn't mind
continuing the journey
after sunrise.
I'm very sorry, but at midnight,
a carriage will be waiting
for me at the Borgo Pass.
Whose carriage?
Count Dracula's.
From Dracula's castle?
Right. That is
my destination.
Look, he wants to
travel on to Borgo Pass tonight.
I beg you
to stay the night here.
But all of this
is mere superstition.
I mean, in a mountainous
area like this one,
I don't understand how...
Anyway, what I mean to say
is that I'm not afraid.
I told him already,
this is a business affair.
I must go there, really.
Wait.
Since you mean to leave,
put this on.
Put it on, for God's sake.
It will protect you.
Thanks.
You are very welcome,
Good night.
Good night,
and I wish you a good journey.
Good night.
Good night and good luck.
Giddy-up!
Tell me,
do you really believe
there are vampires
who come out of their tombs
and roam about looking for blood?
I have seen the victims!
Nonsense!
Come, Sara.
Count Dracula's carriage?
I am Dracula.
You couldn't have appeared
at a better time.
I have no idea what happened
to the coachman and my luggage.
With all that, I thought
I had come to the wrong place.
The walls of my
castle are cracked
and there are
shadows everywhere.
But come in.
Make yourself at home.
Listen to them.
They are the
children of the night.
What beautiful music they make!
The eternal
struggle for survival.
Every living creature needs
blood to keep on living.
The spider weaves its web
to catch the unwary fly.
Blood is life,
Mr. Renfield.
I think you will find this part
of the castle more appealing.
I certainly do.
I thought you might be hungry.
You are very kind,
Count Dracula.
Sit down.
Thanks.
I trust no one
knows of your visit.
Absolutely no one,
just as you recommended.
I assume you burned
all our correspondence.
I followed all your
instructions to the letter.
Excellent,
Mr. Renfield. Excellent.
It was nothing.
Just a scratch.
Won't you have some?
I never drink
wine.
And now, if you're
feeling refreshed...
I would like to talk about
the lease of Carfax Abbey.
But all the documents
are in my briefcase.
I took the liberty
of sending for your luggage.
Everything is in order.
You just need to sign it.
I hope there are enough
tags here for all your bags.
I am only taking three boxes.
We shall leave tomorrow night.
Everything will be ready.
I hope you find it comfortable.
Thanks.
It looks appealing.
Now I shall leave you alone.
I may be occupied
during the day tomorrow.
In that case,
we shall meet here at dusk.
Good night, Mr. Renfield.
Look!
Fingers frozen
stiff on the helm.
He must have died of fright.
What a terrible tragedy!
Not even a shred of
the sails is left.
It must have been
a terrible storm.
What about the sailors?
What became of them?
Master! Master!
We've arrived!
Can't you hear me,
Master? Master!
What's that?
It's coming from that hatchway.
It is believed to be due
to severe weather.
A madman is the sole survivor.
Maritime authorities will deliver
the cargo to its destinations.
You will tell Dr. Seward,
who is sitting in the next box,
that there is
a phone call for him.
Once you have given him
this message,
you will remember nothing.
Dr. Seward, there's
a phone call for you.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
Yes?
I happened to
overhear your name.
Are you the Dr. Seward who
has a sanatorium in Whitby?
That's right.
I am Count Dracula.
I have just rented Carfax Abbey.
I understand it's next to the
gardens of your sanatorium,
Correct. It lies
next to my property.
It's a great pleasure
to meet you, Count.
Would you like to join us?
Count,
allow me to introduce my daughter Eva.
Miss Weston.
Mr. Harker.
Count Dracula has just
rented Carfax Abbey.
It will be a joy to see those
dark windows lit up again.
Count, I beg you to excuse
me. There's a phone call for me.
In the meantime,
please be seated.
My pleasure.
A very nice house could be
built out of those Carfax ruins.
Of course,
it would take a lot of money.
I shall barely touch them.
They remind me
of the crumbling walls
of my own castle
in Transylvania.
What they remind me of
is that old toast.
"Lofty beams upon deserted walls
"beat with the echo
of our laughter
"as if the dead
whispered through them."
How nice!
Wait.
The next part's even nicer.
"For those who are already dead,
let us empty our glasses
"and let us cheer for him
among us who must die first."
You can keep the rest to yourself,
Lucia.
To really die...
To be really dead
must be sublime.
But, Count...
Something worse than death
awaits the living.
Laugh all you like.
I find him fascinating.
Lucia the romantic.
That explains it.
That part about
crumbling walls...
I prefer someone
a little more normal.
Like Juan?
Yes, my dear.
Like Juan.
Well, Countess, I'm very tired.
I leave you with your count
and his crumbling abbey.
May you have sweet dreams.
Good night.
The fog is getting thicker.
Yes.
Another death.
When was the last transfusion
performed on Miss Weston?
About four hours
before her death.
Identical symptoms in each case.
A baffling loss of blood
that we've been
unable to prevent.
Give me the magnifying glass.
And these same two
marks were found
on each victim's neck.
,
we're dealing
here with vampires.
Vampires?
Nosferatu?
Yes, the vampire
of Transylvania.
That's right.
Nosferatu the vampire.
The vampire attacks
his victim's neck
and leaves two tiny white wounds
with a red dot in the center.
But, Professor Van Helsing,
that theory is implausible.
Medical science nowadays
does not accept
the existence of
such a creature.
That's just a myth.
A superstition.
Dr. Seward's patient,
Renfield,
whose blood I have
just analyzed,
is obsessed with the idea that
he must eat other living creatures
in order to
sustain his own life.
I am going to England with
Dr. Seward to study Renfield's case.
And perhaps I will prove to you
that the superstition
of yesterday
can become the
scientific reality of today.
Look.
No, don't take it away,
Martin! Don't take it away!
You're a good man. Don't!
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
Now you're interested
in spiders. Spiders!
You're no longer
happy with flies.
Flies?
Tiny wretched flies!
Who could be happy with them?
You! A raving lunatic!
When nice plump spiders
aren't available,
perhaps.
All right, do as you please.
But now come with me.
The professor wants to speak
with you again. Let's go!
It's a very strange case.
Nevertheless, the only thing
Renfield has craved so far
are small bugs.
Not human beings.
That's what we think, Doctor
But you say that he
slips away from his room.
That he's gone for hours.
Where does he go?
Come in.
Well, Mr. Renfield.
You look much better now
than when I arrived this morning.
Thank you, Professor.
I feel much better.
Martin.
They tell me you studied
at Oxford University.
That's correct.
I graduated from the
school of law in 1927.
I was accepted by
the bar in 1928.
After that...
Excuse me.
An inferior organism.
Unworthy of my attention.
What would you have
done with that fly
had we not been here?
He'd have gobbled it up.
Tell me,
Mr. Renfield,
what makes you eat flies?
The wings of flies, sir,
represent the aerial power
of the psychic faculties.
There's more to this
fellow than meets the eye, Doc
I've never seen
you like this, Eva.
What's wrong? Are you
worried about something?
Have I done something
to hurt you?
You haven't done anything,
Juan. Don't worry.
But there is
something wrong. Tell me,
I don't know what it could be.
I've been feeling
frightened lately.
When night begins to fall,
I get this feeling,
as if something were
tightening around me.
Oh, Juan.
Get your filthy hands off me!
Come on, Renfield.
You must let me out of here!
Why is it so important to you?
I scream at night.
I might bother Miss Eva
and even cause her nightmares.
Nightmares?
Yes, Doctor.
Yes.
Nightmares.
It sounds like a wolf howling.
Yes, it does.
But I hardly think there
are wolves so near London.
He thinks there are
and I've heard howling at night.
He says they're talking to him
and he screams back
at the top of his voice.
He's crazy.
I should have known.
You know very well
why the wolves talk.
Isn't that true,
Mr. Renfield?
And you also know
how to make them stop.
You know too much
to go on living!
We won't get another word
out of him for the time being.
You can take him away, Martin.
Get up, flycatcher.
I'm warning you
once more, Doctor.
If you don't let me go,
you'll be responsible
for whatever happens
to your daughter.
What is that herb
that made him so upset?
Wolfsbane.
Peasants in Central Europe
use it to drive vampires away.
Renfield reacted
as soon as he smelled it.
Yes.
He must be watched
closely day and night.
Especially at night.
Yes.
You were saying
you had gone to bed.
Yes. I was reading
and I fell asleep.
I began to dream.
A dog barked.
And it looked as if the
whole room filled up with mist.
It was so thick
that I could hardly see
the light by my bedside.
It looked like a tiny
spark lost amidst the fog.
I saw two red eyes staring at me
and a livid, white face
through the fog.
He came closer and closer.
I could feel his
breath on my face.
And his lips... Ah!
But, Eva, it was just a dream,
The next morning,
I felt very weak,
as if all life had been drained out of me.
When did you have
this dream, Miss Eva?
The night
that Father left
for Switzerland.
In other words,
the night after
Lucia was buried.
Let's see.
Think for a moment.
Do you remember anything
that might have caused
this nightmare?
Nothing.
There's something
troubling Eva, Doctor.
Something she doesn't
want to tell us.
And the face
you saw in your dream,
you say it came
closer and closer?
That the lips touched you?
Where?
Eva.
No, Father.
Please!
What do you have on your neck?
Please, Father.
How long have you had
those marks on your neck?
Marks?
Since the day after that dream.
Count Dracula is here.
It's a pleasure
to see you again, Doctor.
I was sure you were back.
Miss Seward.
Excuse me, Count Dracula.
This is Professor Van Helsing.
Van Helsing,
the distinguished man of science
whose fame is known even in
the mountains of Transylvania.
Doctor, I beg you to excuse me,
but your daughter had better
go to her room immediately.
Aren't you feeling well?
I hope it's nothing serious.
I had a terrible dream
a few nights ago
and I haven't been able
to get it out of my mind.
Could it be you've taken
my stories too seriously?
Stories?
I made a humble effort
to entertain your fiancée
by telling her
a few of the legends,
somewhat gloomy ones,
about my distant motherland.
Daughter,
I'm sure Count Dracula will excuse you.
You must go your room
as Professor Van Helsing
has advised you to do.
But, Father, I tell you
I'm feeling fine now.
You'd better do as
your father says.
Very well, then.
Good night, my dear daughter.
I must go, Doctor.
Professor Van Helsing,
I hope I shall have the
pleasure of seeing you again.
Good night.
Good night, Juan.
Mr. Harker.,
I shall come by later
to enquire how you're feeling.
Thank you.
Good night, Miss Seward.
Good night.
I'm very sorry that
my visit was so untimely.
Not at all.
On the contrary,
it may turn out to be
of great importance.
Moreover, before you leave,
you could be helpful to us.
It will be a pleasure
to do whatever I can.
Just a moment ago,
I discovered an amazing phenomenon.
Something so incredible
that I do not trust my own eyes
and I'd like you
to help me prove it.
Look.
Dr. Seward,
please accept my apologies.
I couldn't help it.
Considering that
you have not yet lived
even one entire lifetime,
you are a wise man, Professor
Did you see the
expression on his face?
He looked like an enraged beast.
Dracula is our vampire,
Vampire?
For God's sake, Professor!
Vampires cast no
reflection in a mirror.
That is why Dracula
shattered that mirror.
Look, Professor,
this makes no sense whatsoever,
Dracula is the monster
who killed Lucia Weston.
The same one who left those
marks on Miss Eva's neck.
Him?
Well, please understand
that I mean no offense
but that's more like something
one of the patients here might say.
Yes! And that's exactly what
physicians in this country
and the police will think.
What gives vampires their power
is the fact that people refuse
to believe in them.
But, Professor,
according to your own theory,
the vampire must return
to his grave before dawn.
He must return to
his native land,
which is where he was buried.
Now, Count Dracula's
native land is Transylvania.
Then he must have brought
some of his native soil with him.
Perhaps in boxes big enough
to serve as his bed.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Renfield, what were
you doing out there?
Come on.
Come with me.
Renfield, did you hear
what we were saying?
Pay attention to
what he's telling you.
That is your only salvation.
And the same is true for her.
Save me!
Save my soul!
I am weak.
You are strong.
I am crazy.
You are sane.
I shall save you.
But you must tell us
everything you know.
Everything.
Fool! Fool!
And I thought
you were a wise man.
What do I stand to gain
by telling you everything?
That physician keeps me
locked up here all day.
And when I behave nicely,
he gives me a bit of sugar
so that I can catch flies.
But if I serve the Master...
An intelligent madman
would rather serve
the one who can grant him life.
Him? Who are you
talking about?
Why mention names
among friends, Professor?
What ties do you
have with Dracula?
Dracula?
I've never even heard
that name before.
You're lying!
Crazy people, Professor,
do not have the ability
to distinguish
between what is true and false.
For that reason,
I take no offense.
I begged you to let me out
but you wouldn't do it.
Now it's too late.
It has already happened.
What has happened?
I dare not say it.
I dare not.
I would die in
torment if I tried.
And you shall die in torment
if you let innocent blood
stain your soul.
No!
God will not condemn
the soul of a poor madman.
He knows very well
that the power of evil
is too great for those
of us with weak minds
to resist.
Then, Renfield, trust me.
Tell me what I want to know.
What do you want to know?
The name of the creature
that has deranged your mind.
The one you call "Master."
No!
Don't ask me that!
No! Don't ask me that!
You must tell us!
!
Leave me alone!
Renfield, tell us
before it's too late.
OW Before your soul
is damned forever.
I shall tell you.
Master! Master!
I wasn't going
to tell them anything!
I haven't told them anything!
I'm faithful to you, Master!
Dr. Seward!
Miss Eva...
Over there... Dead!
Thank God, she's still alive.
She's alive,
but she's at great risk.
She's under his influence.
That would be terrible.
I can't believe it.
Nevertheless, it's true.
We must put an end to it.
We must confront it.
Is Dr. Seward around?
No. What do you need?
That flycatcher
has escaped again
and he could try
something foolish.
Dr. Seward and his famous
scholar are in the abbey
chasing vampires.
Vampires. Flycatchers.
Look, Mr. Harker,
if there's a brave man
after my job, he can have it.
I'm going to look for work
at another asylum
where the crazy people
are nice and reasonable.
Let them think they're
Napoleon or royalty.
Something worthy of my time.
"The mysterious lady in white,
“that merciless scourge
of childhood,
“played another of her tricks
last night
"a little after nightfall.
"The testimony
given by two girls,
"both confirm it's a beautiful
lady dressed in white
"whose modus operandi
is to offer
"candy to her victim.
"She then lures the victim
to a deserted corner
"where she delicately bites
the victim's neck."
What would she know
about the lady in white?
Why would she know
anything about it?
She shouldn't have read that.
For God's sake,
Mr. Harker!
When did you see Lucia
again after she was buried?
Once when I was on the terrace.
She came out of the shadows.
She came towards me.
She stopped and stared at me.
I began to speak to her.
And then
I remembered
that she was dead.
Her face took on
a horrible expression
like that of a hungry beast.
Like a wolf,
She turned
and disappeared
into the fog again.
So the lady dressed
in white was...
Lucia.
Miss, I promise you
that from this day on,
Lucia will rest in peace.
Her soul will be forever freed
of that awful appetite.
Since you can save
Lucia's soul after her death,
promise me you'll save mine too.
You're not going to die,
my love. You will go on living.
No, Juan, you mustn't touch me.
And you mustn't
kiss me ever again.
What are you saying?
Professor, explain it to him,
Tell him,
I can't.
Eva.
Juan, it's over between us.
Our love, our wedding plans.
Please, Juan,
don't look at me like that.
I love you.
I love you more
than life itself.
But this terrible thing...
He wants it to be this way
and I must obey.
You know what you're doing?
You're driving her crazy.
Mr. Harker, you should be
worried about what's out there.
The last rays of
the sun are gone.
Night hovers over us again.
We've put wolfsbane in this
room and in your bedroom
to free you from Dracula,
in case he comes back.
,
all right,
because either
she returns with me
to London or I call the police.
Seward, my friend,
I must be in charge here
or whatever I do
will be useless.
Miss Eva must keep this
branch of wolfsbane in her bed.
Be careful that she doesn't
drop it while she sleeps.
Under no circumstances
must those windows
be opened during the night.
I understand, Professor.
Come, my daughter.
Yes, Master.
You've come back, Master
Are you angry with me?
No, Master!
Please!
Not her!
Never again!
No, Master!
No! Not her!
No!
No! No!
Please!
No, Master, please!
Mr. Harker,
though I have devoted my life to
the study of
the strangest things,
little known
facts that the world
is perhaps better
off not knowing,
a world content to busy itself
instead with mundane affairs.
Dracula's name is
associated with a legend
still told among
his fellow countrymen.
The legend tells
of an ancient family
that disappeared
over five centuries ago
and was said
to be made up of vampires.
Since I discovered, by chance,
that Dracula cast
no reflection in the mirror
and that in addition,
that three large boxes had
been sent to Carfax Abbey,
and since I also knew that
a vampire must sleep
during the day
in his native earth,
I quickly realized that
Dracula had to be the person
whom Renfield
calls "Master."
One of the undead
who has been able
to prolong his life
beyond its natural limits
by feeding on the blood
of other living creatures.
The only way we can save Eva
is by finding the place
where the living corpse
of the vampire rests
and driving a stake
through its heart.
What a strange conversation
for men who are not crazy!
Renfield, you I will force me
to put you in a straitjacket.
I'm afraid that would be
of no use at this point.
What? What's
that, Doctor?
Again?
I'm on my way, sir.
Right away, Doctor.
The doctor's favorite
lunatic is at large again.
Well, I'll be! That madman
must be Hercules himself.
What's he done now?
Come and see for yourself,
From now on
any mental suggestion
you receive from me
must be carried out.
Whenever I want you
to do something,
it must be done.
It must be done.
When you come out of this state,
you will remember nothing
of what I am telling you now.
Do you understand?
I understand.
I have already told you
what you must do.
Now,
obey.
Renfield, you know
where those boxes are.
Tell us and we
shall protect you.
But I no longer need
your protection.
The Master is not angry with
On the contrary, he's pleased.
He came to my window
in the moonlight
and promised me things.
Not to say them, but to do them.
Do them?
Yes!
To make them happen.
Ed mist spread over the lawn
and came towards me
like a raging fire.
Then the Master parted the mist
and revealed before my eyes
thousands of rats,
their eyes inflamed like his own,
but smaller.
He raised his hand
and they all stopped.
I felt he was telling me,
"Rats! Rats! Rats!
"Thousands, millions of rats!
"And in each one of them,
"a life full of red blood
"promising many years of life.
"I shall give you
all those beings!
"Yes! And many more!
"For countless generations!
"But you must obey.”
What did he want you to do?
What has already been done.
Dracula is in this house!
Where else did you
expect him to be?
He won't be able
to cause any harm.
We've placed wolfsbane
in every room.
So here you are!
For God's sake! This man
is going to drive me crazy.
He broke through those iron bars
as if they were toothpicks.
Come with me, Martin.
Let me show you somewhere
he'll never escape from.
Let's go.
You may be right,
but I still say what St. Thomas said.
Van Helsing.
Now that you've learned
what you've learned,
it would be wise
to return to your country.
Ha!
I intend to stay
and protect those
you seek to destroy.
You're too late.
Dracula's blood is already
flowing in Miss Seward's veins.
She will live for all eternity
as I myself have.
Should you escape, Dracula,
we know how to save
Miss Eva's soul,
if not her life.
Of course I'm all right.
I've never felt better
in my whole life.
Tell me, why are you staring
at me like that?
You're so...
I can hardly believe it!
You look like a different woman.
Darling, you look terrific!
And I feel terrific.
But it's stuffy in here.
And that smell.
It's the wreath of flowers
the professor wanted me to...
Marta!
Yes, miss?
Throw away those awful flowers,
will you?
And please open the windows
and let some fresh air in.
The professor won't approve.
Don't worry about him.
It's much nicer out here.
I'm happy to see you like this.
I was really worried about you.
I don't know
what was wrong with me.
It's as if
I'm waking from a nightmare.
Juan, the moonlight
is beautiful, isn't it?
Look. Have you ever
seen so many stars?
Millions and millions.
And they seem to be so close,
as if you could reach out
and touch them.
Would you like me to
offer you a handful of them?
Do not forget, Van Helsing,
that over the years
those who crossed my path
paid for it with their lives
and some in very
unpleasant ways.
Come
here!
Stop!
You shall not move your hand
unless I tell you to.
Take out whatever you have
in there and put it in this box.
Hurry up!
Did you obey?
Yes.
Yes, that's what you said.
No, I didn't, Juan.
What do you mean?
I could have never told you
such a foolish thing.
You made it up.
No,
you told me that the night frightened you.
And what is there about
the night to frighten me?
I love the night.
It's the only time
when I feel truly alive.
Careful, a bat! It could get
tangled in your hair.
Yes, I will.
I will.
You'll what?
Me? I didn't
say anything.
I thought you did.
God, that bat was huge.
Juan,
I want you to promise
me something.
Whatever you want,
my love. Whatever you ask.
That strange professor
and his herbs...
I can't stand them any longer.
Will you do me a favor
and take them away from him?
And the crucifix.
Take it away from him too.
He'll say he wants
to protect me again.
From the night,
from Count Dracula,
from everything.
I don't know what to believe.
But he might be right.
He told me some terrible
things about that Count Dracula.
What is it?
What's wrong with you?
Why?
Your eyes. They look at me
in such a strange way!
Oh! Eva!
Eva, my daughter!
It's all right, Eva, my love.
The cross.
Juan!
After what's happened,
I can't look at it.
But... What's happened?
I can't tell you!
I can't!
You must tell me.
I have a right to know.
Dracula.
He came.
He opened a vein in his arm
and forced me
to drink.
What is it?
Who is it, Martin?
A bat, Professor.
Very big and black.
Don't waste your
pellets. It's no use.
You'll never harm that bat.
What can we do?
He's crazy.
They're all crazy.
All of them, except you and me.
And sometimes I even
have my doubts about you.
It was a good deed,
driving a stake through
the heart of that poor girl.
Now her soul will rest in peace.
Let's go to the abbey.
Look! An opening
in the wall.
Master!
Master, here I am!
Here I am!
Eva! Eva!
He went in this way!
I didn't bring them here,
Master! I swear!
I didn't know, Master!
Wait!
Master! Master!
I've always been faithful!
I am your slave.
I did not betray you!
Don't kill me, Master
Punish me! Torture me!
But let me live!
I cannot go before God
with so many deaths
on my conscience
and so much blood on my hands!
He came in through here!
Eva! Eva!
Use this pole, Harker!
I've got it.
Eva, we're here!
Eva! Eva!
Eva!
Harker! Harker!
I found them.
Look.
His life as a vampire
is coming to an end.
What about Eva?
You must be brave.
Find me a stone.
Something
that I can use to drive a stake
through his heart.
What about Eva?
Is she...
She's not here.
Then she's still alive!
Where are you?
Eva! Eva! Where are you?
Eva! Eva! Eva!
You're safe, Eva!
You're safe!
Oh, Juan!
You should have seen
the horrible look on his face
when he saw the sunlight.
There is nothing to fear now.
Dracula is dead forever.
Aren't you coming?
I'm staying behind.
I shall make good
on my promise to Renfield.