TOEI COMPANY, LTD.
NEW YORK 1966
BRUTAL CHANGE IN CITY CRIME!
VICTIMS FOLLOW AMONG THE POLICEMEN!
NYPD HAS TAKEN KARATE FOR
SELF PROTECTION!
OPPOSITION DEVELOPS OVER KARATE
TEACHER POST!
OKINAWA KARATE AND...
...TOKYO GOBUKAN
NEW YORK CITY POLICE DEPARTMENT
I repeat...
I strongly recommend Mr. Higaki Isshin
as the city's first Karate instructor.
Mr. Higaki was recognized at a young age as a
Karate genius by the Okinawan Karate society.
Also, he is well respected among the
Karate players in the U.S.
I understand.
Endorsed by you, a hero of the Japanese-American
soldiers of WWII, I have no objections.
But Mr. Nikaido has just opened
a flashy new Dojo in town.
He's a Fifth Degree Black Belt of the Tokyo
Gobukan School, and has connections at city hall.
Recently, they've been pressuring the
New York City Police Headquarters.
I want to settle it amicably.
Please wait for the final decision.
But...
Come on!
You ready to fight?
I didn't come here to fight.
What?
Because I don't have any
reason to want to fight you.
Well, you may have no reason,
but I've plenty of reasons.
I want that Karate instructor's
job, and you're in my way.
That's no reason! We're
both good Karate men.
They'll choose one of us.
Leave it at that.
That's all crap.
You gonna fight me, or is
your Karate just for show?
Get back.
Right.
Wait!
Nikaido, now listen.
Stop this foolishness.
Get lost!
You're a coward Nikaido!
Higaki!
Father!
Yumi!
Father.
Father!
Higaki, I'm willing to spare your life.
But you have to get out of this town.
Alright.
Father! Father!
Yumi, please pull it out.
Pull it out. Go on! Quickly!
Yumi. You remember them. Fix
those faces in your mind.
You hear me, and never
ever forget them.
DRAGON PRINCESS
(Hissatsu Onna Kenshi)
LOS ANGELES
Yumi!
No help!
Get up!
Come on!
Yes.
Yumi!
Isshin
Planning by: YOSHIMINE Kineo
Screenplay by: MATSUDA Hiroo
Photography by: NAKAZAWA Hanjiro
Sound Recoding by: MUNAKATA Hiroyoshi
Lighting by: KOBAYASHI Yoshio
Art Direction by: KITAGAWA Hiroshi
Music by: KIKUCHI Shunsuke
Fix your eyes.
Editor: TANAKA Osamu
Assistant Director: MORI Mitsumasa
Continuity: TAKATSU Shoko
Fight Choreography: HIO Koji
Stills: FUJII Yoshio
Production Manager: HORI Kenji
Set Design: IHO Kunio
Set Decoration: YABE Kazuo
Makeup: IRIE Shoji
Beautician: ISHIKAWA Yasue
Wardrobe: UCHIDA Minako
Script Supervisor: ISHIHARA Keiji
Film Processing: TOEI CHEMICAL INDUSTRIES
Cast:
SHIHOMI Etsuko
KURATA Yasuaki
CHIBA Jiro
OTSUKA Go
KATO Yoshi
TAKECHI Toyoko
SATO Gajiro
SATO Kyoichi
Alright. Attack me.
Yes, sir.
KOMATSU Hosei
OIZUMI Akira
HIO Koji
KAWAI Genji
RYU Kenji
KARIYA Shunsuke
TAKATSUKI Tadashi
NAGUMO Yusuke
OMAEDA Takeshi
SAITO Kazuyuki
NISHIMOTO Ryojiro
SOMA Gozo
YOSHIZAWA Yuko
SUGATA Tetsutaro
YAMADA Koichi
OZAKI Masumi
Brian BOETTCHER
Bart JOHANSSON
Liner GETZMAN
UCHIKOSHI Akiyuki
YAMAMOTO Midori
SHOKO Toshie
SAKAI Tsutomu
KAMEYAMA Tatsuya
SAWADA Koji
YAMAOKA Junji
TAKAHASHI Kenji
HARUTA Misao
J.A.C (Japan Action Club)
AMATSU Bin
ISHIBASHI Masashi
CHIBA Shinichi
Defend yourself. Come on.
Get up!
Directed by: KOHIRA Yutaka
Come on. Attack me!
"Karate is difficult."
"Karate is something I hate!"
Come on. Attack!
Come on you. Don't think of me.
Think of Nikaido.
Just think of me as Nikaido!
Come on.
Father.
Yumi... Yumi.
Yes.
You had no real childhood,
practicing all the time.
Everyday Karate. Maybe you thought
I was pushing you too hard,
just so you could eventually, one day...
But that's not really true,
it wasn't just for me.
You see, Okizaki too,
Nikaido killed him.
That's how he got the job
as Karate Instructor.
Okizaki was blocking him.
And now, he's back in Tokyo,
running the Gobukan, and
doing well they say.
He's got backing from politicians,
and right now he's lauding
it over the Karate world.
I'm alright, I'm alright. I'm ok.
That's the reason I taught you.
So you can get him.
Don't let him deface Karate.
Expose him for the killer he is.
I know I've been a poor father. Yumi... please
don't begrudge me... it'll only make you bitter.
And when I'm gone, I want
you to go back to your...
...grandfather in Tokyo. I'm
sure he'll help you.
He's a good man.
Father, I swear I'll avenge you.
I'll get Nikaido. I promise on my life.
Father. Father! Father!
TOKYO
Watch it will you?
- Sir, can I have one?
- There you are.
Hey how's things?
Hey, your mother's looking for you.
Oh, alright.
How's that, huh?
Tastes good, thanks.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hey, watch it.
I believe that's mine.
Watch it, you scared me.
Wh... What is it?
Give it back!
Well, I just found it, so
it's mine. Alright!?
Damn it!
So you wanna fight, do you?
I'll show you.
This isn't a show.
Just shut up. Get out.
Now you come back here.
Wait!
Tell me, Ryusen-ji Temple, you know it?
Ryusen-ji? You're the monk's relative?
I'm sorry.
- Here.
- Thanks.
GOBUKAN
Alright, enough.
Osu!
Right, teacher.
First group.
Osu!
Second group.
Enough.
- That's a draw, huh?
- No
You got the first real blow in sir,
so you have beaten me there.
Well, and so what's your name?
Ah, I'm new. I'm Okiyama Masahiko.
Well, he's a good fighter.
I think he's going to be too
much for you to handle soon.
Teacher, we're the big four here.
There's no way he's gonna
be a match for us?
What is it?
I'd like to see Sensei Nikaido.
- You're his relative?
- No.
- Are you here for a lesson?
- I'm not.
What do you want?
I would like to have a contest
with Sensei Nikaido.
Huh!?
You're crazy girl.
A contest? You're nuts.
Come on, you'll have to leave.
Go on, get lost.
Listen girl. Go on, this is no
place for a young woman to be.
That's right.
If I can't fight Sensei Nikaido,
I'll take the big four, alright?
What!?
They'll probably cripple you for life, kid.
I'm willing to take that risk. I'm not worried.
Now look, so you really wanna fight do you?
Well alright! You fight me then! Come on!
Come on!
Now, what's wrong? Come on.
Kuroe...
Don't do it.
We want no one hurt.
It's alright, huh, she just said
that she's all prepared to get hurt.
Not her. It's you I meant.
What was that!? Alright, you're
trying to insult me are you, huh?
Well you wait, I'm going to
deal with you next.
Senpai!
Damn! This time, for sure...
Wait.
Now just who the hell are you anyway?
Higaki Yumi.
Senpai!
Higaki?
Fools! I always said be careful.
Inukai!
Enough.
Just remember this.
Yes. I'm very sorry, sir.
Osu!
Okiyama. Tell me, this girl,
she give you her name?
Yeah, she did.
Higaki Yumi.
Does the name mean anything to you?
No... Nothing.
I see. Well, maybe she's just a nutcase.
But she could fight reasonably well.
Oh, so you think that you could
beat her easily, is that right?
Well, of course I'd beat her.
She's just a girl.
Well, why did you let her go then?
At least you could've thought the bitch a
nice hard lesson, couldn't you?
Come on.
You seriously suggesting a
man should fight a girl?
Osu!
- Damn you!
- Hold it! Enough!
There'll be plenty of time.
He'll get his comeuppance.
- Yokoi.
- Yes?
Osu!
Teacher. Higaki?
She's his daughter?
I heard that Isshin died recently in
some broken down slum in Los Angeles.
I guess he must've trained his
daughter in Karate to avenge him.
That stupid fool. How in the
hell could she beat you?
Priest!
Kotaro, are you working hard?
Yeah, all the time. I live humbly
and I'm always short of money.
Don't lie.
Your mother was complaining.
She says you haven't been home recently.
Hey!
One mother, one child.
Stop worrying your old mother.
Okay.
- What's so funny?
- No, it's nothing.
Hey, priest. Today, I've brought
you an unusual visitor.
Instead of scolding me, maybe
you'll appreciate me for once.
- Mh?
- Never mind.
Hey, this way! Over here.
The "Preacher Man" is waiting for you.
- What do you mean by "Preacher Man" ?
- Thanks. I'm leaving.
Yumi?
You're so grown up. The living
image of your mother.
And how's your father?
Come with me. We'll go
to your mother's grave.
Your dear father's ashes should
be laid to rest with her. Right?
Your father was such a fool, he
just wouldn't listen. Nope.
He told me America was the best
place for a career in Karate,
and insisted on taking you with him.
Your mother had just died, and you
were still practically a baby.
I argued and argued with your father,
but he wouldn't listen to me...
...and he wouldn't change his mind.
He was such a fool really.
Oh, Yumi.
There'll be time for you girls later.
This won't take long sir, I promise.
Well, so it's Karate again, some
new championship?
Ah, it's to celebrate the 30th
anniversary of my Gobukan school.
Hmm, a bit weak. You may
not get much support.
No. This contest will be a
real international affair.
You see, we'll encourage entrants from
all of the major world schools,
but I'm quite confident that
the pupils from my school...
...will emerge the final winners.
After that, I hope that we can set up a
big financial foundation for my school.
I realize that my school
wasn't founded very long ago,
but in terms of the quality of my pupils,
we're way ahead of most of the schools.
So then, if we could manage to
win this championship,
then all of the good pupils
would flock to the school.
And I can imagine that
what you have in mind,
is to use my political status to
get the thing off the ground.
Yes. After all there could be
some advantages for you.
At a conservative estimate, half a million young
men will enroll in Karate schools this year.
- That's a lot of votes isn't it?
- Indeed
Another point. Entry fees will be quite high.
There's going to be an awful lot of money in this,
plenty for everybody, and some of
that can go to your party funds.
All in all, it could be a very nice deal.
I must admit it sounds like
an attractive proposition.
Alright, count me in.
You can use my name, but I warn you though,
your school had better win this. And win
in a big way, or it's all a waste of time.
You can rely on us. We have plenty of
good men, including the big four here.
That's good to hear. Well, let's celebrate
then in anticipation of victory.
- Here.
- Sir!
We're very grateful to you, sir.
Just you win it. Remember that.
Yes, sir!
- Good morning.
Now, come on folks. Buy yourself a magazine.
Just take a look at what I've got. It
doesn't cost you anything to look at them,
and maybe you'll see something
you really fancy.
Real artistic pictures. We've got
some beautiful full frontals,
all the latest issues, best selection in
town. And some nice hot group stuff as well.
Take your breath away. Come on have a
look here folks, very reasonable.
- Alright, I'll have one.
- Yes, ma'am. Thank you.
- Hey mother.
- Yeah?
- I just made a sale.
- Good for you.
Come on, quick, have a look here.
Sexy magazines, straight from America.
Alright, let's do this.
Hey, listen to me. The boys have got money
problems. It's all this inflation you see.
So we're going to have to put up
the dues. We need 50% more.
What? That's outrageous.
But how can we pay that much?
Now please sir, are you gonna try
to starve us to death or something?
If you don't like it, go somewhere else.
Ma'am! Are you alright? Are you alright?
- Damn you.
- Bastard, come on.
Damn you.
- Well, go help her.
- But they're yakuza...
And so what, you're just gonna stand
by and let them get away with this?
- What could I do?
- Lousy coward!
Are you gonna pay?
Come with me. Please, please help.
Look. Please help.
Please help us.
Now, have the money ready
tomorrow. You got that?
You can go to hell!
I'm not gonna pay you anything.
You lousy bunch of hoodlums!
- What? Are you crazy?
- Damn you. I'm not paying, no.
Get that scum.
I'm not paying you.
You heard me.
What the hell is this, huh?
Damn you!
Wow, you're tough.
You got 'em all!
- Senpai, are you serious?
- Yes.
I'll do my best.
- I'll give it a try.
- I won't be beaten!
Bitch!
- Teacher, it's me Yokoi.
- Right.
Here's the list of all the entrants.
Oh, thank you.
Osu!
HIGAKI Yumi
CHINEN Jiro
Teacher, what's wrong?
Chinen from Okinawa.
Gonzales from Cuba.
Suuccine from Libya.
LIBYA
CUBA
NAHA, OKINAWA
Wait!
Dear!
Stay back!
You bastards...
Well now, I guess you've nothing
else for us? That job's finished.
Now hang on... some other
tough entrants might show up.
Well I guess so. As a matter of fact, I
saw a really tough guy a few minutes ago.
You mean Yokoi?
No... I know all the big four.
The guy he was practicing with.
Oh... that's Okiyama.
Okiyama, so that's his name?
Well I know one thing he's one
of the best Karate men I've seen.
In fact, I'm gonna have to try
him out one of these days.
The international men are dead,
now we're gonna win the
championship for sure.
It's as good as in our pockets.
What!? He wants me to
cripple the young girl?
Yes... you'll be well paid for it.
The boss doesn't want her in circulation.
It'll be easy... and profitable.
Come on, think of the money!
Senpai, I need money!
Why not let me try.
Oh... a greedy one, eh?
Okiyama, now look, are you trying
to cut us out of this, huh?
Fifty fifty, split it down the middle.
Oh, cool it. Hey, let's get on
with the party huh?
All right girls, before I
go I'll finish this beer.
How are you?
Out of my way.
I never imagined any girl
could be so good at Karate.
Just a few days to
go... what will we do?
Think of something.
If we lose in public to a woman, then
the school will be finished for good.
There's only one thing to do.
Teacher, leave her to us. The big
four will handle her.
No, you four will stick to your practicing.
I want you to do nothing else.
You useless bigmouth, you!
Now stop it!
Grandfather!
Who are you?
Grandfather, get back... they're
Nikaido's men. They killed my father.
Hold it!
Hold it there.
Ten years ago...
My father Robert Okizaki of the NYPD
tried to stop Nikaido's appointment...
...and you three bastards killed him.
Here's the evidence right here...
This dagger... It's just like the one
the police found in his body.
I see. You deliberately lost to
her to force us out.
That's right.
And it was you that killed Chinen too.
Nikaido will pay.
I'll take him.
Ten years I've worked, practicing
just for this day.
Yumi.
Yumi...
Grandfather!
- Grandfather.
- Yumi...
Fighting with that arm again
is out of the question.
It was difficult to set.
That's a really bad fracture.
I warn you. You fight with that, and you'll
permanently disable it. You understand?
Listen. Wait until your arm is better.
Understand? You wouldn't have a chance, right?
Right. And you might get killed.
Maybe, but I'm resigned to that possibility.
Tomorrow is the only chance to
get Nikaido, the last chance.
He must lose, or there'll be no way
of stopping him later on. I know it.
Listen, if anything should happen to me, take
care of Grandfather. He's gonna need help.
Your grandfather's calling for you.
Yumi...
So then... you intend to
commit suicide, do you, eh?
You fool!
You must win.
You've never lived, you know that. Those
years, living in the dark shadow of your father...
And your life will only really
begin... when Nikaido's been killed.
So you mustn't die now. You have
to beat him by any means.
Fair or foul. Never mind
about rules, just get him.
Kill him... but stay alive
"Just remember. It doesn't always
take strength to accomplish things."
"Quite often, a weak tool,
will achieve what you want."
"So let your weakness serve
you as the weapon you'll use."
"And it can help you, because, your
enemy will count on that weakness,"
"and let himself be out-maneuvered."
"Then you strike. Then you'll
have a chance to win."
"Letter of challenge."
"To the director of the Gobukan
School, Nikaido Kosen."
"We challenge you to a duel to the
death on the Suzuki Hara slopes."
"We shall be there at dawn.
Higaki Yumi, Okizaki Masahiko."
The girl's only got one arm, it's
the man's that's the problem.
Inukai... you and Yokoi, you
can deal with him first.
Make sure they're both killed.
I want no further trouble.
And after it's finished, we'll
go to the stadium for the contest.
OSU!
- Over here...
- Right.
There he is... come on, get him!
Hey, there he is.
All right... go. Go!
Osu! The girl's not there.
What?
Go and search the slope.
Osu!
Hey, let's search the whole slope.
There she is! She's there!
Isshin
You really think you can
beat me one-handed?
THE END
Thanks to Bill and Kentaifilms
for translating a few scenes.
Transcribed by Chanbara & wigsplitta
Subtitled by Venom10463