Either you're flat orl am.
I beg your pardon.
Excuse me.
Always the lady.
Say-- Say, what the--?
Why,I frighten your
hiccup away, Marthy.
Yes, you did.
And I'm going to hit you.
See here.
If you soak me in the eye again...
...I'm gonna quit you.
-You get me?
-No. Only on the back this time, Marthy.
I get you.
-Well,I think you lose them, Marthy.
-Yes.
Yes,I did.
Oh,I got it.
Ten-- Ten swallows of this
without breathing...
...and...sure cure.
One, two, three, four, five...
...1 0. MaybeI got hiccup too, Marthy.
See?I told you.
It's a sure cure, never fails.
I think we got to go to Johnny the Harp
for get some more whiskey.
Yeah, well. Right you are, I'm bone dry.
Wait, I'll get my bonnet.
Johnny, he'll be surprised to see you
and me together once more.
Hold that, will you?
You're not sorry
you took me back, are you?
Oh, no, Marthy. I'm darn glad
I found you in Norfolk.
Aye, you been too old
to go walking streets, Marthy.
Old!
But you had better stay
with old Chris on the barge.
Well, I'm glad you found me.
Honest,I am.
Yeah, I'm glad to be here...
...dump that it is.
You're a good old punk.
-Come on.
-Yeah.
Marthy. Where are you going?
No, Marthy, no, we're in the boat, huh?
I forgot where the front door was.
-It's all right. It's all right with me.
-That's it, Marthy.
Oh, Marthy, hold my hand.
Hold my hand.
Well,I declare. How can you
do a thing like that?
Wait a minute, now. I'm all right.
I wasn't a tightrope walker for nothing.
See?
Oh, Marthy. Look out.
That's whatI get
for being a tightrope walker.
See, that's-- Where are we?
There we are.
-We go down and get a drink.
-No, wait, hon.
Oh, the horses. Oh, where are you?
-Here, Marthy.
-Old fool,I thought I'd lost you.
Just an old fool.
Come on. Here we go.
Come on. Oh, what was that?
Wait, wait. The doors.
Stopped.
-That's not funny.
-Marthy.
-There's the entrance.
-All right...
...wait, wait, wait.
Hold on.
-Yeah.
-Listen.
You wait here, Marthy.
-I go let you in.
-Oh, all right.
''Ladies' entrance.''
Well, that's a g--
Well, why not?
Said she,
with all the dignity in the world.
-Well, hello, Johnny.
-Hello, Chris. How are you?
Come and have a drink on me.
Come on, Larry.
Drinks for the house,
and have one yourseIf.
Oh,I got money, plenty money.
Speak of the devil, Chris,
we was just talking about you.
-Hello, Chris, put it there.
-Larry, give us a drink.
You got haIf a snootfuI now.
Oh, I'm a little drunk, not much.
Just feeI good.
My Josephine
Come board the ship
Long time I wait for you
The moon, she shines
She looks just like you
Same old Josephine, eh, Chris?
Well, you don't know good song
when you hear it.
ltalian fellow on other barge,
he learn me that song.
Come on, get your drink. Skoal!
-Drink hearty.
-Here's how.
-Come on, Larry, order drinks--
-No, no. No, Chris.
Some other time. I've gotta go home.
Where you in from this time?
Norfolk. Oh, we make a slow voyage...
...dirty weather, just fog.
Fog all the time.
No, no,I go, Larry.
I forget, it's Marthy.
She come with me.
What's the matter with you,
you old punk?
Gonna keep me
standing out there all night?
I'm sorry, Marthy.
JustI talk with Johnny.
What you think you like
for drink, whiskey?
Well, I'll take a scoop of lager
and ale for a chaser.
I go bring back for you, Marthy.
Lager and ale for Marthy, Larry.
Whiskey for me.
Right you are. By the way, Chris,
we've got a letter for you...
...from St. Paul, Minnesota.
And a lady's writing.
Then that must come from my
daughter, Anna. She living there.
I don't get letter from Anna,
must be year.
That's a fine fairy tale, your daughter.
Sure, I'll bet it's from some skirt.
Oh, no, this come from Anna.
I see....
By golly,I think I'm too drunk
to read that letter from Anna.
I thinkI go sit down for minute.
You bring drink in backroom, Larry.
All right.
Well, where's my lager and ale,
you old stiff?
Oh, Larry bring.
Larry bring, sweetheart.
How are you?
Good news?
Well, what do you got there?
Well, by jiminy,
what you think of that?
My daughter, Anna, say
she coming here right away.
She got sick on job
in St. Paul, she saying.
Let me see.
It's a short letter, it don't tell me
much more than that.
By golly, that's good news
all one time for old fella.
You know, Marthy,I told you
I don't see my Anna...
...since she was little girl
in Sweden, 5 year old.
How old will she be now?
Oh, she must be-- She must be
20 year old, by Jove.
-You've not seen her for 1 5 years?
-No.
I think it's better Anna live on farm.
Then she don't never know that....
That old deviI sea.
She don't know father like me.
This girI will marry a sailor herseIf, likely.
It's in the blood.
No, by golly, she don't do that.
Here! What are you trying to do,
spill my suds for me?
Oh, what's up with you?
Ain't you a sailor yourseIf?
Yes, and that's just whyI say it.
Sailor is all right fella,
but not for marry girl.
I know that.
Anna's mother, she know that too.
When is your daughter coming?
Soon?
Why,I forget.I see.
Well, she say she coming
right away, that's all.
She'll be coming here to look for you,
I suppose. Better hang around, Chris.
-Marthy--
-Well, what do you want?
I'm wise to what's
in the back of your nut...
...old squarehead.
You wanna get rid of me
because your kid's coming, huh?
Wanna kick me out, huh?
Well, see here, Chris. There
ain't no Swede on no boat...
...that's man enough
to get away with that.
Don't you start nothing you can't finish.
No,I don't start nothing, Marthy.
No, you don't.
You....
You're a scream.
Oh, honestly....
You're a knockout.
I don't see nothing for laugh at.
You don't? Go and take a slant
at yourseIf in the mirror.
Oh, gee.
Old squarehead, huh?
Trying to kid Marthy Owens, huh?
Oh, I'm onto the game.
I wasn't born and dragged up
on no waterfront for nothing.
You thought I'd make trouble, didn't you?
Not me.
I'm packing my duds
and I'm quitting you.
Yeah, I'm leaving you flat.
There's plenty of guys
on plenty of boats waiting for me.
Always was.
I always found them.
So cheer up, old squarehead.
I'll be out of the way
before your kid gets here.
You'll be rid of me for good,
and me of you.
-And good riddance to both of us.
-You. That's a good girl, Marthy.
Oh, ''good girl.''
Cut that bull.
Oh, well, you was always square
with me, so it's fifty-fifty...
...and nobody owes nobody nothing,
do they? Nobody's sore.
-Still friends?
-Oh, by golly, yes, Marthy.
Still friends.
Blow me another scoop of lager and ale,
and I'll drink your kid's health.
-And I'll--
-I'll do that, Marthy.I get it right away.
Another lager and ale for Marthy,
Larry. Whiskey for me.
My Josephine
Come board the ship
Long time I wait for you
The moon, she shines
-She looks just like you
-Oh, help us. Help us.
Help us, help us, help us.
Come on, get your drink, Marthy. Skoal!
I celebrate--I celebrate...
...because my Anna coming home.
You know, Marthy, my Anna--
What you think she look like, Marthy?
-I don't know.
-I bet you she's a fine, good, strong girl.
Pretty like everything because,
you know, live on the farm...
...they make them that way.
AndI bet you someday she marry...
...good, steady land fella here in East.
Have little house all her own.
Have kids!
Then I'm old grandfather, by golly.
By Jiminy Cricket,
we gotta celebrate that.
-Come on, Larry. Give us a drink, there.
-Wait.
You're soused to the ears,
that's what you are.
-Oh, you bet, you celebrate--
-I know,I know, but go on...
...put some food in you and sober up.
Here, you old fool. You don't know
when your kid's coming here, do you?
-Oh, well....
-Well...
...you wanna be sober
when she does get here, don't you?
-Oh, by golly, that's so, Marthy.
-Well, then...
...go throw a beef stew in you and--
Go on, around the corner.
I do that, Marthy.
I been coming right back.
Oh, well, that's that.
Give me a whiskey.
Ginger ale on the side.
And don't be stingy, baby.
-Well, shalll serve it in a pail?
-Well, that suits me down to the ground.
Gee,I needed that bad, all right, all right.
Oh, sure. You look all in.
Have you been on a bat?
No. Traveling.
Day and a haIf on a train.
Had to sit up all night
in a dirty coach too.
I thought I'd never get here.
-Where'd you come from?
-St. Paul, out in Minnesota.
Minnesota?
Then you're the--?
All the way from Minnesota, sure.
Say, what are you laughing at? Me?
Oh, no. Sure, kid. No, l--
I was thinking of something else.
Well,I wouldn't blame you, at that.
I guessI do look rotten.
I'm just out of the hospitaI two weeks.
I'm gonna have another drink.
What do you say?
Will you have something on me?
Sure thing. Thanks. Larry?
Larry!
Little service here, please.
-Same for me.
-Oh, same here.
Sit over here. Let's be friends, yeah?
I'm a dead stranger
in this burg, you know.
-Skoal. Here's how, huh?
-Here's luck.
Let you smoke in here, won't they?
Sure, but throw it away
if you hear someone coming.
Well, ain't they fussy in this dump.
ls there anything wrong with me?
You're sure looking hard enough.
I ain't gotta look very hard.
I got your number...
...the minute you come in the room.
ls that so?
Well,I got yours too, without no trouble.
You're me, 40 years from now.
That's you.
ls that so? Well,I wanna
tell you straight, kiddo...
...that Marthy Owens never--
Oh, let's cut out the scrapping.
I don't want no hard feelings
with no one.
-Come on, let's shake and be friends.
-Sure.
I ain't looking for trouble either.
Let's have another, huh?
Say, don't you think you'd better
go kind of easy on that stuff?
Well,I guess you're right.
I gotta meet someone too. My old man.
I ain't seen him sinceI was a kid.
Don't even know what he looks like.
I just got a letter now and then.
This was always the only address
he gave me to write him back.
He used to be a sailor. He's a janitor
of some building here.
-A janitor?
-Sure.
AndI was thinking, seeing he ain't
done a thing for me in my life...
...he might be willing to stake me with
a room and eats untill could rest up.
ButI ain't expecting much from him.
Give you a kick when you're down,
that's what all men do.
AndI don't suppose he'll turn out
no better than the rest.
Do you hang around this dump much?
Oh, off and on.
Why, maybe you know him, my old man.
Well, it-- lt isn't old Chris, is it?
-Who, old Chris?
-Yeah, Chris Christopherson.
-That's his full name.
-That's him.
Anna Christopherson is my reaI name...
...only out there,I call myseIf
Anna Christie.
-So you know him, huh?
-Oh, I've seen him around here for years.
What kind is he?
Well, he's as fine an old guy
as ever walked on two feet...
...and that goes.
Well, I'm glad to hear that.
Why, you think he'll stake me
to the rest cure I'm after, then?
Surest thing you know. Where'd you
get the idea that he was a janitor?
Well, he wrote me he was himseIf.
He's lying.
He's a captain on a barge.
A barge? What kind of a barge?
Well, coal, mostly.
A coaI barge?
Well, well. If that ain't a swell job...
...to find your long-lost old man
working at.
Oh, gee.
Well, that puts the kibosh
on his giving me a rest.
Why? Couldn't you live on it too?
Who, me? On a dirty coaI barge?
Well, what do you thinkI am?
Well, what do you know about a barge?
Bet you ain't never seen a barge.
That's what comes of him bringing
you up inland where you'd be safe.
Say, his bringing me up,
is that what he tells people?
Well,I sure like his nerve.
Why, he let them cousins keep me on the
farm and work me to death like a dog.
Well, you didn't fall
for that farm life, did you?
I should say not.
I had to slave for all of them.
Was all right till my mother died...
...butI was only a poor relation,
you know...
...and they treated me worse
than they dared treat a hired girl.
Oh, what a life on that farm
out in Minnesota.
With them Swedes, woman-hungry.
One nightI was alone in the house
and one of the sons came back.
After that,I hated them,
so I'd kill them all ifI stayed...
...soI ran away. St. Paul.
Yeah,I overheard Chris saying as how
you was in St. Paul.
-Working, he said.
-Oh, that's no lie.
I went there to work, butI was still a kid.
It's all men's fault,
giving you the wrong start.
I'm just out of the hospitaI two weeks.
The judge gave all of us girls 30 days.
Well, the others didn't seem to mind
being in the cooler much.
ButI couldn't stand it.I went nuts.
I never could stand
being caged up nowhere.
I got good and sick, and they had
to send me to the hospital.
And it was nice there.
I was sorry to leave it, honest.
If my old man doesn't help me...
...it's men again.
Men all the time.
Oh, howI hate them,
every mother's son of them. Don't you?
Well, there's good ones
and there's bad ones, you know.
Now, your old man, old Chris.
Oh, he's a good one, honest.
Well, he'll have to show me.
Wait till he finds out.
Well, you know,
he's kind of simple.
He's got nutty notions.
You know, he thinks that--
He thinks you're working
as a nurse girI in St. Paul.
You know, he thinks that-- He means all
right, honest. He thinks the world of you.
Honest, he does.
Quit your kidding.
Well, as soon asI get rested up...
...I'll clear out and get back
to the old job in St. Paul.
Josephine
Come board the ship
Long time I wait for you
-What's up?
-That's him.
-Who?
-Your old man.
Golly, Larry. That grub, it taste good.
-ls Marthy in back?
-Sure, and another tramp with her.
That's him, you see.
He's coming in here.
Now, brace up.
Oh, hello, old Chris.
Say, listen, I'm gonna blow down to the
barge and pack my duds and beat it.
She's in there. Your Anna.
Yeah, she's just come.
She's waiting for you.
And you treat her right.
She's been sick.
Well....
So long.
Well, so long, kid.I gotta beat it.
I'll see you later.
Anna.
Hello, Father.
She told me it was you.
I just got here a little while ago.
Oh, it's-- It's good for see you
after all them years, Anna.
Well, it's good to see you too.
Anna lilla. Anna lilla.
Oh,I had an awfuI trip getting here.
I'm all in.
Had a hard time finding
this place, too, you know.
I've never been in
New York before, and....
I'm just out of the hospitaI two weeks.
You, Anna? Oh, by golly.
But you feeI better now,
though, don't you?
You look little tired, that's all.
I am...
...tired to death.
I need a long rest.
That's whyI made up my mind
to come and see you.
I thought if you had a place where
maybe, if you didn't mind having me...
...I could rest up for a while. Untill felt
able to get back on the job again.
Oh,I got nice place for rest, Anna.
You rest all you want.
You don't never got to be
nurse girI no more.
You stay with me, by golly.
You're really glad to see me, honest?
Oh, Anna, I'm glad more like
everything for see you,I tell you.
Don't you talk no more about getting job.
You stay with me.
I don't see you for long time...
...and I'm getting old.
I got no one in world but you...
...and I'm going to tell you
about everything...
...and you tell me all thing
what happen to you.
But not here, now.
This ain't no good place for young girlies.
Only no-good sailor fella come here
for get drunk. You come with me.
You need lie down, get a rest.
-Where are you going?
-We go onboard.
-Onboard your barge, you mean?
-Aye.
Well, nix for mine.
Do you think that's a good place
for a young girl? CoaI barge?
Yeah,I think, Anna.
You don't know how nice is on barge.
Tug come, he tow us out on voyage.
You got just water all around.
Sunshine, fresh air, plenty good grub for--
For make you strong, healthy girI again.
You need a rest like that.
You work too hard for young girI already.
You need vacation, eh?
Well, it sounds pretty good,
to hear you tell it.
I'd sure like a trip on the water, all right.
I'll go down with you and have a look.
Maybe I'll take a chance.
Seeing America from a coaI barge,
that's a good one.
We go?
Wait a second. What's the rush?
-Gee, I'm thirsty.
-Oh, I'm sorry, Anna.
What you think you like for drink?
Well, I'll take a....
Oh,I don't know, really.
What have they got here?
I don't think they got much fancy drink
for young girI in this place.
Well, say, ginger ale
or sarsaparilla, maybe.
Well, make it sarsaparilla.
I tell you, Anna, we celebrate,
just this once...
...because we meet after many year.
They got some good port wine.
Now, that's good for you,I think.
lt ain't strong, neither.
One glass, he don't go to your head,
I promise.
-All right. I'll take port.
-I go get it.
Well, who's the blond?
That's Anna, Larry.
-Your daughter, Anna?
-Aye.
Don't you think she's pretty girl, Larry?
Sure, a peach.
You give me drink for take back.
One port wine for Anna.
She celebrate with me just this once.
Small beer for me, please.
Small beer for you?
She's reforming you already.
You bet.
I can't stand it.
I better beat it.
I take back, Larry.
Why, you look a little tired, Anna...
...butI make you take
good, long rest now.
You drink your wine.
That put new life in you.
Skoal, Anna.
You know that Swedish word?
Skoal.
I guessI know that word,
all right, all right.
A bridge, Anna, it's pretty, eh?
Gives you the creeps, though.
It's like a great big spiderweb.
Oh, you're tired, you sick, Anna.
Someday, bridge, he look
awfully pretty to you.
I bet your life those big buildings
make you open your eyes.
Well, it scares me
to think of being up so high.
I bet we look like ants to them.
I bet they can't even see us down here.
On trip back,
I take you up in Woolworth Building.
There you see everything.
I've seen too much already.
You know, Anna, you was
awfuI pretty girl.
I bet you all men see you
fall in love with you, by Jiminy.
You cut that.
You talk just as they all do.
No harm your father talk that way, Anna.
Oh, fine father you are. Like a stranger.
Why didn't you ever
come out west to see me?
I'm sorry, Anna,
but after your mother die...
...I want come see you
end of every voyage...
...but whenI get money
for coming west,I forget.
I get drunk and spend all money.
I don't know why, Anna,
but that's the way with most sailor fella.
That old deviI sea.
She make them crazy fools
with her dirty tricks. ls so.
Well, it's good you got something
to blame it on.
Kind of tough for me, though.
I know, Anna, I'm sorry.
But if you stay with me,I make you glad.
I make you forgive me
for being no-good father.
lt sounds okay with me.
I'll try anything once.
I'm glad you like it here on barge
with your old father, Anna.
Who saidI like it?
Well, you change a lot in one week.
The sea air make you feeI good again, eh?
Maybe.I don't know.
Four bells. What time is that?
Six o'clock.
Funny, all this sea talk.
I'm getting onto the lingo.
Now, there's where you belong,
on a reaI ship like that...
...sailing all over the world.
I do that many year whenI was big fool.
Oh, rats.
Say, was all the men in our family
always sailors?
Yes. All men in our family crazy fools.
My father and my three brothers
is buried at sea...
...lost on sailboat.
Just like your brothers was drowned.
Sailor man is no good, Anna.
They don't never come home.
Don't never do nothing
what good men do.
And sooner or later, that old devil,
she swallow them up.
But she don't gonna got me.
No, by Jiminy, not me.
Beefing about the sea again.
Well, I'm getting soI kind of like it.
Old man?
Father.
Father!
Anna, you was scaredI got hurt.
Oh, gee,I thought you were
overboard, honest.
You been sorry if that old devil,
he got Chris, eh?
Why, sure. Ain't you my father?
Oh, that's a sure thing.
You like me little, maybe?
Can the sentiment, Pa.
I'll fix you a whiskey toddy.
I'll pull off your boots first, though.
Oh, Anna, you make old fella
want to cry.
Nix on the sob stuff now.
Heave, hearty!
Oh, don't go away, Anna,
don't go away.
You was my little girl.
My Anna lilla. Anna lilla.
Anna.
-Anna.
-Yes. HereI am. What do you want?
Why you don't come turn in, Anna?
It's late, it's after four bells.
I like this fog, honest.
lt makes me feeI as ifI was
out of things altogether.
Fog.
That's one of the worst dirty tricks
of that old devil.
Funny.I feeI sort of strange tonight.
Sort of nutty...
...as if I've been living
a long, long time out here in the fog.
I don't know just how to tell you
whatI mean.
But it's like I've come home
from a long visit someplace...
...andI seem to have forgotten
all that's happened.
Like it didn't matter anymore.
You must think I'm off my base.
Oh, Anna,I want always
make you happy.
We fooI that old devil. We sell barge.
And you and me, we live together
in nice little house inland.
lnland? You mean leave the sea?
By golly, we have a little house,
just you and me...
...and maybe sometime comes along
a nice land fella.
You get married. You have kids.
Oh, by Jiminy,
that sure is a pretty picture, Anna.
Maybe.I wanna be with you...
...but somehow
I don't wanna leave the sea.
She's old devil, Anna.
Don't let her get you.
Well, ain't it natural, me loving the sea?
It's in the blood, ain't it?
I think I'm a big fooI for bring you
on this voyage, Anna.
Now you're talking nutty yourseIf.
You act as if you were scared
something was gonna happen.
-Only God know that, Anna.
-Well, then, it'll be God's will...
...like the preachers say,
what does happen.
No. That old devil, she ain't God.
Ahoy!
-What's that?
-Oh, that scare me for a minute.
ls just some fisherman
lose his course in fog.
Sound come from this side.
They come in from open sea.
Ahoy!
What's trouble?
Heave a rope when we come alongside.
-Where are you, you scut?
-This way!
Right you are.
Why don't he stay where he belongs.
Johnson, come and give a hand.
Anna, you go in cabin,
get whiskey, please.
Those fellas will need a drink
for fix them up.
Johnson, come here.
Give me a hand here with this fella.
-What is it, sir?
-They come in from the open sea.
-Must be sailor fellas.
-The open sea?
That old deviI is doing
something again, Johnson.
Three of them there.
-Did you see them there, Johnson?
-Sure, a couple of them is out.
Make fast rope there, you fella.
Right you are. Heave away.
Come in here.
-Johnson.
-Johnson, you get that other fella there.
Right away.
Anna, get whiskey, quick.
These here sailor fellas...
...their steamer got wrecked in storm.
Been five days in open sea.
Johnson brings another fella.
You take whiskey to him.
Take your whiskey, here.
Are these all?
I'll get whiskey inside. Take that to
the man's who's coming onboard now.
What's this tub?
Well, we're safe anyhow,
with the help of God.
Sure, it's me, Matt Burke himseIf,
dreaming again.
You drink this
and you'll find it's no dream.
The deviI with the drink.
But I'll be taking it anyhow.
Sure, I'm needing that.
It's fine stuff.
But it wasn't the drinkI meant
whenI said, wasI dreaming.
Sure,I thought you was some mermaid
out of the sea, come to torment me.
Aye, reaI flesh and blood, deviI the less.
Cut that.
What's a fine, handsome woman
the like of yourseIf doing on this scow?
Never you mind.
You're a great one, honest. Starting right
in kidding after what you've been through.
I'm telling you, but for the strength
and guts in me, we'd be scoffed...
...by the fishes this minute.
Gee, you hate yourseIf, don't you?
But you must come and lie down
and go to sleep.
Lie down and sleep, is it?
But you'll not be thinking
I'm a weak scut.
Sure,I could lick any man on this boat
with one hand tied behind me back.
I could lick all hands on this tub
one by one, tired asI am.
Ain't you the hard guy, though, huh?
But never mind that fight talk.
I'll take your word for what you say.
You're all in, own up to it.
The devill am.
Well, be stubborn, then, for alll care.
AndI must sayI don't care
for your language.
The menI know don't pull rough stuff
when ladies are around.
Ladies! Let you not be making
game of me.
Whisht, now, milady,
it's one of your kisses I'm needing...
...to take the tiredness from me bones.
One kiss, now.
Let go of me, you--!
Oh, gee,I was scared for a moment
I'd killed you.
''Killed you,'' you say?
Faith, it would take more than a bit
of a blow to crack my thick skull.
Glory be, you got a power
of strength in them fine arms of yours.
Forget it. I'm sorry it happened.
Only, you've no right
to be getting fresh with me.
Listen, now, don't go getting
any more wrong notions.
I'm on this barge because
I'm making a trip with my father.
The captain is my father.
Now you know.
I'm sorry.
I'm thinking I'm not good enough
to kiss the shoe soles...
...of a fine, decent girl
the like of yourseIf.
Will you forgive me now
and let's be friends from this out?
I'm thinking I'd rather be friends
with you than anything else in the world.
-Sure.
-God bless you.
lt is a clumsy apeI am.
Sure, it is great powerI have in me hand
and arm, andI do be forgetting it at times.
You're sure strong, all right.
Sure, it is the will of God in it...
...that brought me safe
through the storm to the one spot...
...in the world where you was.
Think of that, now, and isn't it queer?
Anna, you get in cabin, you hear?
Who do you think
you're talking to, a slave?
You need to rest, Anna.
What are you doing here,
you sailor fella?
You ain't sick like others.
You get in forecastle, they give you bunk.
You hurry,I tell you.
But he's sick. He can hardly stand up.
Look at him.
ls it giving me orders you are, me bucko?
Let you look out, then.
Weak asI am,
I can break you in pieces...
...and throw you over the side,
and your crew after you.
I was forgetting, you're her old man.
Sure, I'd not lift a fist to you for the world.
Come inside. You can have my bed
if there is no other place.
That's your dirty trick, old devil...
...but you don't do that,
no, not that whileI live.
Mulligan! Sure, it is myseIf that's hungry.
And a pie, Matt.
Glory be, what doI care
for a stew or a pie?
It's not for food I'm hungry...
-...but for the sight of your face.
-Oh, go on with your blarney, you gasbag.
Now, Matt, look what you've done.
Pick that up. Shame on you.
Sure, her with the face of an angel
and the sting of a wasp.
Oh, so it's darning you're doing.
Shut up.
You've got a voice like a foghorn.
What's this?
Well, what do you think it is?
Well, holding it up this way, it might be
new underdrawers for old Chris.
-Ain't for him, though.
-Oh, ain't it, now?
-For some sweetheart?
-Maybe.
Don't make me jealous,
or I'll burn it up and him in it.
-No. Give it to me.
-You got a guilty look in your eye.
Now, you give it to me, now. You bully.
Now....
Don't!
-Look what you've done, galoot.
-WhenI get ahold of him that wears it...
...I'll pull out an arm and wave you
goodbye with it.
Supper's almost ready.
Well, I've been hungry.
Well, asI was saying to you before....
Stand up, just to measure this sweater.
Sure,I will. On me head or me feet?
Your feet, silly.
lt is only prayer
or paralysis can save you now, Anna.
Well, I'm praying, Matt.
lt is a miracle
if your prayers are answered.
Thanks, Matt. It's for my father. And him
hating to stand up for measurements.
-Will you wear it for my sake?
-Oh, yeah.
lt is a lie in your throat
and you know it.
No, it isn't.
You made it for me
with your own blessed hands.
And I'll wear it when we dock in New
York and take you out for a day's fun.
Oh, no, you won't.
lt won't be finished by then.
I won't go with you.
Make up your mind to that.
-Yes, you'll go with me.
-Oh, no,I won't.
-Just the two of us.
-Oh, no.
Oh, yes. Oh, yes, you will.
Well, you won the capitaI prize, fella.
Help yourseIf.
Anybody else around?
Here we go, boys.
Why don't you test your lungs too, Matt.
I should test them,
with the fine bellows thatI got?
Well, try it.
Faith, that's a woman's game.
Not for a husky like me. You try it, Anna.
No, Matt. You do it.I haven't got
the wind in me that you have.
Hand it over.
Watch me. Sure, I've air enough
in me chest to blow up a balloon.
Well,I don't doubt it.
What do you mean, you don't doubt it?
I was just kidding.
I bet he goes to 40.
Oh, boy.
Step up and roll the sweet mamas
out of their beds.
Make your own sweet mama jealous.
Only 25 cents to see the most
enchanting scene on Coney lsland.
Now there's Lily and Clytie
without any nighties.
Hey, you, step right up.
Give us a good free look at the mamas
in their pretty lace hootenannies.
Wanna keep us
in bed all night, tightwad?
Loosen up, lads. Give us a little tumble.
I'll bet you couldn't hit that target if you
stayed untiI you grew a long, white beard.
-The devill couldn't.
-Come on, Matt.
Go on and try it.
Bet you can't even hit the net.
-Yeah, how about a home run, Babe Ruth?
-Sure,I dare you to.
With one throw,I could knock them
dames off of their bunks.
Go to it, big boy.
Don't overlook me, carrot top.I have the
shape that makes the old men young...
-...and the young men old.
-Attaboy.
-Mama wants Papa.
-Papa wants Mama.
Some mamas too. Now somebody else.
Somebody that packs a mean right.
What we want this time
is a regular he-man.
You shut up or I'll wrap you
around the target.
Don't get sore, big boy.
It's a hot night.
Roll me out of the blanket.
And that be the end to the story
of the whale and the grasshopper.
Oh, Matt, honest,
I ain't ever laughed like this.
-You're funny.
-Sure, I'd think it was blarney...
...if it wasn't meseIf
was making you laugh.
Oh, sure, Anna, you're crazy about me,
and I'm not after blaming you.
You just hate yourseIf, don't you, Matt?
Oyster loaf for the lady, sir.
-I ordered milk for the lady.
-Well, I've got it here.
Well, let's drink to our good health.
Here's to you.
And skoal, Matt, to you and me.
-Hot mustard, Matt?
-I don't need it.
-Pepper?
-Full of it.
-Well, here's something you do need.
-Oh, is that so, now?
Well, all right. But if I'm needing sugar,
I know where to look for that.
Oh, we're goofy, Matt.
Just like a couple of kids.
Sure, Anna, when you're in love,
you ain't got the brains of a tick.
What do you mean, love?
You know whatI mean, Anna.
It's in me eye and
on the tip of me tongue.
A man like me ain't given to loving
a woman. He knows too much about them.
Every color of them,
from here to the China Sea.
The whole lying, cheating smear of them.
Sailors' bait.
When he comes across
a girI like you, Anna...
...that's as clean as a shell.
You're a lucky girI to be hearing
such talk from the lips of Matt Burke...
...him that the women are so crazy over.
Anna, what's come over you?
Oh, nothing.
Sure, don't lie to me, Anna.
You're as stiff as a corpse.
Hello, dearie.
-Well, I'll be--
-Well, she's a friend of mine.
Aren't you, dearie?
I'm afraidI don't remember you.
-She don't remember me.
-Of course she don't, you old scab.
-Beat it, or I'll have you thrown in the brig.
-No, Matt, maybeI do know her.
That old sea cow?
Go on, clear out of here.
You know a nice young girl
never met the likes of you.
A nice young--?
A nice young--
Pure and white as a lily.
Shut up, or I'll choke the wind
out of your gullet.
Oh, Matt, let her alone.
She don't mean nothing by it.
Anna. Anna, darling.
You see what you've done?
You frightened her.
-Go on, clear out of here.
-I'm going, I'm going.
Let her alone.
Don't go.
I was lying, Matt.
I know her and she knows me.
I recognized her the minute
she stepped across the room.
Shut up, kid. You don't have to
spill over for nobody.
You ain't responsible
for what your old man does.
I'll tell you why
she didn't want to talk to me.
Because I'm a tramp, that's why.
And her old man kicked me off the barge
when she come there to live on it.
Yeah, he didn't want any old wharf rat
around a nice young girl.
Well, it ain't so, though, Matt.
She's lying.
Lying, I'm ly--?
Well,I like your nerve,
all right, all right.
Gee, I'm sorryI came here
to speak to you.
lnsulting me. Well, can you beat it?
I'll be toddling along.
I'm glad you found yourseIf
such a nice, friendly gent.
I hope you're happy, kid.
I'm sorryI bothered you, honest, l--
Oh, forget it, Ann.
You only got one life to live.
And it's a...of a life at that.
Say, skipper, you wouldn't stake me
to a quarter, would you?
You know,I haven't had
a drink in a month.
Take it and beat it.
With pleasure, captain.
Well, so long.
Be a good girl, Ann,
no matter how lonesome.
Happy days. Happy days.
The poor old devil.
SometimesI feeI sorry for them.
Come on, Anna. Don't let it get you down.
Sure, the world's full of them.
I know it's a sad sight for a decent
young girI the like of yourseIf, darling.
What would you say, Matt,
ifI told you that...?
Say what, me darling? Tell me what.
Oh, nothing.
Sure,I know what you'll be wanting
to tell me soon, if not this minute...
...that you love me.
Don't be so sure of yourseIf, Matt.
I'm loving nobody.
And you'll be wanting to marry me,
and maybe I'll be accepting you.
Why, Matt.
You want to marry me?
-Honest?
-Sure, I'll marry you.
Only, don't be putting me to too many
tests, orI might change me mind.
I'm tired, Matt.
I wanna go back to the barge.
You-- You think you love
that sailor fella, Anna?
Well, what ifI do?
You think maybe you marry him?
No.
I'm glad you don't marry sailor, Anna.
ls bad for woman.
They don't never see their men
only once in long while.
You sit and wait all alone...
...and when their boys
grow up and go on sea...
...they sit and wait some more.
Any girI marry sailor is crazy fool,
I tell you.
Your mother, she tell you same thing
if she was alive.
Well, that ain't whyI won't marry him.
I'm not thinking about myseIf...
...but about him.
He's such a simple guy, a big kid.
AndI haven't got the heart to fooI him.
You fooI him? Oh, you go crazy,I think.
I've been thinkingI was myseIf
the last few days.
I'll be outside.
I love to watch the ships passing.
When Matt comes along,
tell him whereI am, will you?
All right,I tell him.
Well, God bless who's here.
How's the world treating you
this afternoon, Anna's father?
Oh, pretty good, if it ain't for some fellas.
Meaning me, do you?
Well, if you ain't
the funny old crank of a man.
Where's herseIf?
-Where's Anna, I'm after asking you.
-She gone out to look on boat.
Well, I'll be going out to her.
But beforeI go, I'll take
this chance while we're alone...
...to have a word with you.
And that word is soon done.
I'm marrying your Anna
before this day is out.
You may as well make up
your mind to it, like it or no.
That's easy for saying.
You meanI won't? ls it yourseIf
is after stopping me, do you think?
-I stop it if it come to worst.
-Sure, it isn't trouble I'm looking for.
You're her father. Wouldn't it be a shame
for us to be at each others' throats...
...like a pair of dogs,
andI married to Anna.
So out with the truth, man alive.
What is it you're holding against me at all?
I don't want my Anna for got married.
Listen, you fella. I'm old man.
I don't see my Anna for 1 5 year.
She's alll got in the world.
You think now when she come on first trip,
I want her for leave me alone again?
Sure, let you not be thinking I've no heart
at all for the way you'd be feeling.
Then you do right thing, eh?
You ship away again
and leave my Anna alone.
Say, big fella like you on sea,
he don't need a wife.
He got new girI in every port,
you know that.
Oh, shut up.
Sure, there's a time come to every man,
on sea or land...
...when he's sick of the lot of them cows,
and wearing his heart out to meet up...
...with some fine, decent girl...
...and building a home to call his own,
rearing up children in it.
Sure, Anna's the one woman
in the world for me...
...andI can't live without her now,
I'm thinking.
You think I'm going let her life
be made sorry by you...
...just like her mother's was made by me?
No, she don't marry you.
Not ifI have to kill you first.
Glory be to God, what talk
from a stumpy runt of a man.
lt is queer fooI's blather you have, about
the sea done this and the sea done that.
You ought to be ashamed to be saying
the like, you an old sailor.
I'm hearing a lot from you,
and a lot more that Anna tells me...
...you do be saying to her. I'm thinking
it is a poor weak thing you are.
Not a man at all.
You see if I'm man
maybe quicker than you think.
You know the truth in your heart. The sea
hit you a clout once and knocked you down.
You're not man enough to get up for
another, but you lie there howling murder.
I'd like to see you
in the best of your youth.
-Do whatI done in the storm and after.
-Why, you young fool, you.
ln old days,
whenI was on windjammer...
...I went through hundred storms
worse than that.
Ships were ships then,
and men what sailing them reaI men.
What you got on steamers now?
You got fellas on deck don't know
a ship from a mud scow...
...and below deck, you got fellas
just know how to shoveI coal.
You might as well
work on coaI wagon ashore, you.
ls it throwing insults at the men
in the stokehold you are, you old ape?
One of them is worth any 1 0 squareheads
ever shipped on a windbag.
-You lrish swine.
-So you don't like the lrish, you old baboon?
Sure, it's that you're needing
in your family. An lrishman.
A man of the stokehold
to put guts in it...
...so you'll not be rearing up grandchildren
to be jackasses like yourseIf.
Sure, old men getting childish
shouldn't play with knives.
Faith, I've haIf a mind to hit you a clout
will put sense in your square head.
Keep away from me, now.
Hello, Matt. Are you here already?
Say, what's up? How did that chair
get knocked over?
Oh, Matt, you haven't been fighting
with him, after you promised?
I've not laid a hand on him, Anna.
I told him to his teethI love you.
That's God's truth, and well you know it.
He tell same thing
to girI in every port he goes.
I know it's true, Matt.
Don't you mind what he says.
God bless you.
And thenI saidI thought maybe
you'd have a bit of love for me too.
So you told him that?
MaybeI have. I've been wondering
ifI do love you.
I didn't want to,I must own up to that.
But l--I guessI can't help it,
soI guessI do.
Oh, sure,I do, Matt. What's the use
of kidding myseIf different?
-Sure,I love you.
-God be praised.
AndI haven't ever loved a man
in my life before, never.
Faith, we'll be having a grand, beautiful
life together to the end of our days.
Matt.
-Goodbye, Matt.
-Goodbye, is it?
I'll be coming at you in a second
for more of the same.
Own up like a man
when you're beat fair and square.
Here's me hand to you.
We'll be friends from this out.
No,I don't shake hands with you, fella.
Not whileI live.
The back of me hand to you,
then, if that suits you.
It's a rotten bad loser you are,
deviI mend you.
No,I don't lose.
Anna said she like you little bit.
But you don't hear her say
she marry you,I bet.
No, andI don't hear her say
the sun is shining, either.
-No,I didn't say it, Matt.
-There, you hear?
You're waiting to be asked, you mean?
Well, I'm asking you now.
We'll be wedded this day,
with the help of God.
-You heard whatI said afterI kissed you.
-I don't remember.
I said goodbye.
That kiss was for goodbye, Matt.
What do you mean?
I can't marry you.
We've said goodbye, that's all.
-I knew that was so.
-ls it making game of me you'd be?
It's a queer time to joke with me.
Don't be doing it, for the love of God.
You don't think I'd kid you now.
I'm not joking, Matt.I mean whatI say.
You don't. You can't.
lt is mad you are, I'm telling you.
-No, I'm not.
-What's come over you so sudden?
You were saying you love me.
I'll say that as often as you want me to.
It's true.
But why? What? What is it?
Because...
...it's the best wayI can figure out, Matt.
I've been thinking it over and thinking
it over, day and night, all week.
Oh, don't think it isn't hard
on me too, Matt.
Well, will you tell me what's preventing
this wedding...
...when the two of us has love?
I'm thinking it's listening
to that old fooI you are...
...him hating me, filling your ears
full of lies against me.
Yes, Anna believe me, not you.
She know her old father don't lie like you.
You sit down, do you hear?
Why do you come butting in
and making things worse?
You're like a devil, you are.
HereI was, beginning to like you,
beginning to forget all the things...
-...I've held up against you.
-You ain't got nothing for hold against me.
Haven't l, though? Well, let me tell you.
Matt, I'm surprised at you.
-You didn't think anything he'd said--
-Sure, what else would it be?
Tell me, and don't keep me waiting.
I can't tell you, andI won't.
I've got a good reason,
that's all you need to know.
I can't marry you,
and that's all there is to it.
So for heaven's sake,
let's talk of something else.
No, I'll not.
-ls it married to someone else you are?
-I should say not.
You're like them women
can't make up their minds...
...till they're drove to it.
Well, I'll make up your mind for you.
We've had enough talk.
Let's go to the other room...
...and dress in your best.
We're going ashore.
-She don't do that.
-Where do you get that stuff?
Never mind,
get on with your dressing.
-We'll see who'll win in the end, me or you.
-Stay, Anna.
She will not. She'll do whatI say.
You've had your hold on her long enough.
-It's my turn now.
-Your turn? What amI anyway?
Never mind what you are.
It's what you're gonna be:
Wedded to me.
Come on with your dressing.
-Don't do one thing he say!
-She will!
-I'm her father.
-She will in spite of you.
She's taking my orders
from now on, not yours.
Orders is good.
Never mind now.
We've no time to be wasting.
-Do you hear what I'm telling you?
-No, stay here, Anna!
You can go to blazes, both of you.
You'd thinkI was a piece of furniture.
I'll show you. Sit down.
Sit down, do you hear?
Let me talk for a minute.
You're all wrong, see?
I'm gonna tell you two something,
and then I'm gonna beat it.
I've been meaning
to turn it loose on you...
...every time you get my goat
with your crazy talk...
...about wanting to keep me safe inland.
I wasn't going to tell you,
but you've forced me into it.
Oh, what's the use?
It's all wrong anyway. You might as well
get cured this way as any other.
Don't forget what you said about it not
mattering to you what reasonI got...
...as long asI wasn't married already.
That's me word, and I'll stick to it.
You make me laugh, honest.
Wanna bet you will?
You wait and see.
You was going on as if
one of you had to own me.
But nobody owns me, see,
excepting myseIf.
I'll do whatI please. And no man,
I don't give a darn who he is...
...can tell me what to do.
I ain't asking either of you for a living.
I'll make it myseIf, one way or another.
I am my own boss. Now, put that
in your pipe and smoke it.
-You and your orders.
-I wasn't meaning it that way at all...
...and well you know it.
You've no call
to raise this rumpus with me.
-lt is him, you've a right.
-I'm coming to him.
But you, you did mean it that way.
You sounded just like all the rest.
lt is queer, rough talk, that,
for a decent girI the like of yourseIf.
Decent. Who told youI was?
I'm talking to you now.
I don't want to hear.
You go out your head,I think.
Well, living with you is enough
to drive anyone off their nut.
Your bunk about the farm being so fine.
Didn'tI write you, year after year,
how rotten it was...
...and what a dirty slave
them cousins made out of me?
What did you care? Nothing. Not even
enough to come out and see me.
Your crazy stuff about wanting
to keep me away from the sea...
...don't go down with me.
You just didn't want
to be bothered with me.
-Oh, that ain't so, Anna.
-But one thingI never wrote you...
...it was one of them cousins
that you think is such nice people...
...that started me wrong.
And it was none of my fault.
I hated him and he knew it.
But he was big and strong, like you.
That's whyI ran away from the farm.
That's what made me get a job
as a nurse girI in St. Paul.
You think that was a nice job
for a girl, too, don't you?
With all them nice inland fellas
just looking for a chance to marry me.
They weren't looking for marrying.
You don't say nothing.
Either one of you.
ButI know what you're thinking.
You're just like all the rest.
And who's to blame for it? Me or you?
If you'd been a regular father
and had me with you...
-...things would've been different.
-Don't talk that way.
-I go crazy.I won't listen to you.
-You will listen.
You, keeping me safe inland.
I was no nurse girI the last two years.
I lied whenI wrote you.
I was in a house, that's what.
Yes, that kind of a house.
The kind that sailors like Matt and you
go to in port...
...and your nice inland men too.
And all men.
I hate them,I hate them....
-Oh, it's a lie, Anna, it's a lie....
-So...
...that's what's in it.
I suppose you remember your promise.
No other reason was to count with you
as long asI wasn't married already.
You want me to get dressed
and go ashore, don't you?
Oh, yes, you do.
I suppose ifI tried to tell you
thatI wasn't that no more...
...you'd believe me, wouldn't you?
And ifI told you that just getting out
on this barge and being on the sea...
...had changed me and made me
feeI different about things...
...as if all that I've been through
wasn't me, didn't count...
...it was just like it never happened...
...you'd laugh, wouldn't you?
And you'd die laughing,
I'm sure, ifI told you...
...that meeting you that funny way
that night in the fog...
...and afterwards, seeing that you were
straight good stuck on me...
...had got me to thinking
for the first time in my life.
AndI sized you up as different from
the ones on land, as water is from mud.
I couldn't marry you
with you believing a lie.
AndI was ashamed to tell you the truth.
And now, give me
a bawling-out and beat it...
...likeI can tell you're going to.
Will you believe it...
...ifI tell you that loving you
has made me clean?
It's straight goods, honest.
Oh, yes, you will.
You're just like all the rest.
The rest, is it?
My curse on you. Clean, is it?
Oh, don't, Matt. Get out of here.
Let me alone. Get out of here!
I'll be going. And I'll be
drinking slews of whiskey...
...so to wash that
black kiss of yours off me lips!
And I'd be getting dead, rotten drunk
so I'll not remember you at all!
I'll ship away on a boat to the end of the
world, where I'll never see your face again!
-Oh, don't go. It's better Anna marry you--
-Let go of me, you old ape!
Marry her, is it?
I'd see her dead at me feet first.
I'm shipping away out of this,
I'm telling you.
My curse on you,
and the curse of all the saints.
-I go ashore too.
-Not after him,I tell you.
Don't you dare.
Oh,I go for get drink.
I'm driving you to drink too, huh?
You wanna get drunk
so you can forget, like him.
Aye. You thinkI like hear
them things? Oh, Anna.
Anna,I think you wasn't that kind of girl.
You want me to beat it, don't you?
You don't want me here
disgracing you,I suppose.
Oh, no, no, Anna. You stay here.
lt ain't your fault,I know that.
It's that old deviI do this to me.
lt was all right on barge,
with just you and me.
Then she bring that lrish fellow in fog.
That fella, he don't
never come, you don't...
...never tell me them things.
I don't never know.
Then everything is all right.
Oh, that dirty deviI sea.
Oh, what's the use?
Go ashore and get drunk.
You wait here, Anna?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Maybe I'll get drunk too. Maybe I'll....
0h, what do you care whatI do?
Go on and beat it.
It's foggy outside.
Oh, God.
-What's the trouble? Feeling sick?
-lnside my head feels sick.
Oh, Anna, you think maybe sometime
you forgive me, Anna?
-I'll forgive you right now.
-Oh, Anna lilla.
Oh, don't bawI about it.
There ain't nothing to forgive anyway.
lt ain't your fault, it ain't mine.
lt ain't his, neither.
I fix everything all right
for you and me, Anna.
Yes?
Then you and me will stick together?
We'll work for each other
and help each other, huh?
-What is it you fixed?
-Well,I sign on steamer Londonderry.
SaiI for Cape Town tomorrow.
Oh, Anna,I only bring you bad luck.
That's how you fix me, is it?
Well,I think that old deviI get me back...
...maybe she leave you alone, then.
Oh, can't you see that you're doing
the same thing that you've always done?
Can't you see that?
Oh, what's the use of talking?
You ain't right.
I'll never blame you anymore.
Oh, Anna.
You forgive me, sure?
SurelyI do. You ain't to blame.
You're just what you are, like me.
And you, you let me
kiss you once again, eh?
-Oh, sure, no hard feelings.
-Oh, Anna lilla.
I can't say it, Anna.
I thinkI go lie down, go to sleep.
Oh, that booze, he don't go well, Anna.
I think I'm never going to drink again.
I can't stand this much longer.
What amI waiting for, anyhow,
like a darn fool?
Anna?
-Anna?
-Yes, what do you want?
Don't say it.I know what's in your mind.
Yes, that's whatI was,
and that's what I'm going back to.
I'd kill you first. And finish it up.
It's a dog's lifeI been living
sinceI found out what you are.
Oh, why don't you leave me alone.
Go away.
Don't you see I'm licked? What do you
want to keep kicking me for?
Don't you deserve the worst I'd say,
God forgive you?
All right, maybeI do. But don't rub it in.
Why haven't you done
what you said you were going to?
Ship away to the other side of the earth,
where you don't have to see me.
-I have.
-What?
You're going away, honest?
I signed on, drunk asI was,
and she's sailing tomorrow.
-Where is she going? Far away?
-Cape Town. lt is at the end of Africa.
That's far for you.
-What's the boat's name?
-The Londonderry.
The Londonderry?
Oh, this is too much.
Faith,I don't blame you
for laughing at me.
True, it is the fooI of the worldI am
to come back to talk to you at all.
Oh, what's the use? What's the use of
me talking? What's the use of anything?
Anna....
Anna, ifI could only be believing
I was the only man in the world...
...ever you had love for,
I could be forgetting the rest, maybe.
Are you trying to accuse me
of being in love...
...really in love, with them?
You fool, you.
I've stood enough from you.
Love them, is it?I hated them,I tell you.
And may God strike me dead,
and my mother too, if she was alive...
...if I'm not telling you the honest truth.
Oh, sure, Anna, ifI could only
be believing you, now.
Why, Matt, you've got to believe it.
What canI do? What willl do
to prove to you I'm not lying?
Anna, would you--? Would you be willing
to swear an oath, a terrible, fearfuI oath?
Oh, sure,I will, Matt, on anything.
Would you swear on this?
Oh, sure. Give it to me.
lt is a cross given to me by me mother,
God rest her soul.
And I'm telling you,
it has great power in it.
And I'm warning you now,
if you swear on this...
...it is me old woman herseIf who'd
be looking down on you from heaven...
...and praying the saints to put a curse
on you if she hears you swear a lie.
I wouldn't have the nerve,
honest, Matt, if it was a lie.
But it's the truth,
andI ain't scared to swear it.
Give it to me. What do you
want me to swear? You say it.
Swear I'm the only man in the world
ever you felt love for.
I swear it.I swear it by God.
And may the blackest curse of God
strike you if you're lying.
strike me if I'm lying.
Oh, glory be to God,
I'm after believing you now.
-Now what's the matter?
-ls it Catholic you are?
-No, why?
-Oh, God pity me.
Sure, it's some deviI's treachery in it.
You swearing on a Catholic cross,
and you one of the others.
-Well, don't you believe me, Matt?
-Oh, but if it ain't a Catholic you are....
I ain't nothing, Matt.
What's the difference?
Didn't you hear me swear?
I'm afraidI love you, God forgive me,
no matter what you are.
I'd be going mad if I'd not be having you.
I'd be killing the world.
We'll be wedded this day.
And we'll be happy, the two of us,
in spite of the devil.
Well, we gotta have a drink on this,
my good man.
-Blast you.
-That's the way to talk.
Oh, Matt, it's time for you two
to kiss and make up.
You'll be shipmates
on the Londonderry, you know.
-Shipmates? Has himseIf--?
-Aye, and I'm boatswain on her.
The devil!
You'd be shipping away to sea
and leaving her alone again, will you?
It's all right, Matt. That's where
he belongs, andI want him to go.
You've gotta go too.
We'll need the money.
And as for me being alone, why,
that runs in the family...
...and I'll get used to it.
I'll get a house somewhere and I'll make
a regular place for you two to come back.
And now you'll drink
and be friends, huh?
Sure.
-Here's luck to you.
-Skoal.
Well, you'll not be lonesome long.
I'll see to that, God willing.
Sure as himseIf will be having
a grandchild riding his foot,I tell you.
-Maybe twins.
-Oh, quit your kidding.
ls it any religion at all you have,
you and your Anna?
Well, in the old country,
we was Lutherans.
Lutherans, is it?
Oh, then I'm damned entirely.
Oh, well, what's the difference?
lt is God's will anyhow.
It's queer, you and me
shipping on same boat that way.
That ain't right.
It's that funny way old deviI sea
do her worst dirty tricks.
Aye, is so.
Faith, I'm afraid you've the right of it
for once, deviI take you.
Why, gee, Matt, you ain't
agreeing with him, are you?
Come on. Here's to the sea,
no matter what.
Be a game sport, man. Drink to that.
Fog, fog all time.
You can't tell where you was going.
Only that old deviI sea.
She knows.
[ENGLlSH]