In 1985, during
the course of the
work undertaken to
irrigate the Gobi desert.
A strange fragment
of rock was discovered.
Several remarkable features
of this rock attracted the
attention of the scientists
engaged on the project.
Research revealed
that it contained a spool.
Further analysis
showed the material to
be extraterrestrial in origin,
and not of human manufacture.
Where did it come from?
Then, somebody remembered
that in June 1908, in Siberia,
an explosion had occurred
equivalent in force to a hydrogen bomb.
An explosion visible
within a radius of 350 miles.
At the time it was thought to have
been caused by a giant meteor.
Seventy seven years later,
an international
expedition tried to determine
the trajectory and
the point of impact,
and to find some debris of what
was called the Tongu meteor.
Shortly afterwards, under the auspices of
the World Federation for Space Research,
scientist meet to celebrate
the anniversary of the
establishment of the first
space station on the moon.
Professor Harringway,
from the United States
makes a public statement
about the famous meteor.
Our calculations indicate,
confirmed also by the results
recently transmitted to us
by our colleagues on Luna 3,
that the mysterious Tongu
meteor was really a spaceship
from another planet,
which exploded in
the air before landing.
This hypothesis stimulated
scientific thought throughout the world.
Reporters of every
nation are waiting to hear
what the nuclear physicist
Professor Orloff has to say.
Professor Orloff, is this another
hoax of the flying saucer variety?
And what about this spool
that was found in the desert
some 350 miles from
the crater of the explosion.
How do you explain
that, Professor Orloff?
Oh, I believe there
was a grave emergency.
When the rockets, normally used
for deceleration, refused to function
the captain of the spaceship
decided to save what he considered
was most valuable.
I'm referring naturally to
the spool which may contain
a document of prime importance
in an unknown language.
Recorded apparently
by a magnetic process.
An international
committee of expert linguists
was offered access to the
world's largest computer,
to try to decipher
this strange language.
This is Dr. Tchen Yu.
Not only is he one of the world's
leading authorities on languages,
but also his biological work
is of immense importance.
Humanity is in debt to
him for the technique of
transforming inorganic
substances into foodstuffs.
He directs the
committee with world
famous mathematician
Professor Sikarna,
whose work rivals
even that of Einstein.
In the astrophysical domain
we've made rapid progress,
and although we haven't
deciphered the mysterious
message, we have determined
the ship's launching base.
At the moment there
can be no doubt.
This spaceship
was launched within our
solar system, I can even say
that it was definitely launched
from within the path of our planet.
Now, since there can
be no life on Mercury,
there is only one other planet
that it could have come from.
I am referring to the
Earth's sister planet,
Venus, the morning star.
Listen!
The elements existing on Earth.
That's right.
It certainly is a chemical physical
analysis of the atmosphere and
What's that, sir?
What we have just heard
are the first words of the
inhabitants of another
planet, a cosmic document.
Yes.
Yes, but
it's unfortunate that the
magnetic spool was damaged
through the effect of
the high temperature
which prevailed aboard the cosmic
vessel at the time of the crash.
That's the reason we've
only heard a part of the text.
We must try to find a
method to renovate the rest.
First we'll immerse the
spool in a chemical catalytical
medium, and after that,
subject it to radiation.
Tchen Yu.
Yes, that's a very good idea.
All that we have
learned indicates that on
Venus there is a highly
developed life form.
Yet, I'm wondering
why Venus stays silent.
It's very surprising.
Now we know a
little of this language.
We must,
at every cost,
communicate with her.
I agree with you. It's high
time we made an attempt.
Well then, I'd like to
propose a course of action.
I think the most
logical thing to do,
would be to request
that our government's
consent to train all the
radio and radar stations
of the world on Venus.
Polar station calling Moon
space station, attention please.
Luna 3.
Attention please, Luna 3.
Thank you.
This is station Luna 3.
I'll keep it in mind.
Station Luna 3 calling Earth.
No replies yet from Venus.
Our signals are reaching the
planet, but so far there's no reply.
We'll keep you informed.
- Good morning, my friends.
- May I please have an interview?
This afternoon I have news of
the utmost importance to announce.
As you probably know already,
our most modern spaceship,
the Cosmostrator, is now
completed, and ready to set
forth on our exploration of space.
The World Federation for
Space Research has decided
to change the destination
of the Cosmostrator.
Instead of sending her to
Mars, she will be directed
toward the planet Venus.
Oh, that's great news, isn't it?
Have you any idea as to
the date of the take-off?
One more question if
you don't mind, professor.
Do you think there's
anybody living on Venus?
Did you manage to
make contact with Venus?
No, my friends, Venus is
silent, but we'll soon discover why.
And who's going with you?
Well, let me present
some of the other
scientists who will take
part in this expedition.
They are all
first-class specialists.
Chosen from among the most
qualified in their particular fields.
They, with others who are coming,
will form the crew of Cosmostrator 1.
Well, all the units of propulsion
are in perfect working order.
Well, that's fine. The crew can
now attend to their personal affairs.
We'll start late tomorrow night.
We'll fly following the
hyperbolic trajectory.
- Good, I'll make a last check.
- See you later, Durand.
Talua.
Will you please make a
thorough recheck of the radar.
Right away, professor.
This is Intervision calling the world.
We have just showed you the preliminary
tests of the Cosmostrator's rockets.
Arriving now is Brinkmann.
The first Amercan spaceman
to land on the Moon.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have an important
announcement to make.
Intervision is going to
present you minute by minute,
the historic launching of
the Cosmostrator.
We know very well how much
you'd like to be here with us.
Unfortunately, that's impossible.
The only ones admitted
are those directly concerned
with the countdown and
final blastoff of the rocket.
So I will try to describe in detail
everything that's taking place.
Intervision will bring to you the
wonderful story of this great event.
Ah, but here come the
first members of the crew.
Among them is Professor
Durand, the chief engineer.
He's a French scientist, well
known for his work on robots.
- Thank you.
We'll load the Crawlercopter
later on in the evening.
That's of course if it's alright
with you. - Yes, of course.
I've checked out your
electronic equipment. - Good.
Professor Durand,
report from Station A,
- your celestial charts are ready.
- Thank you.
Hello, Durand.
- Oh, Durand, I'm glad to see you again.
- So am I.
Still working as hard?
How about showing me
your latest creation in robots,
I hear it's a masterpiece.
Around here we have
nothing but masterpieces.
Omega.
Come here, Omega.
Omega, what's the weather
report for the next 10 hours?
The barometer will rise 4 millibars.
Four millibars, [??] and clear.
Well, that's fantastic.
- Your latest invention?
- Oh, nothing special.
- Just a small gadget.
- You're a lot too modest, Durand.
What else does it do?
He reacts to stimuli
in his environment,
evaluates them with
his electronic brain.
I recently managed to give
Omega an elementary memory.
Wonderful.
Perhaps he might consent
to play chess with me.
Why of course. Why shouldn't he?
Oh, Harringway.
The specially picked crew of the
Cosmostrator have reached Urania.
Eight of them, scientists,
mathematicians, and astrophysicists.
Seven men, and
and a woman.
She's the physician
of the expedition,
and has already spent
two years on Luna 3.
Sumiko.
Brinkmann.
Have I changed that much?
I don't know. I've got it! Your hair
used to hang down to your waist.
- Mr. Brinkmann.
- Yes.
- You forgot this.
- Oh, thank you.
Robert Brinkmann.
The man who's always
forgetting something.
I have a reputation for that.
You're right.
But there are things
I'll never forget.
No, Brinkmann.
On a voyage of this kind,
there'll be no room
for excess baggage.
Dr. Sumiko Ogimura.
Thirty hours left.
Thirty hours and the
Cosmostrator will blastoff
into the unknown.
Now we will leave the air.
In the next few hours the crew
of 8 picked for the Cosmostrator
will be unable to
communicate with the world.
They are going into a
state of artificially induced
sleep till the time comes
for them to take off.
This is to make sure
that they will be in good
physical condition
for the effort to come.
This is Intervision.
Good afternoon.
Brinkmann.
In 2 minutes you'll be asleep
like all your kind.
Whether you want to or not.
You'll be able to see
and hear your heart.
I'm very glad you're
coming with us, Sumiko.
That way, I'll be near you.
Your heartbeat is normal.
Sumiko.
My heart is...
No, Brinkmann, no.
No, please, we mustn't
speak of that, ever.
Goodnight, Robert.
It's time for you to
sleep too, Dr. Sumiko.
Yes, you're right.
This is Intervision.
Intervision calling the world.
It won't be long now
until the blastoff.
Tension is mounting among the
scientists and technicians on the base
as zero hour approaches.
Everything is ready.
All we're waiting
for is the crew.
And here they are.
Interviews of the
crew are finished.
They are now boarding the vehicles
which will take them to the Cosmostrator.
Time check.
Fifty one.
Fifty two.
Fifty three.
Fifty four.
Fifty five.
Fifty six.
Fifty seven.
Fifty eight.
Fifty nine.
Sixty.
Okay.
Rockets primed,
ready for blastoff.
Breathe calmly.
Relax.
Don't tense up.
Ignition system ready.
Ten seconds.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
- Four.
- Stand by.
Three.
Two.
One.
Zero.
Luna 3 calling Urania, have
Cosmostrator on our radar screens.
Appearance normal.
Feeling alright?
No ill effects, huh?
Riding the clouds.
At over second cosmic velocity,
we've left them way behind us.
I'm going to loosen this
belt, it's uncomfortable.
Hey, be careful. Don't forget there's
no gravity. We're in free fall now.
Durand,
switch on the artificial
gravity field, will you?
Orloff, careful.
I'm pushing the button.
That was a dirty trick.
Cosmostrator calling Luna 3.
Come in, Luna 3.
This is Luna 3.
We are receiving you well.
Over and out.
Hello, Luna 3, we
hear you loud and clear.
Minus two.
Plus five.
Course normal.
Our course is exactly
hyperbolic, no deviation.
We are passing within
1200 miles of you.
This is Luna 3, we have
established visual contact with you.
That's the Sinus Roris crater.
On the top of it is Luna 3.
There's the solar reflector.
They're signaling us.
That's where her husband fell.
I brought him back to the
camp, but he was already dead.
We were friends.
You know,
Sumiko is a wonderful women.
This is luna 3.
Have picked up unexpected
swarms of meteorites on our radar.
Their present trajectory
shows that they may
cross your path and
be very dangerous.
We are receiving you. Over.
Here are the trajectory
coordinates and orbital velocity.
Alpha X, seven degrees
two minutes.
Beta epsilon.
Forty eight degrees
forty two minutes.
Listen, I've had an
extremely urgent message
from Luna 3, a
meteorite warning.
Professor Sikarna, here's
the latest meteorite report.
Alpha X, 7 degrees, 2 minutes.
Beta Epsilon, 48
degrees, 42 minutes.
A meteorite swarm should
reach us in 48 hours at the latest.
That is if there are
no orbit fluctuations.
Keep close radio
contact with Luna 3.
Cosmostrator calling Luna 3, have
received your meteorite warning,
will be sending you regular coordinates
of our course, so stay in close contact.
This is the beginning
of my personal logbook.
There's no one in the nerve
center of the Cosmostrator.
The computer is
keeping us on our course.
In case of unforeseen
circumstances,
it can take immediate
decisions to alter our speed
or direction.
This electronic
brain will be our pilot
for the next 30 days.
Because no human being
could handle the immensely
complex machines of
the spaceship by himself.
Up to now,
we have covered a
distance of two million
six hundred thousand miles.
Doctor Ogimura is noting
our reactions carefully,
and keeping close check
on our health and well-being.
The special liquid food which can easily
be absorbed in a state of no gravity,
is proving very
successful with all of us.
Our chief engineer spends most
of his time in his machine shop,
testing his automates
over and over again.
It is thanks to them,
and to the fact that they
are in perfect running order,
that we are relieved
of many tiresome tasks.
Our expert in cybernetics
has to be everywhere.
He's one of the key
men of the expedition.
Professor Sikarna devotes all his
time to the message from Venus.
He and Tchen Yu are trying
to decipher the damaged spool,
which means they spend
long hours at the Marax.
The electronic brain is
working night and day,
but no one can be sure
what the result will be.
Harringway, our commander, is
keeping a constant check on our course.
Your computer
was active last night.
It switched the rockets
on for nearly 17 seconds.
Perhaps to avoid
the meteor swarm.
We won't be running
into it till tomorrow.
It looks like your automats
don't have the same
idea that you do.
Professor Orloff is an
enthusiastic chess player.
It has beaten all of us, but I think
he's found his master in Omega.
King-G8.
King-E6.
It's amazing.
He plays his
endgame wonderfully.
I thought that I had got him, but
you see he's put his king on E6.
And I'm forced into
the corner at H8.
King-E7.
Check mate next move.
That is the tenth
match that I've lost.
I should give up, I guess.
I would suggest that you
make an improvement in Omega.
Oh, really.
If he only had a heart,
he would let Orloff
win once in a while.
Don't you think you
could be able to do that?
Just a little bit
of heart, Durand.
Meteorites!
Brinkmann, switch on
the emergency gyros!
Brinkmann, see if Tchen Yu
and Sikarna are alright.
How could this happen?
I thought that the
Cosmostrator was
able to avoid meteor
swarms, automatically.
Well, she didn't react
quickly enough,
she was regulated to a
shower of under mass 8.
That was why we had to
switch on the emergency gyros.
Orloff.
How much course deviation?
Twelve degrees.
Seventeen minutes.
Our speed?
Constant, 8.2 miles a second.
I estimate the principal
swarm will be on us soon.
If we continue at maximum
speed, it'll mean disaster.
Cut the motors!
We're going to decelerate.
The braking motors
aren't working.
What's the matter, Durand?
A meteor fragment has
damaged the deceleration unit.
We'll have to go outside and
try and repair it, right away.
I'll go at once.
How long before the
main swarm hits us?
I can't say, it may be
on us any second now.
Brinkmann, will you help me?
Professor Sikarna,
Tchen Yu, are you alright?
No bones broken.
That's fine.
Please give me our
present deviation,
direction coordinates,
and corrected course.
Watch out.
Everybody fasten your belts.
Stand by.
The principal swarm's in sight.
Is it safe to start
the motors yet?
Repair is completed.
Durand's back.
Cosmostrator calling Luna 3.
The meteor swarm has past.
Everything okay on board.
Three weeks have gone
by since we left the Earth.
We should reach
Venus in about ten days.
In spite of our enormous speed,
the stars seem to
hang motionless.
Due to all types of disturbances
caused by the planet,
radio contact with Earth
is no longer possible.
Nothing.
Too much interference.
I can't hear a thing.
Keep trying.
Alpha X.
Thirty two degrees,
eight minutes.
Beta Y.
Seven degrees.
What are you doing.
I'm making a heart for Omega.
Ten consecutive defeats
are driving our friend crazy.
I want him to enjoy
his favorite game.
I would like you to do
something also for me.
It would be nice to see
you eat occasionally.
I swear not to forget anymore.
Sikarna said exactly
the same thing.
Professor.
What do you want?
No, please, not now!
Your health is
my responsibility,
and you haven't eaten for days.
I haven't a second to spare.
Sumiko.
You mustn't insist.
He's nervous.
He's having a very
hard time with that spool.
You understand.
Knight-E6.
Check.
He doesn't like that.
King-B8.
Mate!
Congratulations.
You've won at last.
A neat classical end play.
I think you deserve to win.
He plays a good game,
he's not very easy to beat.
But I did it at last.
Man has defeated the machine.
Yeah, too much heart.
- Want to try?
- Why not?
Will you all come to
the Marax, please?
Perhaps it's the
cosmic document.
We have finally deciphered
the last part of the spool.
It gives complete meaning
to the cosmic document.
I will translate.
We will initially
subject the planet to
a very intense
bombardment of radiation.
The conquest and occupation of
the Earth will then present no difficulty.
When the ionization
intensity has fallen by one half,
the final extermination
phase can start.
This can only mean,
an attack, against are planet.
An invasion by the
inhabitants of Venus.
The cosmic document was
not intended for us to read.
It's a cold blooded
blueprint of destruction.
We must inform the Earth!
I'll try and make contact!
- Wait, Talua!
- No, let him try.
Will it do the Earth any good
to know what we know?
The Earth is in danger,
we must warn them!
No.
Our planet was in peril before they
discovered the spool and nothing happened.
That's no argument, as we haven't
any idea how the Venusians
calculate time.
If the Earth knew of the
terrible danger threatening her.
Unrest and even hysteria
would spread like wildfire.
From pole to pole the whole
world would be in a panic.
No.
No, Orloff.
I'm convinced you're wrong.
For years and years
the whole of the human
race faced the danger
of an atomic war. -Yes.
And they survived.
Not through ignorance,
but through knowledge.
Because they knew
what the danger was.
No.
There won't be a panic.
Tchen Yu, don't
you agree with me?
I'm sure that if we meet
the inhabitants of Venus,
we'll be able to
convince them
that it will be folly
to start that war.
Talua!
Try to contact the Earth.
I can't get through, too
much disturbance from Venus.
Our signals are distorted.
The Earth won't hear us.
Well, what do you say?
Should we turn back to Earth.
No.
Ach! Nonsense.
Return?
No.
Never.
Uh-uh.
Durand, our speed?
Thirty one thousand
miles per hour.
- In 3 days we'll reach Venus.
- Good.
Talua, check our course.
Orloff.
The latest readings.
Gamma radiation
increasing steadily.
I'll recheck the neutron count.
Five thousand miles.
After only 31 days of flight, we
have nearly reached our destination.
All our efforts to
communicate with the Earth
via Luna 3 have
been unsuccessful.
We have started to decelerate
by means of our rocket motors.
Professor Harringway
is guiding the ship
into an elliptical orbit
around Venus.
We are now a satellite
of this silent planet.
We are still
trying, but in vain,
to establish radio contact
with her inhabitants.
A thick wall of clouds
surrounds the planet.
Three thousand
five hundred miles.
First analysis Venus atmosphere:
Twenty seven
percent carbon dioxide,
Fourteen percent, formaldehyde.
No oxygen. Atmosphere poisonous.
Now, we're faced
with a difficult decision.
As you know, we can
only land and take off once.
No point in taking any
unnecessary chances.
So one of us has got
to go ahead as scout.
2,000 miles.
We're close enough now,
I'll go in the Crawlercopter.
Okay, Brinkmann.
You've got to try and
find a landing place for us.
We'll stay in orbit at 150
miles altitude, alright?
The Crawlercopter's ready.
One thousand five hundred miles.
- Well.
- Now, let's don't be formal.
Action stations!
Action stations, everyone!
Seven hundred and fifty miles.
Stand by.
We are now entering
the atmosphere of Venus.
Attention!
We're flying at
300 miles altitude.
Present speed is
4.3 miles a second.
Are you ready, Brinkmann?
Alright, let her go.
Release!
Brinkmann, hello!
Hello, Brinkmann.
Hello.
What's the matter
with his receiver?!
I'm not getting you.
There's something wrong with
your receiver, can you hear me now?
I can't understand you, something's
wrong with your transmitter.
Talua, what's the matter
with our transmitter?
Heavy electrical disturbance.
We're completely blocked out.
Hello.
Brinkmann!
What is it, Brinkmann?
Harringway, can you hear me?
I'm now at 1500
feet, visibility nil.
Radar indicates that the
surface is extremely mountainous.
I can't see anything, I'm completely
surrounded by thick clouds.
Wait a minute.
Yes! I can see land.
I can see land!
Hello! Hello!
Cosmostrator, I can't hear you!
I'm landing. Here she goes!
Brinkmann is not receiving us.
I can't make contact.
Our altitude?
Twenty four thousand feet.
Omega, you take the lead.
Go on.
I'm right behind you.
I don't understand.
I'm puzzled by these strange flashes
of light which we keep seeing.
They're bursting all around us.
What do you make
of them, Orloff?
In my opinion,
the atmosphere in
this area is ionized.
- But what's the cause?
- Atomic radiation!
Then that means that
they're attacking us.
And Brinkmann!
We must fly lower.
We must get below
this bank of clouds
if we want to establish
contact with Brinkmann.
It's the only way.
Brinkmann calling Cosmostrator,
please answer me, over.
Omega.
Hello. Answer me.
Be careful!
Danger!
Go on, Omega.
Intense
radiation.
Eight curries.
How long can we stay here?
Eight minutes maximum.
Turn back, Omega.
Cosmostrator.
Cosmostrator!
I don't hear you!
Hello! Hello!
You hear me?
This blasted radioactive forest
won't let radio waves through.
Go on, Omega.
Go on.
Keep going.
Keep on!
Hold it, Omega.
They're attacking us.
Cosmostrator!
Do you hear me?!
The Crawlercopter's exploded!
A flash!
Did you see that?
What was it?
I don't know.
The computer shows a pressure
wave, apparently an explosion.
Distance, 120 miles.
Brinkmann.
Or, it could be a signal
from the Venusians.
We'd better land at
once as best we can.
Talua,
make a careful
check on our position.
And try to contact
Brinkmann again.
Omega, back here, quickly!
Stand by.
Deceleration rockets.
Thrust.
His Crawlercopter exploded.
Poor old Brinkmann.
There's the cause.
There's a high tension
line underground.
Durand, get the
crawlers out of the way,
or the next time
the voltage mounts
exactly the same
thing will happen to us.
Omega!
Brinkmann, we
thought you were dead!
Ha ha, I was lucky.
You might have chosen
a better place to land.
Why, what do you mean?
There's a high
tension line over there.
Now, your machine blew
up just because you landed
right on top of that
surface power line.
All we have to
do is to follow it,
and it will probably lead us
to the inhabitants of Venus.
There's no point
in trying to do that.
I've already found the
inhabitants of Venus.
And I've brought one
of them back for you.
What is it?
I wonder if it
is a form of life.
I'll investigate at once.
Alright, Tchen Yu.
And while he's doing that
let's go and try
to follow that line.
Okay.
Omega.
Come on.
Crawler, please come in.
We're following the power line.
Something very strange here.
A white sphere
that looks like a
an immense golf ball.
It's incredible!
Do you think it's
a machine, Orloff?
Well, I can't say yet.
I don't know.
Everything here is so strange.
It's as if we're trying to decipher
a book in an unknown language.
Let's hope that soon
we'll be able to read it.
Then perhaps we'll understand.
Orloff, let me know when
you've got your instruments ready.
I'll need all the
figures I can get.
Okay, Sikarna.
Good. Thank you.
Talua, stay in close
contact with us.
Very well, professor.
I am looking at Venus on the
observation screen of the Cosmostrator.
Everything is strangely quiet.
Is this the calm
before the storm?
Why don't the Venusians answer?
Or are these metallic insects
really the masters of this planet?
Tchen Yu is
working day and night
to solve the mystery of
these strange creatures.
We have investigated
your strange inhabitants.
They're completely harmless.
They're not a form of life.
When I think how
scared I was in that hole.
Your discovery is more
significant than you think.
I put one of the micro
crystals in the Marax.
Listen.
Yes.
Those were the
voices of the Venusians.
I would say that these
strange metallic insects
had a way of storing sound
in their crystalline nuclei.
Are you trying to tell us
that the Venusians used these insects
to record both speech and sound?
- That's right.
- But that's fantastic.
Yes, but it's true.
Well, that would
mean that the hole
which Brinkmann fell into,
is a chamber of archives.
Containing some of the records
of this planet.
But then where can
the inhabitants be?
They certainly saw our spaceship
land, they couldn't have missed it,
yet nothing happened.
Nothing at all.
And my machine blowing up,
you call that nothing?
I need more figures.
More data!
And especially, more
of those metallic insects.
The research program
is going according to plan.
We are all fascinated
by the vitrified forest.
But our spacesuits are so heavy
that working outside
the ship is difficult.
The investigation of the power
lines leading to the white sphere,
and measurement of tension
changes is done by oscillograph.
The storms which whip across
Venus only make the work harder.
That's where the
lines lead to, alright.
There's no doubt.
That's it.
Tchen Yu was collecting samples
of the sand carried by the storm.
Sometimes they are radioactive.
Sometimes they are not.
He is searching
for traces of life.
The long Venusian night
is always preceded
by a violent storm.
Then the outside work must stop.
And we spend our time studying
what we have found so far.
Do you think this vitrified
forest is a biological formation?
Why not?
It could come from
a dried-up seabed.
You're wrong.
It's not a natural formation.
Professor Sikarna has been feeding
figures and data into the electronic brain.
He now has some conclusions.
He says that the vitrified forest
is an enormous energy projector,
capable of destroying
all life within a radius
of millions of miles.
Then it was built by the
inhabitants of Venus.
Yes.
This vitrified forest was made
to be a weapon of aggression.
But then something
went unexpectedly wrong.
Perhaps they decided to disarm.
I'm afraid it was
more serious than that.
The metal insects
you found for us,
show us something
very significant.
That's very interesting.
Go on, tell us more,
Professor Sikarna.
I do not yet have all the facts.
But I think that a terrible
catastrophe took place on Venus.
I reach a certain stage,
and I can't get any
further. It's chaotic.
It's like,
it's like everything was broken.
Now, if there really
was a catastrophe,
which changed the
face of the whole planet.
Then it was so huge
a catastrophe as to be
absolutely beyond our
powers of comprehension.
We can only solve this problem,
by means of further
systematic research.
Take this great white sphere,
to which all these
power line lead,
and whose function
we don't understand.
It appears to be
a giant transformer unit.
Or else it is a
a force field generator!
Another strange thing
is that there is periodic
tension in the main power line.
I would even suggest
that there might still be
Venusians inside the sphere,
who have survived the
colossal catastrophe
that befell their planet.
They could still be trying
to send an SOS
to another station.
What should we do?
We must go out and explore.
We'll follow the main power
line to the other at end. - Yes.
Calling the Cosmostrator.
We have been driving
for nearly 7 hours now.
We are following the energy line
and so far we haven't
found a trace of life.
This power line's got
to end somewhere.
Doctor Harringway,
shall we keep going?
Yes.
We're still going forward.
Keep on following
us and watch out.
What's that?
I don't know, they're
not natural forms.
They must have been
buildings of some sort.
There must have been as
high a temperature here
as on the sun.
And every living
thing was destroyed
by an incredible catastrophe.
What are you thinking, Sumiko?
Of the damage.
Come.
The power line goes in here.
This must be the entrance.
Let's follow it.
I agree with you.
Come on, Omega, we're going in.
Look, Venus and the Earth,
and their orbits around the sun.
Perhaps it's a model for
instructing space pilots.
No, it probably has
a deeper significance.
Over here, there's a shaft.
Looks like one of the
Venusian nerve centers.
A huge control room.
But who was servicing it?
Since it's apparent
that this whole
installation is
still under tension.
Omega.
What is it?
Beats me.
Strange, what could it be?
It might be the
missing power source.
Look at those bubbles.
Could be a kind of organic life.
Omega, stop!
He's coming after us. Look!
Up the ramp, Sumiko. Quick!
Sumiko, I'm coming!
Hold on to me, Sumiko.
- Don't panic, Sumiko!
- We'll find a way out.
Don't shoot,
Durand, don't shoot!
What was that?
Where are the others?
I can't see them.
I see what Durand meant now.
It's a model they used to work out
their plans of attack on the Earth.
Remember the cosmic document?
It said they would
first subject the planet
to a highly intense
radiation bombardment.
Thanks to this device they
calculated how atomic beams
could be directed to our planet.
I think you're quite right.
And directly beneath us is
their operational headquarters.
Professor Sikarna.
The glass forest is radiating
energy. Come quickly!
That's just what
I was afraid of.
Look at that.
The spheres turned red.
Gravities increasing.
I am not surprised.
But it's incredible.
No.
Now everything is clear.
The sphere creates
an artificial force field.
Which strengthens
the gravitation of Venus.
Or diminishes it.
This very moment the
power is augmenting.
When the the energy is inverted,
the field will reverse itself!
And we'll be hurled
into space again!
Don't worry professor,
there's still time.
Call Harringway, quickly!
Hello, Harringway!
Come in, please!
The shadows!
Thrown on the wall
when they were hit
by an atomic explosion.
Incredible.
And now, the only
thing that is left of them
is their shadows.
The Marax is picking up commands
from the underground nerve center.
Look at the key it's
using to decode them.
Why, it's,
it's incredible, Sikarna.
E equal to MC squared.
That's Albert
Einstein's old formula.
Yes, but their
integration factor
is a curve closed upon itself.
Take a look. It's interesting.
But that's wonderful,
those are seeds.
They're plant seeds.
Where did you find them?
I found them on the surface,
near the nerve center.
They were certainly carried there
by one of those big storms.
If these seeds are still fertile, it
proves there is life on this planet.
Professor Sikarna wants
everybody in the Marax, please.
Our research on the metal
insects found in the cave,
have told us a little of
this planet's history.
As to the message we
heard, there's no doubt about it.
The inhabitants of Venus
were contemplating
launching an atomic
attack on our planet.
But the attack
wasn't carried out.
An accident they didn't
expect, upset their plan.
Their atomic weapons
got out their control,
a chain reaction was unleashed,
and they all perished.
Only their shadows remained.
And their energy projectors,
although partially destroyed,
are capable of working again,
if their energy reactions
are set in motion
by some accident,
or even by one of us.
Why,
what do you mean?
That we've started the reaction?
When that rock fell
into the black mud,
what happened?
But the rock was thrown out
as if the slime with a living thing.
Then something
terrible happened.
The slime began to grow rapidly.
First it dilated.
Now tell us,
what happened next?
The black slime started to move.
Yes, it began to follow us.
- We were cornered.
- What did you do?
I used the deuteron
ray gun, and I shot into it!
You should never have done that.
You started an atomic reaction!
But there was
nothing else to do.
We had no other
way of getting out.
Yes.
You started a chain reaction,
over the whole
atomic installation.
Now we're really in a nice mess.
What can we do?
- What time was it?
- Seventeen hours ten.
I remember.
Yes!
Yes, it was at that moment
that the sphere turned red.
It looks as if mass changed
into energy by a process
rather like that
of the atom bomb.
The people of this planet
knew how to reverse the process.
They've changed
mass into energy,
but also they could change
energy back into mass.
Fantastic.
The inhabitants of Venus are,
or rather were,
far in advance of us in
the applications of physics.
That's one thing we
have to acknowledge.
Omega, stop!
Omega!
Durand! Durand,
Omega's out of control!
Brinkmann, switch
off all the automats!
Talua, come and help me!
The glass forest!
The glass forest, Orloff!
The sphere is turning red!
Orloff!
The radiation from
the glass forest
has upset Omega's
electronic brain.
The Farax computer's
gone out of action as well.
Look!
If the radiation keeps
on increasing like this,
we won't have a chance.
Even the Cosmostrator's lead
shielding won't be enough to protect us.
Durand!
I think he has internal
injuries, I must operate.
Start up the rockets, Orloff!
We must take off at once,
before it's too late!
The motors won't work!
The gravity field is
increasing more and more.
The radiation's paralyzed
everything, nothing is working.
The whole Cosmostrator is
nothing but an inert lump of metal.
There's only one chance.
We must try to do
what the Venusians did.
Make the energy of the
glass force in the sphere
change back into mass once more.
Yes, but how?
When the mat attacked
you on the tower,
and you decided to use the ray gun,
which changed the mass into energy,
I think I saw something was
happening in the Venusian nerve center.
I think I know
how to start the
reverse process.
Can I use the rocket plane?
No, you're forgetting
the gravity field, it won't fly.
But the Crawlercopter will work!
You mustn't go alone.
I'll come with you.
We're entering
the Venusian city.
The hurricane is
getting much worse.
How is Harringway?
The doctor's operating now.
Sumiko will manage.
Swab.
How are you coming
along, Durand?
Fine, I've managed
to fix the computer.
Tchen Yu, can you hear me?
Where are you?
We're starting to climb down
into the Venusian nerve center.
My space suit!
It's punctured!
I'm coming to help you.
No, Talus, go on down.
You must save the others!
Harringway!
I can't hold out for long!
My air's escaping!
The sphere is white again!
Look, Sikarna!
Talua has succeeded
in reversing the field.
My spacesuit is punctured!
My oxygen's escaping and
the safety device has failed.
Try to hold out, Tchen Yu.
You've got to!
The gravity is back to normal!
I'll set off at once
in the rocket plane!
I'll get you out
of it, Tchen Yu.
Hold on, I'm coming with oxygen.
Tchen Yu?
Hello, Tchen Yu.
Hold out!
Brinkmann is coming!
Tchen Yu!
I must talk to him.
Tchen Yu, listen to me!
Those seeds that you found.
They're growing! They're
growing, Tchen Yu!
You've proved that
there's life on the planet.
Yes, Tchen Yu, there's
still life on Venus!
Sumiko.
There's life.
The braking motors,
Durand, the braking motors!
Talua! Tchen Yu! Brinkmann!
Come back at once!
We can't hold the
Cosmostrator down!
We're being
pushed off the planet!
The reverse
process is in action.
The energy field is
acting like a catapult!
The negative
gravity is increasing!
Brinkmann, can you hear me?
We're being hurled into space!
Talua! Tchen Yu! Brinkmann!
Are you receiving me?!
Sumiko.
Sumiko!
Orloff, we must try and go back!
Please! Please!
Cosmostrator, where are you?
Are you receiving me?
I can't get back!
I'm being hurled off the planet!
Cosmostrator, you're taking off?
You're leaving me?
Harringway! Orloff!
Don't leave me!
Cosmostrator!
Luna 3 calling the Earth.
The Cosmostrator is returning.
We have called them, but at
the moment there is no reply.
I greet the Earth.
I greet you all.
We have learned much.
But we have sacrificed
a lot.
To much!
Let us honor the
memory of 3 great men.
Talua saved the expedition from disaster.
Tchen Yu,
discovered life on Venus.
And Brinkmann was the first
human ever to set foot on the planet.
May they never be forgotten.
We found traces
of a great civilization
that had advanced
beyond our comprehension.
The Venusian science had gone
beyond their power to control it.
A dreadful catastrophe
fell upon them.
They were destroyed
by their own machines.
We still have a
grave task before us.
(Bad audio dropouts) We must use our knowledge
to establish life again on Venus. And then, after that,
go on to explore the other planets.
We'll fly further and further.
It's Mankind's destiny.