[music playing]
NARRATOR: This is Los
Angeles-- our lady,
the Queen of the Angels as
the Spaniards named her.
The fastest growing
city in the nation.
It's been called a bunch of
suburbs in search of the city.
And it's been called the
glamour capital of the world.
A mecca for tourists, a
stop over for transients,
a target for gangsters, a haven
from those fleeing from winter,
a home for the hard working.
It is a city holding
the hopes and dreams
of over two million people.
It sprawls out
horizontally over 452
square miles of
valleys and upland,
of foothills and beaches.
Because of that vast area and
because of a population made up
of people from every
state in the union,
Los Angeles is the largest
police beat in the country.
And one of the toughest.
We're going to take
you into the City Hall
where police
headquarters are located.
Here in Communications are the
ears and voice of the police.
The lights on the complaint
board flash 24 hours a day--
citizens reporting a
prowler, a lost child,
a man molesting a woman, and
auto accident, a wild party.
Spend an hour or two
here and you would think
the whole city is gone berserk.
Minute by minute the orders
go up to the radio cars
in the far flung divisions.
Watson, Wilshire,
and West Los Angeles,
Hollywood and Hollenbeck
Heights in North Hollywood.
The work of a police, like
that of woman, is never done.
This is the case history of a
killing taken from the files
of the detective division.
The facts are told
here is that happen.
The story properly
starts here in Hollywood
Division Headquarters at one
o'clock of a June morning
last year.
Officer Robert Rawlins had
finished his tour of duty
and signed out.
It had been a touch day.
He'd be glad to get home.
His wife would be waiting up
for him, as she always did.
Hey, fella.
Come here.
What were you doing
back at that radio shop?
Just looking.
Was on my way home.
Live around here?
A couple blocks down.
Let me see some identification.
Sure.
Yeah, I guess I
forgot my wallet.
Look, I've got to see
some identification.
How about my Army discharge?
I got it right here.
[gun shots]
[crash]
Police department, operator 27.
MAN [ON TELEPHONE]:
Uh-- I want to report
the shooting of a policeman.
Hold on, please.
[ringing]
Copy that again, please.
MAN [ON TELEPHONE]:
I'm calling to report
the shooting of a police man.
What's the address?
MAN [ON TELEPHONE]:
5057 State Street.
Just west of Santa Monica.
Just a minute.
WOMAN [ON TELEPHONE]:
Receiving hospital.
Operator 2.
Operator 27.
5057 State Street,
50-57 State Street.
An officer has been shot.
Send an ambulance.
All units.
All units in the
vicinity of State
Street, Santa Monica
Boulevard, proceed
at once to 5057 State Street.
5-0-5-7 State Street.
An officer shot.
Code three.
[sirens]
80-K to Control One.
WOMAN [ON TELEPHONE]: Control
One to 80-K. Go ahead.
This is Breen.
Instruct homicide to
throw out a dragnet
and pick up all
suspicious characters
in the area of the shooting.
Also, notify Sergeants
Marty Brennan
and Chuck Jones to report to
me at the scene of the crime.
Control One to 80-K. Rodger.
[sirens]
I see.
Well, what have you got so far?
Well, not much, Captain Breen--
a couple of cartridge casings.
Hello Marty, Chuck.
Aye, Cap.
Eyewitnesses?
Who was first on the
scene-- reported it?
I was.
I live here.
I'm a light sleeper.
But my hearing is good.
And my cat was--
Did the officer say
anything before he collapsed?
Yeah, he gave a
description of the fella.
He was--
WOMAN [ON RADIO]:
On the shooting
of the officer-- suspect
is a white male American.
Age 26 or 27.
5 feet 10 or 11.
155 to 165 pounds.
Brown hair.
Regular features.
Pencil mustache.
Repeat broadcast.
All units--
-Is that about it?
-Yes, sir.
Exactly.
And the officer kept saying,
"he looked like such a nice kid.
He looked like such a nice kid."
As if he couldn't believe
what had happened to him.
I see.
Is that all?
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, well anything else I
can do I'd be glad to help you.
We may call you.
Get his name and
address-- will you , Bob?
This door been checked, Lee?
Yeah.
It's OK, Captain.
Find anything?
Nothing but some
smudges so far.
Found this in the
glove compartment.
I think its nitroglycerin.
It doesn't look quite right.
Well, check it down at the lab.
Right.
Open this up, Joe.
No key, captain.
Well, pry it open.
Hand me that bar, Frank.
A regular arsenal.
Yeah, get a load of that.
What is it?
I don't know.
It looks like some kind
of an electrical device.
United States Navy.
It's either stolen
or war surplus.
Send all this stuff
down to the lab
and check the serial number
on that Navy equipment.
Yes, sir.
Captain Breen, we
found these in the weeds
over by the radio store.
What do you got?
A pair of croc gloves, Captain.
Well, he thought of
everything, didn't he?
All right.
Give them to one
of the technicians.
Yes, sir.
Marty, you and Chuck
come along with me.
Let's go downtown and see what
they picked up in the dragnet.
Right.
[sirens]
You know him Marty?
Yeah.
I know his wife too.
Ever since high school.
Captain, I wish you'd let
Chuck and me handle this case.
All right.
I don't want any dead heroes.
Just want the man
who shot Rawlins.
NARRATOR: The suspects
began to arrive
at headquarters in droves.
The police tossed
every motel and hotel
and many private homes in
a four square mile area
around the scene
of the shooting.
Every available radio car
and patrolman and detective
was out on the dragnet.
The strings were being
drawn tighter and tighter.
Many a man returning from
a data, or a late party,
or a poker game, surprisingly
found himself in a squad car.
It's sirens screaming
as it brought
him to the detective bureau.
The dragnet gathered
in some strange fish
and many ordinary ones.
All the rest of that night
the detectives probed,
needled, questioned, quizzed.
Everything was
checked-- fingerprints,
names, addresses, stories.
Every fish in the
net was examined.
Most of them thrown back into
the sea, not worth keeping.
Except a few parole violators
and slightly shady characters
whose stories needed
a lot of verifying.
I wasn't prodding no
cars, just taking a walk.
You know, getting in condition.
You were running when the
radio cop picked you up.
Yeah.
Maybe that's why the
guys call me "punchy."
He's got a point there.
Two felony convictions,
no warrant, no warrant.
He's on parole.
Book him.
Violation of the parole.
Let's have the next one, Joe.
What were you doing
in that vacant lot?
The vacant lot?
Lot.
What were you doing in
it at that time of night?
[non-english speech]
You say your name
is Ralph Henderson?
So what?
Well, you know, it's
a funny thing Ralph.
There's a guy around
this town that's
been wearing your fingerprints,
only his name is Pete Hannon.
OK.
So I'm dead.
So what's one more
confession in my life?
Now you're talking, Hannon.
OK.
Hello, Harry.
What have we got here?
Oh, some robbery suspects--
candidate's for San Quinten.
Handsome here is the big shot.
He runs the outfit.
Have a gander at his record.
Car theft, escape
from reform school,
robbery, assault
with a deadly weapon.
Not bad.
Look at the heater
we found on him.
German Luger.
Fully loaded.
Redhead here tried to carve
up one of the arresting
officers with this pretty toy.
Nice boys.
NARRATOR: By dawn, many minor
wrongdoings had been uncovered
and a few incipient felonies.
The checking of the
suspects have been thorough,
painstaking, and tedious.
But all the work
was for nothing.
The man who had shot Officer
Rawlins was not among them.
He remained no more
than a description.
A shadow of a man.
Mysterious, elusive, deadly.
Hidden away somewhere
in the vast city.
As for Rawlins himself,
he couldn't help.
He was in a coma at Receiving
Hospital Mrs. Rawlins
waited out the long, tense
hours while her husband fought
to live.
Many another officers wife had
so waited, many another will.
The word came shortly
after dawn up.
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: A
white male American.
26 or 27.
5 feet 10 or 11.
155 to 165 pounds.
Brown hair.
Regular features.
Pencil mustache.
NARRATOR: This was no
frightened fugitive.
What went on in his mind?
Why had he set his hand
against his fellow man.
Taken the life of
another, of a stranger,
of a man who was
merely doing his duty.
He must have some
plan, some goal
that called for a sudden death
to anyone who got in his way.
Good morning, boys.
Morning, Lee.
Hi, Professor.
And I thought this
was safe cracker soup.
You going to drink it, I hope.
I'm really a nice guy.
Stick around.
I'll prove it.
Come over here.
Hold this for me.
Will you, Chuck?
Thank you.
Now if you'll hand me
that hammer, Marty.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Nitroglycerin.
I didn't ask for a collection
of fingers, just fingerprints.
All those nice finger
prints on the car
belong to the man it
was stolen from, Cap.
Nothing on the
guns, the pick locks.
Not even an interesting smudge.
The gloves.
Common type.
Worn by undertakers.
I'll check on them.
They won't show anything.
What did your
scientific test show?
A couple little things.
Tool identification
on these pick locks.
I got one under the scope.
You want to take a look?
Yeah.
Take a look.
I see.
Well, it seems to tie the
tool up with the lock.
Now, if that microscope could
only tell us who did it.
I'm working on that.
You know, only an amateur
would carry that liquid dynamite
in the car.
This boy's no amateur.
He took the precaution
of desensitizing
it so it'll take normal shock.
Took a lot of other
precautions too.
No fingerprints,
no identification,
nothing definite.
Except he's scientific-- knows
electricity, is inventive.
Yeah.
And happy on the trigger.
This is Captain Breen.
Get me Captain Stevens
at burglary, will you?
I hate to disappoint
you, Lee, but I think
you've come up with something.
Hello, Steve?
How are you?
Did your daughter's
marriage come off all right?
Good.
Look, Steve, on those burglaries
of electrical equipment lately,
were there any where pick
locks were used to gain entry?
Good.
Well, let me know if there's
another report of one,
will you?
I've got an idea
that Rawlin's killer
may be tied in with those.
And uh-- give my regards
to the newlyweds too.
So long, Steve.
Well, what are you waiting for?
You've got a job, haven't you?
Get going.
Yeah, let's go, Junior.
Hold this for me.
Will you, Lee?
Thanks.
NARRATOR: And so with
no fingerprints and only
a vague description to go
by, Sargent Brennan turned
to the modus operandi file.
A criminal, like
any human being,
has his own habit patterns--
unconscious traits
that can lead to his downfall.
On the way out, Junior.
Those are the burglars that
used pick locks for entry.
Oh, great.
This narrows it down to
just a couple of hundred
suspects in this area.
Do your math, will you?
It may not be so bad.
This guy has improved
on the system.
Maybe he's left his
trademark of some other job.
Well, here we go.
Legging it all over town
asking a million questions.
It's what your
paid for, isn't it?
Am I paid you associate
with you too, Junior?
You could do worse.
Not this year.
Come on.
WOMAN [ON RADIO]:
Car 12 Car 1-2.
In the 10,000 block
on Mississippi.
A 394-15 disturbance.
Car 80-K. Code One.
All units-- on the broadcast
of the suspect arrested
in the shooting of
Patrolman Rawlins,
cancel the cancellation.
Suspect released from custody.
Oh.
Hello, Mr. Martin.
You'll find Mr. Reeves
in the machine shop.
Hello, Roy.
Glad to see you.
How are you, Mr. Reeves?
Fine.
I was hoping you drop in.
I wanted to thank
you for showing us
how to handle that repair job.
Helped a lot.
Well, what have
we got this time?
A solar graft.
We have plenty of
these around, Roy.
Not like this one.
Yes, I see.
I suppose as usual you've
added your own improvements.
You know, it seems wrong
that a man of your talents
should bother consigning
equipment for rental.
I'd like to see you
devote yourself entirely
to experimental electronics.
It'll come one day.
I'll have a place like this.
Why wait?
I've got a pretty
good set up here.
They have modern
equipment to work with,
a lab, and my confidence in you.
Thanks, Mr. Reeves.
I have other plans.
But Roy, you can't
tell where it'll lead.
You might even work your
way around to a percentage
of the business.
I like it this way.
You just rent out my equipment.
Right, Roy.
All right.
Well, if you should
change your mind.
I'm not likely
to change my mind.
I suppose you want me to
set this up for rental too.
Mr. Reeves, you've already got
five pieces of my equipment.
And you'd like to know
what results I've have
from the rentals so far, hm?
Well, I can't say
as I blame you.
I think you'll find
this satisfactorily.
Satisfactory.
Goodbye, Mr. Reeves.
And you'll come back
again soon, won't you?
Sure.
Oh, incidentally.
How's that television
projector coming along?
The one you said would
reflect a 12 foot image?
Still working on it.
I just wanted you to know I've
already set up a rental on it.
In fact, I think
they'd like to buy.
It'll come pretty high.
Oh, money is no consideration
with this customer.
Tell him he can
pick it up tomorrow.
I thought you said it
wasn't finished yet?
It'll be finished.
It uses an image
fixer and then projects
by ordinary incandescents.
Roy, this is the
best television
projector I've ever seen.
Let's hope that your
customer thinks so.
He will.
[phone buzzing]
Yeah?
Send him right in, Charlotte.
There, you see our
customers is right here.
Begging for the
privilege of buying.
Better be running along.
I'm not much good at business.
Oh, but Roy.
He'll want to congratulate you.
Just see that the
price is right.
All right, Roy.
I'll get you a good deal.
So long.
See you.
Well, Mr. Dunning, come in.
Isn't it a beauty?
It's a beauty, all right.
You like it?
I certainly do like it.
You see, it's mine.
What do you mean?
Let me have the police.
I built it.
Spent years on it.
Well, you must be crazy.
Roy built this machine himself.
Your friend is a crook, Paul.
You've been taken in.
Hello?
Get my the burglary detail.
Dear Jim, regarding
your inquiry
on the 38 caliber Smith
and Wesson revolver-- oh,
come in boys.
Burglary detail just
sent this report through.
A man named Dunning
reports tracing
a stolen television projector
to the Reeves Electronics Lab.
You think it's a tie
with the Rawlins case?
Well, take a look at this
fella Reeves and see what gives.
I'll notify burglary
we're following up on it.
Right.
Come on, Junior.
What else did he place
with you for rental?
Oh, a number of things.
All warn surplus that he
bought on his veteran's rating.
Well, is this more
of his equipment?
Yes.
He left it here on consignment.
I'm sure that Roy can
explain everything.
Well, maybe he can,
Mr. Reeves, if you'll
tell us where he lives.
But I don't know.
Mr. Martin is on
the phone, sir.
I'd better talk to him.
I think so, Mr. Reeves.
I'll take it in the
superintendents office.
Tell him that you sold
the set and his money
is waiting for him here.
Find out what time
he's coming by.
Put Mr. Martin on.
Hello, Roy.
Yes.
I sold it.
Your money is
waiting here for you.
Yes.
I'll be working late tonight.
What time will you be by?
First thing in the morning.
Well, maybe you better
come in tonight, Roy.
A couple of things
I want cleared up.
Like what?
MR. REEVES [ON TELEPHONE]:
Oh, technical things.
Besides, I don't like to
leave the money in the plant
overnight.
How about 8:30?
Fine.
I'll see you then.
I leave the front door unlocked.
He'll be here at 8:30.
Well, I'll just run along
home and get some dinner.
Uh-- We'd like you to
stay too, Mr. Reeves.
Why?
For company.
You want to cooperate.
Don't you, Mr. Reeves?
Certainly.
Good.
Now, you just wait
in your office.
We'll be around.
Very well.
This way, gentlemen.
Reeves.
Is that you, Roy?
Go outside.
Lock that alley door.
Where are you, Roy?
Who's in here?
No one.
I'm alone.
Come on in.
I've got your money for you.
Bring it out here.
All right.
Just a minute.
Oh!
[gun shots]
No.
None of them even
looks like Roy Martin.
He had such a fine face.
Didn't keep him
from carrying a gun.
Or didn't you know that?
No.
I didn't.
I told you all I know--
all he ever told me.
What about his friends?
Didn't he have a girl?
No.
I don't think so.
He had no interest in
anything but electronics.
Where'd he pick up the stuff?
Books.
Magazines.
Mostly from the signal call.
He was attached to a radar unit.
Get a teletype off
to the War Department.
It might help.
[buzz]
Yes?
WOMAN [ON TELEPHONE]:
Ready on your call
to Receiving Hospital,
Captain Breen.
Hello.
This is Captain Breen.
What is the latest
report on Sergeant Jones?
I see.
Well, let me know if there's
any change, will you?
Thanks.
Sergeants in pretty
bad shape, Marty.
He's paralyzed.
May never walk again.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's funny that Martin showed
up at 7:00 when he told you he
wouldn't be there until 8:30.
I don't know why.
Except he was always
unpredictable.
I'll tell you why,
because you warned him.
That's why he came early.
That's why he came
in the back way.
But you heard me tell him
the front door would be open.
And the key that let
him in the back way?
He must have had one made.
Why don't you
tell us the truth?
CAPTAIN BREEN: Marty.
Now look, Paul.
You can make it a lot
easier for us to believe
your story if you just
give us some facts--
something that might help us.
I told you all I know.
I've been gullible, all right.
Bet he can make a fool of me.
But I'd do anything
to make up for what
he did to Detective Jones.
Sure.
Sure you would.
You can go now.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks.
My friends-- they can
vouch for my character.
That's good.
We'll call you if we need you.
Thank you very much.
I think he's telling
the truth, Marty.
I think he's just
said, like he said.
What about the
stolen stuff he was
trying to peddle for Martin?
We'll use it for bait.
Maybe Martin will come back
for it, then we can ask him.
Here.
Nevertheless, I want a 24
hour tail put on Reeves
and I want a watch on
his home and his factory.
Right.
You can keep those.
OK, Captain.
NARRATOR: And now the
killer changes his tactics,
his modus operandi.
It would baffle the police.
They always expected burglars
to remain burglars, not
go in for stick ups.
They'd never tie
this up with him.
Wearing a variety of disguises,
coming and going like a shadow,
ready to kill if
cornered, he struck
the bottle stores in
a one-man blitz that
had the robbery detail busy.
The killer, always resourceful,
always thinking along
lines that would
baffle his hunters
had discovered an
ideal avenue of escape.
Under Los Angeles is a vast and
intricate system of huge storm
drains built to
siphon of the flash
floods of the rainy season.
Many of the tunnels
are large enough
for two cars to drive abreast.
Here was 700 miles
of hidden highways,
ideal for the use of someone
who needed to hurry from place
to place without being seen.
Ideally as a hiding place
for guns and supplies
in case of emergency.
Listen, Lee.
Well, the reason I
asked you to come over
is I think I've
hit on something.
An identification?
No, not quite.
But a tie-up.
Now these are the shells from
the gun the killed Rawlins.
These were fired in
the liquor store holdup
in which the bandit got away.
And these were fired at Jack.
Now, as you know, every ejector,
even in guns of the same model
and caliber is difference.
Each one leaves its own mark
on the cartridge casing.
Now look at these fine
striations, this deep gouge.
The same on all three.
In other words, the man who
killed Rollins and the man who
shot at Jones and
Brennan, the stick up
was blitzing the liquor
stores are all the same man.
Right.
All we need to know is
what that man looks like.
Get me Chandler in
robbery, will you?
I've got an idea about that.
Also it'll give us a
chance to see if Reeves
is on the level with us.
Uh-- Steve?
Breen.
About those blitz
hold ups you're on.
Round up all the victims and
have them down her tonight,
will you?
Oh, it's just a little scheme.
Thanks, Steve.
That's good.
Now, sketch another one of
the same type, only this time
thin it out a little.
-All right.
-Hi, Lee.
How's it coming?
You' ready for the night?
We'll be ready.
Think it'll work?
It should.
Where'd you get the idea?
From a kidnapping
case in Chicago.
I thought these slides
might be an improvement
over the method they used.
Could be.
Captain thinks so.
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
May I have your attention
for a moment, please?
You all are going to sit-in on
a little experiment tonight.
We're going to try to build
a picture of a face-- a face
of a man who's cunning,
resourceful, and definitely.
He's a man who killed
a police officer.
Now, some of you he held
up at the point of a gun.
You may have seen this face,
remembered something about him.
And we want you to tell us
exactly what you remember,
whether it's his hair,
eyes, nose, or mouth.
And we're going to try to
put those pieces together
so that they add
up into a picture
of the face of the man we want.
Now, you can see how
we're depending on you.
Lights.
Now first, we're going to
concentrate on the type of hair
our man had.
And if the picture looks
anything like his hair,
I want you to speak right up.
All right.
The first slide, Lee.
His hair had waves in it.
Well groomed.
That's the idea, Miss Smith.
Is that any closer?
Um, no.
It was parted on the side.
Oh that's more like it.
Except it was thicker.
Oh, that's very close.
Yes, that's the way
his forehead looked.
It was broad and high.
All right, hold that slide.
Now, the next series
of slides will
take into account his eyes.
Oh, one minute, please.
Wait.
One minutes.
His eyes were a
little like that.
Maybe a little
smaller-- like beans.
Go on, Lee.
Now-- now you've got it.
Now hold that slide, Lee.
Anyone else?
That looks like him,
only a little madder.
He had a patch over one eye
when he come into my dive--
uh-- my place of business.
I remember noticing the
one showing was blue.
Well, the guy that stuck me
up had horn-rimmed glasses.
He was wearing a
Bandaid across his nose
when he knocked me over.
Hmm.
All right.
Hold that, Lee.
Well, so much for the eyes.
Go ahead.
[speaking spanish]
Yes, Miss Montavo?
I-- [speaking spanish]
[speaking spanish]
Like that, Captain.
But more snuff-- wider.
Try another one, Lee.
[speaking spanish]
She says that's about it.
Thank you very
much, Miss Montavo.
Get Reeves.
Anymore comments?
MAN 1: That's pretty
close, all right.
Pretty close.
MAN 2: Perfect.
All right, now let's start
on the mouth and chin.
The next series, Lee.
I think his lower
lip stuck out lower.
The mouth was thin and
mean, like it never laughed.
Go ahead.
Something like that,
but thicker lips.
There.
That's it.
That's him.
All right.
Now hold that right there, Lee.
Oh.
Come in, Mr. Reeves.
Good evening, Captain.
Did you ever see
that face before?
Oh, it's Roy.
Except for the hair being a
little lighter and the eyebrows
a little heavier, it's Roy.
You're sure?
I'm positive.
I'd know him anywhere.
Lee, I want to
retouch the photograph.
Now, lighten the hair and give
more body to the eyebrows.
Right.
Lights.
That's all.
Thank you very much.
You've been a great help.
It's positively amazing how you
found out what he looks like.
Well, we're look for an
amazing criminal, Mrs. Johnson.
Thank you, and good night.
Goodnight, Captain.
NARRATOR: And so the face of
the unknown killer built up
from fragments of evidence was
sent out all over the country--
to chiefs of police, to
sheriffs, to county constables,
and county jailers, to
the wardens of prisons,
to all post masters
and postal inspectors,
to the agents of the Treasury
Department, to the FBI.
They showed that picture to the
inmates of jails and prisons,
to men with a wide acquaintance
among the cat burglars
and the violence boys, informers
and con men and sharp shooters
were quizzed, those
on the fringe of crime
and those deep in the rackets.
Many wanted to
help, nobody could.
No one in the
underworld recognized
that mysterious face.
He was as unknown as if he
had lived in the 16th century.
Reeves.
Roy.
Listen carefully, Reeves.
Control yourself.
I know you're
alone in the house.
Act like you're
alone/ The cops are
watching every move you make.
The police?
Here?
They've got you staked
out like a muskrat hide,
watching you around the
clock-- here, at your plant,
tailing your car.
Sit in that chair.
Pick up three books.
Don't look up and
don't answer me.
All right.
Now glance at the books.
Pick up one of them.
OK.
Now that's the book you want
to read before you go to bed.
Now, get up and
turn off the lamp.
Come here.
ROY: Come here.
Go in the den.
Pull those drapes tight.
Now get away from them.
What do the cops know about me?
Not very much, Roy.
No fingerprints.
They haven't even
got a picture of you.
They're trying to make one.
How much cash you
got in the house?
None.
I never keep any
cash in the house.
It isn't good business.
I suppose you think
it was good business
letting me walk into that trap.
-No.
I don't.
Don't do anything you'll regret.
Now, listen to me.
It isn't too late.
Give yourself up,
come to your senses
before you kill someone else.
What do you mean, someone else?
What do you mean?
Nothing.
The two officers, they
said one of them might die.
But he's still alive, isn't he?
Reeves, I never thought
you'd stooge for the police.
You almost got me killed.
Come on Roy.
You know the police
are right outside.
You'd never get away with it.
That's right.
Now you're being sensible.
I know there's money here.
Where is it?
Don't, Roy.
I'll get it.
It's not enough.
The stuff you've got of
mine is worth thousands.
I'll get more.
Get it and keep it handy.
I'll be back next
week or next month,
but get it and have it ready.
Just give me time.
PAUL REEVES: Oh!
Look, I don't want
policeman out side my house
or following me around.
That's what made Roy suspicious.
I'm leaving in the morning.
I'm afraid I'll have
to disappoint you, Paul.
Unfortunately, you're our bait.
I won't do it.
I've done enough.
Look, no one's done enough
until we find this killer.
I asked you to keep look
out on this house, Marty.
I did.
Two of the best undercover
men in the department
were assigned here.
That didn't keep
Martin from getting in.
What's the matter?
You tired?
You got any idea
how long you've
been on this case, Marty?
Months.
Long enough to have come up
with something by this time.
You know any more about
more about the Rawlins killer
than you knew the first week?
Yeah, that he's
about the toughest
nut I've ever had to crack.
That's what I told the
chief when he called me
in this afternoon
wanted to know why
the case hadn't been broken.
Look, Captain.
Rawlins was a friend
of mine, so was Chuck.
I've got a bigger stake in
this than the chief knows.
I'm doing everything I can.
I'm afraid it's
not enough, Marty.
Maybe you're too close
to it to see it clearly.
Maybe it needs a fresh
team, a new viewpoint.
I think you better take a
couple weeks off, Marty.
Starting tomorrow.
Anything you say, Captain.
Hiya, Marty.
Hi, Chuck.
Meet Miss Scanion,
my new body guard.
He's the one I've been
telling you about.
Oh, you mean the one
with the steel trap brain.
How do you do?
Hello.
Say, this guy been behaving?
-After a fashion.
-See.
She takes me out in my
go-cart, puts me to bed,
wakes me up, dresses me.
You're perfectly capable
of dressing yourself now,
Mr. Jones.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Well, how's it
been going, junior?
Oh, pretty good, Chuck.
Pretty good.
Is that's why
you're off the case?
How'd you know?
Breen was in to
see me this morning.
Oh.
I suppose he also told you they
put a new team on the case.
He told me everything.
Yeah, lets see what
his new boys dig up.
Maybe they'll examine the
facts of the case a little more
carefully.
What facts-- In a man's
shop, highly intelligent,
works alone?
That he has no record,
never leaves a fingerprint,
knows every more we make?
Sure, plenty of facts, only
they add up to nothing.
Sure.
Forget it.
You got yourself
a 10 day vacation.
Go on down to the
beach, get a suntan.
By the time you get back
the case will be broken.
Isn't that what you want?
You know it better than that.
All I know is what I hear.
You sit there batting
your gums about how
the old man let you down.
Maybe he's trying
to wake you up.
He's got a funny
way of showing it.
There you go, flying
off the handle-- always
taking things for granted.
I wish I could get up and
boot some sense into you.
He knew what this
case meant to me.
He still does.
That's why he's trying
to get you mad enough
to do something about it.
You don't really figure
that his idea, do you?
I know it is.
Ah, its a tough case, Chuck.
Not an angle, nothing to go on.
You'd know what I met if you
were out working with me.
I have been working with you.
That's all I've had
to do lately, just
sit around studying what
little facts we have trying
to figure out who we might be.
You know the kind of a
guy we're up against then.
I tell ya, Chuck.
This guy's a genius
the way he operates.
As if were right there
with us every time
we go our after a lead.
Oh, sure.
Breen's been tipping him off
just to make you look bad.
I almost like that.
The way he beats us to
the punch every time.
There's you angle.
You just hit it on the
head, but you don't see it.
Look, start adding.
One-- he's unknown
to the underworld.
Two-- he beats you
to the punch, right?
And three-- it's almost
as if he were with you.
Isn't that what you said?
Yeah.
Well, tie that up with a
lot of other little things,
like the fact that he uses a
police gun, and the accuracy
of the shooting.
Anybody could buy a police
gun, and the Army could've
taught him how to shoot.
Yeah, but who taught him
how the police operate?
I know what you're
driving at, Chuck.
But-- but a cop?
Those things happen.
Yeah.
Now, if I were
still on the case
I'd start with
out own department
first, then Santa Monica,
Culver City, Burbank, Pasadena.
See you later, Junior.
Hey-- Don't let him out
of your sight, beautiful.
That was the first time in
years he's used his head.
But you get a print
of every mug we take.
We always send LA
a copy, Sergeant.
It's personnel photos I want.
You mean [inaudible]?
That's Rawlins
killer, isn't it?
That's right.
You checked your
own department.
We did that first.
NARRATOR: And so the
tedious quest went on.
Sergeant Brennan wore out his
shoes and his patience going
from police station
to police station,
checking photos until
his eyes were blurry.
For police work
is not all glamour
and excitement and glory.
There are days and
days of routine,
of tedious probing, of tireless
searching, fruitless days.
Days when nothing goes right,
when it seems as if no one
could ever think his way through
the maze of baffling trails
a criminals leaves.
But the answer to that is
persistence and the hope
that sooner or later something
will turn up, some tiny lead
that can grow into a
warm trail and point
to the cracking of a tough case.
Well, that does it, boys.
Can't say I'm sorry you
didn't find him in here.
I'd hate to think it was a cop.
Doesn't seem to be anybody.
Just a lot of pieces of a
face that never existed.
Do you mind if
I see that again?
Sure.
Frame it.
Put it on your dresser.
Wait a minute.
He wasn't a cop.
He was a radio technician right
here in our dispatch office.
What did you say?
I'm saying he
worked here in '42.
Well come on, give.
I remember the kid well.
He was sort of
strange, never bothered
with anyone in the department,
just kept to himself.
He was in line for a
promotion when he was drafted.
Where was he
living at the time?
I don't remember
Try the dead files.
He never asked for his
job back after the war.
I remember writing to
him about it though.
He was an excellent worker.
Oh yeah, here we are.
Yeah.
This is it.
Took a while before he answered.
But like he says in the
letter, he wasn't interested.
Postmarked Hollywood.
No return address.
What do you want us
to do-- all the work?
Oh, thanks a lot, Freddy.
Remember, he was a
civilian employee.
Well, how about it?
Anybody recognize him?
Not on my route.
I never saw him before.
Yeah?
OK, fellas.
Thanks very much.
I thought for a minute-- no.
And yet, that face.
I wonder--
Yeah?
Well, this may
not mean anything.
But he looks like a
guy that on my route.
He never gets any
mail, but I see
him around there all the time.
He lives in one of the courts.
Where?
Come on.
I'll show you.
It's not that easy.
What time does your route
take you past those courts?
About nine o'clock.
Why?
Just thinking.
Hey!
Got any chocolate milk?
Sure have, buddy.
Here ya are.
Thanks.
Which apartment?
Straight on back.
Second in the L. Number seven.
All right.
Kind of warm today, huh?
Oh, it's not too bad for
this time of the year.
Good morning.
Morning.
You're new on the
route, aren't you?
Yeah, a substitute.
What happened to
the other fella?
Sick.
Oh, what's the matter with him?
I don't know.
I catch everything.
Hear about on the radio,
next morning I got it.
Too bad.
You aren't very social.
The regular fella always
stops and talks to me.
I'm sorry, lady.
I'm a little late this morning.
I was hoping maybe
you could help me.
There's something very funny
going on in this court.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I was scared to go to
the police with it.
I thought maybe I
might be poisoned.
What?
Yeah, by the manager.
She's a witch.
She's a what?
A witch.
She puts poison in my milk.
Oh, I see.
Look, switch the bottles
when she isn't looking, see.
Drink her milk.
Then you'll be safe, right?
Why, I had a little accident.
Got a mop?
I'll clean it up.
Leave it be.
I'll clean it up myself.
OK, mister.
This place is called
Bellevue Court.
I drew this from memory,
but it's pretty close.
That's where he's hiding out.
Right there.
You sure he's our man, Marty?
Captain, I couldn't
go on that face.
He's our man.
Now there are five
cottages in this area.
And two, number six and seven in
the "L" at the end of the road.
Our man lives in number seven.
His building department plan
will show you the whole layout.
It's bounded on three
sides by Fuller,
Santa Monica, and [inaudible].
Now, the court is partly
surrounded by a high wall.
[ringing]
Breen, homicide.
Good.
You keep your eyes open
until we get there.
Morgan has just gone
into his bungalow alone.
Any questions?
All right.
You all have your instructions.
Let's go.
We're right on time.
Wait five minutes, go around
and block the side entrance.
Keep your lights off.
[barking]
He's loose.
I want a radio car in a hurry.
[sirens]
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: All units.
All units in the vicinity
of Santa Monica and Fuller.
The murder suspect in the
Rawlins killing is at large.
[crash]
[gun shots]
I want a map covering the
storm drain system in this area.
Get it and meet me at
Venice and Garfield.
Jones, Miller, you stay here
in case he comes up for air.
I want a man at every other
drain entrance along this line.
He's got to come up somewhere.
Come on, Marty.
You're driving.
Keep this drain covered.
He's liable to pop out anywhere.
Why Venice and
Garfield, Captain?
It's the main
intersection in the system
if you're heading
north that way.
80-K to Control One.
Air frequency seven.
This is an emergency.
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: Control One
to all cars on frequency seven,
stand by.
Control one to 80-K, go ahead.
Notify homicide,
send the following
to Venice and Garfield.
Four squads, battle lanterns,
gas masks, tear gas.
Urgent.
This is a Code Three.
WOMAN [ON RADIO]: Control
One to 80-K. Rodger.
And he'll probably head
down this main drain to where
it comes out at the Rio Hondo.
Now, you take your squad
and cover that exit.
Right.
Keep all spare radio cars
cruising back and forth
along this main street.
Watch the curb inlets.
We'll go in here.
Any sign of him?
No.
We've searched every
foot between here
and the Rio Hondo outlet.
Then he must be up ahead.
Let's go.
[gun shots]
Yeah, it's done.