Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Ja, wunderbar.
Look at that Karl.
- Well Roy, you seem to like my country.
- Like it? I think it's marvelous.
Say, I wish we were staying here
two years instead of just two weeks.
But you know Karl, it does sound
funny hearing you call it your country.
- I keep forgetting you're not English.
- Oh, sometimes I...
- Oh, I feel almost English myself.
- Well...
that's natural, after
all you can't be at Oxford...
3 years without feeling slightly British.
I wish Helen were here.
After all you've said
about her, I don't blame you.
Your brother is not
coming today Herr Rutledge?
Oh yes, he'll be along soon Gretchen, nothing
can keep Monte away from this good beer.
- Nothing except a good looking woman.
- Jawohl.
That brother of yours,
he's a naughty boy but I like him.
- He has a way with them, hey Gretchen?
- You, you don't know half of it.
Another conquest for Monte.
Yes. I don't know why he wants to
mess about with every woman he meets.
- Yeah but you have Helen.
- I'm not at all sure.
- I'm not half good enough for her.
- She must be a wonderful girl.
Oh, she is, she's marvelous.
You have to meet her
when we get back to Oxford.
- I'd like to.
- Would you like to see what she looks like?
Yes. I didn't know
you had a photograph of her.
Yeah and neither does Helen,
I took it myself when she wasn't looking.
Really?
- Stunning, isn't she?
- Why, she's marvelous.
- Cheerio, you blighters.
- Hello, it's Monte.
Meet the countess, step
up gents, to the one and only...
- No Monte, don't please.
- Oh, it's all right.
This little pretzel doesn't
understand a word of English.
- No?
- Gretchen.
- Ja.
- Bier.
Found at the museum.
- She's a work of art alright.
- You should've left her there.
Quiet.
I say Monte, why
do you bring around this sort?
Bring her?
Good heavens, I can't get rid of her.
Go home, will you? Go home.
You see, I'm stuck.
- Hello, who's the dowager?
- That's Helen.
Oh but of course, that's only a
snapshot, wait till you meet her.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Go away.
I say, this is getting
serious, I've got to get rid of her.
Oh, you know, I've a very
important meeting in just 15 minutes.
I say you chaps, be, be
sporting and take her off my hands.
But after all Monte, we may be
sporting but we're not feeble minded.
Well, you can do what you
please with her, I'm going.
- Hey, listen Monte...
- Auf Wiedersehen.
Here, just a minute now please.
Leave her to me, I'll get rid of her.
Please, yes.
- Roy. No Roy...
- No, carry on, carry on.
Pretty boy, you please me very much.
What's that?
It is nothing, I am not at home
to anyone except my husband.
And he is away on army business.
He will not be home for hours.
So, you see...
Charming.
But really, I, I say
you mustn't think that...
Your name?
My name is Rutledge sir.
- You are stopping in Munich?
- At the Hotel Bayrischer Hof sir.
My seconds will call on you later.
- But I say you...
- There is nothing further to discuss.
♪ Sailing, sailing over the bounding main. ♪
♪ Where many a wintry wind shall blow,
here Jack comes home again. ♪
- Hello, where you going?
- ♪ Sailing, sailing, ♪ England.
England? Why, we're
not going back for 10 days.
What's wrong?
- Baron Von Kranz.
- Who's he?
- Oh, he's just a friend of mine.
- Really?
Quite a social success, aren't you?
How do you meet these barons?
Well, unfortunately
I met this one through his wife.
- And this means...
- A duel, can you imagine it?
- Running away?
- Oh, don't be an ass Roy.
You don't expect me to go
through with a farce like this.
But Monty, it's the only thing you can do.
Oh, there you go again.
I suppose when a woman
is no good and her husband...
finds it out, I got to get shot just
because is the honorable thing to do.
Well, what do you think people
will say? You never live it down.
What do I care what people say?
Well, you can talk all you like
Monte but you can't walk out like this.
Can't I?
Goodbye, see you at Oxford.
- Hello Roy.
- Hello Karl.
OH, what's up? Where's Monte?
Gone to England.
England? Well, what's the matter?
- Oh, nothing.
- But I say...
Herr Rutledge?
- Yes?
- Von Richter.
Von Schlieben.
- We represent Colonel Baron Von Kranz.
- Yes.
Have you chosen your second?
According to custom, we have
selected the time and place.
You have the choice of weapons.
What is your choice?
What is this?
Golden Ave.
Why, that's a famous dueling place near here.
It says at 4 o'clock tomorrow morning.
- 4 o'clock in the morning.
- Well, how did this happen?
I'm, I'm sorry Karl. I, I lost my
temper with one of your officers.
- But Roy...
- Say Karl, do you know how to be a second?
Wait here Roy.
Bitte.
Good luck Roy.
♪ Did you ever see a
Lassie, a Lassie, a Lassie. ♪
Lassie go this way and that. ♪
Hey, will you cut it out?
- Hey, did anybody see my green socks?
- Check in the garbage.
- Hello there Roy.
- Hello Elliot, glad to see you.
- I'm certainly glad to see you back.
- Thank you.
And where's your German accent?
Well, I couldn't get it
past the Custom officials.
Oh I say, what have you done to your arm?
Oh nothing, it's just a little
scratch. I was hunting in Germany.
- I'll see you at dinner?
- Right-O.
- Good.
- See you later.
Say, why aren't you getting dressed?
Aren't you coming to meet Helen?
- Oh yes but don't remind me of it.
- Don't be foolish, she expects us for tea.
Tea?
Listen, it'll do you
good to meet a nice girl.
Oh well alright but first
we got to get you dressed.
Say, we got to get him
dressed, he's going to see his girl.
Now, now, wait a minute now.
Listen, I've got to have my shirt.
Wait a minute, I. Listen,
I'm old enough to dress myself.
- No, you're not.
- Will you cut it out?
Say, listen, will you pl...
- Will you...
- Say, my green socks.
- Is Helen in?
- Miss Helen is not at home sir.
- She's expecting us.
- Would you care to wait?
Yes, thank you.
Fine reception.
- Roy, maybe she's forgotten.
- Not Helen, she's not that sort.
Roy, I feel sick, I, I think I'd better go.
- Monte, will you sit down?
- Oh, I got an awful headache.
I think I'll go to the
chemist and get something for it.
Monte...
- Roy?
- Helen.
Oh, terribly sorry, mother's fault, shopping.
I simply flew. My, isn't it hot?
- You shouldn't have hurried so.
- Oh but I wanted to.
Roy, you've no right to
look so cool. I'm broiling. Feel.
- Yes, you are, aren't you?
- No, not one.
- Well, you're so marvelous I, I hardly dare.
- Oh, silly.
Oh, that's better, cigarette Roy?
- I thought your brother was coming.
- Went out with a headache.
Poor boy, it must be the heat.
Extra, extra, all about the war.
- Well, they've done it.
- I never thought they would.
- I still can't believe it.
- Well, it must be true, it's official.
Oh shut up, I'm trying to think.
It's terrible.
Karl, you won't have to go, will you?
Me? Oh Roy, I hope not.
Oh, they can't want me, I'm not a
soldier, what use would I be to them?
I couldn't kill anyone.
They couldn't make me
do that, could they Roy?
Oh, I think it'll all be
over in a couple of weeks.
- I'm not so sure.
- I wouldn't worry about it.
Then suppose England comes in.
Why Roy, that it'd be horrible.
I never could do that. Why, I love England.
Oh, will you shut up?
Monte, Germany is declared war on France.
Oh Roy, how do you spell ecstatic?
Special delivery letter for Karl Arnstedt.
- What's the matter Karl?
- Someone ill?
Karl?
May I ask the Prime Minister if he has
any information he can give us today.
Our ambassador at Berlin received
his passport at 7 o'clock last evening.
And since 11 o'clock last
night a state of war has existed...
between Germany and ourselves.
Seven?
- What size?
- A seven and a half if you please.
I, I'm afraid it's a bit small sir.
Move along there,
move along, you'll grow into it.
Present arms.
Come on there, come on, present, arms.
Give it to him, you bloody fool.
Hey, what's wrong
with you? Sleeping sickness?
Here, here. Let go of
that gun, you clinging vine.
Let go, do you hear?
God, you're enough to turn a man's stomach.
Hey, you with the fallen arches...
- I enlisted Monte, in the Royal Flying Corp.
- You're a fool Roy.
- Really?
- How lovely.
My grandfather was in the guard
during the Revolution.
Oh, he was?
- Oh Roy, you look marvelous in uniform.
- Thank you.
- Doesn't he?
- It's ripping.
- Where?
- Tell me, what have you joined?
- The infantry?
- No, the Royal Flying Corp.
And all the misery in
this world has been caused...
by and for capitalism.
Why should we fight this war? For capitalism?
You will die, you will die.
All your sons will die for capitalism.
Down with capitalism, down with war.
- Down with the anarchists.
- That's right.
Get back now. Who
do you think you're shoving?
There's the man I'd like to kiss.
- What's the matter? Afraid of a kiss?
- Maybe he's yeller.
Go on you, go on and fight for your country.
- Slacker.
- Come on.
But really, you don't understand,
I didn't mean to do anything.
Say, I'd rather marry the girl.
You never get your wings that way.
- Hi, how are you?
- Oh boy.
Say listen, that first
solo flight certainly is a great thrill.
It certainly felt great.
I will.
Look boys, it's Monte.
- Hey, how it go Monte?
- Oh, great.
- Well, tonight is the night Monte.
- Yeah.
Say listen, be more cheerful, you
have a treat in store meeting Helen.
Must be Friday the 13th.
Gee I, I wonder if she'll
wear her canteen uniform.
- If she does, you can count me out.
- Oh, she looks stunning in it.
Who wants to be stunned?
I'm only going as a favor to you.
You and I don't like the same kind of girls.
Hurry up, will you?
Oh, it's a waste of time to Polish these.
She'll probably step all
over them the first dance anyway.
It's safer to sit it out.
Quiet little corner and a have
a chat about votes for women.
- Hello there.
- Hello.
Whose window are you warbling under tonight?
Lady Randolph's Charity Ball.
Wash your neck, come along.
Oh but I haven't had been invited.
- That's all right, I'm on the committee.
- No, I don't think I'll go.
A smart boy.
I wonder where Helen is.
She should be here by this time.
How do you do sir?
- There's she is.
- Don't point, it's rude.
- Oh, Helen.
- Roy.
- Hello.
- Hello old thing.
You're frightfully late, I
was afraid you weren't coming.
- Oh, Helen, this is Monte.
- How do you do?
How do you do?
Well, that's done at last.
You know, you two been
avoiding each other for weeks.
- Helen, may I've this next dance?
- What? Oh, of course.
- Oh Roy, there you are.
- Good evening Lady Randolph.
I must say, you take your duties on
my committee very lightly.
- I'm sorry.
- Where you've been?
You've completely disarranged my program.
There are no end of things to be done.
Helen dear, you don't mind, do you?
- Come along Roy, come at once.
- I'm sorry, Helen.
Monte, would you take
this next dance with Helen?
Oh, how do you do Monte?
How do you do? Now come along.
Well?
Hello Roy, I, I really must go and find...
Jimmy Kerrigan, he has
something most important to tell me, I...
- Who is this Jimmy Kerrigan?
- Kerrigan? I've never heard of him.
What do you thinking of?
If you must know, I was thinking of Monte.
- Do you like him?
- Yes, I like him, he's a marvelous dancer.
Oh, Monte does all those things well.
- Helen.
- What?
May I?
- Oh, Monte.
- Oh hello there.
Come sit down.
You having a better time
than you expected Monte?
Marvelous, been dancing with a beautiful
brunette, name of Eleanor, she's perfect.
Oh, Eleanor Madden, you
don't really think she's beautiful?
- Kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty?
- Stop it, I'm not a cat.
Yes, you are.
Well, if I'm a kitty, I'm a thirsty kitty.
Roy dear, will you please
get me a glass of punch?
Why, of course I will.
- No, I'll go Roy.
- No, I'm the committee.
You stay here and look after this wallflower.
- But really, I...
- Oh, if you'd rather not.
Well, I, I didn't mean...
Don't you like wallflowers?
- I shouldn't have done that.
- Oh, you're not sorry Monte.
- Awfully sorry, I had no right to.
- What if I'm glad?
- But what about Roy?
- Isn't that my business?
- I suppose so but...
- Hush.
- Compliments of the committee.
- Thanks awfully Roy.
- Perhaps he isn't been properly charming?
- Me?
- More than charming.
- Good for you Monte.
Taste?
- She loves me.
- She blisters you.
- It's worth it.
- Is she worth it?
Depends on who she is.
- Hello.
Well, thank goodness Lady
Randolph lost sight of me for a minute.
Roy, you've been neglecting me shamefully.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
You see, it's this beastly committee.
- Lady Randolph won't let me alone a minute.
- Oh Roy, there you are.
- Yes, here I am.
- Do you mind? Where is that list?
Would you mind finding Sir
John for me? It's about my Canteen Unit.
I must've the queen's
signature, it's so important.
My dear, why don't you get into
your uniform? You look so pretty in it.
And Monte,
shouldn't you dance with Mary Blunt?
- Yes, why don't you?
- And Roy. Roy...
when you found Sir John, I want you
to lead the Grand Dance for me.
And really, there are so many...
- things you've got to do.
- Yes, I'm, I'm terribly sorry, back soon.
- You see, those girls been looking for you.
- I know but Lady Randolph, I'm supposed...
So you really joined
Lady Lizzie's Canteen Unit?
Rather, chance of a lifetime.
- We go to France in two weeks.
- Two weeks?
Oh Roy said you're sailing the 15th.
Is that so?
- Bored?
- Tired, take me home, Monte.
- Home?
- It's not far.
I've taken a flat in town,
near Canteen Headquarters.
But, I mean...
- Roy will be quite upset to find you gone.
- That's what he gets for being on committee.
- But, really...
- Very well, I'll find someone else.
- Oh, I didn't mean to be rude.
- Well, come on then.
- Are we here?
- Well, it's number 27.
Want to come up for a cigarette and a drink?
- Oh really, you must be awfully tired.
- No, I'm not.
Come see my room, I've only had
a place of my own for a week.
It's a new toy.
What a baby you are.
- Alley-oop.
- Alright.
Well, this is jolly.
- Sit down and I'll get you a drink.
- Thanks.
- Say when.
- Whoa. When, when.
Would you be shocked if I put
on something more comfortable?
I'll try to survive.
- Well, are you more comfortable now?
- Yes, are you?
Oh, yes.
You know, it seems
strange being here like this...
after hearing Roy rave about you for months.
- Does Roy rave?
- Oh rather, he idolizes you.
Oh, I do wish he
wouldn't, it makes me feel guilty.
- I can understand his raving now.
- Oh, don't be silly.
- You're not a bit like Roy, are you?
- I should say not.
Roy is frightfully high
minded, he doesn't approve of me.
He wouldn't approve of me
either if he knew what I'm really like.
- Doesn't he know?
- No.
When I'm with Roy,
I'm the way Roy wants me to be.
That's caddish,
isn't it? But I can't help it.
- I understand.
- Roy wouldn't.
- May I ask you a very personal question?
- Yes.
Do you love Roy?
No, not really. Not the way
Roy wants me to love him, I can't.
Roy's love means marriage and
children and never anyone but Roy.
I couldn't bear that, I want to
be free, I want to be gay and have fun.
Life is short and I
want to live while I'm alive.
I know that, that's the way I feel too.
I...
I think I'd better go.
- Must you?
- I really should.
Pull.
Cold in here now, isn't it?
Have you a match?
Why so gloomy?
- God, I'm rotten.
- I can't see it.
Can't you? Well, then you're rotten too.
- What do you mean?
- And Roy worships you.
- You.
- Well?
Don't you make yourself sick, you and Roy.
- God, that's funny.
- Get out of here.
Don't worry, I can't get out fast enough.
Get out and stay out.
Where you've been?
I stopped at a
at a bar after I took Helen home.
- How you like her?
- Oh, she's all right.
- Pass in a crowd, eh?
- I daresay she would.
Just what do you mean by that?
Listen Roy, let me tell
you something, even if it hurts.
Yes?
I wouldn't be so idealistic
about Helen if I were you.
And why not?
Well I, I just wouldn't, that's all.
- Well, why not?
- Oh, I don't know, forget it.
Never mind crawling, out with it.
Listen Roy, I tell you,
women are all the same.
You look at every woman as a barmaid.
You don't know anything about decent women.
- Oh, all right, you know it all then.
- No, you've said enough, shut up.
Karl. Karl.
Zep overhead.
- South by east.
- Right-O.
Yes sir, yes sir, right.
All lights out sir, lights out quick.
Zeppelin overhead,
Zeppelin overhead, everybody out.
- Hey, come on Monte.
- Zeppelin overhead.
Come on Monte, what's the
matter with you? Get up.
- We don't all have to go, I'm tired.
- Oh, shut up.
- Let's go, hurry up, come on.
- Be right with you Elliot.
- Come on Monte, get up.
- Alright.
Alright, let's go, hurry.
Karl...
Karl.
Danke.
- Well, so long there Tommy.
- Good luck Elliot.
Alright old chap.
- Go get them Monte.
- Goodbye.
- Good luck Roy.
- Right.
Perfect.
Look Roy, there she goes.
Let's go.
Kapitan?
Kapitan, Kapitan.
Kapitan. Kapitan.
Jawohl.
Hey Roy, they hit our motor.
Cut the gas, we'll burn to death.
- Roy.
- Oh, shut up.
Well, this is a mess, all right.
- Yeah, just our luck.
- Lucky we weren't both killed.
Well, we're through.
Herr Kapitan.
- Look at it Monte.
- Roy, it's falling.
- Look at that Roy.
- Great, isn't it?
They're done for.
Look out, run.
Just a minute.
Why the blazes don't you
look where you're going sir?
I'm sorry sir.
Isn't it customary to
salute one's superior officer?
- Thank you, what is your name sir?
- Lieutenant Roy Rutledge.
- Make a note of that.
- Yes sir.
Would you like to try it and find out?
They are, they glisten in the sun.
What the hell you trying to do?
Took me three hours to write that.
- You're nothing but a pest anyhow.
- Shut up and get out.
Have a little fun.
- You shouldn't smoke so many.
- What difference is it make?
- You know it's bad for you.
- Buy a chocolate Miss.
- Change Miss.
- Please.
- That's a good boy.
- What a life it would be married to you.
- Oh, you don't fancy it?
- Beastly, no smokes.
- Think of all the money we'd save.
- What would we spend it on?
- Oh, a diamond dog collar.
- For me?
No, I'd buy a muzzle for you.
You wouldn't spoil my
beautiful mustache, would you?
No, we keep that in the parlor under glass.
- Hello Helen.
- Oh hello Roy.
Roy, I'd like you to meet
Captain Redfield. Lieutenant Rutledge.
- How do you do?
- Beastly weather.
- Yes, isn't it.
- You'll get used to it.
- Thanks.
Gee, it's great to see you again
Helen, it's been four whole days.
Really?
- Have you been over long?
- Three weeks.
Oh. Three weeks.
- Everything all right up your way?
- Oh, yes.
- Your squadron near here?
- Twenty miles up the line.
Twenty miles, that far.
- You chaps have it rather soft, haven't you?
- Do you think so?
Well, I mean to say being able to
dash about the countryside and all that.
- Wish I'd picked the RFC.
- Well, why didn't you?
Roy.
- Well, I be going.
- Oh, don't go.
I think I'd better.
Goodbye Helen and don't forget your promise.
I won't.
Who's that bag of wind?
Would you mind
not talking about my friends like that?
- Oh now, Helen please.
- Oh, you were perfectly beastly to him.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry,
guess my nerves are a bit raw.
- Things haven't been so easy this last week.
- Oh, you've been fighting?
- Did you shoot down any Boche?
- Yes, I managed to get a couple.
Really? How thrilling, tell me about it.
- Oh, it's really nothing much to tell.
- Three bars of chocolate Miss.
- Oh, Jymes.
- Bread Jymes, we want bread.
- We want bread.
Coming sirs, coming.
Did you ever try hurrying Jymes?
Sorry sir but I stopped to dig
a few of the cockroaches out of it sir.
Well, put it down.
- Well, where is the bread?
- Did you ever try hurrying sir?
Jymes, more bread.
- Drown the cockroaches this time.
- Yes sir.
- Jymes, what's the taste in this soup?
- I can't say sir.
- It's not soup, it's soap.
- Say, I think it's shoe Polish.
Right.
Sorry sir, cook said the
soup was a bit weak tonight.
Maybe you taste
the disinfectant in the water sir.
Well, strike me blind, it's a hair.
Wash it off and wear it Baldy.
- Hello, you chaps.
- Hello Monte, how goes it?
- Still no news of Harry?
- No.
Somebody always gets it on the night patrol.
What do you think Marryat? You saw it happen,
is there any chance he got down alive?
No, I don't think
so, the searchlights got him.
We were flying low and they heard us,
we started to climb but it was too late.
Shrapnel began bursting all around him, two
bursts caught him and he started to drop.
It was awful to see him down there, twisting
and diving, crippled, always dropping.
Trying every way to get clear of
those lights, then another burst got him.
- We could hear him screaming...
- Stop, I can't stand it.
Good thing he took your place
Rutledge, you might've got it instead of him.
Oh, I'll get it sooner or later, we'll
all get it. Isn't there any end to this?
- Oh, shut up, you're always whining.
- Shut up yourself.
- Who'll make me?
- I'll make you.
- Sit down Jack and be quiet.
- Alright, what's the matter with you fellas?
Would anybody like to take
Monte's place on tonight's patrol?
Lay off.
- No more soup.
- We need some.
- We need some soup.
Jymes. Hurry it up.
Splendid.
Splendid, Jymes.
- Splendid.
- That's what comes from hurrying.
What was dinner before you dropped it Jymes?
- A tasty bit of salmon sir.
- Sewer trout again?
Hasn't the cook anything else?
- Well sir, it's that tin of pork and beans.
- No, we don't want it.
Can he do anything with the garbage?
Oh well, never mind,
we aren't hungry, are we?
- Coffee Jymes.
- Yes sir.
- And Jymes.
- Yes sir?
- Don't let anything hurry you.
- No sir.
Drinking again?
- You dirty louse.
- Hey Baldy.
- The sooner you get shot down, the better.
- Oh, Baldy darling.
- Now that didn't hurt Baldy.
- Baldy...
Attention.
As you were.
Following officers
will report for night patrol.
- Drayton.
- Yes sir.
- Fuller.
- Here sir.
Maloney.
Oh no, not an old bald headed man
like me up there in the cold, cold air.
Perhaps Fritz will warm it up for you.
- Neville.
- Here sir.
Monte Rutledge.
- I don't feel very well tonight sir.
- That's all right boy, none of us feel well.
- But you don't understand.
- I think I do Rutledge.
But I say sir, you don't understand, there
seems to be something the matter with me.
I know what's the
matter with him, he's yellow.
- Oh, shut up.
- Oh, let's say it.
Didn't Harry go west last night
because he took this man's place?
- Keep quiet Jack.
- I'll not keep quiet.
- He's yellow and we all know it.
- That's a lie, I'm not yellow.
I can see things as they are, that's all.
And I'm sick of this rotten business.
You fools, why do you
let them kill you like this?
What are you fighting for?
Patriotism, duty, are you mad?
Can't you see they're just words?
Words coined by politicians and profiteers
to trick you into fighting for them.
What's a word compared
with life, the only life you've got.
I'll give them a word, murder. That's
what this dirty rotten politician's war is.
Murder, you know it
as well as I do. Yellow, am I?
You're the ones that are yellow.
I've got guts to say what I think.
You're afraid to say it, so afraid to be
called yellow, you'd rather be killed first.
You fools, you poor, stupid fools.
Oh Monte now, pull
yourself together, will you?
Stand up Rutledge.
I've taken a lot of shirking from you since
we came out here but this is a bit too much.
Sir, he really is ill.
You're a disgrace to your squadron.
- Go to your quarters.
- Yes sir.
Have a cigarette.
You don't think I'm yellow, do you Roy?
Why, of course not, you're just
more sensitive than the rest of us.
- I wonder.
- Stop thinking about it.
I wish I could.
Haven't I been up twice on the
night patrol? I'm trying to do my share.
Of course you are now.
You, you must be pretty well
fed up with me after all this.
- Oh, that's rot.
- I'm not yellow.
I'm not.
Oh now Monte,
come on, pull yourself together.
Staff Colonel, everybody out.
Come on Monte.
Stand easy.
Well men, I don't like
what I have to say but let's face it,
You all know the
central munitions dump at Spraug.
You've tried three times
to bomb that depot without success.
No fault of yours, of course,
they've guarded it too closely.
That munitions depot at Spraug
must be destroyed tomorrow morning.
Now, then, today a German bombing
plane was forced down within our lines.
We were lucky enough to capture it
before they had a chance to destroy it.
We fixed it up so it'll fly.
And we want to use this plane
to bomb the Spraug depot.
There's no question that
the venture will succeed this time.
The enemy won't suspect one of their
own planes until after the depot is bombed.
Then, when they discover the trick...
well, you you may have
a little difficulty in getting back.
I need two men to fly this plane.
- I'll go sir.
- Are you sure you want to go?
- Quite sure sir.
- Very well.
I'll go with him sir.
- Who are these men?
- Lieutenants Monte and Roy Rutledge sir.
- Brothers, eh?
- Dismissed.
Now, young men,
I want you to realize how important this is.
The Seventh Brigade is
been ordered to go over the...
top in a surprise attack
tomorrow evening at dusk.
The brigade doesn't know it but I, I'm
afraid they're going to be slaughtered.
There's too much artillery in front of us.
If you destroy that munitions
depot early tomorrow morning...
it will weaken the enemy artillery,
and we may be able to get through.
Hundreds of lives depend on you.
- You understand?
- Yes sir.
Now, another thing.
The plane you are to fly is far too
dangerous a piece of armament...
to let the enemy recapture it.
It must return or be destroyed.
If you were captured,
you'd be shot as spies anyway.
- Baldy.
- Oh, Baldy?
You'll take the morning patrol in
towards Spraug as far as you can.
You might possibly help
them get back, by all means.
Yes sir.
You'll get your maps and final
instructions just before taking off.
Report to the field at 3 A. M.
Until then, let them do as they please.
- 3 o'clock, you two.
- Yes sir.
- Good luck.
- Thank you sir.
Thank you sir.
- What time is it, Monte?
- Ten past 9.
Helen's canteen closes at 10,
we've just enough time to get there.
You think they'll let us have the motorcycle?
- Why, of course, we're it tonight.
- Yeah, we're it all right.
- Not sorry, are you?
- Oh, let's not talk about it.
I'm not even going to
think about it until 3 o'clock.
What's your program? Wine, women and song?
Oh, perhaps I'll do without the song tonight.
See you at Grosson's?
Either there or at Jacques across the
street, wherever you hear the most noise.
Don't you want to come
in with me to see Helen?
- Oh, I better not.
- Right-O.
- Where's Helen?
- She's gone out.
- Was she expecting you?
- No.
Would you care to leave a note?
- Yes, I think I will.
- Pen and ink on the table.
- You'll see that she gets this?
- Oh, yes.
- Thank you, good night.
- Good night.
- Hello, what's up?
- She isn't in.
That's tough, want to come along with me?
- Where to?
- Grosson's.
Right-O.
Your switch on?
Will you close it, will you?
- Helen.
- Well, if it isn't old Roy.
Old solemn Roy himself.
Sit down Roy, Sit down the
floor and hang your legs over.
- Take your hands off her.
- Oh, I can't take my hands off.
You heard what I said,
take your hands off her.
- Who asked you to this party anyway?
- Oh Helen, let me take you home.
Home? Who wants to go home?
I'm having a marvelous time.
I was until you came in.
I advise you to get out
before you're kicked out.
Keep your, keep your
filthy hands off of my girl.
Your girl? You fool, I wouldn't belong
to you if you were the last man on Earth.
- You're nothing to me, nothing.
- Come on Roy, let's get out of here.
Oh, let's have it out,
I don't love you, I never have.
I never had any fun with you
anyway, you and your high ideals.
You're too good to live, you're
just a stupid prig if you ask me.
You make me sick, do you hear? Sick.
Now get out here, I hate the sight of you.
Come on Roy, let's go across the street.
Sweet, sweet baby.
Handsome, big, strong baby. N'est-Ce pas?
- N'est-Ce pas kiss Papa, eh?
- Oh baby.
Hello Cheri.
- Ah, don't take it so hard Roy, forget it.
- Is your friend sick?
No, he'll be all right, drink up Roy.
I still can't believe it.
You just don't know anything
about women, they're all the same.
I've been telling you that for
years, maybe you'll believe me now.
- Helen is not that sort.
- Oh, nonsense.
- It's the war, she's changed.
- No, you're wrong Roy.
War doesn't change people. It's...
it's like getting drunk, it
brings out what people really are.
You can't make me believe
Helen was like that before.
- Well, she was, I've known it all along.
- You too?
Oh, I'm sorry Roy, don't
take it so hard. She isn't worth it.
- I suppose you're right.
- Of course I'm right.
Listen Roy, never love
a woman, just make love to her.
You see, like this, look.
Go ahead Roy, try it.
That's the way.
Oh. What you do baby?
All wet, no, no, no, no.
Imbecile, Oh baby, voila.
Hey listen Monte, Monte go
easy, we got to go up at 3 o'clock.
Oh listen Roy, the hell
with this 3 o'clock business.
- What you mean?
- Just that, to hell with it.
Say, you're crazy Monte,
we can't get out of it now.
Oh, why can't we?
Listen Roy, all this idealistic
stuff won't get you anywhere.
You tried it on Helen and what
happened? You got a kick in the face.
You can't go through life
thinking the way you do.
The people take advantage of you
and make a fool of you the way she did.
It's beginning to
look as though you're right.
Of course I'm right.
I was right about Helen and now I'm
right about this 3 o'clock business too.
- This is another thing entirely Monte.
- Why is it?
They're just taking advantage
of you in another way, that's all.
It's chaps like you that are meat for them.
All they got to do is make it
sound heroic and you fall for it.
Hey listen Roy, what's
the difference if we don't go?
- But we can't get out of it now.
- Why can't we?
Listen, tell them, tell
them the motorcycle broke down.
Tell them anything, what do you say Roy?
Well...
- Come on, old ooh-la-la.
- Oh, no, no, no, Cheri.
Oh baby.
- N'est-Ce pas?
- Oh, oui, oui madam.
Oh baby.
Oh, stop looking at your watch
Roy, you're not going anywhere.
- Yes I am and so are you.
- Who said I am?
Listen Monte, we're a little drunk
and we've been talking wildly.
It's no way out of this
and we know it, come on Monte.
No, no, let me alone. Come on, old ooh-la-la.
Monte.
Why, they'd court-martial us
in a minute if we didn't show up.
Why, that's desertion
Monte, they shoot people for that.
Come on, let's get out of here, come on.
- Come on.
- I suppose you're right.
- Oh, no, no, no, no Monte.
- What a pair of fools we are.
Let's go.
- Easy, now.
- Easy.
Look out for the firing pin.
Right-O, I got it.
- Contactor.
- Contact.
Just for altitude and ground speed
here, keep this site trained on the target.
Then pull the release when you
hit the stop, you understand?
- Don't forget the leveler, goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- Contactor.
- Contact.
Remember this ship
weighs 20,000 pounds, good luck.
Thank you.
Roy, the depot.
Roy, look there.
They've seen us, they coming on us.
For Christ's sake.
Hey Roy, look. They hit our right motor.
I got him.
Roy, look over there.
It's our squadrons, they coming.
Roy, they've gone.
Jesus.
Son of a Boche.
Hey.
It's me. Hey, it's me, god damn it.
- It's old Baldy. Hey. Baldy.
- Hello, it's Baldy, look Roy.
It's Baldy.
You see that guy?
Look at old good Baldy.
Good boy, see that? He's got him.
Hey look, he's got him, he's got him.
They've changed around.
Our strut is gone, that son of a bitch.
Roy, he got us. Roy,
go down, go down, go down.
One more for Baldy.
No more control?
Pull her up.
Oh, my God, we're on fire, we're burning.
Roy, get down.
Do something Roy.
Ah so, we meet again.
It was you who bombed
the depot at Spraug, nicht wahr?
Yes.
And you were flying
a German plane, nicht wahr?
- Yes.
- Very clever.
It is a pity you must take
your congratulations from me.
There are a few questions I must ask you...
if you answer them
simply, it will be easy for you.
To what squadron of the
Royal Flying Corp are you attached?
Just why were you sent to bomb
that munitions depot this morning?
Was our natural target.
But possibly it was to clear the
way for a little surprise attack, eh?
You are surprised.
We know all about it,
so you need not be afraid to talk.
Now please, when and
where is the attack to be made?
Oh, you are stupid
not to tell, it is nothing.
For you the war is
over, nicht wahr? We are friends.
Listen, if you tell me, I will see
that you are sent to a special camp...
reserved only for certain prisoners of war.
It's near Munich, far away from all this.
You will have every comfort.
And in a few months
from now, when the war is over...
you will be alive and in good health, which
is more than most of us will be able to say.
So, you see? It can be easy for you.
Now please.
So, you will not tell?
Possibly you do not
know that flying a German...
plane is the same
as wearing a German uniform.
Any disguised soldier is a spy, nicht wahr?
And you know what happens to spies?
I think you two friends
had better talk it over.
I will give you 15 minutes.
If you change your mind and tell, good.
If not, you will be shot.
- Do you think he was bluffing?
- No, he wasn't bluffing.
He's the man I was to fight that duel with.
Really? Quite a coincidence.
- He's got it in for me.
- No, he's probably forgotten by this time.
The brigade will be
going over pretty soon Monte.
Yes.
Roy, look.
Oh, save it to wipe your nose on.
God, what nerve.
Roy.
Roy, I can't face it.
- I'm going to tell.
- Don't be a fool Monte.
Do you realize what it would mean if we told?
Would mean being
alive when this bloody war's over.
But Monte, you can't.
To hell with your heroic stuff,
I want to live, I'm not
going to be shot down like that.
- I'm going to tell.
- Wait a minute Monte.
- But I...
- Listen.
- Let me go.
- You?
Yes, you're all upset.
I'll bargain with him and perhaps
I won't have to tell him everything.
- I, I'll come with you.
- No.
You said he's got it in
for you, now let me do it alone.
Alright.
- Tell the general I'm ready to talk.
- Good, come.
Ah, yes.
- So, you've changed your mind?
- Yes.
My friend will never tell.
- But I want to live, I'm ready to talk.
- You are very wise.
Now please,
draw a rough map for me showing
your positions, brigade numbers...
disposition, hour of attack,
purpose, number of men.
Wait a minute.
I'll tell only on one condition.
- Ah, so, a condition?
- Yes.
If I give this
information, my friend will know it.
Back home after the war, he'll
tell everyone that I was a traitor.
You leave that to me.
Why not let me have that satisfaction?
What do you mean?
I do not understand.
One does not kill a friend.
Friend? He's not my friend.
He stole the girl I love and I hate him.
History repeats itself.
You make rather hard terms.
I'll tell only on that condition.
One bullet.
What if I miss? Give me two to make sure.
No, a good soldier will need only one.
- Very well.
- Not so fast.
He will give you the bullet outside.
Well?
I didn't tell Monte.
Why? What happened? Has he changed his mind?
No, don't you think you
can go through with it now?
What do you mean?
Of course we can, it won't even hurt.
It'll all be over in a second, we
can stand anything for a second.
No, no Roy, I, I can't do it.
- I'm going to tell.
- Listen Monte.
We tell, the whole brigade will be wiped out.
Three thousand men
and they all want to live too.
You wouldn't spoil their chances, would you?
That's not my business, I didn't start
this war, I didn't get them into this mess.
Let them take care of themselves, they'll
get wiped out sooner or later anyway.
I want to live, live.
You won't tell, I'll tell.
- Listen Monte...
- I'll tell, I'll tell.
Let me out, I'll tell everything I know.
The brigade is moving up.
They're going to attack...
Oh Roy...
Oh Monte, Monte...
Monte.
Don't cry Roy.
It was the only thing you...
could do.
- The brigade Roy.
- Yes, Monte?
- They'll be all right now, won't they?
- Yes.
- Who is that?
- It's the general.
You thought we'd tell, didn't you?
Good old Roy.
You won't tell and I...
forgotten it all.
- Oh Roy, Roy...
- Yes.
Where are you? Don't go away Roy.
I'm here, Monte.
Can't you feel me holding you?
Hello Karl, fig eights.
Cold up here in the night
patrol, awful to be in the dark.
Oh. I'm afraid.
Look out, look out.
We're falling, we're
going to crash, do something Roy.
Quick, quick, quick.
It's all right Monte, Monte?
It's all right.
Monte? Monte.
Well?
- You heard what my brother said.
- Your brother?
I'll never tell you anything.
Achtung.
I'll be with you in just a minute Monte.
Come on you Seventh Brigade, we got them now.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org