Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org
Minnie?
Coming right out, dear.
Freshen up this drink.
What's the matter, Cab?
Are ya blind?
Don't you see anything?
Yes, I see something.
I see that my drink
needs freshening up.
Okay, Cab.
I'll fix your drink for you.
But how about singing that song
you wrote about me?
My song.
And sing it
like you really meant it,
huh, Cab?
Sure, Minnie, sure.
Minnie's a hep cat now
She's as sharp
as the cats allow
Say, she's really up to date
when she's topped out
in her drape
Minnie's a hep cat now
Whoa, there ain't
no more Smoky Joe
She's fluffed off
his hi-de-ho
She's a solid jitterbug
when she starts to cut a rug
Oh, Minnie's a hep cat now
Minnie's a hep cat now
Thanks.
You ain't sung it with feeling
since that gal Nettie
took an interest in you.
I'll see you dead
before I let anyone
take you from me.
I'll get it.
Hi, Nettie.
Come in, Nettie.
Uh, no thanks, Cab.
I've got something important
to tell you,
then I must run.
Well, give, honey, give,
I'm all ears.
Well, you'd better be
all voice
because I've arranged
an audition for you tonight
at 6:00.
I'll bring along
a good booking agent,
also the proprietor
of the little jive club
up here to hear you then.
Little jive club?
Well, I know it's not big,
but it's a start.
Remember, a journey
of a thousand miles
begin with but a single step.
Well, I appreciate it, Nettie.
Uh, so tell me what to do,
Manager.
Well, you have your boys ready.
Have them up here
for the audition
at 6:00 tonight.
I'll be ready at 6:00.
Cab, can't you see that gal
is a first-class moocher?
She's not the moocher.
It's you, Minnie.
Yes, my dear, you,
Minnie the Moocher.
She's trying to take you
away from me.
Don't be silly, Minnie.
Nettie's interest in me
is strictly business.
She's trying to help me
make a success of things.
Success means money,
and money means trouble.
Aren't you happy with me
like this, Cab?
Cab, if you walk out on me now,
you'll be sorry.
Oh, Minnie, behave.
I gotta go get
the boys together
for an audition here at 6:00.
You grab me
before I get my dinner down
Jack, we started in
poppin' all around the town
To me it's solid labor,
the jive you think is fun
You forget about romance
when labor's done
Dancin'
You're always dancin'
without romancin"
till dawn time
Laggin'
My feet are laggin'
My heart is draggin'
at dawn time
Before you realize,
the moon will leave the skies
And when the sun
shines up above
that ain't no time to love
Dawn time.
I think it's our time
to say you'll be mine
at dawn time
Before you realize,
the moon will leave the skies
And when the sun's shining
up above,
that ain't no time to love
Dawn time
I think it's our time
to say you'll be mine
at dawn time
Dawn time
At dawn time
You wanna hear another?
Sure, why not?
Livin' and the jive is right
Livin'
Oh, tonight's the night
Give it
Come on, old man, come on
We the cats shall hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
Here's this beat to hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
You gotta come on like G.I.
You dig the repeat
from me, sigh
You put it
right on the Lehigh
Then you can really get by,
oh my
We the cats shall hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
Now you're hep, I'll bet ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
You didn't tell me
he was this good.
Well, I didn't know it myself.
We the cats shall hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
Here's this beat to hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
You gotta come on like G.I.
You dig the repeat
from me, sigh
You put it
right on the Lehigh
Then you can really get by,
oh my
We the cats shall hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
Now you're hep, I'll bet ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
This guy Calloway is great,
just what the doctor ordered
for the Brass Hat Club.
You said it,
and that's where he belong,
not in a little jive spot.
And the Brass Hat Club
will be in a tough spot
when Boss Mason opens
his New York-type club
across the street from him
if they don't have
a good band
to hold the business.
But, well, Boss Mason
is a tough racketeer.
It would be dynamite
to mess up with him.
Don't worry, I'll let
his manager do the messing up.
Oh, you gotta come on like G.I.
You dig the repeat
from me, sigh
You put it right
on the Lehigh
Then you can really get by,
oh my
We the cats shall hep ya
Oh, you reap
this righteous riff
Bop-bop
Now you're hep, I'll bet ya
This righteous riff
Mr. Calloway,
we have a business proposition
to make you.
Business proposition?
Well, you see, fellas,
I have a manager now
and she takes care of
all the business propositions.
Gentlemen, my manager.
I'll fix him.
Come in.
If you're through lookin',
now listen.
May I see the proprietor?
The which?
The gentleman who owns
this establishment.
Oh, you mean the guy
that runs the joint.
Right this way, lady.
All right, so Calloway's
out of this world
and it's liable to put me
out of business.
So what do you want me
to do about it?
What he's got there
ain't no tumor.
You know, I like you.
Huh, Mo?
Yeah, maybe she's got
a friend for me.
Listen, stupid,
this is no laughing matter.
Wait a minute, sister.
Nobody talks to the boss
that way.
No one but her.
Sit down, Mo.
Tell me, sister,
just what do you do?
When I work, I sing.
Yeah?
And I bet
you're pretty good at it.
And, um, we can get
more musicians
and call it
Cab Calloway and His Band.
But Mason is opening up
in two days.
Can Calloway be ready by then?
They'll be right up there
on the bandstand
packing 'em in.
You're right, Nettie.
People start for Mason's club.
When they hear Calloway's music,
they head right in here.
Boy, I bet Mason is burning up.
Minnie was right.
We should've bumped Calloway off
before tonight.
I'm lonesome out there.
Not a customer in the joint.
Hey, Mo,
why don't you go over there
and rub out Calloway?
That'll stop the music.
Then everybody will flock
in here.
That's a good idea, Minnie.
I give orders around here,
no one else.
Don't listen to that
big bag of wind, Mo.
Do as I tell ya.
Listen, you!
You better watch your step.
-Oh, I know what I'm doing.
-Shut up!
-Come with me, Mo.
-Yes, sir.
You want to see me?
Yes, on business.
Oh, business.
Well, I'll call my manager.
Nettie, my manager.
I'm Mason.
This is Mo, the Mouse.
How do you do, uh, gentlemen?
If you and your boys will come
across the street to my place,
I'll pay you double
what you're getting here.
Not interested.
Don't be too hasty
with your decision.
Think it over.
I'll be in my office
waiting for your answer.
I'll give you half an hour
to make up your mind.
It better be yes.
Cab, I'm scared.
Ah, he's bluffing, Nettie.
Let's get a load
of this next act.
You could stand a good laugh.
Oh, Dusty Fletcher.
I ain't drunk!
I ain't drunk, man!
-I ain't drunk!
-Get out of here!
Get out of that bar!
I told you about coming in
and stealing whiskey on the bar
every time somebody
turn their back!
- I didn't steal...
-You did steal the whiskey!
If I catch you in there again,
I'll kick your teeth out
one by one!
-No, you won't.
-No, I what?
I said, "Yes, you will."
Listen, I'm a bad bean
from Boston,
and I was born
with boxing gloves on.
Yeah, and you keep
messing with me
and you gonna die
the same way too.
Got him telling me he's
a bad bean from Boston.
When I get through with him,
he'll be a has-been.
I'll go back and break up
his joint.
Getting mad 'cause I won't
buy no drinks.
Ain't no use in me buying
when everybody else is buying.
I ain't been buying no liquor
and I ain't gonna start now.
I'm gonna keep on drinking
to everybody's health
until I ruin my own.
Yeah, he comes grabbing me
in the collar.
Well, he won't grab nobody else
"cause I'm going back
and relieve him
of his grabbles,
that's what I'm gonna do.
Yeah, I'll break up his joint.
Yeah, I'll break it up!
I'll stick a match
to your joint,
burn it down to the ground.
Don't tell me
how to live my life.
I'll--me, I'd run him
out of town.
Run him out of town!
I'll run him as long as he can
find something to step on.
He gonna tell me something.
I'll go back and run him
back to--
I'll go--I'll go back
in there...
Well, I ain't going back today,
but I'm gonna try
to make it tomorrow.
And tomorrow at 2:00.
I'm going on home
and get me some sleep.
I got to get off the street
'cause I don't want my pastor
to see me like this.
Yeah, you have to be
so careful these days
"cause people are so quick
to scandalize your name.
And I don't think my name
would stand
in the most scandalized.
So I'm gonna
get on in the house
and get me some sleep,
that's what I need.
I'll get on it.
You know, that's a shame.
I know I ain't drunk.
Just that whiskey is heavy,
that's all.
They ought to stop people
from drinking whiskey
and they're haggard.
Get drunk
and it makes you act so common.
And I know I ain't common
"cause I got some class
I ain't never used yet.
He's gonna tell me something
about Green River Street.
I know about that street.
Like I told a boy
last Saturday night, I...
Yeah.
It ain't no use.
Yes, I'll get in the house here
and wake up everybody
so I can go to sleep.
That's the way I do that,
you know.
...but I see him--
I better... I see him.
All right,
open the door, Richard.
That's the boy I rooms with.
Now what's the matter with him?
Hey, open that door up there,
Richard!
Now I know he ain't
gone out nowhere,
'cause I got on the clothes.
Now what's the matter with him?
Hey, open the door, Richard!
That's the reason I don't like
to room with nobody.
He don't want
to open the door for me,
and I owe just as much rent
up there as he do.
I think I'm gonna move
next Saturday,
"cause this old woman,
she chargin'
too much rent anyhow.
Three dollars a month.
Yeah, and got the nerve
to be mad
because we're 11 months
in arrears.
Why, she come askin' me
this mornin', she said,
"When you boys gwine give me
some of my back rent?"
I just told her she lucky
she gettin' the front rent
outta me.
Aw, why don't you open the door,
Richard?
Then, she come askin' me
when I'se gwine to work,
and I ain't thinkin'
'bout no work.
I don't want no job.
I'm goin' back on relief Monday.
I was on relief last summer,
but I don't know,
they got short of help
and they couldn't send
your checks out,
and you hadda go get 'em
and all that,
so I put it down.
What'cha gonna do
"bout the door, Richard?
I don't think
he gonna do nothin'.
But I'll get in.
I'll go around
through the back
and I'll come 'round
through the alley.
I don't need no Richard
to open no door.
I just didn't want a be walkin'
in no dark alleys
this time of night.
I'm walkin' in the alley
and somebody stick me up.
I got to get hurt
'cause I has nothin' to offer.
So I gotta get on in the house.
I've got to get a little sleep,
I know I do.
Now you know I ain't never
drank no whiskey before
that won't let you go
nowhere.
Here, here's another thing!
You keep this ladder
out of this bar.
And you stay out too.
- I didn't bring no ladder.
-You did bring the ladder
-in there.
-Cab Calloway brought it.
I don't care who brought
the ladder in there.
You keep it out.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Okay with me, pal.
It's all right with me.
You tell me
if I can keep it out.
All right, did you tell...
give me half a pint of whiskey,
did you tell her that?
Did you tell her that?
-Come on, give me--
-Listen.
Dusty, you didn't paint
no kitchen.
What did you do with the paint
I had in that bottle?
Yeah, I did!
What was that?
What did you do with the paint
I had in that bottle?
Paint?
Was there paint
in that bottle?
Oh, man, you should
have told me 'fore now.
You put paint
in a whiskey bottle
and set it in front of me?
Well, get me
some paint remover then.
I'll drink that.
-Come on, get--
-Listen, Dusty.
Why don't you get yourself
a job and go to work?
No, you--what is that?
Why don't you get yourself
a job and go to work?
Me? Go to work?
Son, you known me
for a million days, didn't ya?
You ever known me to work?
You ever known anybody
who's known me to work?
Well, coincidentally,
did you ever know anybody
who knows somebody
who thought I'd have ideas
where to work?
Well, don't worry, you won't.
Now, you are impossible!
I don't care what I am,
I ain't tired.
He don't tell me how to live.
Just like I told him
that just...
Now ain't this somethin'.
Now, this old woman
across the street,
she sees everything that happens
in the neighborhood.
Look at her.
Now she done spied
on me already.
She done called her sister
to the window for witness.
She wants to make sure
this is me.
She keep on asking her sister,
"Ain't that him?
Ain't that him?"
Yes, this is me
and I'm drunk again!
I just hope
she says something about me
in the meeting Sunday,
and I'll have her whole family
throwin' eyes at me.
Her husband come out there
last Sunday,
he was so "ineeberated"...
"Ineeberated"...
When he got on his knees
to pray, he went to sleep.
I had to sober up right quick
and pray for him.
I ain't got no time
to be prayin' for nobody.
I got my own soul to sterilize.
But I'm glad you threw
this old ladder out here.
I'll take it
and get on in the house
and get a little sleep.
That's what I gotta do.
Don't open the door, Richard.
Ah, don't open no door.
Uh-huh, I don't want you
to open no door.
I don't want you
to do nothin'.
I'll take my ladder
and climb up on top.
I don't need no Richard.
He want somebody big...
I'll get in by myself.
I don't need him to tell me
how to live my life.
I'll climb up on top.
Tell me how to live my life...
This is my life,
I live my life myself.
I don't need nobody
to tell me.
How to live my life.
He gonna tell me something.
I'm coming on up there, Richard.
He gonna say...
I don't need Richard,
I don't need nobody to tell me
how to live my life.
I don't think
I'm gonna be here long, Richard.
Then he come tellin' me
...how to live my life,
I'm high as a Georgia pine.
But it ain't no use
in bein' too high up.
I get in, I climb up
and tell somebody.
I didn't know
how to live my life.
I get it.
I-I don't need Richard.
Oh, why don't you open
that door, Richard?
Here like
we're paying customers.
So we are.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
we'd like to do
a little novel number,
a tune entitled "Hey Now."
When I say, "Hey now,"
I want everybody to shout,
"Hey now!"
Come on.
Hey now!
Good.
Hey now, hey now
I was walkin' up the street,
feelin' bad and bold
Deep down in my pockets
I didn't have no gold
I looked up to the sky,
to my surprise
I saw a million dollar bill
floatin' before my eyes
I said hey now, hey now
Hey now, hey now
-Hey now!
I took the million dollars
and began to look for some more
Kept goin' up the street,
this time a little more slower
When I got to the corner,
I started right in to shout
I met a good,
fine little chick
that knew
what life was all about
I dug her,
I said hey now, hey now
I got the things I want
plus a great big car
Every day
I'm getting more popular
Say, Jack, if things go bad,
you don't know what to do
Dig this jive expression,
it will see you through
Just say hey now, hey now
Okay, fellas,
let's take a break.
Oh, Cab, you were wonderful,
they love you.
You do?
I said "they."
Oh, that's what I thought
you said.
Say, you must be exhausted.
Come on,
you'd better take a rest.
Well, here we are.
That's for you,
and this is for me.
Cab, I do hope
that racketeer Mason
didn't upset you
with his threat.
Nettie, I'm not worried.
Minnie was right.
I sure do miss her.
I've gotta hand it to her,
I was better off
before I started to click.
No headaches.
Look, Cab,
we made this business deal
on a handshake,
so if you want to quit,
I won't hold you to it.
Anyway, you're tired,
so we'll talk business later.
I'll see you later.
Come in.
Cab.
Minnie.
I was a fool.
I should have realized
there could be nothing
between you and Nettie
but just business.
Oh, Cab.
I came to warn you. Mason--
Cab, they're yelling for you
out here.
Be right out, Nettie.
But, Cab, you can't.
You've got--
Don't worry, honey,
I'm not afraid
of that mug Mason.
Oh, gosh, what shall I do?
And I tell you,
Mason's gonna kill him!
Well, I'm no undertaker.
And besides, how do you know
so much about it?
What's the difference?
I just know, that's all.
I guess we had better
do something about that,
and quick too.
Now?
He has two minutes yet.
-Hey, Cab.
-What's going on around here?
Buddy boy, there's foul play
around these crossroads.
Somebody wants you
to be a dead duck.
Please listen to us, Cab.
Well, my time is up,
I'm still livin'.
Quit worryin', that guy Mason
is only bluff in'.
I guess he thinks I'm bluffing.
Now, boss?
Yes, now.
Say, you wanted to climb in,
now I'm helpin' ya.
Come on in here.
Don't shoot me.
Get up there.
Come on, get up.
Get up.
Yes, but you didn't have to shut
that window on my wrists.
What did you want me to do,
ask you for the gun?
Thank heavens
you're all right, Cab.
Hi, Minnie.
I'm all right.
I'm gonna take this guy
straight to the station house.
Come on, let's get going.
All right, get going,
open the door, Minnie.
Go on, get out.
-Cab, look out!
Minnie, darling, speak to me.
Are you badly hurt?
Yes, I think so.
Put me on the couch in there.
Okay, boys,
Mason's rubbed out,
and I say good riddance
to bad rubbish.
Take little Mo
down to the station house,
and I hope he never gets out.
Minnie, you saved my life.
Why did you do it?
I figured you'd do something
for me sometime.
Sure, Minnie, anytime.
There isn't much time, Cab.
So will you--
will you sing my song?
The one you wrote about me.
And sing it like you meant it,
huh, Cab?
Sure, Minnie.
Sure.
Minnie's a hep cat now
She's as sharp
as the cats allow
When she's dressed up
in a drape
Oh, Jack, she's really great
Minnie's a hep cat now
Ten or more Smokey Joe
She done fluffed off
his hi de ho
She's a wild jitterbug
When she starts to cut a rug
Minnie's a hep cat now
Put your arms around me, Cab.
Sure, Minnie.
How'd you like
to blow your top
Dig yourself
some fine ree-bop
Hi-de-ho, he-de-he
Oh, the hi-de-ho man,
that's me
Say I hepped 'em in Holland
I hepped 'em in London
I hepped 'em in gay Paris
Yes sirree, yes sirree
Oh the hi-de-ho man,
that's me
Ain't you glad
you dug my jive
Look out, man,
I'll take that righteous five
Oh the hi-de-ho man,
that's me
Say, stay solid,
very groovy fella
And then you're gonna be
sharp as me
Yes sirree, yes sirree
Oh the hi-de-ho man,
that's me
Man, that's me
Thank you very much.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to present to you
the famous Peters Sisters.
Raindrops scatter down
like lovers' tears
My Sunday's not happy,
goodness knows
But when it rains,
my cup of sadness overflows
A rainy Sunday
A picture of you
And nothing to do but dream
A rainy Sunday
And memories we knew
go by in an endless stream
I just can't realize
we're apart
The thunder is an echo
of the sorrow in my heart
Don't go to movies
Can't finish a book
Keep turning my radio dial
For all around me
wherever I look
I still see your goodbye smile
in my mind
I'm resigned
I won't find a thing to do
On a rainy Sunday
without you
My dear
-In my mind
-I'm resigned
I won't find a thing to do
On a rainy Sunday
without you
My dear
Boys and girls,
come on and gather 'round,
cause there's
a brand new dance,
yes, it's hit this town
You can clap your hands,
and you can beat out time
-and when we're through--
-Jack, it's really fine
Well, look who's here?
-Look who's where?
-Well, how do you do?
Tell me, who are you?
I'm a little old lady
from Baltimore
From Baltimore?
Yes, from Baltimore
Meet the little old lady
from Baltimore
Well, let's see
what you can do
I'm the hip old lady
from Baltimore
From Baltimore!
Yes, Baltimore
She's a hip old lady
from Baltimore
Well, lead on,
we'll see you through
-Well, au reel.
-Can you dip?
I'm hip to that dip
And the Rain Jane too?
You mean the whole thing, too?
How about the boogie woogie?
I do that too
Oh well, jump back sister
we'll follow you
I'm the little old lady
from Baltimore
-She's from Baltimore
-Yeah, from Baltimore
A little old lady
from Baltimore
And it's groovy
What's groovy?
The thing
What thing?
That I do
Folk, I'm going down
to St. James Infirmary
to see my baby there
She's stretched out
on a long white table,
SO sweet,
so cold, so fair
Let it go, let it go
God bless her,
wherever she may be
She can search
this whole wide world over,
but she'll never find
another sweet man like me
When I die,
bury me
in my straight-leg britches,
put on a box-back coat
and a Stetson hat
Put a 20 dollar gold piece
on my watch chain,
So you can let
all the boys know
I died standing pat
Then give me six
crap-shooting pall bearers
Let a chorus girl
sing me a song
Put a red hot jazz band
at the top of my head,
SO we can raise
Hallelujah as we go along
Folks, now that you
have heard my story
Say, boy, hand me over
another shot of that booze
If anyone should ask you
you just tell 'em
I've got those
St. James Infirmary blues
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'd like to dedicate
the next number
to the girl I love.
JP Morgan's got dollars,
NYU's got scholars,
Capistrano's got swallows,
but I got a girl named Nettie
Fifty-second street
loves its reebop
Every butcher
loves a pork chop,
Every flower loves a dew drop,
But I love a girl named Nettie
A aeroplane needs a propeller
An ice man needs a pick,
A hot dog needs mustard
You bet I need my chick
Every wolf
has got a smooth line,
Every Frenchman
loves grape wine,
I'm not worried
'cause I've got mine,
I got a girl
named Nettie
Every jitterbug loves swing
A bookie loves a horse
Everybody loves something
I love to be my gal's boss
New York City's got subways
California's got warm days
Monte Carlo's got cafes
I got a girl named Nettie
Boston's got
its good baked beans
Gumbo's got its New Orleans
Got my girl
and her name is Nettie
Folks,
the girl I'm gonna marry,
not next year, not next month,
not next week,
not tomorrow,
but right now.
Don't falter
at the altar,
when you take
that great big step
Don't falter
at the altar,
because you try and be hip
Lift your feet high
Ain't no time to sigh
It's your last free mile
So smile, brother, smile
Don't falter
at the altar,
'cause you have
no cross to bear
You father didn't falter,
son, that's why you're here
I can see
by the bookings in this paper,
sister, that you're not booked.
So, don't you
get any notions, sister.
Will you take this woman
to be your lawful wedded wife?
I do, I do
A-to hold and to cherish
all the days of your life
I do, I do
Will you love this man
with all of your heart?
I will, I will
Through one-night stands
until death you do part?
I will, I will
Does anybody here,
living or dead,
who thinks these two
should not be wed?
I see no reason
why a man this sane
should take on himself
a ball and chain.
Overruled! Overruled!
I hope you two
never have a strife
Now here it is
You are now man and wife
kiss the bride
Kiss the bride!
Man and wife!
Hi de ho, man and wife.
Every jitterbug loves swing,
A bookie a loves a horse
Everybody loves something
I love to be my gal's boss
New York City's got subways
California's got warm days
Monte Carlo's got cafes
I got a girl named Nettie
Boston's got
its good baked beans
Gumbo's got its New Orleans
Got my girl,
and her name is Nettie
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm