What are you looking for?
Where is my hat?
Well, why don't you look for it?
Why don't i look for it?
I've looked everywhere!
- Everywhere?
- Yes. Everywhere that a hat might be.
That's the trouble with you wives,
You're always hiding things
so we can't find them.
I can't even find the telephone in this house.
But i'll find that hat if it's the last thing i do.
Yoo-Hoo.
Tilly.
Have you seen my hat?
- Why... L...
- Don't stand there stuttering!
- Have you seen my hat?
- Of course she's seen your hat.
You may leave.
There you are.
How do you expect me
to uphold the dignity of my home
When you belittle me
in front of the servants?
This has gone far enough.
If i don't find that hat,
I'm leaving this house
never to darken its doors again.
Ahem.
I'm gonna take one more look
And if i don't find it...
Have a care.
Oh, you've found it!
Yes. What was it doing under the bed?
Now where are you going?
I have an appointment with stanley.
What about our radio?
- What about it?
- It hasn't worked in three months.
Just because you've been
too indisposed to put up an aerial.
- I'll put it up tomorrow.
- You'll put it up today! Right now.
I thought you were going to meet me.
I was, but i've got to put the aerial up.
Mrs hardy wants to get japan.
Gee, i'd like to hear japan, too.
Do you mind if i help you?
I don't mind.
That is if you'll help me.
Back your car in.
- What's the matter?
- Get some water! Water!
Now pick that ladder up.
Pick up the ladder.
Well, come on, pick up those things.
The quicker we get the aerial up,
the quicker we get away.
W-Why don't you be... C-C-Careful?
Have you got everything?
Everything.
We don't have to go down for a thing.
Put one of those poles on that end.
Ohh!
Hey! What did you go down for?
Here. Now put that end on that pole.
Go ahead! Oh!
Take that.
Ohhhh!
Will you stop your playing?
I think you'd better go in the house
and i'll pass the wire down to you.
Well, go ahead.
Hook that on binding post a.
Listen! I think you better let that radio go.
I should say not!
I'll get that thing working
if it's the last thing i do.
Come on.
Now listen, if you don't be careful,
I'm gonna break your neck.
Oh, oliver, darling, this is terrible!
Don't cry over me, dear, i'm not hurt.
I'm not crying over you,
the man came and took the radio away.
Hey!
Get that thing out of here, will you?