- Here's Singapore, in
the south of Malaya.
Population approximately 550,000.
University, ship building,
important seaport.
- Doesn't it say anything
about the 32 nightclubs there?
- Have you already
worked down in Singapore?
Not to work.
However, I once had a
friend, an oil sheik.
He took me with him down there.
He was quite a guy.
Those are the guys that run around
in turbans, aren't they?
- Listen, honey, when they
take those turbans off
they're just like any other man.
Got a light?
Oh.
Looking forward to going to Singapore?
Mm, I don't really care when I dance,
as long as the pay's good.
That's him now.
Hm.
Hi.
- Hi.
I've already been to Singapore.
And you look like it.
Oh, Gary.
Ah, hello, Gary.
Hi, Georgia.
You're looking prettier every day.
How in the world do you do it?
- Mike.
- Yeah?
- Have you told the girls
what this is all about?
Sure, Gary, a tour for a dancing troop.
First engagement, Singapore.
I have 12 of them here to pick from.
Okay, Georgia, let the girls in.
We don't have much time.
- All right if we start
now, Mr. Blackwood?
Of course.
Oh, but one at a time, please.
Okay, May?
Smile, will you?
How do you do?
That's Mr. Webster, the manager.
And this is May.
She's the finest dancer in town.
What was your last engagement?
With the Corkettes, one year.
One of the finest.
Mm, legs?
Pardon me?
- Mr. Webster would like
to look at your legs.
Oh, sure.
Thank you, you're hired.
Please wait outside.
Oh, thank you.
Hm, May, Corkettes.
And this is Rhonda Hunter.
Dancer?
Not really.
But I pick things up real fast.
Hm.
Thank you, we're looking for dancers.
- But what's that got
to do with Singapore?
Come on, honey.
Don't hold us up.
Babs?
This is Babs.
Her legs are worth their weight in gold.
Can those golden legs also dance?
- I was solo dancer in
the Apollo Varieties.
And why did you leave there?
Well, the boss really went for her.
But his wife thought otherwise.
All right, you can work with us,
as long as you don't have any affairs.
Mr. Webster doesn't
tolerate any fooling around.
I had all the boys I can take.
Come on.
Carolyn.
This little one's from
the national ballet.
Could you dance a little bit for us?
Glad to.
Would you put this one on for me?
Sure, let's have a look.
Thank you, Carolyn.
You dance wonderfully.
But I'm afraid ballet is
not What we're looking for.
Oh.
Don't be sad, honey.
I tell you what, come in again tomorrow.
Yeah?
Yeah, I've got something else for you.
Oh, thanks.
Hello, Cat! Come in.
Hello, Gary! Hi, Georgia!
- Well, Cat? Lost some weight?
- I hardly eat anything anymore.
Well done, Cat. Just don't put on
any weight again. Please wait outside.
I'm looking forward to working
with both of you again!
All right.
Here are Gladys and Doreen.
I told you to let them in separately.
These babes have been working
from the start as a duo number.
- And we would very much like
to stay together, if possible.
- On this tour you'll be
dancing with other girls.
That doesn't matter.
As long as we get to go overseas.
All right, you can both work with us.
Please send the next one in.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- See you.
Linda.
Hello there.
Mm, you're a stripper?
At times.
- Didn't I see you work
the Sapphire Club last month?
How observant of you.
How come you quit that place?
The boss wanted to.
I didn't.
Oh, are you always so pickiunish?
That depends on the boss, boss.
Shall I dance for you?
It's not necessary.
You're hired.
Wait outside.
- Okay.
Next girl please.
My name is Nelly Hastings.
A new one, I haven't seen her work yet,
but she's always been with good troops.
Let's see her dance.
Thank you, you're hired.
Please wait outside.
So Mr. Blackwood has supplied
all the girls we need.
Fine, Georgia.
Go and tell the girls when
customer dance rehearsals
will start, will you please?
Okay
- All right.
- Listen, Gary, I thought
you were the boss.
But you let Georgia select all the girls.
I select all the girls.
You?
But you didn't say a word.
Why should I?
I have a little trick.
When I keep my legs apart like so,
it means I'm not interested.
When I cross them like
this, ah, then it's okay.
You always were a crazy guy.
When do things get underway?
Oh, 10 days.
10 days?
Well then, have a good trip.
Thank you.
We're now flying
over the Pacific Ocean near Honolulu.
Altitude is 15,000 feet.
Mayday, mayday, mayday,
Clipper 247, Clipper 247.
We are 9,000 feet and losing altitude.
Number two engine burning.
Drop further to effect
the emergency landing.
Present position is...
Repeat your position.
Damn, I can't pick him up anymore.
Clipper 247.
No, Mr. Hastings, I can only repeat
there's absolutely no reason
yet to fear the worst.
Until now we only know
that the plane caught fire
and that we've lost radio contact.
Yeah, I'll let you know immediately,
soon as I hear something new.
Blackwood Agency.
No, Mr. Alberts, I don't
have any further information.
But of course there's a
search party out there.
I tell you, rescuers are
looking all over for them.
There's still hope, even after four days.
Yes, I'll call you as soon
as I hear something new.
- Stop that bawling,
you're driving us all nuts.
Water, just one swallow.
No more today.
Tomorrow you'll get another ration.
Gary, give me some water.
Who do you think you are?
The fifth night.
We can't hold out much longer.
You're starting that too, Georgia?
A ship has to go by here sometime.
Or we've got to at least see some land.
Water, please give me water.
Look, a bird!
- Where there are birds
there must be land.
Are you crazy?
Give that to me.
Look at that, Gary, over there.
Land, there's land.
Help me paddle.
We've got to make it.
Paddle with your hands.
Come on, come on.
Don't stop now, we'll make it.
It's not far now, then we'll be safe.
Oh, I can't go on anymore.
Come, I'll help you.
There you are, Georgia.
Lie down.
I can't go anymore.
Here.
Babs.
Kate.
Georgia, darling.
Oh, Gary.
Gary, Gary.
Water.
Ah.
Water, water.
- What, Gary?
- Come on.
Come on, come on.
- Oh.
- Water?
- Where is it?
- That's wonderful.
- Let's go.
- Come on, girl.
- Oh, water.
- Oh.
Oh, how wonderful.
Come here!
Look, fresh drinking water.
There it is, there it is.
Oh, way over there.
- Watch out.
- Oh, let me in.
- Wonderful.
- Cold.
Oh, feel it.
- Oh, is anything
more wonderful than water?
Mm, wonderful.
Okay, girls, that's enough.
Let's go and have a look around.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on, Georgia.
Ready?
Let's go.
- That was good.
- Feeling better now?
- Stupid shoe.
- Don't lag behind.
Oh, I'll help you.
- Thanks.
- Yours are too high for here.
- Kate, your scarf.
- Oh, keep it.
Coming?
- Oh, this is like paradise.
- Yeah!
In any case, we're safe here.
Wait a minute! Did you hear that?
No.
Well, let's move on.
I didn't hear anything either.
I like it here.
Who would have thought
of this yesterday?
- Ouch! That stings.
- Help!
Hold on!
Thanks.
Come. Let's get over there.
OW, ouch.
Careful, girls.
Listen, what a strange silence.
Well, let's keep going.
I wonder where it leads.
I wonder how much further
we're going to have to go.
Ouch, my shoe.
This way.
It's not very good for shoes.
No, it sure isn't.
Gary, look what I just found.
What?
A hammer.
There must be someone on this island.
Really?
A hammer with a long handle.
It must be for the purpose
of excavating some sort of metal,
most probably uranium.
Can you eat that?
Yeah, you could try it.
Come on, let's go and find out.
Need long boots for this walk.
Come on, hurry up, look.
Come here.
Look, a cabin.
- Oh.
Let's get out of here.
A dead man in a huge web.
Oh, Gary.
- I have to get him down.
- Gary!
It's not working!
I need something.
Gary, there!
- My Bag! I have to get it.
- Are you crazy?
I wouldn't be seen dead
in a place like that.
Maybe we're safer in the cabin.
I'm so scared!
Hey there.
Do you think we should?
I don't know.
Come on.
Blackwood Agency. Yes, that's me.
What?
Did you find them?
No trace of them?
So they could still be alive?
What? The search is canceled?
You can't just give up if you
haven't found them yet!
After all, nine lives are at stake.
I'll take every step to force you
to continue the search!
The poor professor.
When he made the last entry in the diary
he didn't know how horribly he would die.
- Well, his discovery
of the uranium deposits
didn't help him any, even if it does
represent a tremendous fortune.
We must keep it from the girls
that Professor Green had
a premonition of his fate.
You see here in the last paragraph?
He says he thought something
terrible was going to happen.
He just felt the danger.
- I wonder where that
peculiar hissing came from
that he always heard.
Oh, Gary, I'm terribly scared.
I'm so afraid.
Don't worry, Georgia.
As long as I'm around,
nothing will happen to you.
I promise.
- Hi, Georgia.
- I'm hungry.
I've made something for you to eat.
Lucky there were some canned goods here.
Mm, food.
- It must have been a
really gigantic spider
to be able to spin such a huge web.
Maybe there are more of them.
- But a bite like that couldn't
have come from a spider.
Stop it, you're all ruining my appetite.
Aren't you at all afraid?
Afraid?
I can't change anything.
- I'm terribly afraid something
awful is going to happen.
Look.
- We found the professor's
trunk full of stuff.
They'll certainly be useful.
- One, four, five, six,
seven, eight, okay.
If we divide the provisions up carefully
they should last for a month.
What did you say, Georgia, a month?
Do you really think we'll
be here a whole month?
I don't know.
- We have to go tomorrow
to the highest cliff
and light a smoke signal
to try and attract a ship.
10, 11, 12.
Give me that shirt.
No, it belongs to me.
After all, I found it.
- But my dress is in
worse shape than yours.
No, I want to have it.
Give it to me.
Hey, stop that fighting.
Give me that shirt.
Georgia.
Thanks, Gary.
I suppose we could have guessed
that Georgia would be getting it.
- Haven't you ever noticed
that Gary pampers her?
What's this?
Where did you get the pullover?
- I found it here, if you
don't have anything against it.
Ha.
- Now stop it or I'll
take care of both of you.
Give me something to drink, Gladys.
Mm.
Take it easy, Gary.
We're all a little nervous.
It's really no wonder.
- Don't you think I'd rather
be in a bar in Singapore
with a nice cold drink than to
be on this godforsaken place,
drinking this horrible stuff?
Bah.
Darned heat.
Look out, will ya?
And stop making so much noise.
- If you don't like it,
you can do the dishes.
Or do you think I'm doing
this for my own pleasure?
Stop blowing your top and off, will you?
I simply can't stand
this frightful heat any longer.
- How about throwing your
dirty blouse some place else?
I want to sleep.
I sure hope you don't lose your lipstick.
You'd hardly be able to get
along on this island Without it?
I'm through.
It's about time.
Now I'll shower.
Give it here.
Come on, come on, girls.
Let's go to sleep.
I'm going to sleep outside.
Goodnight.
- Me too.
- Goodnight.
Here.
Goodnight, Kate.
Good, I found the professor's revolver.
Get some sleep, Gary.
I can't.
I think I'll go out for a little walk.
But don't worry, I'll
be back very shortly.
Gary.
Oh, Gary.
Gary!
This damned heat.
I don't know what I'm doing anymore.
- Those were shots,
I heard them clearly.
Oh, I hope nothing's happened to Gary.
I'm going.
If you're not coming
with me, I'm going alone.
Stay here, don't leave us alone.
You won't find Gary.
Oh, just leave everything as it is.
We must find Gary.
Babs and Ann, you go in that direction.
Where in the world is Kate?
Here, Georgia.
You two go in that direction.
Kate and May will go along with me.
Hurry up.
What about me?
You?
You remain here
and put things in order while we're gone.
Hey, Gary.
Would you quit that whistling?
You're making me nervous.
I'm not afraid when I whistle.
Gary!
Gary.
Come on, we gotta keep looking.
Without me, I'm staying right here.
Did you hear anything?
No.
But there's something moving there.
I don't hear anything.
Gary.
Hey, Gladys, don't leave me alone.
Then hurry up.
Gary.
- Gary.
I heard a scream.
I heard it plainly.
The scream came from there.
Linda.
Come on, girls, help me.
How awful.
She's been strangled.
The spider.
Ann, Ann.
Oh, it's horrible.
Oh, Georgia, the professor's been killed,
Gary's disappeared, and now
we've just buried Linda.
Which one of us is going to be next?
I don't want to die, I don't want to die,
I don't want to die.
Ann, Ann.
Now stop it, will you?
Stop it, before you drive us all crazy.
Stop it.
- Not me, not me.
- And I tell you, they'll
never find us, never.
But I'm sure the police are moving
heaven and hell to find us, honey?
The police?
The cops I know, if they catch you
speeding a little bit or find you drunk
they send you right off to the cooler.
But you just let somebody get lost
and they won't lift a finger.
Do you believe that
they'll go running around
for a few broads who are lost?
But how are they to know
that we've been rescued
and on this little island?
Rescued?
Who's been rescued?
We perhaps?
Show me the island.
Show me where does it lie in the ocean.
Show it to me.
- By the time they find
us we'll all be dead.
You, you, and you, one after the other.
Babs!
Get a hold of yourself.
You're only getting all
the girls worked up.
Well, if it isn't Miss Georgia.
Of all people it has to be you.
Who has Gary and Linda
on her conscience, who?
Babs, do you know what you're saying?
Exactly, through your jealousy.
You should never have left
Linda alone in the cabin.
Shut up, will you?
What can Georgia do about Linda's death?
- Take your hands off me
or I'll break your arm.
Just you try that baby, take that.
Oh!
Oh you.
Nelly, leave her alone.
Stop it!
Babs, Nelly, stop it!
I got you.
Get off!
Babs!
Stay here, let her fight.
Oh no, no.
So help me.
Come here.
No!
Leave me alone.
Come, come.
Is the ship getting any closer?
I don't know.
Come on, throw it on.
Should I get some more?
No, no, that's enough.
That's giving enough smoke.
They must see us.
They can't just leave us here.
Hello, hello.
Stop all that screaming, Ann.
You're driving me crazy.
Let me go.
Hello, take us with you.
Hello, we're over here.
Please don't forget us.
Yell with me.
They must hear us.
Hello, hello there.
Take us with you.
May, it sailed right by.
It sailed by.
We'll never get home now, never again.
28 days,
28 long days and nights.
And nobody even knows we're here.
And today a ship sails right
by us, our rescue so close.
Ann, May.
Oh, Georgia, a ship.
There, a ship.
Oh, it's gone.
How terrible.
And we only have enough
food left for three days.
Ann, Ann.
Come on back.
Come on.
- Here, you go
ahead and start unloading.
I'll take the oars up.
Okay, Bob.
What are you carrying
the oars so far away for?
Think the mermaids will steal our boat?
Oh, don't talk to me about women
on this godforsaken island.
- You should have taken one
along as part of your rations.
I wanted to, but it wasn't approved.
- Hey, come on over here
and give me a hand, will ya?
Okay, I'm coming.
Take it easy.
Easy now, easy does it.
Boy, that junk is heavy.
- Bob, you know, I'm sort
of glad the professor
picked us out to help him with his work,
even though it's lonely over here.
Give me some whiskey.
If there aren't any chicks,
then at least some whiskey.
You only think about whiskey and women.
You better change or
you'll never get anyplace.
Get off my back.
I'm sick of your preaching.
Take the professor, for example.
Ah, that guy's always been lucky.
While we explore all sorts
of islands for six months,
he comes with us once
and finds this stuff,
and of all places, on
this miserable island.
Oh, careful now.
Stop grumbling, will ya?
Oh, go on.
I'll go and look for the professor now.
Okay, get on out of here, will ya?
In the meantime, I'll unload.
And have fun.
Yeah, sure.
Gladys, Gladys.
Quick, girls, we're in danger.
Make for the beach.
We can't leave her here.
So that all of us will be killed?
Let's go, come on.
Look over there.
How terrible, the web in the cabin.
The gun.
Gary took it with him that night.
And this is his bracelet.
But where is Gary?
Please, Georgia, let's go.
I'm so afraid.
Perhaps there are more spiders around.
Come and sit with me.
What do you want from me?
Well, give you three guesses.
I was going to ask ya for the time.
Georgia.
- Georgia.
Here we are.
- Gladys is
gone down by the lagoon.
We were swimming when suddenly
she was pulled into the reeds.
And she screamed terribly.
Who was it?
Didn't you see anyone?
No, it all happened so quickly.
A scream...
And she'd already disappeared.
- Maybe the spider killed
the professor and Linda.
We found a gigantic spider, dead.
- It was shot with the
professor's own revolver.
- And Gary's bracelet was
laying there beside it.
Ssh, what's that noise?
That's him, get back, quiet.
Hands up!
— Hm?
Stop or I'll shoot.
Hey, hello, baby.
Hands up!
Anything you wish.
Get going into the cabin.
What a coincidence.
That's where I wanted to go.
I said get going.
All righty.
I think he's handsome.
He doesn't look so terrible.
They're the really dangerous ones.
Too bad.
Okay, turn around.
Mm.
Where's Gladys?
What did you do with her?
Let me speak to him.
Where is Gladys?
Gladys?
No idea.
I don't know the young lady unfortunately.
We just got here down on the lagoon.
- You see, Georgia?
- Where we were swimming.
And that's where Gladys disappeared.
On the lagoon?
Ah.
Don't laugh.
You'll be sorry about that.
Oh, I don't know.
Just look at what's coming down the path.
- Gladys.
- Oh, Gladys.
Where have you been?
Who's that?
My friend, Bob.
We work together for Professor Green.
Why, he's a big uranium research man.
I met him before in the reeds.
A researching researcher.
Then you had better luck than I.
I was nearly shot.
- Hi there.
- That is, if the
revolver had been loaded.
And you?
You here on a summer vacation?
Hm, fine summer vacation.
If we hadn't found this island
we wouldn't be here to tell the story.
We crashed on our way to Singapore.
- Ah, then you're the American
dance troop that got lost?
Yes.
Well how do you know that?
Oh, all the newspapers in the world
have carried your story.
What?
I bet Professor Green was surprised
when all these girls showed up.
Professor Green is dead.
What with the professor, dead?
What?
He was hanging in a huge spider web.
That's how we found him.
Linda is dead, and Gary, our manager,
has also disappeared.
Spider web?
Do you really believe that?
- By the way, our ship is
coming back in two days.
We must radio information right away
so that they can sent an
agent to clear the matter up.
You mean it, a ship's coming by.
Our expedition ship.
And will take us with it?
Yeah, of course.
- We're rescued.
- Yeah.
Look, isn't this pretty?
The boys will be surprised
when they see how we've
dressed ourselves up
in our island costumes.
And they promised us real whiskey, kids.
I can hardly wait.
Hold this.
Shall I put this in my hair?
- You look great, just
like a real islander.
Well I am.
Haven't I been here for four weeks?
- I can't believe that
we'll be back in New York
in a couple of days.
- When we tell them at home
what has happened to us,
nobody's going to believe us.
Where are Georgia and Ann?
Outside on the veranda.
They're out there with Joe
trying to make radio contact
with the expedition ship.
I wonder if a lot of reporters
will be on board when we get there.
- Hope so.
- Uh-huh.
- What's important for
me is that Jimmy's there.
Who is Jimmy?
My friend.
We're going to be married.
What if he's got eyes for another?
You don't believe that yourself.
I'd scratch his eyes out, and he knows it.
- Kids, we made radio
contact with the ship
and we'll be picked up tomorrow.
- And tonight we'll dance
and really raise the roof.
Tell me, what kind of a girl is Ann?
Usually quiet and one of the nicest.
She's away from home for the first time.
Her folks live in Minnesota.
I've never seen her so relaxed.
I'd like to dance with her.
Mm-hm.
- Come on, Bobby, I want
to be all alone with you.
How about the house?
Not in the house.
Some place where we'll be all alone.
You know what?
We'll meet at the lagoon.
Okay.
But so that no one will notice.
Good.
We'll meet in 15 minutes on
the trail down to the water.
All set?
- Of course.
Oh, but be on time.
I hate waiting.
Thanks.
Having a good time with the chicks?
Shut your mouth.
Fallen for her?
Thank you.
Tell me, are you always so quiet?
- You know, when you've lived
on islands for a long time
you forget how to say
nice things to girls.
Well, try it once.
- Well, I'm really glad
that your airplane crashed.
Well, that's a nice thing to say.
- I mean, otherwise I wouldn't
have gotten to know you.
And I'm glad about that.
Oh, you say that to everybody.
No, I don't know any girls.
When I think of the ones
I do, I'd rather work.
Well, I must say, you certainly are
a master at paying compliments.
Perhaps you're right.
I should pay more
attention to young women.
Sometimes I envy Bob.
He's so uninhibited and carefree.
Bobby.
Any girl is good enough for him.
A real man is interested in only one girl.
Then I'm a real man.
How?
- Because I'm really
interested only in one girl.
Who's that?
What does she look like?
Cute, elegant?
Elegant, mm, on the contrary.
A little bit disheveled and neglected,
but very pretty.
Her name's Ann.
Oh, Joe, that's one of the nicest things
that's ever been said to me.
Well I meant it.
I'm really fond of you.
You know, when you leave
for New York, here,
so you won't forget me too quickly.
- But, Joe, please don't
let me wait too long.
Come on, I got 12 minutes left.
What's in 12 minutes?
My next rendezvous.
Oh.
Hello, big boy.
Well, I'll be darned.
That's not bad either.
Hey, all right, you really
don't know where to start here.
Gladys.
Oh, you're here.
What's on your mind, huh?
Nothing.
In love?
Mm-hm.
- And you really think that
Bobby's the right man for you?
I don't know.
I only know one thing, I love him.
I hope he doesn't let you down.
I'd be very sorry for you.
Hello daddy-o.
How about throwing those lamps
on somebody else for a change?
Yeah, baby, like you swing too.
Come on, Gladys.
It's not worth it.
Don't bother me.
Hey, Georgia, give me a drink too.
All right.
Thanks.
- Bobby.
- Yeah?
- Do you have to turn
all the girls' heads?
Who me?
They turn mine.
- Hi, Georgia.
- Hi.
That dance sure made me thirsty.
- Georgia, aren't you at all
excited about going home soon?
Mm-hm.
Okay, let's drink to that.
Yeah.
Well, here's to the trip.
Cheers.
- Do you think people are
still talking about us?
Of course.
Now all the more, since we found you.
Will the papers print our story?
- Oh, baby, will the
papers print your story?
The magazines will carry your pictures.
And what do you think radio
and TV will do with you?
You'll be amazed at the reception
you'll get back in New York.
Maybe they'll drive us down Broadway,
with confetti and all.
Mm.
In any case, you become
a world famous troop
and hm, who knows?
Maybe you'll wind up in Hollywood.
Oh, Bobby, I might make it yet.
- Thank goodness I still
have a few minutes left.
'Cause my next rendezvous
is very important.
And this time who's the lucky one?
If you won't tell anyone, Gladys.
- Bobby
- Hm?
Gladys is a fine girl.
Up until now she's been shy of men.
Please, leave her alone.
Exactly.
I've always yearned for a girl like this
and never found one.
And why am I telling you all this anyway?
Oh, Joe, I'm so happy.
Well, that's what I expected.
Same old story.
You're nice to a man
and before you know it he's getting fresh.
- Ann, I must tell you
something right away.
Come on.
- All right.
Hey, Ann.
Let her run.
They're all good for nothing.
They're all the same.
Come on, let's have a drink.
- Well, Gladys, it's just
as I told you earlier.
Don't you see that Bob
is just the kind of man
who wants nothing else than
to play around with women
without a single serious
thought in his head?
- You're right, I don't
want to see him again.
Gladys.
Look, Bob, you can keep those remarks
about Arm to yourself, get it?
Don't tell me you're serious, fella.
You haven't fallen for that
little broad, by any chance?
Well, good luck then.
And what if I were?
Then I'd feel sorry for you.
What are dancers?
Hot goods for cold nights.
Or do you think your Ann is different, hm?
For a guy like you, the worst girl
in the world is too good.
No, not here.
Come on.
Take that.
I gotta run.
I got a date.
- Okay.
Hello, Gladys.
Oh, leave me alone you.
What's the matter with you, kid?
Have you gone crazy?
You ask me that.
No man in this world, even if he belonged
to your best friend, would
be safe with you around.
Are you talking about Bobby?
Who else?
But you can keep him.
I'm through with him.
I've got news for you.
Bobby just made it clear to me
that you're the kind of girl
that he's been looking for.
Do you mean that, Babs?
- If it weren't true, do
you think I'd leave him?
Babs!
Go to him, he's waiting for you.
Bobby.
That was a scream, ssh.
It sounded like Gladys.
And Bobby's also gone.
I'll look for them.
You get dressed and follow me.
Oh.
You go up ahead and try and help Gladys.
I'll go back and get the ammunition.
Quick.
Bob.
Bobby.
- Joe.
- Georgia.
Where's the ammunition?
I don't know, maybe there.
Quick, or we'll all get it.
I found Bob, dead.
Was he strangled?
Where are the bullets?
It's too late.
He's here.
Gary.
No.
Wait, each of you take a torch,
then we'll chase him.
We can only destroy him with fire.
Here.
Oh, light mine.
All right, come on.
Come on.
We must surround him.
Two of you take that path over there.
Two go through the bushes.
The rest of you, come with me.
Nobody should go alone.
Always go in pairs.
Come on.
Come on, he's over there.
Come, there he is.
Maybe we've lost him.
Stop, the quicksand starts here.
Oh, Joe, he's sinking.
Better dead than continue living.
Come on, girls, Babs, Kate.