Well, dad, I got
you here on time.
There's your pride and joy
just coming off the turntable.
Yes sirree, the old
Hurricane Express.
Hold on, Steve,
I'll take her down.
Sure jealous of
this old boiler, dad.
Why shouldn't I be?
Why, boy, she's part of me.
Or maybe I'm just part
of her, I don't know.
I took her out on her first run.
And I hope I'll be at her
throttle when I make my last.
Too bad the old
heap's out of date.
What do you mean, out of date?
You're talking about
the Hurricane Express,
the fastest train
in the country—
in any country.
Out of date?
Well, I wouldn't complain.
Them playthings?
The Hurricane Express
gets you there on time.
She's safe and she's sure.
OK, dad.
You stick to your engine
and I'll stick to my plane.
And I'll beat you to Springfield
by three hours, as usual.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
If you hauled as
many packages as I do,
you wouldn't land them
in a week and a half.
You win, dad.
Don't let your wheels get rusty.
Hi, James.
It's all tuned up,
Larry, and raring to go.
Well, so am I.
Gloria?
This is a surprise.
What are you doing
in the enemy's line?
I'm going to be a
passenger on your plane.
Gee, that's great.
But what a story for
the scandal sheets.
"Miss Gloria Martin, Secretary
to the Railroad General Manager
Does Her Traveling by Air".
Well, this is a
special occasion.
I'm not going to
make a habit of it.
I wish you would.
Anyway, I'll get a big
thrill out of seeing
our railroad from the air.
Well, well, Gloria, this
is an unexpected pleasure.
How are you, Mr. Grey?
Fine, thank you.
Isn't it time you were
getting ready, Baker?
Why?
Aren't pilots allowed
to talk to passengers?
Well, sometimes.
But not when the manager
wants to talk to her himself.
Oh.
I'll see you later, Gloria.
I'm glad to see you're
getting air-minded at last.
When are you going
to quit the railroad
and come to work for me?
Why, I hadn't given
it any thought.
Boy, we're sure making it nice.
I hope that West Bound
don't hold us up.
Don't worry about
the West Bound.
Tom Jordan will have her on the
side when we hit Plainville.
Hey Bill?
That pump valve is stuck.
Better take a look at it.
Larry, the
West Bound and Hurricane
Express are going to crash.
CO-What are you doing?
I'm going to try and
sidetrack one of those trains.
CO-You can't
make a landing here,
you'll stack up the plane.
I've got to take that chance.
We can't let those trains crash.
Has Baker gone crazy?
Tell him I said he is
not to attempt a landing.
Orders from Grey.
I knew he'd stop you.
He can't stop me,
orders or no orders.
Those people are racing
to certain death.
My god!
Save yourself, Bill— jump.
Oh, dad!
Yes, Mr. Grey.
I gave him your orders, but—
Well, you tell
Baker he's fired.
You take the plane on yourself.
He died instantly.
He might have saved
himself if he had jumped.
Jim Baker wasn't that kind.
He knew it was his life
or ours, and he gave his.
You did this.
You killed my father.
It wasn't my fault.
Honestly, it wasn't.
But honestly, someone— someone
struck me down from behind.
Struck you down?
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Then these wrecks haven't
been accidents after all.
Oh, but who could have held such
a grudge against the railroad?
Why, there's plenty of them.
Old Stratton, for instance.
Didn't he threaten to get
even with the railroad
for sending him to jail?
And didn't he escape on back?
Well, whoever is back of it,
it means my father was murdered.
And I'll bring that
murderer to justice if it
takes the rest of my life.
The Hurricane
Express— It gets you there.
Sometimes.
Dad?
Gloria.
What are you doing here?
I had to come.
Dad, you've got to go back.
Back?
To prison?
Yes.
You were safe in prison.
Now they suspect that
you're behind all
these mysterious
accidents on the railroad.
There's been another
terrible wreck.
Oh, never mind the wreck.
I know all about it.
Dad, then you did have
something to do with it?
Why, Gloria, are you
turning against me, too?
When I tell you the railroad
company did frame me.
They held out
evidence in my trial
that would have cleared me.
I do believe in you, dad, and
I'm trying to find the papers
at once, but I must be careful.
Does anybody suspect that
you're uh, Gloria Stratton?
No.
To them, I'm just Gloria
Martin, the general manager's
secretary.
Good, good.
Everything depends upon you.
Until you secure that evidence,
I'll be a hunted animal—
a fugitive from justice.
And when you returned
from fixing the pump,
where was Jordan?
When I climbed into
the cab, Jordan was
just reaching for the throttle.
But Mr. Edwards, I tell
you, I was just coming to.
Now, we've heard
your story, Jordan.
Carlson?
Yes, sir?
You reported that the 59
ran through your signal.
Did you see anybody
in the engine cab?
Yes, sir, I did.
Who was it?
Uh, it was Jordan,
the engineer.
That's a lie.
You couldn't have seen me.
Oh, I get it.
It's a frame-up.
And you're in on it.
If, uh, you're through with
me, Mr. Edwards, I— I'd
like to get back to my station.
All right, Carlson, you may go.
That concludes the inquiry.
Jordan, you will remain.
The evidence in the
case proves that you are
guilty of criminal negligence.
You are discharged.
Discharged, am I?
After 30 years of
faithful service.
And now the lying
word of a boomer agent
that just slipped in here
about three months ago.
Need you render a
decision now, Mr. Edwards?
As counsel for the road,
I feel that this matter
requires further investigation.
Why, the evidence is clear.
My decision is final.
So you're making me the goat?
For the past three months,
things have been going wrong
on this road— late trains,
open switches, overlapping
orders, mysterious
wrecks, and you can't
find out who's responsible.
Well, you're not going
to frame it onto me.
Nobody's trying to frame
anything on you, Jordan.
You're discharged for cause.
Oh, that's the answer, is it?
So you're blacklisting me—
driving me out of railroading.
All right, Mr. Edwards.
You've made a marked
man out of me.
Now you watch my smoke.
Is that a threat?
I am done talking.
Actions speak louder than words.
I believe Jordan
told the truth.
There must be someone behind
all these wrecks— someone with
a grudge against the railroad.
Why Larry, what
makes you say that?
Didn't you notice how
Carlson acted in there?
He was afraid of something.
He knew more than he told.
And I'm going down to Plainville
tonight and check up on me.
Larry, what good
will that do you?
I intend to find the man
that caused that wreck
and murdered my father.
MR. But don't
you see, Stevens?
Even if Jordan is
innocent, we can't
admit that there've been
any mysterious happenings
on the road.
We've lost too much
business already.
The air transport company
is eating into our passenger
traffic, and—
Do you suppose that Walter Gray
could be our mysterious enemy?
I wouldn't be
surprised, but, uh—
You know, he's never forgiven
you for having fired him
as traffic manager of the road.
I know.
But there's someone else I
have more reason to suspect.
Who's that?
Stratton?
Now that you mention
it, you know,
it is strange that all
these things have happened
since he escaped from prison.
You know, I'll never
be safe until Stratton
is again behind the bars.
Uh, this man will be in your
engine cab throughout the run.
All aboard!
What's happened?
The Hurricane Express.
Stop her or she'll be wrecked.
Quick, The Wrecker— he's
on the Hurricane Express.
Don't move.
OK, Sandy, tie him up, too.
Quick, we've gotta stop him.
Do you see anything suspicious?
No, not a thing.
Open up,
Hemi, it's Matthews.
Everything OK, Bill?
OK.
It won't be long now.
And what a smash it's gonna be.
But what's gonna
happen to The Wrecker?
He's on the train.
Don't worry.
He won't be on there
when she crashes.
It's only Bill.
Hello, Bill.
Seen The Wrecker yet?
Help!
Bill?
What's happened?
Somebody dragged me in
here and knocked me cold.
The Wrecker!
Watch it, here she comes.
I couldn't fix the smash.
That guy, Eric Baker butted
in and stopped the wreck.
How we gonna get
the gold out now?
Where's The Wrecker?
Why, he got away in the plane.
Here he comes, now.
He's come back to get the gold.
You stay here and
guard the gold.
Take no chances— shoot to kill.
I've got you covered.
Get down out of there.
Larry Baker?
So you're The Wrecker, huh?
I am not.
There's a conductor that
killed the engineer and guard.
A conductor, eh?
We got the man that
slugged you, Bill.
Can you identify him?
I tell you, he's The Wrecker.
He was fighting the fireman
when I came up in my car.
In your car, eh?
Yes, I was chasing
this train to get
him— the man who murdered my
father in yesterday's wreck.
How did you know The
Wrecker was on this train?
I found out at the
station in Plainville.
And you're positive that this
was the man you were fighting
with in the engine cab?
I'll swear to it.
That proves your whole
story a pack of lies.
I found him tied up in the
compartment of a Pullman car
just before the crash.
Mister detective?
M-mister detective?
The conductor's
done been murdered.
Somebody cut his head off.
Ooh!
L-l-lordy—
th-there's his ghost.
Well, looks like
everybody's been seeing me
in two places at the same time.
Show us what you're
talking about, Sam.
Get busy with the crew.
Clear the engine, back
it down the main line.
The Hurricane Express
must get through on time.
There it is, right over there.
See it right there?
Well, can you beat that?
And it sure looks like me.
No wonder Baker
thought he saw me.
This proves he told the truth.
So that's how
The Wrecker works?
Well, he can't be far away.
Ah, let him go.
This clears Baker.
Someone's getting
away with the gold.
Say, we can track
them in the plane.
The Wrecker again.
We can head him off
at the next station.
I'll get the emergency pole.
Dad, please.
Don't you realize—
Larry,
wait, you don't understand.
Dad, don't.
Stop.
That's one of Gray's
transport planes.
I knew that he had
a hand in this.
I've got him.
I've got The Wrecker.
Walter Gray.
Yeah, the head of
the air transport
line— the one man
who had good reason
to want to wreck our train.
That's a lie.
Who is this crazy fool?
He's Tom Jordan.
He used to work for the road.
Yeah.
You're the one that
made me lose my job.
You slugged me and
caused the wreck.
I know nothing about it.
Just what are you
doing here, Mr. Gray?
Why, uh, I, uh, I
was flying overhead
and saw the train crash and came
down to see if I could help.
You did not.
You were on the train.
I had my eye on
you from the start,
but you gave me the slip
just before the wreck.
I'm sorry Mr. Gray,
but we'll have to hold
you until we clear this up.
Why, this is ridiculous.
I'd better phone ahead and stop
the engine at Junction Point.
Look, here's the car.
We can chase the engine.
Good.
You see that Mr. Gray here is
turned over to the authorities.
And you'd better stick
with him, Jordan.
We'll overtake the
train at the junction.
You talk like a fool.
If I hadn't run off
with the express car,
those robbers would
have got the gold.
But dad, the railroad
company already believes
that you're The Wrecker.
This makes it look worse.
I'm not trying
to steal the gold.
It gives me a whip
hand over the railroad.
A whip hand?
What do you mean, dad?
They sent me to
prison on a frame-up.
They held out evidence
that would have cleared me.
And they'll either
produce that evidence,
or they'll never
get this gold again.
You—
Wait, Larry.
He's my father.
Your father?
Yes.
He's trying to save the
gold from The Wrecker,
and he thought you
were one of his gang.
Oh, so you're working
for the railroad, eh?
Yeah, I'm working
for the railroad.
Why, look.
We'll throw a scare into them.
Without the temper, we'll
be to death.
Th engine is stopping.
Bring her around, Sandy.
We're landing.
Well, they shan't
get that gold.
- Wait a minute.
- Huh?
We can't face that machine gun.
I've got a better plan.
Be ready to shove
off when we come back, Sandy.
OK.
Hide in here until they get
the rest of the gold aboard.
All set to go, Sandy?
OK.
Barney, look out!
Larry Baker's on the plane.
They got us, keep low.
we're safe now.
They're too far away.
Larry, the plane's on fire!
That's got 'em.
Count 10 before you pull the
cord and you'll be all right.
If she hadn't
crashed so far away,
we'd still have a chance
of getting the gold.
I've got it.
The engine.
You're right.
If we can get her running, we
can run down there in no time.
Dad?
Dad, where are you?
Dad, are you all right?
All right so far, Gloria.
Dad.
We must get this
gold away from here
at once before The
Wrecker's gang arrives.
But they're miles away
from here now, dad.
But they must have
seen the plane crash,
and they're sure to follow us.
There must be a
farmhouse around here
where we can get a car.
Yes, that's a good idea.
Oh, ooh, ooh.
Dad, what is it?
Oh, I hurt my leg
when I landed, I guess.
Now you two go after
a car and I-I'll
wait here till you get back.
I'd better wait here with
dad, he seems to be badly hurt.
Please go alone.
I'll be back soon.
Now quick, quick,
we've no time to waste.
Well dad, you're
not hurt at all.
Oh well, I had to
do that in order
to get Baker to leave
us here alone so he
wouldn't suspect anything.
Dad, you're not going
to steal the gold.
I'm going to use it as a
weapon to fight the railroad.
But that's not the
way to clear yourself.
I'm justified in
using any means
against the people that sent
me to prison on a false charge.
They held out evidence
that would have cleared me,
and wither they'll
produce that evidence
or they ll never
see that gold again.
Don't you see, you're
only making it worse.
Oh, nothing is worse
than rotting in jail
when you know that
you're innocent.
Douse that light.
There's a car coming.
Careful, Matthews.
I think I saw a light flash
in the cab of that engine.
Yeah?
Well, you get your gun ready.
We'll hand those birds
a little surprise.
It's the railroad dicks.
They left their
car in the brush.
Let's grab it.
What's that?
They've got our car.
Hurry, Gloria, this
is the last box.
Mind now, if you
damage the car any,
I'll take it out
of your deposit.
Well, I'll be careful.
Gloria?
We can't be far from it now.
There they are.
Stand where you are, Baker.
We're going to save you
the trouble of getting
that gold out of plane.
Here, Sandy.
Watch him while we
get the stuff out.
Say, what you got there, Baker?
It ain't here.
The gold's gone.
Baker's got the gold!
Stop him!
Hurry
up, get in the car.
Don't come any further, dad.
Someone might recognize you.
When is the next train to town?
There's an early
local in a few minutes.
Thank you.
He's making for the trestle.
Anybody hurt?
No, I guess not.
But the thieves we
were chasing got away.
Lucky you weren't killed.
Well, I'll have to report this.
You better come back
to town with me.
There's the dame
that was with Baker.
She knows where the gold is.
We've got to get a hold of her.
She'll tell.
You step off the train at the
next station and phone Jake
and tell him to meet the train
with a taxi at the terminal.
Hi.
Where's The Wrecker?
Here he is now.
Walter Gray.
So you're The Wrecker.
Never mind that.
All we want out of you is
where Baker hid the gold.
You'd better come through.
We know you were with Baker
when he stole the plane.
Speak up, or else.
I'm giving you just one
more chance to talk.
Up with your hands,
every one of you.
Larry.
Quick, Gloria— get the police
while I keep them covered.
So you're The Wrecker— the
man who murdered my father.
I swore I'd get you.
You're not going to shoot
me down in cold blood.
Why shouldn't I?
You didn't give my
father a chance, did you?
Don't shoot him,
he knows where the gold is.
What's the rush, sister?
No you don't.
You're staying right
here till The Wrecker
gets through with you.
Hands up.
I've got you covered.
No you haven't.
Drop that gun, Baker.
Can't see me, eh?
Well, that's too bad.
What did you do with the gold
bars you took from my men
today?
been expecting you.
Something must have gone wrong.
Well, I am not going
to wait any longer.
The Wrecker is not going to
get away from me this time.
Well, go ahead and shoot.
That's the signal the
detectives are waiting for.
Oh, it kind of worries you, eh?
The Wrecker, I've killed him.
It's Larry Baker— the
man we met in the hall
was The Wrecker wearing a mask.
You search the house,
the rest of you outside.
He can't be far away.
Did you see any sign of him?
- Nuh-uh.
The Wrecker.
But Baker's gone.
Stay where you are.
I've got you at last.
Take off that mask and
let's see who you are.
It's the boss.
Grab hold here
and get him out of the car.
Larry Baker.
Say, what did you want to
bring his body here for?
He's
not dead, you fool.
He ain't?
But you told us we were to—
I know what I said.
But Baker knows
where the gold is.
We've got to make
him talk first.
Pull him out and see if
you can bring him to.
He's dead to the world.
You must have hit
him an awful wallop.
Well, I can't wait
till he recovers.
I've got to get
back to the office.
If I'm not there in the morning,
it may arouse suspicion.
As soon as he comes to,
make him talk, and phone me.
Get that rope
and we'll tie him up.
That'll hold until he wakes up.
Come on, let's finish our game.
What's that?
Sit down and play your hand.
If you're going
to jump every time
a rat runs across this roof,
you'll give us all the willies.
You have to make a run for it.
Stall
them as long as you can.
I'll get word to
Gloria to send help.
No.
That'll take too long.
I have a better idea.
The Wrecker thinks I know where
the gold shipment is hidden.
Now, if I can trick
him out into the open,
we stand a good chance
of capturing him,
and his gang, too.
Yes.
How you gonna work it?
Everything's OK.
You can see for
yourself, there's
nothing to get jumpy about.
Come on.
Listen—
We hunted around for the rest
of the night, Mr. Edwards,
but we couldn't find
a trace of The Wrecker
or how he got Larry Baker away.
You've got to find him.
His mysterious attacks
on the Hurricane Express
are ruining this railroad.
Yes, and making plenty
of business for Walter
Gray's air transport company.
How about Gray?
Are you having him watched?
No, sir
Well, do so at once.
We've got to find Larry
Baker and unmask The Wrecker.
Hemingway, get over
to the airport at once.
Don't let Walter Gray
get out of your sight.
OK, chief.
Come in.
Gloria, this is a pleasure.
What brings you here?
Nothing, Mr. Gray, except
that I've lost my job.
Oh.
My previous offer
still holds good.
Why not come to
work for me, Gloria?
Thank you.
When do you want me to start?
Right now.
I'll show you your office.
I've uh, held this in
reserve for you a long time.
Hello, Mr. Jordan.
Morning.
Could I have a word
with you, Mr. Gray?
Sure.
Go right into my office.
I'll be with you
in a minute, Gloria.
You're taking an
awful chance having
that girl in this office.
Ah, nonsense.
She can't do any harm.
But I tell you,
we're under suspicion now.
We gotta be careful.
Hello?
Dad?
I've had a hard time trying
to locate you, Gloria.
Larry is leading The Wrecker's
gang to Logan's Flatts.
The Wrecker's going
to meet them there.
Larry is gambling with death.
The Wrecker will kill him
the moment that he finds out
that he can't produce the gold.
Get help fast.
All right, dad, I'll hurry.
Mr. Edwards, please.
Hello, Mr. Edwards?
This is Gloria Martin.
Larry Baker is planning
to trap The Wrecker.
If you send the detective
out to Logan Flatts,
you can capture
him and his gang.
How do I know this isn't
some trick of yours?
But Larry is taking
to capture The Wrecker.
You've got to believe me.
I'll go out there
with your men myself.
All right.
I'll have Matthews
round up his men
and meet you in front
of the building.
Quick, Mr. Hemingway,
Mr. Edwards wants you.
They're going to
capture The Wrecker.
I've got to stay here and—
You've got to go.
There isn't a moment to lose.
Why, Larry's life is at stake.
Hey, what'd I tell you?
They must have overheard us.
What if they did?
We'll beat them out
there in my plane.
You get out there
as fast as you can.
I'll follow in my car.
This is the place
you said, Baker.
Now show us where
you've hidden the gold.
Well, I've got to
get my bearings first.
There was a landmark
near this spot.
If there is any
landmark around here,
you could have seen it by now.
No stalling, Baker, or I'll—
It's The Wrecker,
and he's just in time.
Well, did you get it?
It looks like Baker's
pulling a stall on us.
Quit stalling, Baker.
Show us where the gold is.
And be quick about it, or—
Or you'll shoot me, is that it?
That's exactly
what will happen.
Well, a fine chance you'll
have of finding the gold with me
dead.
I'll give you till the
count of three to decide.
Get ready, Barney.
1...
2...
The cops!
So you're The Wrecker!
You—
But I know that Gray
is not The Wrecker.
But dad, how can you
be so sure of that?
I can't tell you now,
Gloria, but I— I know it.
Well one thing is certain,
dad— you've got to give
the gold back to the railroad.
What?
And give up the only
chance that I have
of forcing them to clear me?
Well, it's the best
thing for you to do.
Mr. Edwards' death has changed
the situation entirely.
Now we know that he wasn't
holding back the information
that would clear you.
Larry is right, dad.
The theft of the gold is the
one— give it back to them.
The Wrecker's the
one we must get.
All right.
I'll do it.
Oh, dad.
Well, I never did
believe that you
were responsible for wrecking
the Hurricane Express.
Report for duty.
I'll see that you
get your.
Thank you, sir.
Go.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yes?
Stevens talking.
Who?
Stratton?
You have the gold
shipment that was stolen
from the Hurricane Express?
You'll find it in
the old Forsythe Mine.
35 paces from the entrance
to the north tunnel.
Is that right?
You gotta hand it
to The Wrecker—
I'll bet the detectives
are howling yet
about the way we rescued Gray.
Fine chance you got of proving
you ain't The Wrecker now.
So that's The
Wrecker's game, huh,
to fasten his guilt onto me?
Sure.
That's why he let you live.
While the police
are hunting you,
The Wrecker will be
sitting free and easy
with nobody suspecting him.
He's smart, all right.
Hello?
Yeah.
It's the boss.
Yeah, sure, chief.
Right away.
The Wrecker says
the gold is hidden
in the abandoned mine shaft.
The railroad detectives
are on their way there now.
We've got to beat them to it.
The Wrecker has learned
of your message to Stevens
and he's beating the railroad
detectives to the gold.
It won't be long
now, Mr. Stratton.
We'll wait till The Wrecker's
about to enter the mine,
and then we'll pull
our little surprise.
The Wrecker's not with them.
He's outwitted us after all.
You're not Stratton.
Come on, boys.
This interfering fool
won't trouble us again.
All our enemies are out of
the way, and the gold is ours.
It's Stratton.
Don't shoot.
It's The Wrecker wearing a mask.
See?
He's giving us the signal now.
I thought you said you were
going to wear a grey mask.
We nearly shot you by mistake.
I had to change my plans
at the last minute in order
to fool Baker.
Get busy, boys— the
gold is over here.
Clear that stuff away.
Hustle, now.
The gold is under it.
The gold at last.
They won't get it
away from us this time.
Sure looks good to me.
Don't move.
I've got you covered.
OK, Larry, we've got 'em.
It's Stratton himself.
He tricked us.
Well, thanks to
Stratton, I've got you.
And I'll get The Wrecker, too.
All right, Gus,
let 'em have it.
Look out, Stratton.
Run for your life.
shooting.
You sneak up on Stratton.
I'll take care of Baker.
It's Larry Baker.
The Wrecker's gang
has him cornered.
We gotta stop that
machine gun first.
Now we'll get the
rest of the gang.
The railroad
detectives got Gus.
We have to beat it.
Quick, Matthews, stop 'em.
They're headed to the plane.
Aw, they've give
us the slip again.
Yes, but they
didn't get the gold.
Come on, I'll tell
you where it is.
Well, there it is, Matthews.
You showed up just
in time to save it.
Well, the sooner we get this
stuff out of here, the better.
I'll help you put
it in your car.
Hello?
Operator?
This is an emergency call.
Get me Crestview 4211.
Hello?
The Wrecker's gang are holding
me a prisoner in a warehouse
near the freight yards.
Yes, Mr. Gray, I
know where it is.
I'll be right over.
Gloria.
Oh.
Why didn't you want me
to phone the police?
Well, the fact is Gloria,
I'm afraid The Wrecker
is your father.
Quick!
Hide, Gloria.
We'd have gotten the loot
easy if those detectives
hadn't showed up when they did.
What are we going to
tell The Wrecker now?
So, you failed?
Never mind the excuses now.
We have one more chance to
get our hands on the gold.
Stevens has ordered it shipped
on the Hurricane Express
tonight.
I'll be on the engine
myself and stop
it at the sighting near Ashbox.
The two of you will
be there with a car
to take the gold away.
Get going now and
see that there's
no slipping up this time.
Come on, he won't get away.
I tied the knots myself.
Now you believe my
father's not The Wrecker.
I never dreamed it was Jordan.
Hurry, Gloria.
We must warn the railroad.
No.
If we do that, they'll
never get The Wrecker.
Larry Baker is the
one we must warn.
They should be here
by this time, Larry.
The Hurricane Express will
be along at any minute.
Yeah.
Here they come now.
What?
Look out, Sandy.
What's the meaning
of this, Jordan?
Why, The Wrecker struck me
down, and I think I got him.
Then The Wrecker
is Gray, after all.
No, he isn't.
Walter Gray.
Then The Wrecker's
wearing a mask.
He's in bad shape.
See if there's a doctor
on the train, Bill.
Help me get this mask of him.
Mr. Stevens— the Wrecker!
You knew?
Your father and I
discovered the truth today,
but we had no proof.
That's why your father returned
the gold to the railroad—
to set a trap for Stevens.
So you've got me, Matthews.
But you wouldn't have done it if
Baker hadn't— leave me alone.
You can't do anything for me.
I can't last very long.
Dad.
Stratton.
Wait.
Stratton's innocent.
I framed him.
I wanted to be
General Manager, so I
plotted to get rid of Stratton.
But the directors
gave Edwards the job,
so I had to use other means.
I've caused all
the wrecks in order
to ruin the railroad so that I
could buy it at my own price.
I wanted to use the gold
to finance my scheme.
I'm sorry, Stratton.
And I hope—
I congratulate you, Stratton.
When you're back as General
Manager of the railroad,
I hope we can get together
and merge our lines
into a real transport
company, combining
the best features of railroad
and air for our public service.
And Larry, if you can forget
the rotten way I've treated you,
I'd like to have your
back as chief pilot.
Thank you, Mr. Gray.
Get back to your job, Jordan.
The Hurricane Express
must go through on time.