That's what. I.
Thought.
When you.
Are out of the Studio sixty. Six times.
Through the ages of. Hours.
By the destructive power. That is cut
off communication with the outside.
Just fifteen hours after
the first. World has been
a silo. And I awaited my nuclear bomb
three billion people murdered by
a thousand nuclear bombs and
a lethal. Baby there's no one left
to hear my voice living human
being to record the end of
the world. Now this is Ted
Johnson for
a change. Lost
their Our last. Sign of life. Paris Moscow
was quiet now.
It's holding
a forty seven. We may be saved
just as I planned it. I'm
sorry honey I'm afraid he didn't
make it. But there's always hope.
Let's go inside.
And it right Joanna. From
any city. Like that the
radiation and provisions
for the three of us.
I need. I couldn't very well order there
eight to come out here and stay with this
even though you are engaged to him.
Don't you did Larry even know or.
Don't open the door and you go sure it's
very very hectic you compare me now. To
open door went and picked.
Come. Back up to.
Waist don't touch it read up with
radioactivity it's not Larry.
Everyone wait we'd better
check the governor.
Written for you mention he still
breathing. He should be dead
but he's still breathing nobody
can take that much and still live
Don't touch him it's my responsibility. Or
you are my brother. We've.
Made your. Springs from.
The storm. He's still alive you
must be dying. The college
filled seven hundred forty
ranch and. Was a bit of
a storm coming from you know the state
here still turns but they're going to not
only that it's too late
for them but not as. More
and.
And
.
Why. Why
why
whorl
. The.
War
or Alright. Alright.
For. Her
better or worse the Iraq lawsuit is
a girl that your boy was all aboard.
While. This does all of the.
Arab stuff the the. Lawn of
the little girl I like is
the. Right.
Yes yes. Of course the last day
I had the only three people my
where stays up to get the sob story.
You can stay here or this is the way I
planned it I had the belief of three people
only. Please
continue to support America
to confession for.
Ways. I didn't mean us and
I was just looking C.B.
No one was alive in the house
What's your name I'm Jim Anderson
a great driver from the
cliff so I rest yes sure
my. Right hand I knock you down
and one of the house you know the
cat stays oh that there
was this all could stay we're
all going to die anyway.
It looks like we're stuck with each other
so let's understand the rules oh I'm the
ranking officer I mean person I mean
the man if we're both I vote for me
I will be fine and this is serious
shadow job and my second in
command will be Steve. This cumber
is registering forty seven mentions
of radioactivity now fifty is considered
dangerous five hundred people but that
depends on the individual different people
have different absorption rates and
capacities we may well we may not there's
a lot we don't know about it some of us may
be dying now. How long we probably can
leave them yeah I got some things working
for me knowing big things so how long
before we can get. New life
forms will move us into
a stupid kid. I don't believe. In your
reading or long or short role for
me and I'm sitting in the room she's right
the six of us in this house may be the
beginning of a new era
a new civilization seven my brother
still alive but not for long I'm afraid
but be that as it may I spent ten
years getting ready for this day
a preview as to why we're still
alive this is my house with its own
generators and food supply these clips
surrounding the house on three sides
are full of lead bearing art that acts as
a barrier against radioactivity the
lake here on the port side is heated
from an underground heat source
probably know about Cain or are maybe
a crack in the earth's crust anyway the
warm air from the lakes waters creates an
updraft and
a strong enough I might add to carry
radioactive contamination out of the valley as
long as it doesn't rain if the rains come
too soon we'll all be contaminated and
die that is if we don't let other
forces destroy us before that time
what other forces Nevermind that now but
make no mistake about it you're not
welcome here. This was planned for just
three people that's how much food we have
if we divide that among the six of us will
soon have empty stomachs and rebellion
I have the keys to the store room I and I
alone will say when and how much food we
eat and the argument about that and
I'll settle it with this oh you're
a big man back in that gun just don't
you let go of it I don't intend to
where you going with that my brother
save the food your brother is
a coward the face that picked up
two men that had never seen you
like this before with ten kind of animals
we're still human and we've got to act
like it it's just what I'm
afraid of their argument
why.
Bring your I don't. I'm not going to die.
But I was not I'm the one that. Says
America you so upset on mentions
I don't understand it's I'm glad you got
something I don't want that I need fresh
meat raw meat. When you're
in with the chef. Over
I think it would be good. Fun to watch him
getting something cause I'm not no water
. Just just let me rest. Will be OK with.
Him. You can tell me how you do happen
to be near this valley yesterday
we're not exactly on the main highway we're
camped on the other side of the lake
that's not too far off the highway. There
on a regular morning was going to be
a get to sleep that they had their own car
wouldn't stop leaders friend you know
who love Mary she's an old
friend of the fan look if you can be
a friend of my family any time you walk.
Out of there before my eyes then. I'm
manager.
I mean. I can see the stock.
Now you know I can't work with
a fan. That's looking at.
It about. My fiance he was
supposed to be yesterday.
Going to marry. Her So I. Really say.
That's not.
A rule come. To. My
snap out of it. Let's go your father's store
and see if we can find some can be for
my brother Steve some of the out what if
the radioactive the outside. Perhaps I
will become big.
How we do enjoy. It forty nine
That's up to since last night
this is just some magic forces holding those
clowns about of this family that's the
warm air from the lake creates an updraft
this I know but we also told you this
morning I've known about this valley for
a long time and Blake to read about
it in college in geology. Will you
a geologist I work for a company about
a hundred miles south of here then you
just didn't stumble in here yesterday by
accident no my brother I had it here the
minute we heard about the bombings smart
thinking on your part you know
the real force of the atom has never been
fully calculated I think it reaches the
film yesterday yes but only as we know it
affects our present form of life our life
as we knew it before this nuclear inferno
cover the US You think some other form of
life could have survived I'm only saying
that it's true force has never been fully
understood Are you confusing me now General
do you remember the age bomb test match
still some years ago sure I kept in one of
those ships five days after the blast I
told the animal ship out of targets
the role the outside world never had
a true account of the test what
are you trying to say John.
Coyotes in the daytime. Must be
a lot of game in this valley now contaminated
game fighting for life just the way
we're.
Smatter Granger. There's a live game
outside I can tell this we heard
a coyote during the day I can feel it
and I'll be beat Granger that that
game contaminated game that
you've done I you would die. Me.
I can be that can joke I've got to have
some meat fresh beer that's all you're
going to get for
a long time that's what you think
that's just what you think.
The only.
Just.
I'm. Just.
The poor.
Just.
For three weeks I thought we'd all be
dead by now even Granger got out of bed
yesterday. I was your brother before.
Well he did give me a funny feeling like
a cliche have been dead long ago but there's
no such thing as logic getting more so
logical about my brother you know what
it was like he hasn't taken the water in
three weeks not since he's been here. He
doesn't need and last night he stepped out
of the aisle to didn't come back until
dawn radiation of the fact that his mind
is a mutation Steve face it is
a freak of if you will
comic world about. I'm
going outside. For
a walk. While I don't go
too far stay inside about.
Why. Because I will face all
the five. Hundred high range
anymore sleep I'm not. I'm not
afraid of anything out there.
I like it. Would you like to go with.
Room. I think is dangerous.
Things should be destroyed.
Destroyed my brother. Yes for our
safety you can't do that young
not just because he's my brother but don't
you think it's important as. I don't see
why. I'm sure your. Studies.
If it does rain in the next few weeks I
think we're gonna live somehow I knew we
wouldn't die my father always seems about
it you know right after the bombs came I
didn't much care if I lived or died
don't talk like that it's true Joanna
but these past few weeks with you
now I feel I've got
a big reason to live me Tuesday Joanna.
What's wrong. Did I misunderstand.
I'm sure you're right there was.
Something out there that's things feeling
sound something stronger than the last
time I felt it was just some harmless
animal in the bushes that's all now we stay
the more let's go back
in the house please.
The bank
where.
Where. The and where.
The prayer
the
the. The person.
The
Boron
nightmare.
But.
It was just
a list of their footprints
the Grangers you
think he ate that rabbit he must that he
spends most of his nights prowling around
in these woods forty nine
mentions nothing Commandery that poisoned
me to no avail. No no human could
decries all the miles of
man and God. There may be
a new set of laws JOHN LAWS proportionately
are right nothing about the mountain
and Steve say what you mean we're only
guessing but we know the risk low amounts of
radiation can produce
change now for some reason
a man could survive complete saturation
a thousand generations of change could
take place in a matter of weeks
a match to
a test what you mean nothing go on with
the theory afraid they're more Granger's
out here and even worse than him all of
us have survived more tumors of exposure
than we ever thought possible you are
mean we only become like your brother
stocking these words at night eating raw
meat possible keep right theories as to
what to do in the Situation. You know
my brother couldn't find the answer
to something he looked it up in the Bible
he believed that it held the answers to
everything where I am
would be to save B.N.
Deliver the say at the LORD I will
deliver the the back and of the
wicked. I will redeem the out of
the land of the terrible I had
enough of that Bible when I was
a kid it's easy to see it
had no effect on you make.
An ego for Granger.
What was it. Maybe you better tell us
what the Bible says about rain in our
situation we had better pray that it doesn't
rain not for weeks anyway because if it
does rain in this valley it will be coming
down through clouds saturated with
nuclear death. Maybe we'll be safe like
no in the Iraq right now there's about
forty wrenches of activity in this room if
it rains that will move up into
the hundreds of branches in
a matter of hours and we'll all be
dead are like Granger around lucky
but maybe the other grass from the
lake will hold the clouds back forward
we've been lucky so far. I can see
that I hope you're right sweetheart
and if the weather does clear starting
tomorrow we'll have to go on half rations
how much is half of nothing I've stored
some seeds and grain and I have books and
materials on every craft necessary
to sustain my. Mickey Rooney
farmer in Cressman. Another thing we're
about out of fresh water but there's
a spring fed pool not so far from the cliffs
hold your own the biggest one of them
from the start. At least save I checked
it today and starting tomorrow we can
all take turns bathing they're
getting one. Taken in the past two
months and I have an almost more days
together. Maybe that's why you're still alive
. But
what
my onboard.
Borer
whorls
brain bomb attached to the
letter writing by Facebook
a grange the crowds are going to come in
the valley you're lying to me disco rain
come on. Come back to the house
gonna try to break break.
Break come back to our why.
Why
why.
Why. Why
the band.
Sunshine feels
a Coke can. Quietude. Give anything
to her the downtown traffic again.
I didn't realize how isolated
it would be from the house.
Good looking. Clean cut that. Something.
Maybe. Is all lies you.
Tom. Are interested in.
We better not be rude.
Well what have made
a place where it would
be unfair competition
which whisky always comes back to
Mom white America
when he's like I'm
a point in feeling when I didn't
hear any better or worse something
moving over there in the bush is probably
one of the valid probably Okemah say why
the poor one
when the other let's get out of this
one
. Range is not the only
one hundred games and after they've
finished off the game we'll be next
this place is cursed Steve we've got to get
rid of your brother. Is the only way to
find out what we're up against or just see
that the animals on the ship so much so
Trast. They far warned of something like
this you know you keep mentioning that
you're going to keep up the mystery going
to tell me about it tonight back at the
house I'll show you after the others
have gone to bed I have the evidence
let's look at it you said I didn't see
anything to prove you said it was just my
imagination that's right he just became
upset Steve somebody was looking
at me tried to talk to me but he
said nothing you'd understand
nothing I didn't just for that matter. Where
you were go swimming alone in the pool
any more I'll stand guard my
skin was tingling my pulse was
pounding you're still upset
and I go back the House Steve
do you believe in mental
telepathy. I'm afraid I'm reading
a thought if that's what you mean what
am I thinking it's not the same way you
were thinking about me
a few days ago I'm sorry. I
feel like I'd like to be alone
right now I'm sorry to join
Maybe I don't scare me like that I just
want to talk to you that's all you know I
but I haven't said
a dozen words to you since I got here
and look what's so bad about me I don't
drink I don't smoke and once
I even gave some money to
a drunken bum my old man. And I
don't even hard to get stuff
C'mon. Down you belong to Java I
belong to me did me.
Nobody. Oh it's you must care for days to
some of the best was Can these mountains
. That is lifting words you did it.
Made him oh so that's where I'm
a good little girls back
in my place. Whatever
was. The first taste is
never a good misjudge it's
a long second one that puts her on
a chest. The
air or the bottom of the room.
Where.
The
brain.
Will believe this but I just saw Granger
walk up the mount trail through that
bargain to didn't face it do
you remember anything about
a match to
a bomb test. And they ruined right after
that with. Something I have to show
you. A whole lot my thought was that
all the animals about I get zero
I that of course not all that. Was ever
said they were all destroyed I was lied to
realize that I'm a liberal.
Through an H.-Bomb it was
a lot of taking photographs but no
obligation getting it seem right thousand
animals on that ship.
That was a test mine was
a line has little over three days.
Thirty Survivor was
a monkey its skin looked like rubber
but it felt more like metal armor
plated nature's answer to
complete nuclear radiation that's
a million years of evolution with
one bomb. Within the for three days
when we got back to the inspection ship
they were dead if we could figure out what
killed them and may help us we never knew
after we watched them down we went down
to inspect they were normal except for
their appearance but they refused food and
water new species yes they were
the forerunners of whatever it is
we have out there sometimes I have
a feeling that. I know this
much that two forms of life I
survive on this valley and only one can
win and it's got to be us you know I
started this thing just to
stay alive but you've given me
a deep feeling of responsibility
toward the well man and are I.
Think I'll turn in now and down. As I'll
tell the girls the first thing in the
morning. As. A comparison of
them as soon as possible.
Maybe with the new good
days in the fall. When
Arnold. Stole. My
life. A
sea captain can perform the marriage
ceremony in case of an emergency Joe and I
want you to marry Steve I want
you to have children that we
know wedding God and
know killed and you have
a responsibility to the future what would
mother tell the mother and Larry what
would he fall they're both dead
I mean I mean when are those those
what have you been listening to be
ye that. Are more effective in
a week if he is still alive. And if I.
Were to do another. This little
gadgets that are open that store room
for me. Can you
imagine us having a kid.
Tell him it's mother was
a lot of dancing. I wonder what's
wrong with Joanna Ritchie goes
around own little world now reflect after
a rock or. Maybe we are. Not me baby.
Don't go far don't you you're just playing
dirty to her but you still water.
All I want is
a key to open that store room. All
this time you can say it was you with
me but you met her
through life. OK OK so I
lied
a little room I'm the polls. The only
friend you ever had in this world
was the only one the love
you what I remember I.
Remember. Now. I want to change after.
We got what that was least two more months.
And we're running out of supplies. Only
enough for about two more weeks.
Why.
Why why.
Why. Why
why.
Why
.
Or what but him he's.
They wouldn't give me any.
There's more of you out there.
Stronger. Much stronger
I'm in I'm any more.
Trauma I had.
Well the neighborhood there boy devil. Look
at the head of the green bone structure
like those animals eventual. And the
same mutated skin the animals I had and.
More like him up there
stronger. Stage to this one
stage three strong stage four maybe
invulnerable I'll Bob stage one who's that
of Granger my brother stage one.
Of the.
There's no doubt about it. That coming
close to the house every night. We'll have
to take turns dining guide Steve I did
Mickey but we can't trust him with
a gun and he's and I know your
kind Spondon builds water.
Chemistry sometimes you're
a life. Well Art to pay
you know some data were
made in low I have no out but yeah
our wireless that's the the one
that we're selling can always find.
The good. Old.
Time with job to. Our pay you back. That.
QUEST permission to time
a boy. And they can grab it saying I. Own
.
One automatic they'll start
your winter and shops.
Like I've got my motor running you
could see you with fanfare you think.
You can. When. I have told.
Multiple. Back that.
Now wasn't that. When you came in that.
Hearing. This is where I knew.
It was that right that I get by with
a blank. No
don't worry my job please.
Drop by. Good then we'll have no
more of this disgusting behavior
right sailor. One of your every crowd.
Never made.
But I.
Well one of you gotta say about.
Personally I hate the stuff
and I've never. Caught the
I must have dozed off.
Isn't the house any place not wish to be
lost in the woods somewhere you know I'm
really worried about that oh you should in
the program it's just you're right I had
no idea he was an alcoholic. If he doesn't
show up by daybreak I'll go out and find
him I'll go with you that was my mistake
you don't suppose he tried to get
back up over those cliffs do you. Better
not if he does it'll be the end of the.
Night. One
Dawn another Iraq
bomb
one wrong one warn
others
thought.
Iraq being
a Wainwright just the rabid
borrow
or was another the
bank the I'll read
the bank
the Bible
ride
bank
or are.
Still not. You know
dogs don't go into that.
Don't go into that bog
deal being killed or.
Or or.
Job. DAY what happened or sprained my
ankle or sent back up over the cliff
he went back to what is still
that you go after the that fateful hour
we have to. Manage our what
difference does it make. The I've
had the course
a mother gets washed up redone
to tell Joanna I just got
a sprained ankle understand George
Cameron get back to the house.
He's dead Really Steve
it's better this way
report brings your room and my whole
family's current knowledge Steve
you'll enjoy I know the new family
now perhaps for the whole human race
look at those pictures.
So I agree Stupak was.
Glass. Said the parent of the
monkey in your drawings.
Matt.
But he was aware of the quick. The doing
to me that's just your imagination
our real life you're the only.
One insists this thing trying to talk
to or I love the way you look. Like
an ape sketches of my soul.
That this thing is man sized
A man not an ape how do we find it
how do we tell it you're the one
who said we've come up with an answer but
how can sound fresh breeze contaminated
there the things that kill
a man drives on. The point you're
driving at some of the just that in
order to kill it we must first understand
it and we know it has fears it was close
enough to join it to attack or
what it would power into the pool.
Don't scream I mean it.
You mind. I never had time for your
kind of. Something new in my life.
Oh. Well you won't hit me when the just
the two of us there be no point to it now
but I mean I. Get along.
Just to go back to the house have
a few words for the tiles are here.
You don't know when you're through.
That the two but how long you met
her yeah that's right now you know
you and your dime store stuff keep
a cheapie I didn't know how to keep
you are to lie met her. She hates
your guidance. When I tell myself.
C'mon let's not fight back
a couple of kids let's go take
a. Beat I don't want any part of you.
When.
I decided to come back to town.
Right around the corner.
The boy.
I guess work at where she
got it. Where little before
she didn't come back stayed outside or
cool off I guess OK maybe I got out of the
saddle with you tomorrow maybe i'm beat
right now you can exit your when I get I'm
going to kill you kill me
I want to laugh all day.
He was spared by the bombs on never now
he'll kill you Stephen get him first
now here take this M.
Just sneak up on Mickey and emptied into
him. John you know me better than that.
I think in the major of the mountain town
but there's so much at stake. At least
that we are guided here.
If one of the store will.
Be ready to use it.
And how long before
a guy can get out of here so I'm
going to sign you can leave now you
know this reminds me that kids around ten
little Indians. Got knocked off one at
a time same way last first
they were seven now did
not A. Very. Little. Then they
were not. By that again. Please try that
again. Captain and I know
when to quit right now.
There is
a little. While. But
.
The All right
the
I'm going to be one of
the interesting. The By
very. Very well Michael.
STEELE. But you're allowed around
the Bible you won't need it.
But there's no other way
you know that Alonzo I.
Join us.
Now I said but I can't. Do
this to men and only one.
I like to have. Looks like your ships
falling upon them well you know
the well. You will be private job you
will now be Steve look we're glad you're
lower than Scott. I'm. Only
five when I get to the end of
my own condition the one of me is the US
and I know what I'm fighting the first.
Joy-Ann. Reid was
a little girl in. You know yes
Second I know you went after
him in that fog kill
yourself but I wear believe.
That's why you're acting so brave that's
why you're lean and moving in the eyes
and I'm takin over with Spock's
your daughter. If you gets back.
I know you. Oh man for the kids
it's the way they beat us like meat
all reply to the rate at
which still they get real killers
so. You'll know soon enough
all right
why.
The. Trick.
All right. All right it's. All right
just. All the rest.
Of. The world it's afraid of the war.
And they're really getting good.
Oh you're going to live now well
here give me
a sample of the rainwater now tested. That
doesn't register. But cold water. Or
you know just plain overhead Mark. That.
Water it's afraid of your. Joy
and instead you may be safe
but the free cabin you crack
a nut on don't you see you will get that
thing out there that atomic bean it's
a prey to pure water that's why
it wouldn't go in the pool.
Well you thinking in that sick mind of
yours simple I'm going to shoot Steve
right between the gods name why
well I thought you knew smart man.
I want Joe and I think you
need. It what
a complete sound tried to speak to me
Steve with Larry what killed him
he was created to live in
a contaminated apis here because
the rain must be pure He couldn't
stand it. I guess that means that all the
other people like Larry will be killed by
the rain to. The future yes to him or
maybe. Violent back
with.