I was dictating the wrap-up on the
butcher Benton package
I'm lieutenant dick Jason this hadn't
been a routine case and to find the
answer I've had to put a lot of little
pieces together it began on the day most
cases can be called closed was the day
before the butcher was to be executed he
was visited by his attorney Paul lo in
the death house it was at this first
meeting the butcher Benton case took its
first switch when I did watching the
evidence against yourself strong the
government turned on your oath you
you're a rotten Lyle oh you started now
and now you're still trying to throw me
curves okay I don't blame you for being
edgy but get this straight I didn't
double-cross you I never worked harder
for our client you mean you never worked
harder for a client to get him sentenced
you're a fool butcher if you hadn't
tried to double-cross Queenie Ellis and
Joe Marcella they wouldn't turn state's
evidence against you but you had to get
greedy you wanted to keep the whole
$600,000 for yourself well the boys got
sore and I don't blame them
it was all your idea you planned the
whole job you hired us when you found
out our state's good money you decided
to return for me to die you got those
two crumbs to turn state's evidence on
me you stinking rotten mouthpiece we
both know that isn't true watcher hello
what's the sense of not giving me the
money not gonna do you any good.
Wow I'll have the satisfaction of
knowing that many in three crumbs are
gonna spend it what about Eva don't you
owe her something you tell me where the
money is I'll see that she gets your
share I've got a different idea I'm
gonna kill you and screaming Joe and
I'll take care of even myself he's sick
hit the tape you're gonna die tomorrow
none of what I said
I'm gonna get you all three of you even
for your butcher that'd be quite a trick
song dead man remember what I said
I'm gonna kill you all three of you
you
back in Los Angeles two men sat on a
barroom listening to a newscaster tell
his headline story he played a big
butcher's threat to kill palos Queenie
Ellis and Joe Marcel II for their having
turned state's evidence against him
squee me Ellis didn't seem happy over
the butcher's threat neither did Joe
Marcel II but they had figured once a
dead man always a dead man but this was
one time everyone was in for a surprise
including the entire police department
you've seen the headlines captain solid
I just came in from San Francisco
butchers execution is set for five
o'clock this afternoon.
Mike the newspapers say he still refuses
to talk about that stolen money well I
still have hopes of coming up with
something what's what a drop by for a
dick with butchers execution the
department's marking it case closed that
means you'll be reassigned I spent a
whole year trying to break this case as
far as I'm concerned
butchers death is just the beginning of
course I I can't prove it but I think
that Paul Lowe was the top man and even
though I have to keep working on it
while off-duty I'm going to get low.
Queeny Ellis and Joe Marcel II okay
lieutenant officially I've taken you off
of the case unofficially I wish you luck
do me a favor keep me posted will do
thanks John I headed for Eva Martin
she worked in a local burlesque house
I'm a cop and my job is to ask questions
and get answers so I decided I might as
well start again we've heard
come in
what do you want I'd like to talk to you.
Todd you're a cop aren't you that's a
good question
I can't even find a three-ton armored
car let alone the $600,000
I've been on the case a year I've told
you and I've told you and I've told you
I don't know anything about the money I
never did been who's gonna be dead in a
little while I thought it might make a
difference I never knew anything about
the money
call me dumb I didn't even know Charles
within the rackets until the trial I'll
take it
honey here's your wrap
your moments ago but your benton without
revealing the whereabouts of the
$600,000 stolen in the armored car
holdup paid for his crimes against
society in the gas chamber at San.
Quentin now for a look at the
international scene today come on baby
always tears on Benton feel so badly
about Charles if I know maybe I could
have done something how about a drink we
could both you know I just can't drink
while she's working or see
what's that
well now what's the matter the message
from Charles he told me to open it it
god Banali IVA
alright how about a steak after the show
no thanks not tonight Paul.
I didn't find out until much later
but Paul Lo and opening the letters of
butcher at given Eva found a map
outlining a section of the city sewer
system and clearly identified was the
spot where the butcher and hidden was
stolen payroll he replaced it with a $50
bill I guess he figured $50 to gain
600,000 was not a bad days work
200 miles away in San Francisco the case
took another switch which turned the
next 72 hours into one long hideous
nightmare dr. Bradshaw a distinguished
biochemist was making preparations for a
final experiment which he hoped would
lead the way to a cure for cancer
he'd been successful with laboratory
animals
the last step called for a human body
and dr. Bradshaw's a system quickly made
a deal with a local mortuary and
returned to the laboratory with the dead
body of butcher Benton
you made good time well I didn't waste
any I need trouble now I just handed the
money over and moved the body into your
station wagon that was that good get a
syringe
he's in good shape I hope so we'll get
other blood samples later we'll run this
one through fast right
now we live into the Machine and then
raise him right
ready you mean you're going to give him
two hundred and eighty-seven thousand
volts yes yes I'll get the fluoroscope
set we'll check with that before we
start the second turn off the lights
there you are oh boy you respond
properly in my theory is sound you'll be
more famous dead than alive throw the
switch
we I thought I saw a pulsation of apart
dr. Bradshaw we're getting the free your
blood to slam back to life the heart
muscle simply responded to a terrific
electrical shock that's all
yes but it does prove that the cells
still function dr. Bradshaw he is alive
a shock reaction it can't last his cells
are multiplying now if your theory is
right we could keep that reaction going
longer but it's worth a try
get the body out
get some adrenaline from the supply room
sometime bell night right - hurry hurry
you
you must move your heart can't stand the
strain
now you must lie still please please
please it out easy easy
you must have easy please only
dr. Bradshaw's experiment had given life
back to the butcher he tried to talk but
the electrical voltage had burned out
his vocal cords yet it hadn't destroyed
his brain he knew who he was he knew who
he hated he stumble about the room I
think he thought only about one kill low
squee me and Joe Marcel a tremendous
electrical voltage that dr. Bradshaw had
given the butcher had increased his
cellular structure to the point where he
was no longer a man dr. Bradshaw's
experiment had created a vicious brutal
animal with an almost inconceivable
amount of strength dr. Bradshaw must
have believed the butcher's ray gains
life would last for only a few minutes
therefore instead of calling for help
the doctor decided to handle his
creation alone I easy battened it just
relax I'm a doctor I want to try to help
you do you understand me you're in my
laboratory the execution was carried out
he were declared dead I tried an
experiment on you and brought you back
to life although I didn't intend that
now you've had a great shock now now
come and sit down animal be quiet now
come and sit down take it easy
catalyzed reactions a violent how do you
explain this each cell must have
multiplied a hundred times perhaps
thousands his strength is unbelievable
no no no it's too late for the amyl
nitrite I won't get some blood samples
make some test sign find out what's
happened I get me a syringe
why won't the needle penetrate the skin
tissue must be nearly a solid mass of
cells how are we gonna get the blood
sample surgically perhaps
I take it easy you can't leave here now
I'm responsible for your being alive
towards the end of this case captain.
Lauder and I found out the doctor in his
assistant had been murdered but I'm
getting ahead of my story
the butcher didn't know how he had been
brought back from the dead and he didn't
care all he knew he was alive then this
monster made man started thinking about.
Los Angeles
on that very Los Angeles I decided to
stop playing detective for a little
while I went to the burlesque house to
ask IVA to have dinner with me after all
the butcher was dead and if I got lucky
sooner or later I figured Paulo would
lead me to the stolen payroll in a way
that possibility made me even feel
better
it's not fair to watch the show from
backstage next time I will pay admission
I take it by that remark I like my
routine yeah you're pretty good what I
can't figure out though is while you
stay in a place like this you shouldn't
be hard for someone like you to get a
job in a class fine if you want a
detective I'd be willing to bet with a
line like that your next remark would be
how about dinner
well not exactly dinner but a hamburger
might be a good idea if you're asking in
an official capacity I can't say no I'm
off duty for the past six months all
I've ever called you is lieutenant Jason
do you have a person eight Oh dick give
me 10 minutes for a quick change because
you just made yourself a date attendant
I mean
next something - I haven't had hamburger
in the front seat of an automobile with
a guy and a lot of years well from now
on we'll do it more often funny I always
figurative policemen wasn't really a
human being I mean unless he was
arresting someone or trying to solve a
case he was unhappy shows you how wrong
you were in fact everyone on the force
gets fed up occasionally with the job
maybe maybe we're more human than anyone
else we see so much trouble we get to
hate the work but as long as the world's
filled with people will have to be men
who enforce the laws what made you join
the department now is making with the
questions no honest I'd like to know
well it's really a very short story when
I got out of the Air Corps I knocked
around.
I went to work for an oil company one
day and went back to college on the GI.
Bill just before graduation I noticed
all about the police department exams
seemed a pretty good thing to do with
your life so I took the exams passed
then went on from there if I ask one
more question
try am I still part of the child federal
investigation
I mean right now I don't think so as far
as the department's concerned when.
Benton was executed the case was mark
closed inside of me that's not good
enough
hey I don't fathom the $600,000 is still
missing and a fast-talking underworld
lawyer like Paul Lowe is walking around
a free man someday no matter how long it
takes I'll get him and the money until I
do the Benton case for me is not closed
give you my word digger Charles that
never told me anything about the money
I've been sure that for a long time but
how did you ever get mixed up with
anyone like the butcher
there's trouble ever started just
happened I had a roommate he used to
date Benton all the time
one day she packed and left for Chicago
button carried a torch for and he used
my shoulder to cry first thing I knew we
were having dinner together and few
weeks later I was labeled by the police
as this number-one suspect and and.
Benton's girl but it was never like that
I made only one mistake I felt sorry you
mean until he was arrested for the
robbery and the killing you had no idea
how he earned a living I know this is
going to sound crazy but I only went out
with Benton a couple of times
and all we ever talked about was Madge
my old roommate last time I saw him he
tried to get too friendly and that's
when I told him he had the wrong girl
but like I said I already made my
mistake what about the burlesque house
how do you two fit together
you sound like a lot of other people I
left a small town a couple of years ago
because I won a beauty contest and the
first prize was a screen
after which nothing happens that's right
only it was pretty rough and then one
day I read an ad about girls wanted for
a burlesque show I auditioned I got the
job you know some it's like any other
job if you're looking for trouble you
can find it even in a schoolroom
when the screen test didn't work out why
don't you go on home
well first you have to have a home to go
back to my books are dead so nurse.
Angeles was as good as anyplace else I
don't know about you but I do eight
shows a day at this hour I'm bushed
I know what you mean mind if I Drive you
home no and I'll tell you something else
I haven't minded anything about tonight
not even the hamburger I kept playing
tag with lo he made four telephone calls
three of them didn't interest me but one
bid the one to Joe Marcel II I watched.
Joe head for his meeting with Lo and for
some unknown reason I began to get the
feeling that this case was finally about
to explode in my favor if they were.
I feel starter on two legs but he's
doing it on power that out you three bag
look who's calling names least I get a.
Squealer a story I warned you before all
right Harry that's enough halt take care
of them I want to talk okay mr. Lowe any
future business you've got with this
psycho take care of it upstairs in your
office you keep showing around here
sooner or later he's gonna get slugged
ripped learn okay.
I need a shot bad you'll get one after I
talk to you sober enough understand yeah
I run out of dope
I wonder look at it you used to be the
best torch man in town how I don't think
you could crack a safe if you knew the
combination no jobs nobody wants me
since I turned States on Benton
that's your to it you told me alright
quit cry I got a job for you if you can
stay off that stuff long enough you know
I can infer got a job how much what is
it.
It's too grinded where I knew where he
pulled the job
interesting two grand ain't much other
600,000 we other expensive side that
money's plenty of ah whatever I get
another I'll do it how soon do you want
me to go to work
set it up for tomorrow night call me
before noon I'm mother
one that's all of jobs
butcher was walking slowly toward Los
Angeles he traveled through wooded hills
to prevent being seen by anyone finally
he came to a quiet road he stopped to
get his bearings and then he saw her he
saw something else an automobile for the
butcher that rang a bell with a car he
knew by the next afternoon he'd be in.
Los Angeles and plenty of time to catch
up with the three men who had
double-crossed him
well see you a real gentleman to be
helping strangers in distress I hope you
don't mind me using the babe here is
bait why did this isn't she but that's
what she gets paid for bait that is yes
huh
she's a real secret artist of my outfit
carnival man myself just call me Connie
yeah um well feng we with a little bit
of difficulty here got a flat tire
brand-new car no tools in the back why
some of these dealers make my carnival
grip this look like babes in the woods
sound Gilhooley say who you wish break
let it down let it down no matter who
you with Brenda believe me I can do
better for both of us I'll make a
fortune for the both of us
an hour later the San Francisco Police.
Department sent out an APB
squads were sent to various parts of the
countryside
roadblocks were thrown up to catch the
cold-blooded killer the hysterical girl
had described each squad kept reporting
back to central headquarters and each of
their stories was the same so far none
of them had spotted the car the killer
was driving orders were given to shoot
to kill because from the girls further
accounts they realized they were dealing
with a maniac.
I trust this information will answer all
of your questions if I can be of any
further service let me know
sincerely ji louder captain police la
another all-points of CHP cab please
report sound like they come from a bunch
of loonies sure do there it is
sergeant I want lieutenant Jason to look
these over as soon as he comes in right
the next morning I read the stories of
the brutal murder of the two police
officers I also read the witness's
statement about the bullets having no
effect upon the killer I felt sorry for
the witness and I thought about how
easily a person's mind can become
confused when suddenly they receive a
brutal shock I didn't believe a man
existed who did not be stopped by a slug
from a 45 good morning captain you and
the rest of the force are going on
24-hour duty see headlines win this guy
that's running a mock up North latest
report he's killed two police officers
hey to get away in a green coupe heading
south I've got a hunch this killer is
gonna be our baby he could be in town
right now yeah you better get started
with it okay any new leads on that hole
of mine I think the girl can probably be
counted out if any of the others are
wise they're keeping mighty quiet let it
ride for now the old force is gonna be
on the spot until we catch this killer
newspapers will have a field day
we were wrong about two things
the killer was already in our city and
we didn't know he was butcher Benton he
headed straight for Eva Martin he went
to her dressing room to get back the map
he had left in the envelope with her he
wanted first to check his money then
catch up with Lo and the others
can't be
you do look like my different summer
he's you waiting somebody tell me
happened job look like bullet holes are
they
leave me mark.
I opened it like you told me I found 50
dollars I didn't know why you left him a
positive note I was here
don't don't don't play crazy
the name of Paul triggered his hate he
left her dressing room started for squee
me Ellis and Joe Marcellus place because
he knew with them out of the way Paul.
Lowe couldn't open the strongbox where
the money was hidden
he thought of squee me and Joe first he
was saving Paul Lowe for last
hey IVA can I borrow your eyebrow pencil
operator got me police headquarters
but then I chase him please
when do you expect what
tell him Charles Benton is alive and and
even bullets can't stop I'm not crazy
just say a friend of Charles Hill now
she tried to tell him the butcher was
alive and on his way over to kill him
swimmy didn't believe her and in a way
you couldn't blame him who in their
right mind would believe a man had
returned from the dead
what's Queenie actually believed was
that the butcher before his execution
had hired a killer to carry out his
threat
music what you don't look so good to me
alright favor I could take over the
matinee trick play what it's easy okay
but I can do it
step up to doo doo doo oh I'm nothing I
just thought of something
yeah Eva agreed to let Franz sing to the
show she hoped she'd be able to
interrupt the butcher before he arrived
at squeeze Hotel or failing that at
least be able to warn him to stay out of
sight you want to meet captain yeah I
just had to run down on those
fingerprints a stolen car up north I got
nothing on the driver who was killed
with a woman with him take a good look
at these there's something funny about
these yeah the boys in the lab can't
figure it out either those are the
killer's they were found on the steering
wheel looked like they'd been stamped in
with a steel die we sure do these are
butcher Benton's what they look the same
to me how did the lab boys explain that
I don't their best guess is a twin
brother an identical twin could have the
same pattern of whirls with only slight
variations
ever hear of the butcher having a twin
brother no even if he did it wouldn't
explain these free prints he didn't pick
up your message let's add some wacky
dame calls you and she says Charles
Benton is alive then bullets won't stop
him if we buy the twin theory who was
she
what'd she seem well she wouldn't leave
her name it sounded kind of hysterical
to me said she was a friend of the
butcher's Eva Martin you know with the
follies and see what that girl knows
yeah
some guys have all the luck I never drew
an assign with the follies
meanwhile the butcher headed for
squeemish hotel he didn't seem to be in
any particular hurry actually seemed
like any normal person on his way to
work on his way home
he rolled up angels flight arrived at
the top scanned the hotel building and
then noticed the only exit from squee.
Me's apartment a fire escape
you
the butcher was figuring his next step
and as he looked at the dead cop and
thought about tall low the next man on
his list seeing Joe might le Monson's
last night when I told him I didn't want
him around here no more give me a shot
look can we help just find out if it's
how to code to get me that's a joke -
then let's drink up and get out I don't
want no trouble around my place you're a
real pal
drink up and get out I said
operator get me to believe
what's happening guy named screamy got
thrown from the fifth floor that he's
dead on a mackerel customer remind you
being screaming Ellis
yeah that's it yes I mean no no one
else's you a one enough.
I tell you the bullets never even fazed
and you must been wearing a bulletproof
vest god help us the papers get ahold of
this keep an officer on duty here to be
here for me we're gonna stake out on
Jill more Kelly I'd like to talk to Joe.
Lauder I'm gonna call San Quentin
suppose Benton is alive every available
man has been put on the case now yes sir
all right all right anything new report
on dr. Bradshaw owner of the station
wagon the San Francisco police located
his laboratory in the basement of an
electrical power receiving station right.
Shaw what's he know he's dead and
another man - his assistant the lab is a
shambles but now we're getting some
action from San Francisco Benton's body
never arrived at the mortuary where it
was supposed to go and attendant there
finally broke down admitted he picked up
some quick cash by handing the body over
to a man he was unable to identify the
man was driving his station wagon
blasted man the Chiefs on my neck and
the commissioners are on his and the
mayor's on theirs
now am I supposed to tell him that our
killer is a dead man they found a
notebook in Bradshaw's lab it ties his
experiments in with a professor Dwiggins
at Cal Tech I hope to hear from Dwiggins
soon captain before from the valley on
the hysterical woman reports the
presence the killer
there's the location let's go
you and your boyfriend had a little
fight me get out of the car to take a
walk you noticed as he walked down
toward the Sun Prairie in the direction
where you've seen those lights a short
while before what happened then miss
please try to tell us well I just sit
there few minutes I guess I was pretty
mad and it was a loud crash like like
heavy metal sources from down here I got
out of a talk to get a better look I
heard Jimmy cry out something I couldn't
make out the words I'm down here
look patch it's like was Jimmy and I
coming toward him was with this man
big lifter Jimmy up over his head like
you didn't want a thing
give me screamed just one boy broke.
Jimmy's bad oh sorry.
I started running for a ballast high
they let me use the phone.
Thank You Man
we'll see you together O'Malley see that
the young lady gets home already
Paul lo while driving to his office
heard a radio commentator report the
murder of Joe Marcel II and what shocked
in most was when the broadcast
identified the killer as possibly being
the butcher low headed straight for Eva
Martin at the burlesque theater he
kidney is back mr. Lowe what are you
doing here where's Eva oh I'm taking her
place I'm gonna wear a costume what's it
you I asked you where's Eva hey don't
get physical and watch your tone of
voice buzzer I told you the leader isn't
here I could see that for myself where
is she she's at police headquarters
that's where she is
yes sir no sir captain Lauder is still
with the mayor the killer dropped out of
sight he was last seen in the Hollywood
area yes sir we we know he's dangerous
every angles being covered yes sir I'll
tell him
yes yeah they spit hello you know I'm
sorry it's the best our wardrobe
department could afford the idea I'll
soon the captain will be by now look I'm
gonna see the captain about the way here
all night Oh Oh Charles kill screaming
and Joe Joe to Benton he's alive I saw
him but nobody will believe me I'm
checking it
my guess is whoever killed them is on
the trail of the money low now maybe you
better start talking if you know
anything about it I don't know anything
did the butcher have a brother no no
brother it was Charles I saw the tattoo
on his arm
look I demand police protection where's
the money low you heard yeah demand
protection I know my rights
we put stakeouts on your office at home
that's not enough it's enough as far as
we're concerned wait how you gonna put
me sergeant Dan throw away the key thank
you come up with anything yet dick oh
we've checked every hotel motel and
rooming house in town we run a
cross-check on every hangout butcher
ever used net results blank this is
incredible we not only discover a dead
man turned killer but it's beginning to
look like he plays ghost too
he's somewhere in this city and if we
have to take it apart brick by brick
we've got to get him I may be way off
but I think Paul Lowe could tell us a
lot maybe it's a cinch he's not going to
suppose he had no alternative
he'd you better grab some coffee your
minds beginning to play tricks on you no
now wait a minute
when Lowe came to us for police
protection it was because he was scared
stiff the butcher would add him to the
list of squee me Ellis and Joe MRSA
go on it figures to when he slugged the
sergeant he knew we'd book him right
away
oh this lows a pretty cute character but
we can play the same game you mean will
threaten to release him well not exactly
you tell him you realize that he was
excited that throwing the punch was
accidental tell him we're not going to
make a charge that he's completely
released lieutenant you know we can't do
that.
Lowell made his first mistake when he
hit the sergeant never get him a year as
far as the department's concerned at
least it's a small victory if my hunch
is Right Lowe won't want to be on the
streets with the butcher looking for him
and he may talk and talk a lot enough
maybe for us to get rid of him
permanently even lead us to the butcher
if he's frightened enough that might
work but if it doesn't know dick I'm not
gonna release him I want him out of my
way so bad I can taste it but not bad
enough to be responsible for getting it
killed the good thing about that captain
is the fact we know it but Lowe doesn't
let's give it a try
all right Lowe come on up.
I think you'll find everything in there
you're free to go mr. Lowell wait a
minute
who do you think you're kidding you
arrested me for assaulting an officer.
Court I'll plead guilty with luck I
might get off with six months for a
lawyer you're forgetting a very
important point if no charge is made
there's no trial it was a tough day for
everyone we figured your nerves were on
edge and when you threw the punch you
didn't know what you were doing
I've squared everything with the
sergeant it's all over all forgotten
yeah why'd you bring a stenographer
simply because I wanted a record of our
conversation at the time of your release
okay low let's go oh wait a minute
what's that on those streets and I'm a
dead man
you let me go you'll be responsible for
murder don't come off at low you're
imagining things
you know the butcher threatened to kill
me you set me free we'll do it well
that's just a risk we'll have to take
but the way I look at it mr. Lowell
you'll be okay
but captain I'll make a deal with you
you keep me here and I'll tell you how
to recover the money maybe even catch
the butcher no deals loan you'd probably
tell us anything just to stall for time
come on let's get out of here now wait a
minute all right
I'll tell you the truth
start taking this down.
I Paulo hired butcher Benton squee me
Ellis and Joe Miceli to pull off the
armored car holdup and then lo continued
with his confession he told us about
finding the map he showed us the exact
location of where the butcher had hidden
the stolen payroll and he gave us a most
important answer the explanation as to
how the butcher was able to elude
detection his means of escape was the
sewer systems an entire city
the department went to work fast every
police squad in the city was detailed to
cover a specific area every entrance and
exit to the Los Angeles City sewer
system of 700 miles was covered Captain.
Lauder and I along with several other
squads headed for the entrance where
according to the map butchering the
money our job was to stop it and that
made me think of one specific question
when we found him that this monster be
stopped I for one wasn't sure
everything all set lieutenant
city engineers mapped out each possible
exit squad of officers are spotted at
every point the butcher can be caught
now's the time after I talked to Caltech
I called on the fire department for a
little help
the professor's thought a flame soar
might stop him flamethrower
I suppose their boys have had a chance
to join our squads by now see we have
one with us here have you thought about
what will happen if this doesn't work no
I've been praying too hard that it will
work
this was where we split up I'll go
straight ahead
this Maps right we're off our course we
left a backtrack.
I didn't have it
and the tremendous shock of electricity
that brought the butcher back to life
destroyed him the six hundred thousand
dollars stolen in the armored truck
robbery has been recovered case closed
well here the scientists comments for
your records
either fill in a few spots with my old
guesses but I guess that's about the
size of it you can't sleep.
Oh some not much how's the girl today
well I called the hospital about an hour
ago she'd gone gone where she told them
she was a working girl and that she'd
been away from the job too long already
quite a girl
yeah say uh how about that time off I've
got coming 48 hours beginning right now
miss Resnick
and then something big the past 72 hours
seemed like a bad dream that rest in the
hospital today really gave me a new
lease on life now that it's over right I
can't believe it actually happened the
important thing is to remember it is all
over I suppose you'll be assigned to
another case now I'll have to give up
hamburgers in the front seat of the car
for steaks and a restaurant no I've
thought about that
in fact I decided to do something about
it I started by talking the captain into
a short holiday and just about an hour
ago
I got you fired what what'd you do that
for I figured that being my wife would
take up all of your time.
I wanted to say no I couldn't you're not
supposed to say no to a complaint I
figured that