Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Good evening, Evans.
Evening, sir.
Dinner is served, Mr. Kessler.
Thank you.
Good evening, my dear.
You're more beautiful
than ever this evening.
Mrs. Kessler first, Evans.
Oh yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Evans, how's dad taking it?
Alright, miss Virginia.
They're having dinner.
I'll answer it.
Hello, Virginia.
I told you not to come
here this evening, Ralph.
Why?
Didn't you want to see me?
Well, it isn't that I
didn't want to see you.
You're certainly acting
strange, darling.
What's all the mystery about?
Let's go into the library.
Ralph!
After dinner we are
taking a long walk.
I'd like to speak to you, Ralph.
What's come over your
father, Virginia?
Is that why you didn't
want me here tonight?
Yes.
It stopped me cold.
I'm sorry if I accidentally
stumbled on something you
didn't want me to know.
Well, it must seem weird to
someone who's
never seen it before.
It happens once a year.
He always appeared
perfectly rational to me.
Well, there's something
I must tell you.
It's about my mother.
I don't understand.
Well, it happened
several years ago.
My father and mother were
apparently as happy as two
people could be.
He worshipped her.
Another man?
The usual best friend.
They almost broke
my father's heart.
He seemed reconciled, but he
never forgets their wedding
anniversary and
celebrates it that way.
I guess he isn't the only one
who resorts to make believe.
But it does give one
an uncanny feeling.
Well, it doesn't
frighten me anymore.
Now that you know.
I love you.
You wanted your
coat, miss Kessler?
Oh.
Oh yes, thank you.
I was going to take a drive,
it's such a beautiful night.
Come along?
Yes, of course.
Sure you don't mind going?
No, no, I'd love it.
We'll be back in
an hour, cecile.
Yes, miss.
Hums
that's a nice young
man of miss Virginia's.
I guess so.
If he wasn't, miss Virginia
wouldn't bother with him.
Does she plan to marry him?
I never discuss things
that aren't my business.
If you want to stay here,
I suggest you don't
be so curious.
Well, just the same, I think
this is a crazy house.
And what about those murders?
Jules here says there's
been a lot of them.
And nobody's ever been able to
find out who did the killing.
You talk too much, Jules.
But I only said that...
Excuse me, miss cecile.
I'm going to show you
where we keep our linens.
Mrs. Kessler?
Oh Mrs. Kessler?
I brought you a dinner.
Oh please, Mrs. Kessler,
I got to go home.
Home?
I want to go home, too.
But you are home.
And as soon as you feel better,
I'm going to take you to
your husband and daughter.
But they never write to me.
Oh, but they don't know
where you are, Mrs. Kessler.
Nobody knows that but me.
You see, I found you.
I'm running away.
Running away in a car.
We're going faster,
faster, faster.
We're going to crash!
I can't go home now, can I?
Mrs. Kessler, please.
Please eat your dinner.
I've got to go home.
I'll be back in the morning.
Good night, Mrs. Kessler.
Good night.
You're late again, Jules.
I'm sorry, mama.
But I just couldn't
get away from her.
Jules, why don't you tell
Mr. Kessler about his wife,
that you're hiding her?
Oh, I haven't got
the heart, mama.
It would kill him if he
saw her the way she is.
Poor thing.
She'd be better off if she'd
died with that man when the
car was wrecked.
I guess so.
Jules, I've been thinking.
Maybe she had something
to do with all these
horrible murders.
Oh, ho, ho, she
wouldn't hurt nobody.
She's like a child.
She's still dazed
from the accident.
You know, amnesia.
She'll be better soon,
then I'll take her home.
But if they found out
I've been hiding her,
they might think I had something
to do with the murder.
Jules, you must
tell Mr. Kessler.
Oh, no, no, mama.
We must never tell anyone.
Never.
Sure you won't come in?
No thanks, darling, I
think I better run along.
Good night, Ralph.
Oh, Virginia?
Shall I put your car away?
No thanks.
Evans will take care of it.
Alright.
'Night.
Good evening, miss Virginia.
Would you please put
my car in the garage
when you have a moment?
Yes, miss.
Hello, Casanova.
Have you gone crazy?
The only chance
I had to see you.
You ignored my letters
and my telephone calls.
Did you think that you
could get rid of me
as easy as all that?
Be quiet.
They'll hear you.
You bet they will.
And you're going to
listen to me, too.
I'm not giving up for that
Kessler girl or anybody else.
This is different, cecile.
I never said I loved you.
Are you in love with her?
Yes.
Well, you're not
marrying her, understand?
Nothing's going to stand
in the way of my happiness.
Not even you.
Don't threaten me.
She'll have to know
about us sooner or later.
And besides, I'll make
you a good wife, Ralph.
I promise I will.
Guess what?
What?
I'm in love.
With Ralph?
Yes, dad.
He's a fine boy.
I'm so happy for you, my dear.
Oh, he hasn't asked me to
marry him yet, but he will.
I know he will.
Good night, my pet.
Good night too.
Good night, Evans.
Good night, miss Virginia.
Can I do anything for
you, sir, before I retire?
What happened to
your hand, Evans?
Oh, nothing, sir.
I hurt it when I was putting
miss Virginia's
car in the garage.
Put anything on it?
Oh, the bandage.
Oh, you may have an infection.
How's that?
Just like new, sir.
I guess I'll read for a while.
Good night, Evans.
Good night, sir.
Oh yes, Evans.
Thank you for the dinner.
Yes, sir.
I'm afraid to come home.
You'd kill me.
You'd kill anybody.
Why Mr. Kessler.
Aah!
Woman screams
Exercise number one.
Arms at the sides.
At the count of one, four times.
Cecile?
One the chest.
At the count of two, move
your arms above your head.
At the count of three,
lower arms sideways.
If it's exercise you want,
there's plenty of
it in the kitchen.
At the count of four, lower
the arms
cecile!
And straight.
Arms at sides.
Ready, begin.
One, up, up, down,
one, up, up, down.
One, two, three, four, one,
two, three, four, one, two,
three, four.
Up, up, up.
One, two.
Mr. Kessler.
Yes?
Something terrible has happened.
I tried to wake the new maid.
I think she's dead.
Dead?
How did it happen?
I don't know, sir.
I thought she was
taking her exercises.
Call the police.
I'll see what I can do.
Yes, sir.
Well, Mr. Kessler, we're up
to our ears in another one.
The girl was killed the same way
as the chauffeur six months ago.
Only thing we could
find was this note,
left by some fellow who
wanted to give her the air.
It's terrible, lieutenant.
She was so young.
If we could find out
who killed cecile,
we have the one who committed
all the other murders.
That's easier said than done.
There's never been fingerprints,
to say nothing of motives.
What gets me, Mr. Kessler,
is why you refuse
to move out of this place.
Sentimental reasons.
There's nothing very
sentimental about a house
where anything could
happen and usually does.
My mother lived
here, lieutenant.
I see.
You're the gardener?
Yes, but I wasn't here.
I went home early.
See, I live with my wife.
Alright, alright, alright.
And please don't try to see me.
Signed, Ralph.
Ralph?
Do you know him?
Oh, I'm certain I don't.
The name startled me.
I'm practically
engaged to a Ralph.
Did you notice anything
unusual last night, Evans?
Well, maybe I better not say.
Let's have it, Evans.
When I was putting the
roadster in the garage,
I saw cecile talk
to Mr. dickson.
That's miss Virginia's Ralph.
Go on.
I didn't mean to listen,
but they were talking loud.
Then I heard him say
that he never loved her.
She said she wouldn't let
him marry anyone else.
That made him real mad, and
said nothing was going to
stand between him
and his happiness.
Not even her.
I knew cecile a couple of years.
She offered me the
companionship I needed.
Then I met you and fell in
love for the first time.
I love you too, Ralph.
Surely you can account for
your activities from the time
you left our house
until the next morning.
No, Mr. Kessler.
I had a lot to think about.
I took a long ride
into the country,
didn't stop anywhere and
didn't see a soul I knew.
That's most unfortunate.
All I know is that
I, I didn't kill her.
There isn't any doubt
about that in our minds.
Don't worry, son.
We'll do everything
we possibly can.
Order.
Order in the courtroom.
You solemnly swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth?
I do.
Yes, I manage the apartments
where Ralph dickson lived.
Miss mannix came there often.
As a matter of fact, I
thought they were married.
I went home early and helped
my wife with the house cleaning.
The coroner's testimony
should convince you that
the defendant had
sufficient reason
for wanting to be
rid of the victim.
It's the truth.
Said he wouldn't let nothing
stand in the way of his
happiness, not even her.
We're doing everything
we possibly can.
Tomorrow we're going
to see the governor.
Oh, and I'm sure
something can be done.
But governor, the
man is innocent.
If you would only Grant
a stay of execution.
If you knew him,
you'd realize he couldn't
possibly be a murderer.
I'm sorry.
I've gone over the
facts in the case,
and unless you can
present some new evidence,
there's nothing I can do.
The lord is my Shepherd,
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie
down in green pastures.
He leadeth me beside
the still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
He leadeth me in the
paths of righteousness,
for his namesake.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil.
For thou art with me.
Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
Thou prepareth a table
before me in the
presence of mine enemy.
Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me all the days
of my life, and I will dwell
in the house of
the lord forever.
Yes?
I see.
It's all over.
My name is dickson.
Yes. Of course.
I'd like to see Mr. Kessler.
He's in there.
I hope I'm not intruding.
Oh Ralph!
It can't be.
Apparently my brother
never told you about me.
Come in.
I've been in south America.
I flew here at once.
However, I'm afraid it's
too late to do any good.
So you're Ralph's brother.
I knew about you,
but I never expected
such a striking resemblance.
Sorry to have startled you.
This is my daughter, Virginia.
How do you do?
Won't you join us?
I've had my dinner, thanks.
But I would like to talk to you.
Do I look pale?
No.
Huh?
I feel pale.
The buzzer, Evans.
What's the matter, you deaf?
Did he have a good attorney?
Oh, one of the very best.
He's handled all of dad's
legal affairs for years.
Evans, Mr. dickson will
have coffee with us.
Oh, I'm Ralph dickson's brother.
Well, you sure had me
going for a minute.
But you do look
like poor Mr. Ralph.
Coffee.
Yes, sir.
I realize how incriminating
circumstantial evidence can
be, but it was never brought
home to me like this before.
We did everything
we possibly could.
You know that Ralph and my
daughter were quite serious
about each other.
Yes, he told me in
his last letter.
Sit down.
How long do you plan
to say in this country?
Haven't decided
yet, Mr. Kessler.
But I would like to find
out who killed that girl.
Mm.
It's something I would
like to know, too.
Please consider this your
home while you're here.
If there's anything I
can do, don't hesitate.
Thank you.
I'll see that your
room is put in order.
Are you sure I'm
not troubling you?
No, no, not at all.
Entertain Paul
until I come back.
Paul, oh Paul?
Yes?
I'll show you to your room.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, I almost forgot.
I must see Evans,
oh, about breakfast.
Well, good night Virginia.
Good night, Paul.
Good night, dad.
Come in.
I hope you'll be comfortable.
I'll send for your
luggage in the morning.
It's awfully nice
of you, Mr. Kessler.
Really, I hope that
it's a pleasure to have you.
Thank you, sir.
Well, I guess I'll turn in.
I haven't had much sleep
the last couple of nights.
Good night.
Good night, sir.
Hello, operator?
Give me the police department.
No.
The body has not been touched.
Yes.
Alright.
Good morning, Evans.
Morning, Mr. Kessler.
Now, what's the matter?
The gardener, sir.
What?
He's been murdered.
Murdered?
Strangled.
Well, here we go again.
How long did he work for you?
Oh, about three years, I guess.
Ever say anything to you
about having any enemies?
No, sir.
Were you home last night?
Yes, lieutenant.
To your knowledge, did anybody
come in or go out of the house
during the course
of the evening?
We have a house guest.
Why isn't he here?
I'll get him.
Oh, don't trouble
yourself, Mr. Kessler.
Where is he?
He's upstairs in his bedroom.
Let's have a look at him, Ryan.
Good morning.
You're wanted in the kitchen.
In the kitchen?
Yeah.
Am I seeing things?
He's Ralph's brother.
Why, he's the image of him.
How did this happen?
That's what we'd
like to find out.
He was strangled, Paul.
Would you mind if we
go into the library?
No, that's alright.
Better wait here for
the coroner, Ryan.
Not you, Evans.
Hey, where we you on the
night of January the 13th?
Have you had your coffee yet?
No.
Well, I guess that's that.
No clues, no fingerprints,
no motive, nothing.
But surely if a man was
choked to death there would be
imprints on his throat.
Hm.
There weren't any
on the mannix girl.
And they were killed the
same way, is that right?
That doesn't prove
a thing, dickson.
All the others got it
and always the same way.
The coroner's here.
Ok.
I'll be right back.
What does he mean by the others?
Just that.
Others have been killed here.
Why in the world do
you stay in this place?
We can't leave.
Your luggage, sir.
I'll put them in your room.
What about these other murders?
I'll put your luggage
in your room, sir.
Oh, lieutenant?
Yeah?
I'd like to ask you
a few questions.
Well, that'll be
a change, anyhow.
What's bothering you?
As a rule, I'm not a very
curious person, but er..,
house beginning to get you, huh?
In a way, yes.
What about these other murders?
Well, there's been quite
a lot of them, dickson.
Some of the best brains
in the department
have tried to solve them.
We always run up
against a stone wall.
Were the other murders brought
out in my brother's trial?
That was different.
That was a cut and dried case.
Why haven't the police
closed the house?
Well, we tried to, but Mr.
Kessler took it to court.
Carries a lot of
weight around here.
He does a lot of good, too.
You'd think he'd want to leave.
Ah, I guess he's waiting
for his wife to come back.
She left him several years ago.
An awful scandal at the time.
Front page stuff and all that.
Poor devil.
He didn't have a chance.
Mm.
Well, I guess I'll
be running along.
Glad I met you, dickson.
Good day, lieutenant.
Well, this isn't a
very pleasant way
to entertain a guest.
You know, Mr. Kessler, I have
a feeling that somehow or
other these mysterious murders
are going to be cleared up,
and quickly, too.
Nothing will please me more.
Your wife?
Yes.
She's beautiful.
I rarely talk about her, but
I think about her constantly.
She has eyes like Virginia's.
Her hair, her skin.
They were the loveliest
I've ever seen.
I hope you have the
pleasure of meeting her.
She'll be back someday.
Hello there.
Paul was admiring
your mother's picture.
Father's a sentimentalist.
He has every right to be.
I'll get it.
Hello?
Yes?
Just a moment, please.
It's for you, dad.
Thank you.
Yes?
Yes, I guess I can.
Yes.
Oh, in about twenty
minutes, I'd say.
Surely.
Goodbye.
I'll see you children later.
Business.
Sorry.
That's the only information
I can give you, Mr. Kirby.
Have you notified his wife?
Yes, Mr. Kessler.
Poor thing, she
took it quite hard.
It's terrible. Awful
I want to see the coroner.
Yes?
I'm Jules' wife.
Where have they taken him?
In there, Mrs. Mason.
If you please, sir.
May I have one moment
alone with him?
I won't ever see him again.
Well yes, I guess so.
Thank you, sir.
Aah!
Mrs. Mason, Mrs. Mason.
You better take
her out, Mr. Kirby.
He's alive.
What?
I saw him move.
I'll get the hospital.
You'll be alright, Mrs. Mason.
Steady now.
Get him out of here.
He's not dead.
The doctor will be
here any minute.
Jules?
Please, Mrs. Mason.
Jules, listen to me.
Did you recognize the man
who tried to kill you?
It was ghastly.
I don't believe I was ever
more startled in my life than
when Mrs. Mason screamed.
It must have been
a terrific shock
to see him come back to life.
Yes, it was.
Just a few moments longer and
they would have known who the
assailant was.
I don't like to bring up
the subject, Mr. Kessler,
but these murders, did they
ever happen in the daytime?
No, I don't believe so.
I see.
You evidently have
some reason for asking.
Not particularly.
I was just curious
about that one point.
Sorry dinner is
late tonight, sir.
But the new cook is having
quite a time getting started.
That's alright.
Evans been with you long?
Over some years.
Everything's gone wrong today.
Now I burned the roast.
Oh, don't get so flustered.
You'll be alright.
I was so anxious to make
good, I want to stay.
Where is that mixing spoon?
Here it is, right
in front of you.
Thanks.
I like it here.
It's nice.
Everything's so quiet
and peaceful like.
Ever read the newspapers?
No, they're just full of
trash and murders and stuff.
Mm.
What you don't know,
well, it's alright.
Here's your pepper salt.
Thanks.
Well, Paul, I'm afraid
you have me cornered.
You still have a couple
of moves, Mr. Kessler.
You met your equal, dad.
Oh, your father just got
himself into a bad position.
I hear a storm.
It's your game, Paul.
Want to play another?
Oh, thank you, not tonight.
It's getting late.
Pardon me, sir.
Yes?
May I speak to you
a moment please?
Well yes, certainly.
The cook wants to leave.
I thought you should know.
Why, she just came.
She feels as if her
work is unsatisfactory.
She had so much trouble
with dinner tonight.
Why, that's ridiculous.
Oh, I understand,
it's her first day.
I'll speak to her.
I'll say good
night, Mr. Kessler.
Think I'll turn in.
Thanks for the game.
Good night, Paul.
Good night, dad.
Good night, child.
I'll walk up with you, Paul.
Oh, glad to have your company.
It's a long, lonesome climb
up those stairs all alone.
Where are you going, Marie?
You can't leave us after cooking
such an elegant dinner.
Did you really like
it, Mr. Kessler?
Why, I never tasted anything
to equal that roast beef.
Besides, you can't go now,
it's going to rain any minute.
Are you sure you
want me to stay?
Oh certainly, Marie.
Well, I like it here,
but I thought,
then it is settled.
Wait til you taste my
apple pie, Mr. Kessler.
Apple pie!
My, that will be a treat.
Let me take this.
You might as well unpack
your things, Marie.
Yes, sure.
Thank you, sir.
Not at all, Marie.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Kessler.
Oh, he's a wonderful man.
Now let's see.
What did I do wrong?
Mr. Kessler?
Are you ill?
What?
Something wrong?
No, Paul.
I must have walked in my sleep.
Well, you did better than I.
I couldn't sleep at all.
It's raining.
Why don't you go to bed, Paul?
I'm alright.
Is there anything I can do?
Nothing, Paul.
Thank you.
I think I'll read for a while.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Kessler.
Well, you look like you had a
good night's sleep, Mr. Kessler.
I was so tired
when I got to bed,
I don't even
remember climbing in.
Dad!
Who would do a thing like that?
I wonder if anyone was hurt.
Nothing could have
hurt my father more.
It's unquestionably
the work of a madman.
You alright, Evans?
Yes sir, Mr. Kessler.
Good morning, sir.
Where is the new cook?
She said she was going shopping
first thing this morning.
Have you looked in her room?
No, sir.
Something wrong, Mr. Kessler?
There's her valise.
She didn't leave.
I'm not worried about that.
When did she tell you
she's going to the market?
Last night before
she went to bed.
Do you think there's any
connection between this and
what has happened before?
I don't know.
Have you been through the
rest of the house yet?
No, sir.
Good morning, Mr. Kessler.
Oh, Marie.
You have no idea how
happy I am to see you.
Thank you.
I wonder why he was
so glad to see me.
Mr. Kessler thought
you had been murdered.
Oh, he's so sweet.
I'm going to start
to make an apple pie.
Murdered?
I can't imagine who would
do a thing like that.
I'll get it.
Good morning, miss Kessler.
Won't you come in?
Thank you.
That happened last night.
Didn't it fall?
No.
Find me the person who did it
and you've got your murderer.
Nobody came into this
house last night.
Ryan and his boys were
stationed outside.
Lieutenant?
Oh lieutenant?
Come out!
Come on out, I say!
It's Ryan!
Aah!
Then you didn't hear any
noises during the night?
No.
But there's funny things
going on around here.
Meaning what?
Well, it's happened
three times now.
I put food on the
sink, left the room,
when I come back it was gone.
No.
You ought to hire a
detective to watch it.
That's what you get for
being such an excellent cook.
Thank you, sir.
Oh lieutenant?
Yeah?
Got something?
I don't know.
I, I found this in the picture.
Anybody else know about it?
No, I wanted to
speak to you first.
Ok.
I'll see if I can match it.
Keep the others downstairs.
Why not?
I agree.
Is, uh, this yours, Mr. Kessler?
Yes.
Why?
I'd thought I'd seen it on you.
Found it in Evans's room.
Well, there's nothing
strange about that.
There wouldn't be, Mr. Kessler,
but it so happens that a
thread from this robe was
found embedded in the picture.
Surely you're not
trying to accuse Evans?
Oh, it's incredible.
You're just trying
to make a case.
Well, somebody's been
doing these killings.
Ryan didn't die of heart
failure, don't forget that.
When did you give Evans
that robe, Mr. Kessler?
I don't remember giving
it to him at all.
But naturally, when my
things need mending,
he just picks them up.
I don't care how he got it.
He had it and he used
it on that picture.
I'm going to talk to him.
Now just a minute, lieutenant.
Yeah?
If Evans is the man we want,
it strikes me you've got to
have more evidence.
Huh.
Now everybody wants
to be a detective.
Now wait a minute.
Perhaps Paul has
some suggestion.
Alright, go ahead.
What is it?
Without doubt, the
murderer is insane.
The picture tells us that.
I believe we should
call in a psychiatrist.
A psychiatrist.
You still got the robe.
But before Evans is accused,
I'm definitely in favor of
giving him a sanity test.
What do you say, lieutenant?
Ok.
Maybe I better take one myself.
All we want to know is
if the fellow's crazy.
That's very easy to determine.
Shall we make the
examination here?
If you don't mind, doctor.
Please tell Evans
I want to see him
and then go up to your room.
Go to my room?
Is it possible, doctor, for
a man to be normal, say,
for two or three
months at a time,
then go completely insane
for an hour or two?
Yes, quite common.
This should be most interesting.
Now what?
A fuse must have blown.
I'll light the candles.
A fuse burned out,
miss Virginia.
Oh, thank you.
My father wants
to see you, Evans.
He's in his room.
Yes, miss.
That will have to do, gentlemen,
until the lights are fixed.
I'll be in my room, Evans.
Yes, miss.
I'm sorry, Mr. Kessler,
but we ran out of fuses.
I sent Marie over to the
store to get some more, sir.
That's alright, Evans.
Sit down.
Oh, pardon me, sir.
Go ahead, Evans.
Sit down.
We want to talk to you.
Alright, sit down.
Do you want to speak to me, sir?
This gentleman would like
to ask you a few questions,
Evans.
Yes, sir?
You know these men?
Yes, sir.
What's this gentleman's name?
Mr. Kessler.
Mr. Charles Kessler, sir.
Would you say that Mr.
Kessler is out of his mind?
Uh, I don't understand you.
Would you say that he is insane?
No, sir.
Well, young lady, what
are you doing here?
You can't take it.
It's mine, I tell you.
Ok, sister, it's yours.
Leave me alone.
I'm going home.
Home to my husband
and my daughter.
Of course you are.
And we know where you live, too.
You do?
Sure.
But I'm dead, understand?
I'm dead.
Of course you are.
I'll take you where
you want to go.
Now you just come
with me, young lady.
Tell me, Evans.
Do you think this man is crazy?
Now don't ask him that, doc.
I'm beginning to
have doubts myself.
Please, lieutenant.
Oh, alright, alright.
Am I crazy?
I don't think so.
You don't think so?
I know that woman.
She's wicked.
She can't go home.
Yes, yes, I know.
She's bad.
Now you come with me.
There we are.
Ever see this before?
Yes, sir.
What were you doing
with it last night?
I don't know what you're
talking about, sir.
Look what we found.
Mrs. Kessler!
I'm dead, Charles.
You hear me?
I'm dead.
I'm afraid to come home.
You'd kill me.
You'd kill anybody.
It's Kessler!
Take her out, quickly!
Aah!
Mr. Kessler!
Dad!
Get back in there!
Close that door!
Now you sit right there
and we'll see that
you get home alright.
Give me a hand, George.
She's dead.
What happened here?
We've got the murderer.
Evans.
No, Mr. Kessler, you.
I knew you'd come back.
Nothing can part
us now, my darling.