[ SUSPENSEFUL DRUM MUSIC ]
[ PLANE ENGINE ]
Hello. McCarthy calling.
McCarthy calling. Hello?
Any luck, Mac?
No, I can't even scare
of the news broadcast.
Where do you think we are?
Search me, we lost
a few hours ago.
Probably somewhere between
Cuba and Puerto Rico.
- Is it that bad?
- It ain't good.
Oh oh. I know that wasn't
cut out to be no blackbird.
You had those weather guides
that you all set up,
we wouldn't have gotten
into this mess.
If that new navy base gets a weather
bureau now, it'll be a miracle.
But Mr. Bill,
is this the spot where admiral Wainwright's
plane turned up missing last week?
Yeah.
Oh oh, look out, Admiral,
here we go.
Try to contact him again, Mac.
Hello, McCarthy calling.
Plane C-108 calling.
Why don't somebody answer?
We're lost, do you hear? Lost.
Not a murmur.
- How is the gas oil?
- That's something else again.
Well, there are plenty
of small islands down here,
better get down,
find a spot for landing.
- That's what I...
[ VOICES ON THE RADIO ]
Wait a minute,
there's something coming in.
[ VOICES ON THE RADIO ]
It's a new lingo to me,
I don't understand it.
Think we're near a radio station?
From the way it's coming in we must
be right over the transmitter.
That's a break.
I'm going down and take a look.
Hold on, boys.
There's a clearing ahead,
I think I can make it.
Think?
Ain't you say "think"?
[ PLANE ENGINE ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
"Rest in peace".
If that means what I think it means,
they sure don't waste
no time around here.
Wait a minute... Wait a minute,
they can't do this yet to me.
Let me out here. Let me out
of here. Let me out of here.
- Now, let me out of here!
- Hey, what's the matter with you?
Is that you, Mr. Bill?
Did they have you in a hole too?
What are you talking about?
What do you mean
"have me in a hole"?
- Are we dead?
- Of course we're not dead.
I thought I was a little
off colour to be a ghost.
Oh, there's no such
thing as ghosts, Jeff.
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
What was that then?
That's no ghost, come on.
I can't, my foot
don't took the route.
What are you trying to do,
scare us to death?
Hey, you're hurt.
I'm all right, just
a crack on the noggin.
Where are we?
Search me, it looks like
somebody's marble orchard.
Graveyard.
It's a fine spot for a crack up.
Yeah, let's look around, somebody
must live around here. Come on.
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
Quiet, what are you trying to do?
Wake up the dead?
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
What's matter?
Do you hear something?
No, sir, just my heart
trying to jump out of my chest.
- That's drums.
- Drums?
That's my cue for me to
start parading out of here.
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
Look.
It's a creepy looking place.
Sure dark. Suppose
anybody lives in there?
In that haunted house?
If they do, they sleep on slabs.
Let's find out.
Not me. You're going in and I ain't
going in that mausoleum.
I'm gonna stay right here
until I change my mind.
Wait a minute,
I have changed my mind.
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
Ring the bell, Jeff.
Mr. Bill, you're the one who wants
to go in there, you ring the bell.
[ DOORBELL RINGING ]
Sound like an ice cream man.
There's nobody here.
Who is that?
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
Welcome to my humble home.
- Thank you. We were just...
- I know,
your plane crashed in the jungle.
Oh, yes, how did you know?
Very little happens on this island
that I do not know about it.
Momba, we have guests,
take them to the library.
Have these gentlemen's
bags brought in.
Oh, excuse me, gentlemen,
may I introduce myself?
I'm Dr. Micklos Sangre,
laid of Vienna.
Follow me.
Mr. Bill, let's get out of here.
Oh, don't be silly, Jeff, go on.
Oh, that man ain't no doctor,
there's something wrong here.
Well, that's slim gallery.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
You must forgive us, please,
if we seem unprepared,
visitors are rare in this house.
I'm afraid we're the ones to apologize,
doctor, for walking in on you like this.
Not at all, it's a pleasure,
I can assure you.
I'm Bill Summers,
this is Mr. McCarthy...
- Glad to know you, doc?
- My valet, Jefferson.
Uh, Jefferson Jackson
is my name.
You see, I was named
after my grandpappy.
He was the president of the...
knights of the Pink Goddess...
- Oh, you have been hurt.
- It's nothing, just a crack on the head.
Nothing, you say?
The slightest injury on
this island often proves fatal.
- What do you mean?
- The climate and yet...
Yet what?
They say that evil spirits lurk
here, waiting to pray... on the inroad.
- Ha, that's a lot of bunk.
- Maybe.
How about a spot of brandy
to warm you up?
Fine.
Momba, [ FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
My servant intrigues you?
Is that one of the spirits
that you were talking about?
Momba no. It's true he reflects
the mood of this house,
but he's not as
sinister as he looks.
Gentlemen, the finest
brandy in all Europe.
I brought it here myself.
To your arrival.
The most fortunate
accident for me.
I'm afraid our arrival
was no accident.
You mean to say
you came here purposely?
No, not in the sense you mean.
We were on our way to the Bahamas
when the storm blew us off our course.
We heard your broadcast,
so here we are.
- Broadcast?
- [ BILL NODS ]
You must be mistaken, there was
no broadcast from this island.
Your ears must have
played you tricks.
There is no radio
within miles of here.
However, boats do
stop here fairly often.
How often?
Well, the next one is due
in about two weeks time.
However, I hope you will be
my guest in the meantime.
Very goodhearted, doctor, thank you.
Well, that's settled then,
let me show you to your rooms.
Didn't we just leave him
downstairs in the library?
Oh, he wanted to make sure
that your room
was warm and comfortable
before you got here.
He sure got around here
fast, don't he?
Mr. Summers, this is your room.
Mr. McCarthy's, your
quarters are joined.
Excuse me, Mr. Doctor, but
didn't you forget something?
I think not.
- No?
- No.
- What about me?
- You will be taken care of.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
- In the servant's quarters.
- Momba will show you the way.
- Momba? That goblin?
Do I have to go
with him alone?
He won't hurt you
if he likes you.
And if he don't?
Oh, Mr. Bill, does I have to?
Can I stay up here with you?
No.
You understand, I don't
wish to be harsh,
but it might set a bad example
for the other servants.
Certainly.
It'll be all right, Jeff.
- For who?
- Momba.
[ SPEAKS FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
[ CHUCKLING ]
You ain't, by any chance, a member of the
mystic night of the Pink Goddess, did you?
No? Harlem never was like this.
Dinner at eight o'clock.
Make yourselves at home.
And I'll get something
for your head, Mr. McCarthy.
Thank you, Doctor.
- What do you think?
- I don't know what to think.
Are you sure we were
flying over this island
when we picked up
that broadcast?
I could swear it
on a stack of Bibles.
Ain't you notice the lingo
he was talking at that banshee?
- You mean it was the same?
- Nothing else but.
It was the same bladder
we heard on the radio,
and I wouldn't be surprised
if it was the same voice.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Oh, pardon me,
I should have knocked.
Here you are, Mr. McCarthy.
your head will be
as good as new in no time.
Phew! If it was in me,
I sure would be pale now.
Samantha.
Well, I do declare!
How do you do, bright eyes?
- Where did you come from?
- Alabama.
Alabama, ain't that nice.
After Momba battling around
with a hatchet face,
you is a pleasant surprise.
Is you my little associate?
Well, if I ain't that's what
I'm thinking of. [ CHUCKLES ]
Hey, who is that, Methuselah?
Tahama.
I know a museum that would give a
fortune just to have her on the glass.
- What's a museum?
- That's where they keep dead things.
- Oh, like here.
- Huh?
- What's cooking?
- That's brew.
Brew?
Palm brew at this day and age?
Why don't you, people, know that
prohibition has been repealed?
Taste.
Okay if I do.
- [ SPITS ]
- How's it taste?
I don't know but it ain't cautioned.
- What's it for?
- It's a magic potion.
For scan away the evil spirits.
Evil spirits? Good gracious!
Well, are there evil spirits
around here?
Why, sure, the place
is crawling with.
- And that ain't all.
- Well, is there more?
More? You ain't heard nothing,
just wait till you see the zombies.
- Zombies? What's them?
- Dead folks.
- That walk around.
- They don't! Yeah?
- Especially here.
- Why here especially?
Because this is where
they close to bed.
They is all over this place.
And all you have to do is clap your
hands, and they comes a-running.
[ THREATENING MUSIC ]
Who is they? Who is they?
- Zombies.
- Ugh!
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
What kept you so long?
Ugh!
Mr. Bill. Mr. Bill?
Mr. Bill!
- What's the matter, Jeff?
- I've seen them.
- You saw what?
- They're all over the place,
- they're everywhere.
- What's everywhere?
Hands, big black one,
with frozen faces.
With eyes that looks at you
and they don't see nothing.
What's he talking about?
Oh, zombies!
Mr. Bill, let's get out of here,
this place is a walking cemetery.
Wait a minute, Jeff,
what's this all about?
- What's a zombie?
- Well, a zombie there's...
- Mr. Bill, is...
- SANGRE: A living dead.
- A living dead?
- That's it, that's what it is.
Dead folks was too lazy
to lay down.
Your servant seems to have learned
a lot in the short time he has been here.
Nothing I'm willing to unlearn
just as quick.
- I'm afraid Jeff's been saying things.
- It ain't the truth.
Where did you see
these... zombies?
Mr. Bill, I saw him
down into the kitchen.
They walked in there just like
they owned the place.
Undoubtedly some of my servants.
No sir, not them babies.
They were as fugitives
from their undertakers.
If it is true what he says,
it might be amusing to see
these creatures for ourselves.
- In the kitchen you said?
- Yes sir, that's where I've seen them.
Shall we investigate?
It sounds a little crazy.
Sorry of me, I guess.
- How about you, mate?
- Yeah, sure. I don't mind.
Superstition plays a very important part
in the life of these west Indian natives.
Uh... of course.
This is our kitchen.
Crude and rather antiquated,
but adequate for
our simple needs.
- Samantha.
- Yes, Master?
Have you seen
any zombies here?
No, Master.
Have you, Tahama?
Tahama cooks for the living,
not the dead.
You see?
You better get yourself
a pair of glasses, Jeff.
Oh, Mr. Bill, I don't need no glasses.
I saw them with my own eyes.
Samantha, you were
standing right beside me
when them two
perishables walked in.
The only perishable thing
around here is you, big boy.
You've been dreaming.
Dreaming? I never drift a dream like
that in my wildest nightmares.
Mr. Bill, they was the real McCoy.
He tasted my brew,
made him drunk.
[ CHUCKLING ]
Mr. Bill, don't pay no
attention to her,
I wasn't drunk,
you got to believe me.
You better take it easy, Jeff,
and lay off that brew.
Now that we have convinced
ourselves that were no zombies here,
let's retire to the library.
- That's for me.
- No, you stay here.
Look out for more zombies.
Woman, you is a prevaricator.
Don't you prevaricate me?
You didn't see no zombies,
you just think you did.
Think? I don't think that good,
I've seen them and you did too.
You told me that all
I had to do was to clap...
Stop him!
Don't do that.
I thought so.
Mister, there's something that ain't
never no good for nobody to do no time.
Much less going around blabbing
off your big mouth about.
You mean that Mr. Sangre
don't like for nobody to know that
he got zombies around here?
That's right.
- How come? What do he do, grow them?
- No, but he sure cultivates them.
- What for?
- That's his own business.
And if you're smart, you'll keep
your big nose out of it.
Is you telling me...
Alyce, you're down
early, my dear.
Permit me: my wife,
Madame Sangre.
Mr. Summers, Mr. McCarthy,
our guests.
- How do you do, Madam Sangre?
- How are you?
My wife isn't quite... herself.
She suffers from a strange
malady which I'm trying to cure.
Here is a peculiar case in
contrast to that of the zombies
which your servant
claims to have seen.
Well, supposedly they are dead
yet to attain a certain
amount of animation.
She lives, yet walks,
in the land of those beyond.
Forgive us if we've intruded,
I didn't know you
preferred drinking alone.
I was a little nervous, I thought
it might make me feel better.
Of course.
Permit me. Mr. Summers,
Mr. McCarthy.
Miss Barbara Winslow, my niece.
By marriage.
The doctor...
I mean my uncle, has told me
of your unfortunate accident.
How long do you suppose it will
take you to repair a plane at leave?
Barbara, how can you talk
of leaving to our guests
when they have only just arrived?
I'm sorry, I didn't mean it that way.
You see, my niece
doesn't like this little island.
She can only think of it
in terms of departure.
Any place that don't set well with me,
Miss, I have some leaves.
Unfortunately that's easier
said than done.
None may leave this island
as if he so chooses.
How's that?
Of course I'm only speaking
about myself and my family.
You see, being Austrian refugees,
had to flee here without passports.
Uh... we had no choice.
- But we're different, huh?
- Naturally.
You wouldn't be on this island if it
hadn't been through your crash.
- Isn't it so, Mr. Summers?
- Well, that's about this island
You know, I'm beginning to think
these islands are bad luck for planes.
Oh, I don't understand.
About a week ago, one of our navy
planes disappeared, the same region.
- Oh. Anyone of importance?
- Yeah, Admiral Wainwright.
- One of our ranking admirals.
- He was on his way to Panama.
Mission of some sort
for the government.
How unfortunate.
Well, of course... I will inform the
natives, first thing in the morning,
and if they can learn of your admiral,
I will... certainly let you know.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Excuse me.
I see you take an interest
in my collection.
Yeah, they are kind of curious.
They constitute my hobby, gathered
from all over the world.
Relics, symbols... of black magic,
lycanthropy, voodoo...
- If I so.
- You are Irish, are you not?
- Sure, anybody can see that.
Well, that should be
of special interest to you.
- Why me?
- Because it comes from your country.
The ceremonial masque won by
the ancient druid hight priests
during the rites of transmigration.
MAC: Transmigration?
Yes, it means the transfer of the... soul
of the dead to the body of the living.
Ain't that kind of tap on eleven?********
[ GIGGLES ] Perhaps so.
But I know of many who
would benefit by a new soul.
Lots of people don't believe
in that junk anymore, Doc.
Well, I hear that in an island
a good many do.
I don't know about that.
Dinner is served!
Very interesting, Mr. McCarthy,
isn't it?
Very.
The inconvenience of the material body
always demanding to be fed.
Come, my dear.
The idea of me doing
skull duggar in the kitchen
Well, that ain't no business for a man
who is used to resulting with big shots.
Who are you trying to fool?
Well, the only big shot around here
is your pal, Doctor Sangre.
And I sure know you ain't
no pal of his.
I don't intend to be.
That doctor Sangre is a little
shot compared with Mr. Bill.
- Who say?
- I said, and you know why?
- Did you hear me inquire?
- It's a secret.
But I'll tell you if you promise
not to tell a living soul.
Oh, I won't. Leastwise
not no living soul.
Leastwise?
Why, woman is you keeping
company with a zombie?
Does I look like a widow?
What's the secret about Mr. Bill?
Well, he's on a little special
business for the governor.
- [ AMAZED ] Yeah...
- [ JEFF NODS ]
Yeah, they're gonna send him
all the way to the Bahamas.
[ MOMBA SPEAKS
A FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
- Hey, what's up? What's up?!
- It's almost 12 o'clock. Witching hour.
Witching hour,
what do that mean?
It means you'd better be in bed
or Hex will get you.
Hex! Hex!
The feeding type
and he likes dog meat.
Dog meat?
You don't have to play no second chord
for me to find out who that mean.
- Where's that bear?
- You stay here.
Oh, mister, I got
a date with a dream.
You stay here.
Couldn't we flip a coin or something
to see if I stay or else?
Pay no attention to
anything you see or hear.
[ CHUCKLING ]
Pleasant dreams.
Nighty-night, sugar pie!
Remember.
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
I cannot forget to remember.
Don't worry, mister, I couldn't get
out of here if I wanted to.
Boy, I'm petrified!
Where there's light there's hope.
Boy, I need all the hope
that I can dig up tonight.
Sure wish I'd learned to burn
the candle on both ends.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
There's no legend.
If I just could get a couple of
napoleonic streetlights,
I could really sleep.
Witching hour, nothing in my hands
and I'm caught in the kitchen.
[ CLOCK STRIKES TWELVE ]
My goodness! Fire eaters!
[ SINISTER MUSIC ]
Don't come close to me.
I ain't no fellowman.
[ COMICAL MUSIC ]
- Goodnight, gentlemen.
- Goodnight, Doctor.
Mr. Bill, they after me.
They after me.
Now what?
The zombies, they've
been trying to get me.
Again?
Is your servant
always like that, Mr. Summers?
This ain't no laughing
matter, Dr. Sangre.
You fooled me once before
but you can't do it this time
because I've seem them
with my own eyes.
He seems to be troubled
with hallucinations.
No sir, zombies that's
what I'm trouble with.
You know what, Mr. Bill?
They tried to have me for dinner.
[ CHUCKLING ] Nonsense.
Zombies don't eat meat.
That ain't the way I heard it.
Oh, the crack must have
given him a concussion.
You'll be all right in the morning, Jeff,
as soon as you've had a good night's rest.
You're right about me needing rest,
but I can't get a sleeping
down there in that Mo.
Then stay up here with us.
Mr. Bill, these are the joyfullest
words that I ever heard.
We have so much room in this house,
there's no need for him to sleep here.
- I'll give him an opiate.
- You ain't giving me nothing.
But this is so irregular.
Let him stay here, doc, I know how
he feels and I don't blame my bet.
Oh, forgive me. I forgot,
after all he is your servant.
Good night, gentlemen.
Good night, Doc.
Good gracious on me!
- This joint gives me the willies.
- I second the motion.
I'm not crazy about it either, but
there's nothing we can do about it.
That's what you think.
Nobody leaves this island, huh?
I'm getting off if I have to swim.
And me right behind you.
You know that Dr. Sangre
has got the Hex on us.
Now you're both jumping
at your own shadows.
Shadows?
I don't throw them kind of shadows
of that sort down in that kitchen.
Mr. Bill, this place
is zombified, but good.
Ah, forget it, Jeff.
There may be something to that
zombie gag, Bill. I've heard of them.
Oh, go on. When a
man's dead he's dead.
But supposing he's dead
and he don't know it?
Forget it, want you, Jeff?
Go on to bed.
- Where am I going to sleep?
- Sleep down on the couch.
Yes, I will.
[ WHIRRING SOUND ]
Hey... what's that?
That's a generator as sure as
the shamrocks in Ireland.
Maybe is for electric lights.
Have you seen electric
lights around here?
Maybe they've screwed them in here.
There's only one reason for a
generator to be on this island.
- Radio!
- I don't get it.
Why would he lie
about the radio when...
That's one of the things
that got me mixed up.
But let me tell you this:
if we live through the night and
that radio on the plane is okay,
I'm gonna camp on it tomorrow
like a scare of a gun boat.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
[ SHOUTING ]
Mr. Bill, Mr. Mac!
- What's the matter?
- What happened?
Everything happened.
First it was zombies and then
it was Hex and now is a lady ghost.
She come right through that wall.
Now look, Jeff, the first couple
of times it was funny,
but now you're going too far.
Alive, Mr. Bill, she walked
right through that wall.
Oh, your imagination,
go on back to bed.
Imagination!
Why, Mr. Bill, my imagination
ain't that strong?
Imagination couldn't drop this,
could it? Look at it.
What is it?
It's an earring.
- Where did you say she went?
- She walked right through that wall.
Just like she flew in the air.
Right here, Mr. Bill.
I'll show it to you too.
She walked right through this wall,
and don't ask me how she done it.
All right, solid as a rock.
Any idea who she was?
I didn't ask the lady her name,
I was doing pretty good just looking.
What do you say,
you still think he's crazy?
Well, I'll tell you
better in the morning.
The next time you see anything
like that, hang on to it.
If I do it's got to
catch up with me first.
[ DOORKNOB RATTLING ]
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Nothing.
Looks like even the doorknobs
are haunted around this joint.
Well, I'm gonna find out
what this is all about right now.
With all this hands around here,
does we have to go looking for him?
- You can stay here, Jeff.
- No, sir. Wherever thou goes, I'll go.
- I hope it ain't too far.
- Keep your eyes open.
Let's have a look downstairs.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
- As quiet as a tomb.
- A tomb?
Shh!
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
- Mac.
- Yeah?
- We better split up.
- You don't mean three ways?
Mr. Bill, I think
two is better.
Look, Jeff, where did you say
you saw those things?
Oh, Mr. Bill, you ain't going
down in that zombie nest.
- Where is it?
- Back in the kitchen.
- That's for me.
- All right, I'll look around up here.
Okay, come on, Jeff.
- Who, me? No, sir...
- Shh!
Oh, Mr. Mac, I ain't got
no business down there.
I'll down, you gotta
show me the way.
Does I have to?
Can I draw you a map or something?
No, go ahead, Jeff,
you're wasting your time.
Oh, my goodness, right out of
the skillet into the frying pan.
I couldn't win the night
if I had cooked it back.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
Oh, it's you.
Do you always sneak up
on people like that?
Not always. Tonight
it seems to be the custom.
I thought I'd return
your call, you mind?
- My call?
- It's rather late for research, isn't it?
There were some things
I had to know.
So I noticed.
When you want to know a thing,
you really after it, don't you?
Would you mind, please,
telling me what you're driving at?
Not at all.
This prowling act of yours,
what's the idea?
Oh it's my aunt,
I'm so worried about her.
She is hypnotized, doesn't she?
I don't know,
I think so, I...
You don't think I did it, do you?
Well, I'm in no position to
accuse anybody of anything.
Look, Mr. Summers, I've got
to get my aunt off this island.
She's been this way ever
since she came here.
I'm afraid if we don't do
something soon
something dreadful is going
to happen to all of us.
Well, I've got to trust somebody
around here, that's a cinch.
But in order to help you
you've got to help us.
I'll do anything...
anything I can.
We think Dr. Sangre has a radio
transmitter concealed on this island.
I thought that for a long while.
I don't know where he keeps it,
but there must be one because he's
always getting messages from somewhere.
- You think you could find it?
- I'll try.
Swell.
We'd better get back to our rooms,
is there anything else?
- Not now.
- I'll see you in the morning.
Where'd those zombies come from?
They didn't, they sprouted,
just like mushrooms.
With a description like that
they ought to be very easy to find.
That's just what I'm afraid of.
- Well, let's have a look around.
- Not me, I'm gonna stay right here.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ CHUCKLING ] The tropics
sure gives a man a colour.
Don't do that, Mr. Mac,
you know my heart can't stand.
You know one thing, Mr. Mac,
you see... [ SCREAMS ]
[ SHOUTING ] Mr. Mac!
[ TENSE MUSIC ]
Mr. Bill, the zombies got Mr. Mac.
Are you all right, Mac?
Yeah. Looks like I pulled
another Brannigan.
It's not so bad, it's just a bump.
Yeah, two cracks on the bean
on one night, how am I doing?
I heard someone cry out.
It was me and I wasn't dreaming.
Oh yes, we thought we heard
something, doctor,
- we came down here to investigate.
- So?
I got tangled up with one
of your height men
and got the worst of the argument.
Too bad, I should
have warned you.
Some of my servants
act as gods at night.
You sure it wasn't a zombie?
Ridiculous!
He knows it wasn't a zombie,
doctor, it's our fault.
We should have taken your advice
and stay where we belong.
You're a sensible man, Mr. Summers.
Let's go back to bed, fellas.
I'm sorry, this won't happen again.
You know, the stump don't
look half bad in the daylight.
Yeah, it almost makes last night
seems like it didn't happen.
Don't kid yourself.
That earring happened.
You know, I'm beginning to believe
this thing was dropped on purpose.
- BARBARA: Good morning.
- Good morning.
Howdy.
- I think you dropped this last night.
- That? Oh, no that belonged to my aunt.
I'm so glad I was able to find you alone,
there's something I've got to tell you.
- What is it?
- It's about last night, it's...
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Good morning.
Having an interesting
conversation, my dear?
Miss Winslow was just
telling us about your island.
- That's right.
- How thoughtful of her.
Did you sleep well last night?
Well, as well as we could
with the storm and all.
Good.
I took the liberty of having some
breakfast sent to your room.
I hope you didn't mind.
BILL: Not at all,
it was unexpected treat.
You seem to admire
my wife's earrings.
Oh, I was just...
SANGRE: My wedding
present to her.
- Very unique.
- Quite so.
I dare say there's not another
pair like them in the world.
Really?
They were among
the few possessions
which we were allowed to
take out of the old country.
You don't say!
Well, while you are
here, I want you to...
feel perfectly at ease
and do as you like.
What are your plans for today?
I'm going down and
take a look at the plane.
We're anxious to see what damage
was done by the crash last night.
I see.
Would you care
to join us, Miss Winslow?
- [ ENTHUSIASTIC ] Oh, I would love to...
- No, no, that would be quite impossible.
My niece assists me
as my secretary.
We have a lot of work
to do, my dear.
- Some other time perhaps.
- Certainly. Should we go, Mac?
- I'm all for it.
- Enjoy yourselves.
- But don't forget luncheon at noon.
- Thanks, Doctor.
Bill, let's have a look
at that earring.
They're the same all right.
The only pair like them in
the world, huh? I don't get it.
Neither do I.
Barbara didn't drop it,
Madame Sangre couldn't
have apparently, who did?
This is the most cock-eyed
record I ever bumped, you know?
Well, I'm for getting out of it
as quick as possible.
Let's get that radio started.
Bill, look there.
- What about it?
- Ain't that a fresh grave?
So what?
You're in a cemetery where it's
customary to bury people in fresh graves.
Yeah, but that's been dug
since the storm last night.
Listen, are you getting those
zombies on your mind too?
- You and Jeff make a great pair.
- You still don't get it.
Take a look at that headstone.
That guy was buried
over a week ago,
and somebody must
have dug him up.
Come on.
Boy, will I be glad to get
away from this joint?
It could have been worse.
- Hey Mac, come here.
- What's the matter?
- How do you like that?
- Somebody's dismantled it.
Dismantle it? I'll say they have.
What next on this devil's island?
Mac, we're in a spot.
I don't know why, but
somebody's trying to hold us here.
Trying to hold us, is it?
That Dr. Sangre and his
druids and his zombies...
He better not try to pull
any of his black magic on me.
Calm down, Mac, raving
isn't going to get us anywhere.
I'm going to find that doc.
Are you crazy?
Do anything now to make him
suspicious no telling what he might do.
Take it easy until we find out
what he's up to.
Well, maybe you're right.
But there's one thing I can do
and I'm gonna do it right now.
I said take it easy.
All I'm gonna do is trying to find that
generator we heard humming last night.
Hey, that's an idea.
The old man's got a radio
hidden away someplace.
We could sure use it.
Let's go.
You'd better let me handle this.
Like you said, we don't want
to make anybody suspicious.
And with two of us snooping
around it might look so hot.
Okay, I'll go back to the house and
try to get Barbara away from Doc
long enough to find out what
she was trying to tell us.
- Think you can handle it alone?
- A cinch. It's right up my alley.
My old man used to be a cop.
[ BILL CHUCKLES ]
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
[ CHANTING IN
AN UNKNOWN LANGUAGE ]
- Tahama.
- Yes, Master.
- How much longer?
- Soon, Master, soon.
Voodoo magic works
slow, but it is sure.
The Admiral has fainted.
Your magic is no good,
it puts him to sleep.
I am Mama Lye,
High voodoo priestess.
I send him in trance
so he talk.
Too slow.
He has valuable information
that you must have at once.
The three men upstairs may be
in the Secret Service.
You must make him talk, Tahama.
[ DRUMS AND CHANTS ]
[ WHIRRING SOUND ]
[ SPEAKS GERMAN ]
- Have another piece of pie, honey?
- Already had two.
You already had six, but
does you want another one?
Well, if you insist...
Boy, he's the most pious man
I ever did see.
It ain't the truth.
I bet you none down in Harlem
never baked you no pie like that.
- Oh, I don't know.
- Oh, you ain't so smart.
I have an admirable one,
and it wasn't no common
old valet like you neither.
- Is that so.
- He was an exporter.
- Exporter?
- That's right.
No that's fine.
- What did he have?
- Bags, on the Pullman train.
- What become of him?
- He was killed by a revolving queen.
- A revolving queen!
- [ SHE NODS ]
You all sure have some fierce
birds around this country.
- Do you miss him much?
- Not much.
I sees him every now and then.
- You does?
- Huh? He's Lazarus,
- that zombie you met last night.
- Oh no, is that boy? Huh?
BILL: Jeff.
Oh, it's you, Mr. Bill.
You sure give me a turn.
Have you seen Mac? He's been
missing since early this morning.
No, sir, I ain't seen him. You don't
think nothing happened to him.
I don't know what to think.
Don't mind me, Mr. Bill,
I'm on your side.
You think we'd better go look for him?
All right. Before we go, run upstairs
and get my gun in the bag, will you?
Would you go shoot somebody?
Don't ask any questions.
Meet me in the library.
Yes, sir.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Oh excuse me, mister Doctor,
I'm in you own room.
No I hate either,
this is Mr. Bill's room.
What you doing going
through his bag?
- Jeff, I was looking for you.
- Looking for me? In there?
I've got something to show you.
- You got something to show me?
- That's right.
I know, Mr. Doctor, but
I got business elsewhere.
Nonsense.
This is far more important.
Not to me, Mr. Doctor,
what is the matter?
- Shh!
- Oh doctor.
Watch.
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
That's where that lady went.
- What lady?
- The ghost lady.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
The ghost lady?
Yes, she went
right through there.
- Come.
- Now, wait a minute, doc.
Wait a minute, Mr. Sangre.
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
Mr. Bill ain't going like this,
where's you taking me?
Far.
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
- Where's we going?
- Shh.
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
Jeff, gotta move on,
we got...
You again. What are you doing
in here? Where's Jeff?
I wouldn't know, sir.
It's gone. You know about this,
you devil. Give me that gun.
- I had no gun, sir.
- Don't lie to me.
Somebody has.
Where's Jeff? Where is he?
And Mac, what's happen to him?
- I wouldn't know, sir.
- You're gonna tell me or...
I said I wouldn't know, sir.
You wouldn't talk
if you did know.
I'm gonna find him if I have
to search every inch of this island.
- Yes sir.
[ DOOR SLAMMING ]
Look at this watch.
See it move. Watch it.
You have seen nothing.
You know nothing.
Repeat after me: "I have seen
nothing, I know nothing."
[ WITH IMPERSONAL VOICE ] I have
seen nothing, I knows nothing.
- I don't even know my name.
- I am dead.
- I'm... I have?
- Repeat! I am dead.
- I am dead.
I am dead. I have returned
to the land of the living.
I am a zombie.
- I am a zombie.
I am a zombie,
I am a zombie.
- Get over there where you belong.
- Yes sir.
Move over, boys,
I'm one of the gang now.
[ SHOUTING ] Mac? Jeff?
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
Mac?
Mac, where are you?
Jeff?
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
[ DRUM MUSIC STOPS ]
ALYCE: [ MOANING ] No.
No.
No!
[ WORRYING MUSIC ]
No.
Aunt Alyce, think.
Think hard.
Remember, try to remember.
You've got to get over this.
You must speak to me.
You must.
No.
[ WORRYING MUSIC -
DOOR CLOSES ]
So you're mixed up
in this mess too.
- Oh no, I was only trying...
- I know what you were trying to do.
I thought Dr. Sangre was responsible
for that, now, I see it's you.
I'm only trying to undo what
already has been done.
Hypnotizing her still further?
But it's the only way,
you must believe me.
I wouldn't believe you or
anybody else in this mad house.
I suppose next you and your
vultures will be after me.
Next?
Don't pretend that you don't know
what happened to Jeff and Mac.
No, I...
Look.
[ WORRYING MUSIC STRIKE ]
- Mac! Get some brandy.
Mac, tell me what's the matter? What
happened? Where have you been?
It doesn't do any good.
- I hope you're satisfied.
- No, I didn't.
I saw your friend enter from the jungle.
Is anything that matters.
- What do you think?
- Let's have a look.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
I was afraid of that.
He has contracted a very rare
and dangerous jungle fever.
Is that so?
It paralyses the motor
region of his brain.
He must have medical
attention at once.
But you're a doctor, see
what you can do about it.
I'm sorry, that's beyond my thoughts.
I thought so. You're
going to let him die.
Not at all.
There's a native doctor in the village
who knows more about this than I do.
You'll send for him at once.
Find Momba and
send for Dr. Couillie.
You'd better put him into bed.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Mr. Summers, this is Dr. Couillie.
- Charmed Mr. Summers, I'm sure.
- How do you do, doc?
Dr. Couillie was educated
in your country, America.
Precisely. This is
the patient, I presume?
Yes, make it snappy,
will you, doctor?
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
- I'm sorry, that nothing I can do.
- Nothing? Are you sure?
Positive. This man has
been dead since morning.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
I'm profoundly sorry about the
death of your friend, Mr. Summers.
What has to be has
to be, I suppose.
- Did you have to bury him so soon?
- It was out of my hands.
The local law insists.
The climate and something
even worse makes it necessary.
You mean this voodoo
zombie business, huh?
This voodoo magic is far more
real than you think, Mr. Summers.
You heard what
Dr. Couillie had to say.
Oh, but that's impossible,
dead since morning.
Things like that have happened
before on this island.
There are even whisperings
going on among the natives.
- That he was bewitched.
- Bewitched?! But why? What for?
Maybe for playing into things
that did not concern him.
[ MOMBA SPEAKS GERMAN ]
Excuse me.
- What is it?
- The radio!
Word has just come through they must
have the admiral's information at once.
- We've got to make him talk.
- We might perform the ceremony.
The rites of transmigration.
Get everything ready. Inform Tahama,
and get Madame Sangre to the dungeon.
- Madame Sangre?
- You heard me. Hurry!
- Tahama, [ SPEAKS GERMAN ].
- I'll be right along.
I'll have to go, you've got
to feed the zombies.
Me? I can't stand zombies
and you knows it.
Do as you're told! And you'd
better set another plate.
We're going to have
company for dinner.
Company? You mean
there's a new one?
That's right.
The Irishman from upstairs.
[ TAHAMA CHUCKLES ]
Well, I do declare.
The old woman said we have
a white zombie for dinner.
[ CLAPPING ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
- Company, halt! One, two.
- Jeff.
Can we some dinner?
- What you doing in that line-up?
- Don't bother me, woman.
- Can't you see I was a has been?
- A zombie?
Nothing else but,
and don't ask me my name
cause I don't know.
I don't know nothing.
You ain't no zombie,
zombies can't talk.
Can I hip it's 'cause
I'm loquacious?
How'd you get this way?
I ain't telling nothing.
All I know is that I joined the club,
and as a member I has privileges.
- What privileges?
- Privileges to get fed.
There ain't no new
development with you.
- Woman, where's my food?
- There it is, help yourself.
Company, come and get it.
Where's the white one?
What white one?
The one who flew
the plane you come in.
He's also one of the new recruits.
The only one I know about
is the boys in my squad.
- Is this the best food you got?
- The best.
For zombies that ain't
the 6-bit deluxe special.
Just being a zombie
sure is a drawback.
Where is the salt?
You eat that the way
it is and likes it.
Zombies ain't supposed to use salt.
- I thought you said...
- I changed my mind.
That's more like it.
Take it easy there, woman,
I ain't no herring.
Now, eat.
Wooh! What is you trying
to do, poison me?
How's your feeling?
- How should I feel?
- You ain't feeling dead, is you?
'Cause if you is,
then you is a zombie.
- And if I ain't?
- Then you ain't no zombie.
The rule says: if a zombie uses salt,
he dries up and gets dead again.
How do I look?
Take a look for yourself.
[ CHUCKLING ] Well, according
to this, I ain't dead.
That's all I want to know.
Then you ain't no zombie?
How you know?
'Cause when a zombie looks in the
mirror, you don't see nothing.
That's me, all right.
Well, I ain't no zombie after all.
If I ain't no zombie and they is,
what am I doing here?
Hey, where you going!
Jeff, where have you been? What
are you doing coming out of there?
One at a time, Mr. Bill.
I've just been reincarnated.
- [ SHOCKED ] You what?
- I just got dezombified.
That's the facts, Mr. Bill,
but that's all I remember.
Jeff, you've got to remember.
These zombies, did you
see any of them?
I just got to eat
dinner with them.
Were any of them white?
Why do you ask me that?
Samantha asked me the same
thing down in the kitchen.
No, I'm just thinking of Mac. They were
in such a hurry to bury him.
Bury him? Is Mr. Mac dead?
My goodness!
Maybe he's the one that...
The one? Go on, what one?
I was digging in a graveyard.
[ CHUCKLING ] Can you imagine
me digging in the graveyard?
What about the graveyard?
No, that couldn't have been me.
- Oh, but Jeff, you've got...
[ WOMAN'S SCREAM ]
- What was that?
- Sound like a woman's scream.
What one?
I don't know, but it sounded
like Barbara, I got the flash light.
Off again.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
Down here.
I'm coming, but my heart
ain't in it.
This way.
[ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC ]
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
Madame Sangre!
That's what she got
for trying to warn us.
- Whoever did it can't be far away.
- You mean can't be too far away.
Jeff, look!
Eyes, if you look, I am
responsible for nothing you sees.
Mr. Bill, ain't that a coffin?
It's Mac's.
You don't think he doesn't join up
with the zombies, do you?
I don't know, but if that Sangre thinks
he can use Mac's body to...
- What's the matter?
- Listen.
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
What does that sound like to you?
I don't know, but
it ain't Gene Krupa.
It's the same drums
we heard the other night.
Voodoo drums.
We gotta find them.
Oh, Mr. Bill, ain't we found
enough in one day?
After this is no telling what
he's up to. Mac might be...
- Come on.
- I'm coming.
[ DRUM MUSIC ]
- Mr. Bill, does we have to do this?
- Quiet, Jeff.
I ain't said a word.
[ SHOUTING -
DRUM MUSIC STOPS ]
[ SHOUTING ]
In there.
[ SHOUTING - DRUMS STOP ]
[ CHANTING IN
AN UNKNOWN LANGUAGE ]
That won't budge.
Jeff, you were down here? Don't
you remember how you got in?
- I can't remember.
- Think hard, we got to get in there.
Let me think...
[ CHANTING ]
Who are you?
Speak!
Tell me, who are you?
I am... I am...
Admiral... Admiral...
[ CHANTING ]
Admiral Wainwright,
what were your orders?
Go... to go.
- MOMBA: Stop! Stop!
- Momba, you fool!
- She was just going to talk.
- Unbelievers.
Outsiders come in.
Get them!
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
Mac, go back. It's Bill, Bill
Summers, your pal. Go back.
Mac, go back.
[ OMINOUS MUSIC ]
[ SHOUTING ]
Stop! Stop! Stop them!
[ GUNSHOTS ]
[ TENSE MUSIC ]
[ WOMAN SCREAMS ]
Did you contact the coast
guard all right, Admiral?
There'll be a boat here
for us in the morning.
- But how's your friend?
- Those bullets didn't help him any.
He'll need a little patching up when
that coast guard cutter gets here.
But he says he's raring
to go again.
Say, by the way, how did that insane
doctor manage to get you on this island?
Well he brought our plane down
with a false radio beam.
Killed the crew and tortured
me to get information
about our canal zone
fortifications with his government.
He didn't succeed at first,
and then he decided to try
this... voodoo business.
Oh, you mean those rites of
transmigration he talked about.
Yes, that's right.
He tried to transfer
the Admiral's information to my brain.
He was completely mad on
the subject of hypnotism.
Half the island was
under his spell.
First, he tried to use
Madame Sangre as a subject,
when she broke under the
strain, he used Barbara.
I hate to think what
might have happened
if you hadn't turned those
zombies against him.
You and me both.
If there's one thing
that I wouldn't want to be twice,
zombies is both of them.
[ RESOLVING MUSIC ]
[ CLOSING MUSIC ]