(dramatic music)
(thunder rumbling)
(Manuel speaking in foreign language)
- Has everyone gone?
- Yes.
We are the only ones left.
Has Juanita returned from the house?
- No.
She said she would not come back
until she saw Francisco
and brought him back to us.
- That cursed house.
(Juanita speaks in foreign language)
Ever since those two came here
there's been nothing but death and sorrow.
- Our Francisco, how is he?
- I don't know, mama.
They would not let me see him.
- But why?
- They say he has the sickness.
- Ah! (speaks in foreign language)
- Why, why must we lose our
sons and brothers to them?
- Perhaps it is God's will.
- God's will.
God's will.
Was it God's will that
Augustin Roja's child die
and that other boy, Jose Alvarez?
No, I say no.
It's because of them!
- You speak in anger, Juanita.
The children became ill.
El Patron and his sister,
both great doctors,
could not save them.
- They became ill only
after they went to work
in that awful place.
And why were they buried at night?
So we could not see them
to give them a Christian burial.
Why, why?
- You know why.
They told us the children die
of some strange contagious disease
and have to be buried at once.
- What should we do now?
- We cannot go without Francisco.
We must wait and pray.
I don't know what else to do.
(thunder booming)
- Another wonderful storm.
I congratulate you, dear brother.
You were correct in
choosing this wild land.
- It was not I.
It was Professor von Metzler who said
in such this part of America
you'll find these
electrical storms you need
for your experiments.
- Modest Rudolph.
You never do take any
credit for what you do.
- I want no credit
for these terrible things
we are doing here, Maria.
All I want is to go back to Vienna.
- Vienna.
We will not see an electrical
storm there in months.
But here the very gods conspire
to get them to us all the time.
Well, we go to work.
(thunder booming)
In a moment we shall know
if we have succeeded.
(electricity crackling)
(soft mysterious music)
Quick, prepare the injection of digitalis.
Hurry up with the digitalis.
You took long enough.
One would think you did
not want him to live.
He's dead.
(thunder booming)
What a fool I've been.
I've allowed the dual sonic impulsator
to be attached only to the body.
Let's see what
grandfather's notation says.
You see, the dual sonic
impulsator must also be attached
to a living brain
to transmit living vibrations
to the artificial brain.
- But such a powerful electric impulse
might prove fatal to the
brain of a living person.
- That chance I am willing to take.
It's because we've been forced
to use the brains of children
that we've failed.
What we need is a man,
a powerful man, a giant.
Then we shall succeed.
- But what good will it do to succeed?
- Imagine.
We'll have someone to do our bidding,
who can't be put to death.
Just as we have given it life,
only we can take its life away.
- Maria, we've already caused
the death of three children
and violated the graves of others
just to make the experiment.
My, you are a humanitarian.
You should have stayed in Europe
and given pink pills to sweet old ladies.
This is the last artificial brain
Grandfather Frankenstein made.
The secret of how to
make this died with him.
If I fail in this last attempt,
I too am willing to die.
- Is it so terrible to fail?
- You're a fool, Rudolph!
We hold the secret of life in our hands.
- Maria, Maria,
this has already caused
grandfather his life,
and father--
- Father was a weakling.
He dared not try the experiments,
only on paper.
- You know, Rudolph,
sometimes I think you remind me of father.
- What do you want to do next?
There's no one else left to experiment on.
This boy was the last,
and his sister Juanita was here
demanding to see him.
- What did you tell her?
- The same as the others,
that the boy has a
highly contagious disease
and cannot be seen.
- Good.
These peasants are
ignorant and superstitious.
We have nothing to fear from them.
- When the Lopez family finds out
that Francisco is dead, they
will leave like the others.
He'll be alone,
all alone in this wilderness,
and I can't stand.
- Everything is just right here.
The isolation, the electrical storms
for the energy we need.
I know you want to leave.
Well, you can't.
Where would you go, Vienna?
The police are looking for us there.
They did not understand
our work any better
than these peasants.
Rudolph, we are safer here
than anywhere else.
(intense music)
Now, now that I know what is wrong,
somehow I will find the right man
to withstand the shock of my experiment.
He must be big and strong,
strong as a giant.
(upbeat playful music)
- This is the time, Stacy.
Stacy, get up.
(crowd shouting)
- Come on, Stacy.
- Get up, Stacy.
- Hank, you better win this.
We're stone broke.
- What makes you think I'm losing, Jesse?
- Well, that's that.
- Nobody's beaten Stacy
since I bought this saloon.
And that's over 10 years ago.
- There's always a first time.
I'll take that bet money now.
- Not so fast, not so fast.
I could have the sheriff lock you two up
for disturbing the peace,
but I'll make you a deal.
Leave town and I won't press charges.
- You better pay up, mister.
- Why should I?
- Well, for one thing,
I beat your man fair and square, I did.
For another thing, we
need the money real bad.
And for another thing,
the man you're holding
out on is Jesse James.
- (chuckles) I heard that
Jesse James was killed
up at Northridge.
- There are a lot of folks that think
that the James boys were wiped out.
Well I'm Jesse, all right.
And there's only one way to prove it.
I'll take that bet money.
No hard feelings.
You see, we weren't all
killed at Northridge.
We've sure been on the
run ever since though.
That makes a man hungry.
Why Hank and I haven't had anything to eat
since when was the last time we ate, Hank?
- It's been one whole day,
but it seems more like a month.
- Hank woulda taken your man a lot easier
if he'd had his full strength.
Now, ain't that right, Hank?
- Yep, how about that steak now?
- Now that's an idea.
And we'll pay for it with your money.
(soft mysterious music)
- And I say you had no right
to call in Jesse James and his boys.
This was our deal.
My deal if you come right down to it.
This was that big killings
you've always been telling me about.
You know, the one you've never
been able to come up with?
And now you tell me we gotta
split it with Jesse James.
- If you weren't my brother,
I'd really work you over.
You think we can pull this deal ourselves,
the two of us and Pete out there?
- Well at least you coulda
talked it over with me first.
- I'm the leader of the Wild Bunch.
I ain't talking nothing over with nobody,
and if you don't like it, get out.
- Just the same, my share's gonna be 1/3.
And you can cut up the rest
between you and Jesse James
any way you want to.
- Your share is going to be
exactly what I say it is,
no more, no less.
(mysterious music)
(Pete imitating bird call)
That's Pete's signal.
You must be Jesse James.
- Mm-hmm.
- [Butch] Is that Hank Tracy?
- And you'd be Butch Curry,
head man of the Wild Bunch.
- That's right.
Come on in, Jesse.
This is Jesse James.
This is my brother, Lonny.
- Lonny, Pete Ketchum our lookout.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- Hank Tracy, Lonny, Pete.
- Well, this is the bunch.
We got hit at St. Joe,
Liberty and Little Blue.
We lost 11 men in all.
- I can't hardly believe
the famous Wild Bunch
is down to three men.
- I don't think the James
boys are doing much better.
Frank James hiding out in
Kentucky as a preacher.
I hear the real Jesse
James was shot to death.
- Everybody is trying to make me a corpse.
Well, I don't like it.
You trying to make me a liar?
- (laughs) No harm, no harm at all.
It's just that there's a lot
of four-flushers around here
that's claiming to be Jesse James.
(guns fire)
- Now, we didn't come
here for any trouble.
We came here to do a
little job with you boys.
I'm sorry, Lonny,
but you just backed
yourself into a corner.
- Take it easy, Jesse.
He'll be all right when he sobers up.
Now, to tell you the truth, Jesse,
I figured you'd have more men.
I didn't know that you were
down to Hank and yourself.
But I still think we
got enough to pull this.
And I think you'll agree
that it's worth it,
when I tell you what it is.
Have a seat.
On the way here, you passed
through the Paseo del Norte,
do you know it?
- Yeah, narrow cut about
30 miles out of Bisbee.
- We're gonna take
delivery of $100,000 there.
- $100,000?
- I thought you'd like the idea.
- That's an awful lot of money, you sure?
- Lonny is sparking a girl
that works at the bank,
and when the bank gets fat
to the tune of $100,000,
they transfer it to Fort Buchanan.
And later on they set back
east for the Army supply train.
Right, Lonny?
- That's right.
My word has always been good
enough for the Wild Bunch,
Mr. James.
- No harm, no harm.
That's an awful lot of
money at one at one time.
- Jesse may have looked
down many a gun barrel
for a lot less than that, eh Jesse?
- Right, Hank.
Seems to me anybody
shipping that much money
through a narrow pass would
figure that's a natural place
for a hold-up?
- That's the way the bank figures it too,
and that's why they send a stagecoach
on through the pass with
passengers and no money as a decoy.
- Decoy?
- That's right, when the
first stagecoach gets through,
they signal a second stagecoach,
that's always clear.
That's the one we'll be waiting for
with the money and no passengers.
Simple and sweet, ain't it?
What's the matter, don't you like it?
- Eh, it's too simple.
What's the hitch?
- No hitch, the second
coach has only a driver
and a shotgun.
And we'll hit 'em so fast,
they won't know what happened.
I'd still like it better
if we had more men,
but I think we got enough to do it.
Are you game?
Wanna try it?
- You know me, Jesse.
Whatever you say.
- What's the split?
- Well, there's five of us.
We'll split it--
- Butch.
- We'll split it five ways.
- Well, I didn't ride
300 miles for my health.
It's a deal.
- Marshall, I tell you, I
know that's Jesse James.
I made sure of that.
So you get Jesse, and I
get the $10,000 reward,
dead or alive.
- How do I know you're not sending us
right into a trap?
- Well, I'm riding right
there with him, ain't I?
If I was lying to you, it'd be easy enough
for you to pick me off.
Besides, I'm going straight.
- Oh, I can't afford not
to go along with you,
but let me tell you one thing.
If you wanna collect that reward,
you better make sure you
stay out of the line of fire.
Marshal, I tell you, I'm going straight.
Now, all you gotta do is tell your men,
and I'm on your side.
Well, I guess I better be
getting back to the boys.
They might start to miss me.
We wouldn't want that to happen,
would we marshal? (laughs)
Well, we got a deal.
(soft mysterious music)
- Now, you men know what to do.
But I don't want anybody
getting trigger happy,
because one of 'em
happens to be Jesse James.
Now, let's spread out and get up high.
You two men take this side.
Andy, we'll take this side and the horses.
Let's go.
- All right, let's go.
All right Jesse, this is it.
Now remember, after the
first coach gets through,
they fire two shots.
That's the signal for the
second coach to come on.
You got it?
You and Hank take that side.
We'll take this side.
- What's the matter, Lonny?
You seem nervous.
Something bothering you?
- And just what are you driving at?
- All right, you two,
knock it off, knock it off.
We're all a little edgy.
Come on.
Lonny!
Get ready boys, first coach is coming.
- That's the first one.
(gun fires)
That's the signal.
- Here she comes now, Jesse.
- Get ready, here she comes.
(intense music)
(guns fire)
- How about it, Jesse?
You haven't got a chance.
- Let's get out of here.
- Jesse, look out!
(gun fires)
(guns fire)
- Well, that's the end of the Wild Bunch.
- Ain't he one of them?
- Lonny, he tells me he's going straight.
- So I am, you saw me.
Didn't I try to help you get Jesse James?
- Yeah.
Now I guess you did it that.
I wanna thank you men.
Now, you better get back to
your jobs and your homes.
- What about you?
- My job is going after those two.
And I can't say I like
it very much either.
- I'm going with you marshal.
- You want that reward
pretty bad, don't you Lonny?
- Yeah, I want that 10,000,
but I wanna see Jesse James'
eyes looking right at me
when I shoot him.
- I never figured you'd
try to shoot Jesse James
from the front, Lonny.
All right, let's get these
two men in the stagecoach,
get 'em back in town.
- You guys give me a hand.
(ominous music)
- Just hold it here.
- I'll be all right, won't I, Jesse?
- Sure you will.
Let's rest here awhile and we'll move on.
(Manuel speaking in foreign language)
- We have nothing, nothing.
- I don't mean you no harm.
- Oh. (speaks in foreign language)
(Jesse speaks in foreign language)
(Manuel speaks in foreign language)
- He speaks a little bit.
- Well, my friend's sick.
I wonder if you'd mind if
we'd rest with you a spell.
(Manuel speaks in foreign language)
- Gracias.
(Nina speaks in foreign language)
(Juanita speaks in foreign language)
(Manuel speaks in foreign language)
(Nina speaks in foreign language)
- He's been shot!
- Well, he was cleaning his gun.
- Here, let me help you.
Dip this into the hot
water right over there.
The bullet must come out.
- I know it.
- There's a doctor in Prescott.
- Well, we can't go into Prescott.
We can't go into any town.
- I understand.
I knew what you were when
you first came into camp.
Your friend is dying.
- Dying?
- The wound is very bad, very bad.
I will take him to the doctor.
- Where?
- Do not worry.
He will be safe.
- Thanks, thanks very much.
- The man is dying.
I'm taking him back to the
doctors at the mission.
- No, my child.
You must not go back to them!
- But I have to.
I can't let him die.
- [Manuel] And if you go there,
something terrible will happen to you.
- I'm not afraid.
- I say you are not to go back.
I forbid it.
- But papa!
- I forbid it!
- We must wait awhile.
(mysterious music)
We can go now.
- Hank.
Can you walk?
- [Hank] Yeah.
- Hey you.
- Senor.
- Senor, do you speak English?
- A little.
- We've been following two men.
One's a big man, and he's been wounded.
Do you understand?
Comprehenda?
- Si, senor.
- Well, did you see them?
- [Manuel] No, senor.
- Marshal.
So you didn't see anybody, huh?
Marshal.
Take a look at these.
- Hmm, coulda been them.
I got a hunch they were here.
Well folks say Jesse
James steals from the rich
and gives to the poor.
Adios, senor.
- You're lying, you're lying to us.
They were here and you
helped 'em get away.
I oughta kill you.
- Let him alone.
- Juanita, she went away
with them in the night.
We must go after her.
- No, when Francisco died,
I swore that I would go
away and never come back.
And I will not, not even for Juanita.
- Then I will go back without you.
- You would be lost in five minutes.
You will do as I say!
As Juanita should have done!
(soft music)
- How do you feel, senor?
I'll cook you some broth,
if Jesse's luck can bring
us something to eat.
I'll bring you some water.
(Juanita screams)
- Where's Juanita?
I told her to stay here.
Juanita?
- [Juanita] Look out Jesse!
(gun fires)
(men grunting)
- Ah!
- Jesse.
(intense music)
Oh, you saved my life, Jesse.
(soft music)
Look there.
That is the place I told you about.
There's where the doctors are.
This is our home.
I wait here.
- You know how to use one of these though?
- Yes.
- Don't be frightened, Juanita.
- I'm not, now that you're here.
I'll be waiting for you.
- Who is it?
- We wanna see the doctor.
We wanna see the doctor.
My friend is badly hurt.
- Who sent you to us?
- A girl by the name of Juanita.
- Juanita, is she back here?
- Yes, come on, you're wasting time.
- Just a minute.
Maria, Maria.
- What is it, Rudolph?
- Two men, they are looking for a doctor.
Perhaps it's the police.
- Police here?
Hundreds of miles from nowhere?
You are a fool.
- The girl Juanita is back.
She brought them here.
- And you're afraid of an ignorant girl?
I shall take care of it.
Come in.
What happened?
- You're the doctor?
- Yes, my brother and I are both doctors.
What happened?
- Well, he shot himself cleaning his gun.
- We will be glad to help your friend.
Won't we, Rudolph?
- Maria, I believe that--
- Rudolph, the laboratory.
This way.
Take him in there, put him on the table.
- The man's story is
obviously a false one.
- So much the better.
They must be running from the law.
Why else would they seek us out?
Heaven sent them to us.
- Heaven?
- Please wait in the hall
while we examine the patient.
- All right, I'd like to take
care of the horses anyway.
- If you put them in the lower stable,
they will be well hidden there.
- I'll be right back.
(ominous music)
- Jesse, Jesse!
- Whom are you calling?
- Jesse James.
Don't let him leave me.
Rudolph, it's even better than I thought.
The one outside is Jesse James.
The whole countryside must
be looking for these two.
Perfect, Rudolph, perfect.
I have plans for them both.
- His wound is bad, festering.
- It is nothing.
He's strong as a giant.
What a brute he will make.
- Howdy, ma'am.
I'm Marshal MacPhee.
We've been trialing two men.
Did they stop here?
- Oh, two men?
- [Marshal] Yes, one of them was wounded.
- Oh, no, no.
They're not here.
- Well if you don't mind,
I'll come in and look around.
- I told you they weren't here.
- I'm sorry to bother you, ma'am.
- Your friend is very sick, Mr.---
- Howard.
- Ah yes, Mr. Howard.
He has a very high temperature,
but my brother is an excellent doctor.
- Mm-hmm.
- Won't you come to the library?
I want to talk to you.
Please sit down, Mr. Howard.
Did Juanita tell you some
terrible tales about us?
- Why do you say that?
- Well, what did she tell you?
- Nothing.
We ran into the Lopez family,
and Juanita offered to
bring us to a doctor.
- Nothing else?
- Should she have told us something else?
- No, I suppose not.
Perhaps you're wondering why we live
in this old abandoned mission.
The answer is quite simple.
My brother and I came here from Europe.
We are scientists.
Perhaps ahead of our time.
Our experiments were not always understood
or appreciated in our own country.
So we had to leave.
Finally, we came here.
When I realized that out here
my brother and I could stop
from running, I took
possession of this old mission
and fixed it up for our work.
- Well, I must say it's different.
I mean, making a home out of a monastery,
sort of lonesome I should think.
- It has its compensations.
Won't you join me?
Help yourself.
- Well, thanks.
It's been a long time
since we stopped to eat.
(knocking)
(ominous music)
Yes, gentleman.
- Howdy, ma'am.
I'm Marshal MacPhee.
We're trailing two outlaws.
- Outlaws?
- Oh, don't be frightened.
They're not the type to hurt women.
Besides, one of 'em is badly hurt.
- And who are these outlaws?
- One's Jesse James,
the other is Hank Tracy.
- Well my brother and I have neither seen
or heard anyone today.
But if we do, we shall send word to you.
- Thank you.
- Where will you be?
- I have a feeling they're holding up
in this area someplace.
So I think we'll spend
a few days in Shelby.
- Very well.
- Thank you.
- Just the marshal
looking for some outlaws.
- Oh, did he say who they were?
- No, Mr. Howard.
While my brother is taking
care of your friend,
I hope you will decide
to stay here with us.
- Well, thanks.
Well, I'd like that.
- Now if you'll excuse me.
I will see if I can help my brother.
How is he?
- Lost a lot of blood.
- He looks all right to me.
I intend to use him in my next experiment.
- Maria, please stop
this terrible experiment.
We'll have another
death on our conscience.
- Don't be an imbecile.
If I turned him over to the marshal,
he'd be hanged anyway.
So what has he got to lose?
Now go get that girl Juanita to help you.
Remember, he must stay alive.
- I think it's a mistake to
bring her into this house.
- Let it be my mistake then.
But get her here where I
can keep an eye on her.
Wonderful.
(dramatic music)
- Well, good morning.
- [Hank] Morning.
- How do you feel this morning?
- Pretty good.
You've been awful good to me, Juanita.
Hardly anybody's been that good,
except maybe Jesse.
I can't thank you enough.
- I don't do this because I want thanks.
- Juanita, when I get well
and Jesse and I leave,
will you go with us?
- No, I must stay here.
Someday when the Frankensteins leave,
my people will come back.
- You must be wrong about them, Juanita.
Look how good they're treating me.
- Perhaps, but out there in the graveyard,
I see my brother's grave.
No.
My place is here.
- Then I'll stay here with you.
- Oh no, you mustn't.
I won't let you.
As soon as you get well,
you must go.
- But Juanita.
- No, no.
- [Hank] Juanita.
(soft guitar music)
- You know what?
Today, Hank asked me to
come with you when you go.
Don't you want me to go with you?
- It isn't that, Juanita.
It's just.
- Well, I'm waiting.
- When I first met you, I
told you I'm Jesse James.
I'm an outlaw.
- You are the outlaw, that I know.
But you haven't told me,
do you want me to go with you.
- There's your answer.
- That is all I wanted to know.
No, I can't not leave this place.
I must not.
But I had to know
that you wanted me.
- If that isn't just like a woman!
- Please, do not be angry with me.
You see, I must stay just as you must go.
- Why must I go?
- Because I do not
trust the Frankensteins.
They're wicked.
They're terrible people.
They will destroy you.
They destroyed our village
and some of our boys.
And they will destroy you and Hank.
Promise on my brother's grave,
please go.
Someday when things are
different for you and me,
you come back.
I'll wait.
- It's kinda hot inside.
I thought I'd come out for a smoke.
- Yes, it's nice out here.
- It's kinda nice country.
Why's everybody except Juanita gone away?
- We are scientists.
We make experiments.
These people are ignorant.
They do not understand
and they're frightened.
So they run away.
- Seems like some of 'em
didn't quite make it.
- Ah yes, Francisco, a sweet child.
He became ill, but my brother
and I could not save him.
He was weak, not like your friend Hank.
Hank is improving.
- Thanks to you and your brother.
And Juanita.
- He's doing even better
than I'd hoped for.
- How soon do you think
we'll be able to leave?
- I want to speak to you about that.
I want you to stay.
- I'm sorry.
I made a promise
that we'd leave as soon as
Hank was well enough to travel.
- A promise to whom?
- To myself, you might say.
- It's lonesome out here
and very difficult for us.
We do not know how to cope
with this wild country.
Stay here.
We need you.
I need you.
I'm on the verge of a great experiment,
and I know I will succeed this time.
I will build an empire here.
I want you to share in everything.
My experiments, my life.
- How can I help you?
- Rudolph is weak.
I need you.
I need your strength.
- We'll leave as soon is Hank
is well enough to travel.
- I'm sorry I made a fool of myself.
Goodnight, Mr. Howard.
You're to find Mr. Howard
and give him this envelope.
- What is it?
- You are to tell him it's
a prescription for Hank,
that he's taken a turn for the worst.
And that we need this
prescription to be filled.
- But Hank is doing well,
and Juanita knows it and
she sees Jesse all the time,
especially at night.
- So you've been snooping around as usual.
Well then you know.
To think that this outlaw
with a price on his head
refuse me for that girl.
And yes, I've seen them together too.
- So what are you gonna do, Maria?
Nothing foolish I hope?
What is in this envelope?
- I tell you what, it's a note to Jensen,
the druggist in Shelby,
telling him that the bearer
is Jesse James the outlaw
with a price on his head.
- No, you mustn't.
You mustn't.
- Mustn't it?
Why not?
I would have turned him in before only--
- Only you wanted him for yourself.
Why, you're jealous.
You're human after all. (laughs)
- How dare you!
- So I have to ride into Shelby
to get some medicine for Hank.
He's taken a turn for the worst.
- What do you mean?
When I saw him this evening, he was fine.
Oh, they're sending you
away to get rid of you.
- Now, why would they
try to get rid of me?
Besides, if you're wrong,
it costs Hank his life.
- Jesse, don't trust
them, especially Maria.
Please don't go.
- I'll be back.
- Jesse!
(thunder booming)
- What you're going to do is insane.
- We shall soon see which
one of us is insane.
- Besides, we should
postpone this transplantation
until he recovers from his gun wound.
- He's recovered enough.
- Maria, this is not the
same as experimenting
on one of the village children.
Jesse James will kill us
for what you're doing.
- Jesse James will be
caught and hanged in Shelby.
Now get on with the operation.
(ominous music)
- Jesse.
- While you finish preparing,
I shall activate the artificial brain.
The brain is ready.
- Patient is ready.
- Good.
(thunder booming)
(dog whining)
That dog!
He always senses when we operate.
I told you to muzzle him.
- I forgot.
I'm very upset, Maria.
I haven't your nerves.
- Go silence him.
- Yes.
(dog barking)
- Now at the next stroke of lightning
we shall have the answer.
- Don't do it, Maria.
You are going too far.
No one should temper with the laws of God.
(electricity crackling)
- You are no longer Hank Tracy.
You are Igor.
Do you understand?
Igor.
That is how you will be known.
I am Maria Frankenstein.
As I think, you will think.
We are one.
I will command, you will obey.
You will live as long as I wish.
You will die when I command it.
Remember, you are always under my control.
You are now Igor.
I command you to arise.
Igor.
I am Maria Frankenstein.
I created you.
I command you to get up.
Get up, Igor!
Get the digitalis.
We must save him.
Let me have it.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- Why not?
- No, we're wasting time.
(thunder booms)
- So that's it!
No!
Igor, save me.
He's alive!
Get him Igor!
Get him!
- Save me.
My answer is there.
Save me.
- You killed the others with this
to keep me from succeeding
with my experiments.
- You have been pumping God through hell.
- You did well, Igor.
Come, I want Juanita.
- Juanita.
- Yes, Juanita.
Juanita.
- Come, Igor.
- Juanita.
- She's gone, probably with him.
Well, good riddance to them both.
But I still have you, Igor.
Come.
(bell ringing)
- What do you want?
- I need some medicine.
I'm sorry to bother you
so early in the morning,
but I gotta have this
medicine and get right back.
Something the matter?
- No, no.
It's just that I haven't
got the medicine handy.
If you'll sit down and wait.
- Will it take long?
- I don't know, just sit there.
I'll be right back with the medicine.
- (laughs) All right, let's go.
- Well, shouldn't we wait
till Sheriff Buchanan
and the marshal get back?
- No, I don't think so.
They're not gonna be back for hours.
You see, Jensen,
someone give 'em a tip
that they knew where Jesse
James was hiding out.
This guy you saw,
what'd he look like?
- Medium tall, young, dark.
Looked like he'd be riding a long way.
I'll tell you something else.
He looked mighty tough.
- Jensen, you see this?
This is made to take care of tough guys.
- I don't wanna get
mixed up in any gun play,
especially not in my store.
I'm a married man.
- You're gonna do exactly what I say
and keep your mouth shut.
- I still say, I won't
mix up in any gun play.
Jesse James of all people.
- Now Jensen, you listen to me.
There's $10,000 reward for Jesse James.
I'm gonna collect it,
and you're gonna help me.
- What do you want me to do?
- Nothing, absolutely nothing.
But I do want you go back over there
and make him up some kind
of medicine, anything.
Just act like nothing happened.
And don't be so nervous.
He's liable to catch on.
- What about you?
- Don't you worry about me.
I'll be there.
And Jensen, I want you to listen to me
and remember this.
If anything goes wrong,
I'm gonna hold you personally responsible.
(soft mysterious music)
- How long's it gonna take?
- Not very long.
I gotta measure this, you know?
(guns fire)
- I told you, Jensen. I'd get there.
- Please, Jesse, don't shoot me.
- How did you know my name?
Hold it!
Juanita.
- I came to warn you.
You must not go back.
- What do you mean?
Is Hank all right?
- No, what they did to Hank,
you can't believe it.
It's terrible.
If you go back, they'll
do the same thing to you.
- What are you talking about?
- Hank is not Hank anymore.
- I have to go back.
- If you do, I go to the
marshal at Shelby for help.
I know what it would mean
if I bring him back with me,
but I'd rather see you dead
than see you looking like Hank.
- Still, I have to go back to Hank.
- I'm sorry, Jesse.
I must do it.
I love you too much not to.
And that's the truth, marshal.
Please, please believe me.
- Too bad you didn't tell me about this
when I came to your house.
- I know, I know, I was wrong.
God forgive me.
- All right, let's go.
- Thank you, marshal.
- That's enough, Igor.
Quick, Igor, into the house.
Get in there, be quiet.
If I need you I will call you.
Who is it?
What do you want?
- It's Jesse James.
Open up.
- I'm glad you're back.
- No thanks to you.
- Yes, yes I know what you're thinking,
but it was Rudolph.
He forced me to write that note.
- I want to see Hank right now.
- Well, Hank is not here.
He and Rudolph left together.
- I don't believe you.
- I swear it.
- All right, if you won't
tell me where he is,
I'll find him.
- Why do you treat me like this
when you know how I feel about you?
- All right, I'll shake
the truth out of you.
- Igor!
- All right, then I'll
choke it out of you!
Once and for all, what did you do to Hank?
I wanna know it!
- Bring him in here.
Put him on the table.
Igor, go to your room.
Your room, Igor.
Save your strength, Jesse James.
You will need it.
Yes, I knew who you were
from the very first.
You see, we have something in common.
We're both outside the law.
That's why I offered
you a chance to join me.
But you chose to refuse me.
You, an outlaw, refusing me,
Maria Frankenstein,
granddaughter of a count.
I will use you in my next experiment.
You see, Jesse James,
I have won after all.
(soft music)
- Where's Hank?
What have you done with him?
- You will see Hank soon.
Sweet dreams, Jesse James.
Perhaps of Juanita.
Now, I've got work to do.
- Perhaps it's better
if she doesn't see me?
- Who is it?
- It's me, doctor, Marshal MacPhee.
- I have nothing to say.
Go away.
I'm in the midst of an
important experiment.
- You wait just a minute.
I wanna talk to you.
- About what?
- I've been told you're
harboring Jesse James
and Hank Tracy.
- Who told you such a lie?
- Juanita Lopez.
- (laughs) Juanita Lopez.
I'm surprised that you marshal
are listening to an ignorant peasant.
- Oh just the same, I
intend to search this place.
- Well, search all you care to.
I'll show you around myself.
- Well, that's just
exactly what I'm gonna do.
- Well, shall we start with my laboratory?
- Well Jesse, finally caught up with you.
- Igor, Igor.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
(gun fires)
Take him in there.
- Jesse!
Jesse, what have they done to you?
Jesse.
- Igor.
Come here, quick!
Get her, Igor.
Get Juanita.
Juanita.
- [Juanita] Hank.
- Juanita.
- Kill Juanita.
Kill her.
Kill Juanita.
- Jesse, Jesse.
- Juanita.
- No, please!
- Kill, kill.
- Hank!
(intense music)
- Hank, it's me, Jesse, Hank.
- Kill, kill.
- No Hank, it's me,
Jesse James, your friend.
Hank.
Hank, don't make me kill you.
- Ah!
Hank!
(gun fires)
Oh Jesse, I thought he would kill you.
- Juanita.
Juanita.
- Oh, Jesse.
(soft music)
Our village is free once more.
Thanks to you and Hank.
My people will come back here.
Jesse, I will be waiting for you here.
- No, Juanita.
Look, I am an outlaw with
a rope waiting for me.
- That's not what I want to hear.
(soft guitar music)
- I love you, Juanita.
(majestic orchestra music)
(Juanita speaks in foreign language)
- Go with God.