[orchestra playing “Rhapsody in Blue"]
[tempo accelerates: jaunty]
[man] ♪ Music hath charms ♪
♪ That nothing else has ♪
♪ Music hath charms ♪
♪ Though it’s classy or jazz ♪
♪ A symphony grand ♪
♪ By Schubert or Brahms ♪
♪ A popular band ♪
♪ Or a youth heath the palms ♪
♪ A melody in minor key ♪
♪ Can make the teardrops start ♪
♪ And then again, a glad refrain ♪
♪ Can cheer a lonely heart ♪
♪ Sweet harmony when ♪
♪ There's someone in your arms ♪
♪ Oh, baby, it's then that music ♪
♪ Hath charms ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
How do you do, ladies and gentlemen?
Permit me to introduce myself.
I am Charles Irwin.
And this book is Paul Whiteman's scrapbook.
Its pages are crowded
with melodies and anecdotes
which we are going to
bring to life for you
by the magic of the camera.
Here we have Paul himself.
And by the way,
you may be interested in knowing
how he came to be crowned
the King of Jazz.
Once upon a time Paul, tiring of life
in the great city, had a grand idea -
he would go big-game hunting.
No sooner said than done.
Suiting the action to the camera,
we find him a few weeks later
in darkest Africa.
[orchestra playing fanfare,
mid-tempo accompaniment]
[tuba blats]
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ My Lord delivered Daniel ♪
♪ My Lord
Delivered Daniel ♪
♪ My Lard delivered Daniel ♪
♪ Why can't he deliver me? ♪
Ouch!
Mammy!
[orchestra continues playing]
[chorus vocalizing]
[orchestra continues playing: oboe solo]
[orchestra continues playing]
[song ends]
And that’s how Paul Whiteman
was crowned the King of Jazz.
[whistling]
Why, here comes Paul himself.
- Hello, Charlie.
- Hello, Paul.
Where's the band?
Are you standing in front of them?
- Oh, the band?
- Yes.
I have them right in here.
What, 40 boys in that little bag?
- In the bag.
- [orchestra playing]
[orchestra continues playing]
[orchestra fades]
I'm really very proud of the boys.
Some of them have been in the band
for a great many years.
- Mike, how long have you been in the band?
- Eleven years, Mr. Whiteman.
Goldie, how long
have you been in the band?
Six years, Pop.
- [Whiteman] “Six years, Pop"?
- [hiccups] Pop.
Been in the band so long
he's commenced to look like me.
However, as I said before, I'm really
very proud of the boys collectively
and I'd like to have you
meet them individually.
[orchestra plays intro]
[trumpet solo]
[piano: bridge]
[piccolo solo]
[bridge: acoustic guitar]
[banjo strumming]
[entire orchestra playing]
[ends]
[Whiteman]
Now that you know the boys,
I want you to meet our girls.
[orchestra playing]
[woman] We call our next advertisement
“The Bridal Veil."
It tells the story of a little girl
who finds in an old treasure chest
the laced veil that had been worn
by her ancestors.
The ghost brides of all the ages
pass before her
and, in fancy, the boy who was to become
her future husband joins her
and they start on their honeymoon
to the land of dreams.
Of course they lived happy ever after.
♪ Kissed by faded orange blossoms ♪
♪ White as driven snow ♪
♪ Fashioned with such loving care ♪
♪ Long centuries ago ♪
♪ Worn in every generation ♪
♪ By some happy bride ♪
♪ Hiding modest blushes ♪
♪ From the lover at her side ♪
♪ Dear treasure of the past ♪
♪ I've come for you ♪
♪ At last! ♪
♪ What are the secrets you hold ♪
♪ Within each delicate fold? ♪
♪ What tender memories ♪
♪ You could reveal ♪
♪ What dreams you seem to unfold ♪
♪ Of days romantic ♪
♪ While phantom lovers of old ♪
♪ Around me steal ♪
♪ How many hearts you have thrilled ♪
♪ What hopes you've wakened and filled ♪
♪ If you were only ♪
♪ To tell the tale ♪
♪ And how I wish that I knew ♪
♪ What joy or sorrow ♪
♪ I'll soon be finding in you ♪
♪ My bridal ♪
♪ Veil ♪
[chorus]
♪ O happy bride ♪
♪ When we've strewn your path with violets ♪
♪ Refrains of happiness ♪
♪ May follow evermore ♪
[chorus continues singing]
♪ In a house ♪
♪ Full of happy ♪
♪ Brides ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ Do you remember ♪
♪ The path where we met ♪
♪ So long ago ♪
♪ Ah, yes, you told me ♪
♪ You'd ne'er would forget ♪
♪ Long, long ago ♪
[vocalizing]
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ Listen to the mellow chiming ♪
♪ Of the wedding bells ♪
♪ What a world of happiness ♪
♪ Their melody foretells ♪
♪ With the dawning of tomorrow ♪
♪ Comes our wedding day ♪
♪ To our land of dreams come true ♪
♪ We’ll soon be on our way ♪
♪ Their endless bliss will be ♪
♪ Awaiting you ♪
♪ And me ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ And how I wish that I knew ♪
♪ What joy or sorrow ♪
♪ I'll soon be finding in you ♪
♪ My bridal ♪
♪ Veil ♪
[vocalizing]
♪ Though you are a great, big grown-up ♪
♪ You are like a child to me ♪
♪ And somehow or other you ♪
♪ Make me want to mother you ♪
♪ Every now and then I own up ♪
♪ I want to take you on my knee ♪
♪ The hardest thing for me to do ♪
♪ Is to keep my hands off you ♪
♪ I lick-spit your tie
Smooth your hair ♪
♪ Put things in order
Here and there ♪
♪ 'Cause I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
♪ I like to pick the lint
Off your suit ♪
♪ ‘Cause I wanna keep you
Nice and cute ♪
♪ ‘Cause I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
♪ There doesn't seem to be ♪
♪ Need for me to mention ♪
♪ That I'm the party who ♪
♪ Can give you attention ♪
♪ I like to tuck your shirt
Adjust your hat ♪
♪ Poke all around you
Just like that ♪
♪ 'Cause llike ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ Hardest thing for me to do ♪
♪ Is to keep my hands off you ♪
♪ I get an awful kick simply by ♪
♪ Taking a cinder from your eye ♪
♪ 'Cause I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
♪ I like to mend your things
Darn your clothes ♪
♪ Clean your ears and blow your nose ♪
♪ 'Cause I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
♪ I must, by hook or crook ♪
♪ Make you luck real snappy ♪
♪ If there’s a chance to do
Things for you ♪
♪ I'm happy ♪
♪ Tear buttons off now and then ♪
♪ So I can sew them on again ♪
- Forevermore!
- ♪ 'Cause like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
[falsetto] ♪ I like to touch your hair
Hold your hand ♪
♪ Play with your fingers ♪
[chuckles]
♪ 'Cause you understand ♪
♪ I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
♪ I like to cuddle up close to you ♪
♪ Be Mama's baby, kitchy-coo ♪
[laughing cooing]
♪ ‘Cause I – I like to do things for you ♪
♪ If anything I do pleases you ♪
♪ Don’t thank me ♪
♪ But when I'm bad
Place me on your knee ♪
♪ And spank me ♪
♪ If you like to hold me on your lap ♪
♪ You just go to Mama
I’m no sap ♪
♪ I like ♪
♪ To do things for you ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ There doesn't seem to be
Need for me to mention ♪
♪ That you're the party who
Can give us attention ♪
♪ I tear your buttons off now and then ♪
♪ So I can sew them on again ♪
♪ 'Cause I like ♪
♪ To do things for ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ There doesn't seem to be ♪
♪ Need for me to mention ♪
♪ That I'm the party who ♪
♪ Can give you attention ♪
♪ I like to pull your shirt
Toss your hat ♪
♪ You're acting all pushy
Like a polecat ♪
♪ 'Cause we like to do things for you ♪
[Irwin] And next on the next page
of the Paul Whiteman scrapbook,
you will find the first
of a series of brief anecdotes.
Here's my assignment, boss.
Say, where have you been all day?
This story's half an hour old.
- What's the matter?
- Matter?
If we women are going to run this paper,
I want speed.
And as long as I'm city editor,
I've got to have news hot off the griddle!
Here you are!
Forty-story building burnt to the ground!
- When did it happen?
- Ten minutes ago.
That's better.
Big bank robbery.
Three policemen shot.
- When did it happen?
- Five minutes ago.
That's more like it.
- Woman shoots husband!
- When did it happen?
- Wait a minute. Listen.
- [gunshot]
That's great!
[men]
♪ Oh, what a dance do they do ♪
♪ Lordy, how I’m telling you ♪
- ♪ They don't need no band ♪
-[loud exhale]
- ♪ They make time by clappin' their hands ♪
♪ Just happy as a cow chewin' on a cud ♪
♪ When the darkies beat their feet
On the Mississippi mud ♪
Hey, Bing, this isn't the type of number
for this kind of a production.
-[Bing] What kind of production is this?
-[all] A super-super, special-special production!
[Bing] Well, I guess you're right.
We should get out of the mud and reach
for the higher and the finer things of life -
the silver lining and the bluebird
and life and love.
♪ I look at my doorstep
I look at my doorstep ♪
♪ I look at the bluebirds
I look at the blackbirds ♪
♪ I look at the good luck
Look at the bad luck ♪
And the bad luck there ♪
♪ I never saw bluebirds
Mingle with blackbirds ♪
Doin' things backwards ♪
♪ Never knew good luck
Ever could perch with care ♪
- ♪ Now, I overheard ♪
-[men vocalizing]
- ♪ Those birdies talking today ♪
♪ And I know just why
They're acting this way ♪
Maybe I'd better pick up
the thread of the story.
- Well, you needle it.
- Okay.
♪ First the bluebird said ♪
♪ “We've gotta have sunny weather” ♪
♪ So the bluebirds and the blackbirds ♪
♪ Got together ♪
♪ Then the blackbird said ♪
♪ “Oh, we're birds of a different feather” ♪
♪ So the bluebirds and the blackbirds ♪
♪ Got together ♪
[all vocalizing]
♪ How bout ♪
♪ Trouble, trouble ♪
♪ Round my door ♪
♪ Blackbirds, blackbirds ♪
- ♪ By the score ♪
- Pull it up, now!
- ♪ Bluebirds ♪
- Big!
♪ Bluebirds came one day ♪
♪ And said, “The blackbirds here ♪
♪ Are safe” ♪
Say, who the dickens are these revelers?
Oh, some quartet on the air.
It really doesn't matter.
[solo] ♪ Why, first the ♪
[all] ♪ Bluebird said
“We gotta have sunny weather ♪
♪ So the bluebirds and the blackbirds
Got together ♪
♪ Then the blackbird said
“We're birds of a different feather” ♪
♪ So the bluebirds and the bdlackbirds
Got together ♪
♪ And when they talked it over ♪
- ♪ They let the blackbirds bring the rain ♪
- Aw, tell it.
♪ And the bluebirds then agreed ♪
♪ To bring that sunshine again ♪
♪ For we can't have rain ♪
♪ Or sunshine that lasts ♪
♪ Forever ♪
-[makes scraping noise]
- ♪ Whip-a-boo-boo ♪
♪ You can take those bluebirds
Take those blackbirds ♪
♪ Mix 'em together
You get fair weather ♪
♪ And that's the reason the bluebirds
And the blackbirds got to... ♪
[all] ♪ Gather ♪
[exhales]
[bells chiming]
[guitar strumming, clarinet, slow tempo]
[piano joins in]
♪ In my imagination ♪
♪ I'm finding consolation ♪
♪ Somewhere along the Rio Grands ♪
♪ Sadly, I’m reminiscing ♪
♪ Madly, again I'm kissing ♪
♪ Someone along the Rio Grande ♪
♪ It happened in Monterey ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ I met her in Monterey ♪
♪ In old Mexico ♪
♪ Stars and steel guitars ♪
♪ And luscious tips as red as wine ♪
♪ Broke somebody’s heart ♪
♪ And I’m afraid that it was mine ♪
♪ It happened in Monterey ♪
♪ Without tkinking twice ♪
♪ I left her and threw away ♪
♪ The key to paradise ♪
♪ My indiscreet heart ♪
♪ Longs for the sweetheart ♪
♪ That I left ♪
♪ In old Monterey ♪
[guitars continue playing]
[man, woman]
♪ Stars and steel guitars ♪
♪ And luscious tips as red as wine ♪
♪ Broke somebody’s heart ♪
♪ And I’m afraid that it was mine ♪
♪ My indiscreet heart ♪
♪ Longs for the sweetheart ♪
[full orchestra continues playing]
[singing in Spanish]
[man]
♪ It happened in Monterey ♪
♪ A long time ago ♪
♪ I met her in Monterey ♪
♪ In old Mexico ♪
♪ Stars and steel guitars ♪
♪ And luscious tips as red as wine ♪
♪ Broke somebody’s heart ♪
♪ And I’m afraid that it was mine ♪
♪ It happened in Monterey ♪
♪ Without thinking twice ♪
♪ I left her and threw away ♪
♪ The key to paradise ♪
[woman]
♪ My indiscreet heart ♪
♪ Longs for the sweetheart ♪
♪ That I left ♪
♪ In old Monterey ♪
- Now I've caught you.
- But I -
So this is the way you act
when I'm not around.
- Well, I -
- No use in trying to explain.
- I saw you with my own eyes.
- Well, why won't you let me -
I'm through!
You'll never see me again
as long as you live, you brute.
Good-bye!
Well, wifey, there goes
the best stenographer I ever had.
The next page in the scrapbook
was inserted one day while Paul was away.
And the boys in the band prevailed upon
the property man to do his stuff.
Jack White, a fellow of infinite jest,
But just a little bit nutty.
[instruments warming up]
Come on there, Old Black Joe!
Yeah, Joe, come on.
You'll be terrific.
[orchestra plays intro]
♪ Old Black Joe ♪
[orchestra]
Yuk-yuk-yuk-yuk-yuk-yuk!
When I was a little boy,
my mother said to me -
[orchestra]
What did your mother say to you?
When I grown up to be a big man,
what do I wish to be?
[orchestra]
What do you wish to be?
- Seven of spades?
- Right!
I always wanted to be a cop
or a fireman or such,
♪ But since those days of wishin' ♪
- ♪ I've got a new ambition ♪
- What is your new ambition?
- Ace of clubs.
- Right!
♪ Oh, how I'd like to own a fish store ♪
♪ That's all T wish to! ♪
♪ A lovely fish store ♪
♪ Why, to all the Paddies ♪
♪ I'd sell them finnan haddies ♪
♪ To the Cohens and the Mishas ♪
♪ I would sell gefilte fishes ♪
♪ I’d put a flounder
In my window each day ♪
♪ I’d put it on a scale
And say I’m giving it away ♪
♪ Oh, how I'd like to own a fish store ♪
♪ I’m a fisherman
Aren't we all? ♪
I had a funny dream last night.
I dreamt I saw two fishes fight.
The champion was a tuna fish.
His opponent was a bass.
Before the title fight began
they introduced a few.
They introduced Kid Sharkey.
[imitating trombone playing]
Battling Whitefish.
[imitating trumpet playing]
And Piccolo Pete.
[grunts] Ahh!
- Ace of clubs?
- Right!
The house was packed with poor fish
who paid 20 fish to get in.
And now they're madly yelling
for the main fight to begin.
[yelling]
Everyone's excited.
In the gallery, some fresh trout -
Come on, you tuna fish!
Knock his teeth out now!
The champion leads his left fin.
He leads it to the jaw.
He lands!
The bass, he flounders.
- Catch on?
- Oh, we get it, we get it.
The signal’s off.
The bass went down. He can't get up.
The champ is in his glory.
And then I woke to find my dream
was only a bedtime story.
{orchestra] Whee!
{trombone slides note]
♪ Nice, fresh halibut fish ♪
[trombone slides note]
♪ Lady, come down ♪
♪ At my least, take a peep ♪
♪ Only last night ♪
♪ They were asleep in the deep ♪
- Want any fish, lady?
- [falsetto] No, sir!
- Your sister want any?
- No, sir!
- Well, you know that fish gives you brains.
- What you eat then? Soy beans?
Ha-ha, ha-ha!
- And then the war broke out!
- [snare drumroll]
- [“Stars and Stripes Forever"]
- [shouting]
- Meeting the men and boys!
[orchestra stops]
Leaving their homes and wives
and sweethearts.
Men, men, men, men!
[orchestra playing march]
- Going up and down again!
Going up and down again!
Men. Men going up and down.
Going up and down.
And where were you? Where were you?
And where were you?
[orchestra shouts]
- Never mind me!
- [snare drum imitating machine gun fire]
They got me, buddy.
- Did they really get you?
- Yes, they really got me.
Well, they should've got you sooner.
But tell me your name
so I can tell your poor old mother.
Why, you darned fool.
My mother knows my name!
♪ I would ♪
♪ Like to own a fish store ♪
♪ Where flying fishes play ♪
♪ Oh, how I'd like to own a fish store ♪
♪ On the road ♪
♪ To Mandalay ♪
- Four of spades?
- Right!
[orchestra playing intro]
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ Romeo and Juliet ♪
♪ I’m quite sure didn't have to pet ♪
♪ Upon a hardwood bench
In a park like this is ♪
♪ They had moonlight up above ♪
♪ And all the scenery of love ♪
♪ Things like that
So helpful to hugs and kisses ♪
♪ But you and I, my dear ♪
♪ Need no such atmosphere ♪
♪ A bench in the park ♪
♪ Unromantic and plain ♪
♪ That bench in the park ♪
♪ Can be our lovers' lane ♪
♪ The glimmering light of a lamp ♪
♪ For a moon ♪
♪ A cold, dreary night ♪
♪ But in our heads there is June ♪
♪ A lone little bird ♪
♪ In the branches above ♪
♪ Is plaintively heard ♪
♪ Serenading his love ♪
♪ And what more do we need? ♪
♪ You and I in the dark ♪
♪ On a bench ♪
♪ In the park ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
♪ A bench in the park ♪
♪ Unromantic and plain ♪
♪ That bench in the park ♪
♪ Can be our lovers' lane ♪
♪ The glimmering light of a lamp ♪
♪ For a moon ♪
♪ A cold, dreary night ♪
♪ But in our heads there is June ♪
- ♪ A lone little bird ♪
-[men vocalizing]
♪ In the branches above ♪
♪ Is plaintively heard ♪
♪ Serenading his love ♪
♪ And what more do we need? ♪
♪ You and I in the dark ♪
-[exhales, vocalizing continues]
-♪ A bench ♪
♪ In the park ♪
♪ Bum-bum bum-bum behoodoo ♪
[orchestra continues playing]
[orchestra playing: up-tempo]
[orchestra: tempo slows]
[orchestra: up-tempo]
[orchestra slows to mid-tempo]
[hiccups]
- ♪ A lone little bird ♪
-[bird chirping]
♪ In the branches above ♪
- [chirping continues]
- ♪ ls plaintively heard ♪
♪ Serenading his love ♪
[orchestra continues playing, mid-tempo]
♪ And what more do we need? ♪
♪ You and I in the dark ♪
♪ On a bench ♪
♪ In the park ♪
I beg your pardon, sir. Is this the place
where you report a stolen automobile?
The Universal picture
All Quiet on the Western Front
inspired us to produce
our own little war drama,
All Noisy on the Eastern Front.
In it we hope to prove for all time
that Sherman was right.
[knocking]
Come in!
Marie!
[French accent]
My big American baby!
- Cigarettes?
- Have you been true to me?
-[knocking]
- Hide! Quickly!
Come in!
- Marie!
- Mon capitaine!
You look so handsome!
Soap. [sniffs]
- Smells good.
- Have you been true to me?
-[knocking]
- Hide! Quickly!
Come in!
- Marie darlin'!
- Mon colonel!
Oh, girl, girl, girl, girl!
Mm-mmm!
You are my jazz baby, no?
- Look what I got for you.
- Chocolate! Yum-yum-yum.
Marie, have you been true to me?
-[knocking]
- Hide!
- Quickly!
-[knocking continues]
Come in!
General.
Marie, have you been true to me?
Need you ask me that, baby?
The enemy is shelling the town.
We must leave immediately.
Come! My car is waiting.
Have you got any room for me?
How about me?
How 'bout me?
How about us?
[plucking strings]
[piano playing, up-tempo]
[tempo slows]
[playing “Pop Goes the Weasel"]
[“Pop Goes the Weasel” continues]
[song ends]
[piano plays]
[pump playing “Stars and Stripes Forever”]
[whistles high note]
No record of American music
would be complete
without George Gershwin's
Rhapsody in Blue,
which was written for the Whiteman Orchestra
and first played in the Aeolian Hall in 1924.
The most primitive
and the most modern musical elements
are combined in this rhapsody,
for jazz was born in the African jungle
to the beating of the voodoo drum.
[slow drumming]
[drumming continues, faster]
[drumming ends]
[clarinet solo]
[“Rhapsody in Blue”]
[orchestra joins in]
[song ends]
- Oh, good evening, Mr. Kent.
- Hello, Wally.
- What are you gonna have?
- Oh, I don't know.
Most anything.
Thanks. What is that?
Just what you ordered - most anything.
Well, here's a go, here's a go.
You know what’s the matter
with this country?
It's a tariff.
That's who.
Partly tariff and partly income tax.
Now, you take my wife.
All right. Who you gonna take?
Here's a go, here's a go, here's a go.
Wait a minute. Don't kick that dog.
That's not a dog.
It's a cat.
Well, don't - Then don't kick the cat.
- Don't you like animals?
- No.
Do you like goldfish?
Goldfish? I hate 'em!
Whew. Nat so quiet. Not so quiet.
My boy, don't ever let anybody
hear you talk that way.
A goldfish is one of the most faithful
animals we have.
To mankind.
To the goldfish.
Would you mind if I told you a story
about two little goldfish that I once had?
No.
I bought 'em at a spawn shop.
Two little walli - walli - uh -
goldfish.
I call 'em Ella and Emma.
I brought them home
and put them in a glass bowl full of water.
And I used to sit and watch them grow,
grow into women, into men -
Big fish.
Then prohibition came,
and they jumped out of the bowl
onto the floor.
They used to follow me around
wherever I went.
How I used to love them.
I used to come home each night
and I'd stand at the bottom of the steps
and I'd cry out,
“Hello, Ella!
Hello, Emma!"
And they would answer me back -
One day I'd been working very hard.
I worked so hard, I broke my shovel.
I came home,
and I stood at the bottom of the steps,
and I cried out...
“Hello-lo-lo-lo, Ella!
Hello, hello, Emma!"
But there was no -
No -
[mutters]
Ella! Emma!
Emma!
[clattering]
[orchestra playing: up-tempo]
♪ A little tale we'll tell to you ♪
♪ About the love of someone who ♪
♪ They called the Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
♪ He'd sigh and wail, as lovers do ♪
♪ When thinking of his sweetie too ♪
♪ Poor little Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
♪ In dreams only they had ever met ♪
♪ And at dawn he'd awake ♪
♪ Oh, so lonely for his Juliet ♪
♪ And then he would take ♪
♪ His little sack and hit the road ♪
♪ A-picking rags at each abode ♪
♪ Poor little Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
♪ Happiness, he found a star to catch it ♪
♪ Listen now, for this is where the catch is ♪
♪ His lady love each night making a rag ♪
♪ Then he never used to be dejected ♪
♪ Doing what the fairy tale directed ♪
♪ On the wall he'd tack 'em all
And for a while ♪
♪ He’d smile the blues away ♪
♪ There’ll come a day, I really feel ♪
♪ We 're gonna love in manner real ♪
♪ My little Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
♪ I'm always gay and never blue ♪
♪ I know that love will lead me to ♪
♪ My little Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
♪ Until then so happy we can be ♪
♪ And complaining ain’t right ♪
♪ Until then I promise faithfully ♪
♪ To see you each night ♪
♪ And just as true as stars above ♪
♪ If I should live, I need to love ♪
♪ My little Ragamuffin Rome - ♪
♪ My Ragamuffin Romeo ♪
[song continues]
[song ends]
[woman] A good show, like a good sauce,
requires just a little dash of spice.
So we ask you to peek though this keyhole
at our next page,
and if you see anything spicy,
remember, you should never, never
peek through a keyhole.
- [door closes]
- [gasps]
- My husband!
- Husband?
- Hide quickly!
- Where?
I-In there!
Okay.
- Ah, my darling wife.
- Hello, dear.
[girl]
Daddy, there's a boogie man in that closet.
What did you say, dear?
There's a boogie man in that closet.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
A great big man like you
running around scaring little children.
[orchestra jazz]
[scatting]
[both scatting]
♪ When you find that your mind ♪
♪ Keeps you worried and blue ♪
♪ You can always let your feet
Keep your disposition sweet ♪
♪ I want to see what makes me ♪
♪ Feel the way I do-ooh ♪
♪ Will you kindly cast an eye
On two good reasons why? ♪
[all] ♪ Happy feet
I've got those happy feet ♪
♪ Give them a low-down beat ♪
♪ And they begin dancing ♪
♪ We got those 10 little tapping toes ♪
♪ And when they hear a tune
I can't control my dancing heels ♪
♪ To save my soul ♪
♪ Weary blues can't get into my shoes ♪
♪ Because my shoes refuse
To ever grow weary ♪
♪ I keep cheerful
on an earful of music, sweet ♪
♪ 'Cause we got
Those hap-hap-happy feet ♪
- ♪ Bada-dava-da ♪
- Ah.
♪ Happy feet, we've got those happy feet ♪
♪ Give them a loww-down beat
And they begin dancing ♪
♪ We got those 10 little tapping toes ♪
♪ And when they hear a tune
I can't control my dancing heels ♪
♪ To save my soul ♪
[singing in German]
♪ I keep cheerful on an earful ♪
♪ Of music, sweet ♪
♪ 'Cause we've got
Those hap-hap-happy feet ♪
Well done, girls. Bravo. Splendid.
-[dancers] Thank you, Mr. Irwin.
- You're welcome.
Say, Charlie, what's the big idea?
Don't you think I'm entitled
to a little consideration?
What for, Paul? After all is said and done,
it's dancing that puts a number over.
All you do is stand back there,
wave a little stick, and form a background.
[chuckles] And what a background.
[mock laughing]
How do you know that I can't dance?
You don't mean to tell me
that you're well-versed
in the intricacies of the an
of Terpsichore?
[yelps] No, but I can dance.
Charlie, I have a secret confession.
Ever since I've been a little fellow,
I've been able to dance, oh, quite well.
Ever since I was about -
oh, about so high.
Yeah, but how wide?
Ouch.
You really want to dance?
All right, Ladies and gentlemen,
Mr. Paul Whiteman will now dance,
so help me, Bob.
[orchestra: up-tempo jazz]
[song ends]
What progress pictures have made,
from Edison's Vitascope
to the talkies of today.
On the next page,
we're going to take you back to the days
of the illustrated song,
when legs were limbs
and lightning was considered fast.
[orchestra: mid-tempo]
[man]
♪ The fights were brightly gleaming ♪
♪ On the Great White Way ♪
♪ Where there's a light
For every broken heart ♪
♪ A lonely lad was gazing ♪
♪ On the scene so gay ♪
♪ From all the merry drunks
He stood apart ♪
♪ A kindly faced policeman ♪
♪ Whistling “Broadway Melody" ♪
♪ Observed the teardrops
In the laddie’s eye ♪
♪ “Don’t bring a frown to Broadway” ♪
♪ In a gentle tone said he ♪
[voice breaking]
♪ With trembling voice ♪
♪ The youth began to cry ♪
♪ Has anybody seen our Nellie? ♪
[whistling]
♪ She's somewhere on the Great White Way ♪
♪ Perhaps, dare to tell ♪
♪ There's same city swell ♪
♪ Who ain’t doing right ♪
♪ Tonight by our Nell ♪
♪ She’s just a child ♪
♪ A little wild ♪
♪ But then she's just a kid ♪
♪ Some villain may lead her astray ♪
♪ Ah, heaven forbid ♪
♪ Ana, if you see our darling Nellie ♪
♪ Please send her back ♪
♪ To Shamokin, PA ♪
♪ Has anybody seen our Nellie? ♪
♪ She's somewhere on the Great White Way ♪
♪ The Great White Way ♪
♪ Perhaps, dare to tell ♪
♪ There's same city swell ♪
♪ Who ain’t doing right ♪
♪ Tonight by our Nell ♪
- Now, all together, please!
-[whistling]
Once again!
♪ She's just a child, a little wild ♪
♪ But then she's just a kid ♪
♪ Some villain may lead her astray ♪
♪ Ah, heaven forbid ♪
♪ Ana, if you see our darling Nellie ♪
♪ Please send her back ♪
♪ To Shamokin, PA ♪
♪ Shamokin, PA ♪
♪ Wake from your sleep ♪
♪ All you weary ones ♪
♪ Who are weary ♪
♪ Of the night ♪
♪ Look to the east ♪
♪ All you dreary ones ♪
♪ Who are waiting ♪
♪ For the light ♪
♪ Dawn is breaking ♪
♪ And a new day is born ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
♪ Birds are waking ♪
♪ Hear them welcome the mam ♪
♪ They’re sweetly singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
♪ Yesterday the skies were gray ♪
♪ Look, this morning they’re blue ♪
♪ The smiling sun tells everyone ♪
♪ Come and start life anew ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah ♪
♪ For the dark night is gone ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
[all] ♪ Dawn is breaking ♪
♪ And a new day is born ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
♪ Birds are waking ♪
♪ Hear them welcome the mam ♪
♪ They’re sweetly singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
♪ Yesterday the skies were gray ♪
♪ Look, this morning they’re blue ♪
♪ The smiling sun tells everyone ♪
♪ Come and start life anew ♪
♪ Sing hallelujah ♪
♪ For the dark night is gone ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
♪ Dawn is breaking ♪
♪ And the dark night is gone ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
[orchestra “Rhapsody in Blue"]
America is a melting pot of music,
wherein the melodies of all nations
are fused into one great new rhythm -
jazz!
[fanfare]
♪ Do you ken John Peel
With his coat so gray? ♪
At the break of day? ♪
♪ Do you ken John Peel
When he's far, far away? ♪
♪ With his hounds and his horn
In the morning ♪
♪ Do you ken John Peel
With his coat so gray? ♪
At the break of day? ♪
♪ Do you ken John Peel
When he's far, far away? ♪
♪ With his hounds and his horn
In the morning ♪
[new song playing]
[singing in Italian]
[fanfare]
♪ If a body meets a body ♪
♪ Coming through the rye ♪
♪ If a body ♪
♪ Kiss a body ♪
♪ Need a body cry? ♪
[bagpipes: traditional Scottish song]
[fanfare]
[singing in German]
[waltz]
♪ Angels fold their wings and rest ♪
♪ In that Eden of the west ♪
♪ Beauty’s home Killarney ♪
♪ Ever fair ♪
♪ Killarney ♪
[up-tempo]
[fanfare]
[singing in Spanish]
[singing in Spanish continues]
[fanfare]
[all vocalizing]
[singing in Russian]
[vocalizing]
[fanfare]
[singing in French]
[singing in French continues]
[singing ends]
[orchestra: mid-tempo jazz]
[“Stars and Stripes Forever”]
[“Happy Feet"]
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ For the dark night is gone ♪
♪ The world is singing ♪
♪ The song of the dawn ♪
[“Rhapsody in Blue”]
[ends]
[orchestra: jazz]
[orchestra: jazz continues]
[jazz continues]
[music ends]