So nice of you to let me drop
you at your hotel, Mr Darricott.
Of course it's wretched for that exhibit
to be held so near the Metropole.
Or we could have had a longer talk.
I am told that mountains
can be moved by faith.
But I'm afraid that nothing can be
done about moving The Metropole.
However, I console myself.
We meet again in two hours.
I'm so glad you were able to arrange
your engagements so you could come.
We dine early: 7:30.
After all, we must hear
something of the opera.
Ah, yes.
It might be interesting sometime to find
out if Tosca really had a first act.
Good afternoon, Mr Darricott.
- Charles.
Until tonight?
- Until tonight.
"Calling Mr Mellner. 714."
"Mr Mellner."
Here you are, Mr Darricott.
Thank you, Mr Darricott.
What a marvelous day, Mr Darricott.
You wouldn't think a fellow could run
up a bill of $28 on 3-cent newspapers.
Would you?
Why not? He ran up $40 on
me on 20-cent cigarettes.
You ain't worried, are you?
No. There's no chance in the world
of that fellow not coming through.
You said it.
They don't make them any nicer than him.
A real swell, is what I mean.
Thank you, Fred.
- Always a pleasure, Mr Darricott.
Eugene.
How do I stand today?
Sorry, Mr Darricott.
You just dropped three million.
Three million, huh?
- Three million.
I'm afraid I haven't the cash
on hand to reimburse you.
Shall we call it square if I let
you read the sporting page first?
Anything you say, Mr Darricott.
I took the other dress
shirt to the laundry.
Thanks, Eugene.
Nice of you to go to so
much trouble for me.
I'd rather do a little valet
service for you for nothing.
Nothing?
Than for some of those guys
who give me 20-dollar tips.
It's not everyone who can have an
address like the Hotel Metropole.
And valet service for
ten dollars a week.
We know a gentleman when
we see one, Mr Darricott.
Stop Eugene. You turn my head.
Shall I lay out the evening
clothes for you, sir?
Yes.
In the meantime, I'll draw my bath.
That is, unless someone
is using it at the moment.
So nice of you to dine
with us, Mr Darricott.
I know how rushed you must be.
- Rushed?
I should think an attractive bachelor
in New York would be stampeded.
How does one avoid being trampled
in the jam, Mr Darricott?
I am afraid I cannot
give expert testimony.
I'm just an innocent bystander.
Innocent bystander?
Isn't that the fellow who always
gets shot by accident?
Why, Peyton.
Don't you ever got shot by
accident, Mr Darricott?
It is so unromantic.
Perhaps you could suggest a romantic
way for Mr Darricott to get shot?
Well. In a pinch I might
shoot him myself.
It would be a pleasure
to be a target for you.
I'd tremble. So I'd probably miss you.
Well.
If you're not going to shoot
Mr Darricott at this very moment ..
It might be fun to see if we can get to
the Robinsons on time just this once.
You'd better hurry too, mother.
You're more than
fashionably late right now.
If we could ever get your father to stop
imitating a caged lion, we can leave.
Horace.
- Yes, dear?
Mr Helden and Mr Dorset are here, sir.
Oh yes.
I am sorry, dear. I had hoped
these fellows wouldn't turn up.
Tony, it looks as if you and I must tear
ourselves away from this nice gathering.
They're here about the Austrian loan.
Horace.
- Yes, dear?
I suppose this means you're not going
to the opera with me again. Is that it?
Afraid so.
The second time this week
you disappoint me.
When I had my heart set on the opera.
Horace.
- I am sorry.
What good does it do
me for you to be sorry?
Night after night if I want to go
anyplace I have to go without you.
It's humiliating.
- Look here, my dear.
It's not as if I didn't want to go.
- I do not believe you.
Well. If we could perhaps
discuss this at another time.
But it's always some other time.
I'm sick of it.
I want to go to the opera and
I want to go with my husband.
You've no right ..
- Mother.
And you. Why must you go to those stupid
business meetings with your father?
If Tony has to go into my bank ..
I don't quite see how he will get along
if he doesn't know something of my work.
Now, goodnight.
Run along, son.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight.
There's one thing you must admit
about our family, Mr Darricott.
Never a dull moment.
Well, if you will excuse me.
Oh, Mr Darricott.
You won't disappoint me, will you?
I've had my heart set on
tonight's performance.
You will like it, you know.
- I shall be delighted.
If Peyton and I didn't have this
engagement we simply must keep ..
I wouldn't think of making you
change your plans, darling.
We have to get to the Robinsons.
- Alright. Alright.
Have a good time, Mr Darricott.
Goodnight, mother.
Goodnight.
It seemed as if you weren't
going to have any choice.
Any choice?
Well, the way things have turned out.
I'm afraid you're going to
have me on your hands ..
For tonight.
At least.
I shall be very happy.
I'll get my wrap.
Lovely, isn't it?
Ah yes.
One of my favorite subjects.
Potemkin?
Catherine and Potemkin.
Oh.
A lucky chap.
That he found his Catherine.
Almost too late.
It would have been rather
tragic for her too, wouldn't it?
If she had not found him.
I wonder.
She made him a great man, didn't she?
He made her a happy woman.
And what better can any man ask for?
If he finds his Catherine.
But a woman can ..
But Catherine did find her Potemkin.
But he had to die.
Does Potemkin always have to die?
What a dreadful fate.
What a glorious death.
Shall we go?
To the ..
Opera?
To the opera.
You are not very
complimentary, Mr Darricott.
I am with you and yet it seems
as though you are alone.
I am always alone.
If you could only know what an evening
like this can mean to a man like me.
A home.
A fireside.
A charming woman.
What good are all those things ..
Where there is no love?
But where there is love ..
I want so badly to talk to you Jamie.
Almost too late for the opera.
It is too late.
It all seems so unimportant.
The opera. Tosca. All those people.
If only we could sit and talk.
Perhaps if we could go to your ..
Well.
Perhaps at The Metropole ..?
Well, if I ..
If I had only known. But ..
Unfortunately, my ..
My rooms are not my
own for this evening.
An old friend.
I know a place where we can be alone.
And that's why I am so unhappy, Jamie.
I am so sorry.
If I could believe you
really meant that.
Please believe it.
Please mean it.
I mean it.
Then I believe it.
How lucky I am.
Lucky?
Lucky to have met you.
I have a husband whose
life is not my life.
I have children whose
lives are their own.
They don't need me.
I need ..
Someone.
I had nothing at all until ..
Until?
Until I met you.
And now ..
Five thousand, Mr Darricott?
Six.
- That's a lot of money.
It's a lot of bracelet.
Okay, Mr Darricott.
I will mail you the check as usual.
Thank you. Good day.
- Good day, sir.
Thank you.
Let's take a look at
those bracelets, Fred.
Alright. But you don't have
to worry about them.
He didn't have to steal them.
That dame is only too glad
to give them to him.
What dame?
Say, I had this out with
headquarters six months ago.
The first time he brought anything in.
Mr Horace Fendley might not know
that these things are missing.
But Mrs Fendley does.
You'll never get a report on
them as stolen property.
Okay.
Gadgets like these convert into cash
with much less trouble than a check.
You have to sign your name on
the back of a check, you know.
I'm sorry, Mr Darricott.
Mrs Fendley left her home an hour ago.
Her maid said there was no message.
Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
And a demitasse?
Well, I think we'd better wait, Victor.
Hello Jamie.
Well.
Hello.
Surprised to see me?
Yes.
And no.
There's a simple explanation
if you care to hear it.
Auntie Mabel decided an hour ago
to enjoy very, very bad health.
So mother had to drive out
to Long Island to see her.
She asked me to phone you and say she
couldn't keep her engagement with you.
But somehow I forgot.
But you remembered to keep
her engagement for her?
As a matter of fact, mother
thought it would be a good idea.
That is.
I'm sure she would have thought it
a good idea if she had thought of it.
Funny. I was about to suggest it myself.
You liar.
What you really mean is you're afraid
you've a wasted evening on your hands.
An evening can never be
called wasted until it's over.
I went to a lot of pains
to dress the part, Jamie.
You won't have to be very ashamed of me.
'Banker's daughter takes world altitude
record reaching for compliments'.
Banker's daughter has
just that intention.
I'm ashamed of you, my dear Rachel.
You are positively ..
Beautiful?
Beautiful of course.
But the word I mean
should also convey ..
Brilliance?
Radiance?
I am sure you know the word I mean.
You're just too modest to use it.
When you call me modest.
Smile.
To call you modest, my dear,
takes more than a smile.
Have it your way.
Well.
Do we dine or do we dine?
We dine.
We'll be two for dinner after all.
Yes, sir. I have the table ready, sir.
Thank you.
Forgive me if I seem too bold.
But dinner and the theater will be just
the hors d'oeuvres of the evening?
And if I might make one more suggestion.
Don't you think it's a good idea if we
kept the rest of the menu to ourselves?
You mean ..
Not to tell ..
- Bright child.
And now, Mr Jamie Darricott.
Suppose I tell you I've looked forward
to substituting for mother for months?
And suppose I tell you ..
- What?
That you are a funny kid.
You'll change your mind about that too.
There you are, Charles.
- Thank you, Mr Darricott.
Mr Darricott.
Your cigarettes got in
today from Cairo, sir.
Oh? Send them up Charlie, will you?
- Yes, I will. Thank you, sir.
Good morning, Mr Darricott.
Good afternoon, sir.
Eugene.
Miss Rachel has been
waiting for you, sir.
She is in the living room.
Thank you.
Hello.
- Well.
Well, aren't you glad to see me?
Always.
For the twentieth time ..
I take the liberty of reminding you that
it's very unwise of you to come here.
Meaning for the twentieth time that
mother won't like it if she found out?
You have an uncanny ability
to divine just what I mean.
As a matter of fact Mr Darricott, I came
to deliver a message, as you asked me.
Particularly if mother asks you.
My party is not until ten.
But mother and I thought it would be
very sweet if you could come at nine.
And help us with whatever
pops up at the last minute.
I shall be delighted.
- Thank you.
But that's not what you
came here to tell me.
I did have something else I
wanted to talk to you about.
Ah.
Mother.
You and she are being talked about.
Everyone knows but dad.
You've become a town scandal.
It's an idle world, Rachel.
Hundreds of people with nothing
to occupy their time except ..
That still isn't what you
came here to tell me.
What is it?
It's you, Jamie.
It is you and I.
It's been nearly four months since
we began seeing a lot of each other.
I know.
I cannot keep on any longer this way.
It's not easy for me, Rachel.
- We've got to stop being furtive.
A strange girl.
- In what way am I strange?
Is it strange to fall in love?
To want what you love?
My dear.
I couldn't let you in for ..
This.
- There's no need for this.
We could get married, you and I.
Why not? I have my own money.
I will come into almost three
million on my next birthday.
Oh.
I didn't mean to talk about that.
- That's alright.
You are privileged to talk
about money to me.
Jamie.
Why shouldn't we announce
our engagement tonight?
That's impossible.
- Why?
I see.
Jamie, you've got to break with this.
Hmm.
That is not so simple.
If you loved me as I love you.
You would find it very simple.
How do you suppose I feel
when I see you with mother?
How do you suppose I'll feel
tonight at my own party?
What do you think it will mean to me ..
When I see you lead the Grand March
with her on Friday night?
Catherine.
And her Potemkin.
Rachel.
You must be patient.
Please.
Kiss me, Jamie.
You must go now.
I suppose I have got to start
learning to obey you sometime.
Goodbye.
Pardon me, sir.
It is 12 o'clock.
It's what?
It's 12 o'clock, sir.
Miss Fendley's party.
Oh yes.
I can't imagine what happened to him.
What could happen to Jamie Darricott?
If you knew the number of women who try
to trap him into going to their parties.
If you had any idea ..
- It's such a lovely party.
What difference does it
make if he comes or not?
A lot of difference.
It's my party and he might have had
the common courtesy to be here.
Oh, Rachel dear.
What difference does it make?
Whether he's courteous to you or not?
It's time you left Jamie
Darricott alone, mother.
If he's interested in any one Fendley ..
- Rachel.
It's the truth.
You've fooled yourself long enough.
You don't really think Jamie Darricott
is coming here to see you?
Elaine, dear.
It was so lovely.
Therese, you're not going?
- Yes.
We really must, Mrs Fendley.
I hate to, but I'm leaving
for home tomorrow and ..
When I was your age I never
thought of going to bed ..
Until the others thought of getting up.
- I have so much to do tomorrow morning.
Now that you've met us you
must come and see us often.
Thank you.
Say goodnight to Mr Fendley for me.
- Yes. Indeed I will.
Gaston.
You had better wait.
I shan't be long.
How do you do, Mrs Blanton.
Aunt Theresa. Who is that man?
Are you trying to be funny, Norma?
No. Who is he?
That is Jamie Darricott.
This year's ladies' man.
Ladies' man?
- Ladies' man.
And at the moment 'the ladies'
happen to be Mrs Fendley.
Goodnight, dear.
- Goodnight.
Yes, Anthony?
Mr James Darricott has just come in.
Jamie? Why, I must ..
- One moment, mother.
If he's to join this party I'm leaving.
You are being a silly boy, Anthony.
I am not silly.
He is cheap and disgusting.
Don't talk like that about a friend.
He's not a friend.
Do you know what they say?
Anthony.
I must forbid you to
speak that way to me.
As you wish.
But if he stays, I go.
You are always to do
whatever suits you, Anthony.
Goodnight, mother.
- Goodnight, dear.
Jamie.
Where have you been?
Where have I not been?
I asked you to be here at nine.
You did, my dear.
Do you I'll put up with
your insults much longer?
How do you do.
Would I be insulting you if I asked you
to be good enough to lower your voice?
You are doing it perfectly.
You are trying to humiliate me.
Who is she?
Thank you, no.
Well.
Our débutante child.
My felicitations.
Thank you. Aren't you just a bit late?
Oh .. a bit.
I've been waiting for you since nine.
If you think I am going to forgive
you, you're badly mistaken.
You'll forgive me.
I am afraid I shall.
That's what makes me more
furious than anything else.
Well.
Now for our charming host.
No. You can stay and
talk to me for a moment.
Jamie.
- My dear Elaine.
If you must know, I am sorry I was late.
And you know I didn't
mean anything I said.
I suppose you didn't.
But sometimes.
Sometimes ..
What, Jamie?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
How are you?
Thank you.
Well, how do you do?
We have met before.
Have we?
Oh yes.
Last night as you were leaving the
Fendleys with Mrs Blanton. Remember?
I see.
Yes. I suppose to a 'ladies' man' that
does constitute an introduction.
Then you do know me.
You.
You don't live here in New York, huh?
What makes you think so?
I think I should have known.
Remaining here for some time?
I am leaving tonight.
For my home.
Why?
Surely you don't want to leave New York?
I've got to.
Got to?
That is slave talk.
You ought to be doing what you want to.
While you can want to.
I generally do.
I'm the little man who can
show you all this big city.
Do you know ..
That's one of the few things
that I can take your word for.
But I am taking the train.
Do you know they tell me ..
That they have a train
nearly every day now.
I could show you a lot
of this town in 24 hours.
Somehow.
I think your New York and
my New York are different.
Suppose we find out?
Let's make the grand tour.
See the clock around.
See New York in all its
different lights and shades.
High life. Low life.
Uptown and downtown.
Starting say, with ..
Dinner at the St Regis.
Or The Embassy maybe.
Dance a little.
Drop in a little musical piece.
Catch a night at the opera.
And then a midnight
flight above the city.
We can turn the plane over and over.
The town would go round like a
wheel with you sitting on the hub.
You'll never know New York until
you see it as the moon sees it.
Then a nightclub or two.
And out in time to catch the sunrise.
Somewhere along the Hudson.
The sun does some of its very
nicest rising around here.
Then we could separate long enough
for a bath and a change of clothes.
You think you can live
without me that long?
After 12 hours of Jamie Darricott.
I doubt if I would be able
to breathe any other air.
And after breakfast we'll
keep on going and going.
And at 7:30.
I deposit you at your train.
I doubt if we would be able to
stand more than a 24-hour stretch.
Perhaps you could stand it for 24 hours.
You are strong.
But I'm just a weak,
defenseless little woman.
Ah. But you could trust me.
Perhaps it's me I am afraid of.
You know.
There is only one slight catch.
I'm meeting my aunt here and she stays
with me until I take the train at 7:30.
Ah, then it's a bargain.
You get rid of your aunt.
Telegraph your people you've been
unavoidably detained for 24 hours.
And at 7:30 I will call for you.
Where?
At the Transylvania Station.
I don't know which track.
I will take you to the train
myself tomorrow night.
When I return to New York.
That is the time for the
Darricott round-the-town tour.
You may never get back
and I may be dead.
You?
You'll live for ever.
I doubt it.
Dying is getting to be quite
a habit around here.
And it's a terrible thing to
die without seeing New York.
And Jamie Darricott.
You will come back?
Certainly not.
For one thing. My trunks are packed.
That's easy. Unpack them.
I can't. They are shipped.
Easier still. But a dress.
As a matter of fact, you should have a
new gown when you go out with me.
You are impossible.
Perhaps that's what makes me ..
Possible?
Your aunt is approaching.
You'd better not tell her of our plans.
She'll want to come along.
What is the name of your hotel?
- The Holland Plaza.
And your name?
Norma Page.
I will be there at 7:30.
How do you do, Mrs Blanton.
- How do you do, Mr Darricott.
Hello, aunt Theresa. I waited for you
and then Mr Darricott came along.
That's the best thing
Mr Darricott has done.
Women are always waiting for someone.
And Mr Darricott comes along.
- Unfortunately, not always.
I'm horribly late, Norma.
I suppose I dare not allow
myself to believe that ..
Fate arranged your lateness
for my special benefit?
I am afraid not. It was the hairdresser.
Come, Norma.
Goodbye, Mr Darricott.
- Goodbye, Mrs Blanton.
Au revoir, Miss Page.
Goodbye.
Mr James Darricott calling
for Miss Norma Page.
I am sorry, sir. Miss Page checked out
of the hotel and left half an hour ago.
You are quite sure?
Yes, sir.
She left this note for you, sir.
Thank you.
Mr Darricott. You didn't really believe
you could order me around, did you?
I'm leaving for home as I told
you I would at seven-thirty.
Or is it goodbye? N.P.
Gaston.
Come on now.
You can do better than this.
All aboard.
Seeing someone off, Mr Darricott?
Don't tell me you're
at a loss for words.
I'm glad you came to see me off.
If you hadn't, there's another train in
an hour and I would have taken it.
Now.
If you still want to show
me your New York.
Now more than ever.
Well?
Well.
On your left we have the city hall.
Is this an automobile or bedroom?
It's a loan.
From a lady?
Naturally.
I told the owner I had
to call on a sick aunt.
And you are the sick aunt.
If you don't mind ..
I'll dismiss it when we get to St Regis.
Thanks a lot.
A dirty old taxi that
everybody rides in ..
Is so much nicer than some individual's
too-private car, don't you think?
Or do you?
I think.
Hello, Jamie.
Well, hello.
How do you do.
I am glad your aunt is better.
Oh yes. Much.
You are not alone?
I'm waiting for Horace and Tony.
We dine here and then go on to the play.
Yes. That's nice.
You'll have a splendid evening.
I am sure we shall.
Remember me to your aunt.
Thanks.
She wants to be remembered to you.
Doesn't it embarrass you?
Meeting her here and dining with me?
No.
Well .. it embarrasses me.
We'll go to the Aristide instead.
It's nicer anyway.
There's been a shooting every
night there for the last month.
Let's go this way.
I suppose Mrs Fendley
will hate you after this.
No. She will merely hate you.
Tell me about her.
There's nothing to tell.
To her discredit.
Which is all that would interest
another woman I imagine.
How many cocktails have we had tonight?
I don't know. I gave up counting at six.
Do you want to know why
you gave up counting at six?
Alright. Why did I give
up counting at six?
Because you cannot count over six.
Hector. Number One for Mr Darricott.
Who's that?
It's Jamie.
The town seems to be dripping
with Fendleys tonight.
A sick aunt, huh?
You dirty liar.
Shush. You are a lady.
Two tall glasses and some ice water.
Won't you sit down?
It's just as well you
didn't go with mother.
Because dad would have sighted you.
He's the only one in the whole town who
doesn't know of mother's frenzy for you.
Jamie.
If you and mother don't look out ..
There will be the loudest
eruption since Vesuvius.
Did you hear what I said about mother?
Everyone has except the drummer.
I want to extend to you.
By a unanimous vote of thanks.
For carrying Jamie off this evening.
If you keep him from mother.
I'll give you a pension for life.
Then, when I want him I'll
just take him away from you.
Could anything be fairer than that?
Shall we dance?
We?
I may.
But we can't.
Did you ever dance with Jamie, Miss ..?
Miss ..?
I hope you know your own name. I know.
I am Miss Fendley if anybody
should happen to ask you. But ..
Where was I?
Mother doesn't approve
of me dancing with Jamie.
She wants to have him all to herself.
Rachel.
Will you do me a big favor?
I'll do you any flavor, honey.
Then go home.
You're in no condition
for public appearances.
Jamie, you do me a cruel injustice.
Rachel, please.
Sit back there where you belong.
Well, I'd rather belong to you.
I'm mad about you, if you want to know.
Shall we dance?
So I'll bet you a million.
You're on.
Nope. I have changed my mind.
You're trying to take advantage of me.
Jamie.
Jamie. Peyton Walden here bets
me a million I'll marry him.
I'll bet him a million
he don't marry me.
Come on, Mr Walden.
Put your million in Jamie's hands.
Very likely.
Oh, very likely.
- Put up or shut up.
Where is your million?
Where's yours?
I don't have to have
mine because you lose.
You answered me already.
How do you make that out?
You bet me a million
that you'd marry me.
I am the one to decide.
I decide you don't marry me.
I bet you another million I do.
I'll take that back too.
Alright. Where's your money?
Pay me the million you owe on the first
bet and I'll put it up for the second.
I don't owe you.
- See?
You are a welsher.
Do you imagine I would marry a welsher?
You will marry me.
- Never.
Never, never speak to me again.
Do you hear?
Miss whoosis ..
Would you marry a welsher?
Who cares?
I'm going to make a riot with you.
Rachel.
- What do you want?
Now listen to me.
I want you to get Peyton out
of here and take him home.
You don't want to make a riot with him.
He'll bite himself and
die of hydrophobia.
I'm going home myself.
You want me to get old Peyton home?
That's it exactly.
Miss Page and I are leaving.
I got it.
I'll get old Peyton home.
Never mind, I'll handle him.
Peyton.
Peyton, old boy, old boy, old boy.
Come on.
Go home.
I never knew it could get to
five in the morning so quickly.
I never knew it could get
to five in the morning.
Where to now?
To my hotel if you don't mind.
What is the matter?
Am I a kill-sport by going home
in the middle of the evening?
Why, you haven't even seen the
skyline from my apartment yet.
Mr Darricott.
You don't mean you are asking me to
your apartment to see your ship models?
Or is it your collection of
real old English bindings?
I haven't read a novel for months, so ..
I'm not quite sure what the ruse is.
When I invite you to my
apartment to see the skyline.
I invite you to my apartment to
see the skyline and that's all.
Maybe that's why I am disappointed.
It's really the most beautiful
sight in the whole city.
Particularly at this hour with
dawn just breaking over the town.
Skyscrapers like so many jagged peaks.
The streets.
Like so many canyons.
Alright.
I'll come.
Taxi.
Sir.
I am sorry, Mr Darricott.
I tried.
I don't understand.
I think I understand.
What is it?
Miss Fendley, sir. Miss Rachel Fendley.
Oh.
Alright, Eugene.
I should hate to interfere with
any of your engagements.
Please don't go now.
I may need your help.
Hello.
I got rid of Peyton as you told me.
And here I am.
I told you to get rid of Peyton?
Who are you trying to fool?
Yourself or Miss ..
Miss whatshername there?
I am awful tired.
Yes. I can understand that.
You've got to go home.
- No. I don't want to go home.
She cannot go home in this condition.
Why not put her to bed here?
No. I don't want to go to bed.
You want me to help you?
- I don't know what I want.
What you want most right now is sleep.
Jamie.
Come on, child. Put your arm around me.
There is a bedroom just in there.
You'll find everything you need.
We women must stick together.
No. I don't want to stick together.
There you are. Right over here.
Jamie.
Listen, darling. Over here. Come on.
- No.
Let me help you.
I don't want to go home.
No. Me do it.
No.
Jamie.
I'll have coffee ready
in a few moments, sir.
Good.
And ..
Tell the operator downstairs
that I am not in to anyone.
Very good, sir.
I couldn't get her in the
tub but she's asleep now.
There was a picture in
there of her mother.
It seemed to bother her a little.
A nice little civilization.
A million young men and women all
over the country at this very moment.
Drunk like her.
Not to mention their
fathers and mothers.
Our plane.
It was going to make the town go round
like a wheel with me sitting on the hub.
'You never know New York'.
'Until you see it as the moon sees it'.
It was a nice speech.
What we call a 'good approach' in golf.
But I'm afraid you ..
You dubbed your putt.
We played only the first hole.
Jamie.
You'd better go.
I don't know why I don't
kill you, Jamie Darricott.
I waited here for you tonight.
No-one asked you to wait for me.
Who has a better idea?
If you are lying to me ..
If you're not going to
marry me I will ..
I'll kill myself.
Rachel.
Maybe you don't think I
know what I am saying.
But I do.
Are you going to marry me?
Are you?
I don't think so.
I want to see Mr Darricott.
- Sorry, sir. But Mr Darricott is not ..
You can't stop me.
- I already told you, sir.
Mr Darricott is not at home.
- But I know he's here.
Excuse me, sir.
- Keep out of my way.
Excuse me, sir. One moment.
- I've come for my sister.
Hello brother of mine.
You dirty ..
- Tony.
You keep out of this.
Listen.
I got sick from liquor and Miss ..
Miss whoosis here put me to bed.
And that's all.
And if you weren't such a phoney saint
you'd be on your knees to both of them.
I am sorry.
May I take you ..
- Home?
And let you make an entrance with the
erring sister and a few hallelujahs?
Ha-ha .. and ha.
Say. How did you know I was here?
Peyton followed you and watched you
come into this hotel. Then he phoned me.
But he must have known
that Miss Page and I ..
Everybody knows you have
your women come up here.
You've laid your filthy hands
on my family for the last time.
I hear so many people say
somebody ought to kill you.
Shut up!
Any woman who has anything
to do with Jamie Darricott ..
Has no-one to blame but herself.
Any account I have to settle with him ..
I settle alone.
Get out, Tony.
I think I'll go home
now if you don't mind.
Shall I see you again before you leave?
I'm leaving tonight.
You may have tea with me if you like.
I like.
At my hotel then. Say at ..
Four-thirty?
At four-thirty.
I'll be there.
Goodnight.
I don't know what to say about ..
Don't say it.
Thanks.
You know.
I am beginning to think.
What?
Never mind.
They say you are without a conscience.
The more I know of other people's
morals the more I realise that ..
Mine are as good as the next.
The only difference I can see is that ..
I don't pretend.
They say you are lazy.
Lazier than most people I suppose.
Too lazy to ..
Earn a living perhaps?
Norma.
Since I can remember anything.
I remember being picked up by women.
They used to maul me
around in my cradle.
By and by I learned that I could ..
Make money by it.
I hated to study.
I wouldn't run errands or ..
Deliver newspapers.
Keep a lemonade stand.
Or do any of the things that
kids do to earn a dime.
Eventually.
I became a bond salesman.
But the only opportunities that
seemed to come my way were ..
Well, when some ..
Skittish dowager needed to be
convinced that she wanted bonds.
But never a deal involving
logic or common sense.
That is no excuse.
Of course not.
But the skittish dowagers ..
Usually seemed more interested
in me than in my bonds.
And it was not that I
squandered flattery on them.
If anything they ..
They squandered it on me.
Why?
Perhaps it's because I look at women
the way other women look at them.
The men make.
And the women spend.
How many wives let their husbands
work themselves to death ..
And then complain that
they're neglected?
They spend their husband's money.
On other men.
On you?
On me.
Oh, that is ..
I know.
That is everything that's ..
Low and unspeakable.
Then why did you do it?
I suppose because I thought
I couldn't help myself.
I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
Norma, I am going to ask you something.
I shan't mind what your reaction is.
Except for one thing.
Don't laugh.
Please don't laugh.
I won't laugh.
I used to feel amused when I heard
of it happening to other people.
But now it's happened to me.
And it seems just simple and natural.
I love you.
But that's not a question.
Do you think you could ever ..
Care for me?
That is a question, isn't it?
Well.
I suppose I could fall for you.
I have fallen.
Into the clouds.
Heaven help me when I start to drop.
You don't have to drop.
If you do not want to.
If I don't want to?
Is that your answer to my question?
What do you expect me to answer?
I don't know.
If I thought you could care for me.
I could care for ..
What you might be.
I can be what you want me to be.
That was the whole job, eh?
- Yes, sir.
Yes. I will see her in a moment.
Thanks very much for your frankness.
My detectives traced the
jewelry to your shop.
We'd have had a lot of trouble
getting hold of it all ..
If you'd been unwilling to cooperate.
I always aim to do the right thing, sir.
You've done the right thing this time.
I'll see that you don't lose by it.
- Thank you, sir.
Alright. That will be all.
Well, Rachel my dear?
Hello dad.
You're looking very
smart it seems to me.
Am I?
- Hmm.
Well?
What's the matter?
You lost your nerve?
You've spent your allowance
and you want another check.
'Just this once, daddy'.
It's not money. It's much more serious.
If it isn't money, you take it from your
poor old father that it's not serious.
It is very serious.
Good gracious.
Don't tell me you are in love?
I'm not in love with anybody.
Well.
If you're not in love then ..
There's something I
must talk to you about.
Alright.
Sit down there and talk to me about it.
Well?
It's mother.
And Jamie Darricott.
Mother?
And Mr Darricott?
What do you mean?
You have got to do something about them.
Do something?
In what way?
They're making a fool out of you.
My dear child, don't be silly.
Dad, you ought to kill Jamie Darricott.
You've been reading too much trash.
Jamie Darricott is the
lowest scoundrel I know.
I could torture him for the way he's ..
The way he has what?
- Nothing.
It's just that he isn't fit to live.
Rachel.
Rachel. Listen to me.
I trust your mother.
Thoroughly.
I like Mr Darricott.
You must remember that I haven't
the time to give to your mother ..
That she has a right to demand.
Mr Darricott kindly took her to the
opera and other places when I could not.
And that's all there is.
Between mother and Mr Darricott.
- Dad.
You are blind.
If that's your only grievance
against Mr Darricott.
It is your only grievance against him?
Isn't it?
Rachel.
He hasn't become involved
with you, has he?
Oh, my dear child.
I have never seen you like this before.
Now look here.
If I were you.
I would forget all
about our little talk.
I know more about mother
and Mr Darricott.
Than you think I do.
More perhaps than you do.
Dad.
And there's absolutely nothing.
To worry about.
There. Now, you run
along like a nice girl.
The great banker is going to
settle down and make more money.
And starve a couple of hundred
widows and orphans before nightfall.
Goodbye, darling.
I am not going to dodge anything.
I'll tell Mrs Fendley
frankly what's happened.
As soon as I can.
I am going to repay her.
As far as I am able.
I will give her back everything
that she has given me.
Jamie.
When you tell her.
Don't be unkind, will you.
No. I won't. I won't.
And Norma.
- What is it, dear?
I don't see how I can get out of this ..
Catherine and Potemkin thing.
It's been around town for weeks
that she's going to give this ball.
I know.
You should go.
It won't make any difference to me.
You know that.
I'll be back in a week.
You'll not be back in a week.
You're going to stay right here.
And the day after tomorrow.
We're going to be married.
What do you say?
Of course.
You know.
It's getting to be a habit with me.
Wiring my family that I'm not
taking the train after all.
When you take that train you
will take it as Mrs Darricott.
With me.
- You mean ..
You'll meet me at the station
again some night at 7:30?
I won't meet you at the station.
I will take you there.
That is definite.
- Definite and essential.
Because from now on ..
When you are leaving or arriving.
I will be leaving or arriving too.
Horace.
You frightened me.
Did I?
I am sorry.
Still determined not to go to the ball?
Like this?
It's going to be sensational.
Mary Millbank sent all the
way to Paris for her costume.
That will be all, Louise.
Catherine, eh?
And Potemkin?
Darricott I suppose?
Well, you positively refused
yourself to go. So ..
A great lover, wasn't he? Potemkin.
I don't need to tell
you what Potemkin was.
And ..
He died .. suddenly.
Didn't he? Potemkin?
I think so.
These ladies' men.
I suppose they all have a very definite
idea that they might run at any time ..
Into a sudden death?
Horace.
What are you driving at?
Well, if you mean to suggest that ..
That Jamie Darricott and I are ..
Why do you think I was
referring to Darricott?
It's been very nice of him to
take me out as often as he has.
You were tied up in
business or something.
I really don't know what I
should have done without him.
I have an idea that I owe him something.
For what he has done for you.
Horace. I don't know what
this is all about but ..
Charming jewelry you're wearing tonight.
Thank you.
You.
You haven't worn your emerald
bracelet in a long time. Have you?
Emerald bracelet?
Yes. The one I gave
you on your birthday.
Oh, that one?
I am having it re-set.
I imagine Darricott knows a good
deal about jewelry, doesn't he?
Perhaps.
I haven't asked him.
You ought to.
He might ..
He might have some very
interesting ideas about jewelry.
Horace.
I insist upon knowing what
you've got on your mind.
Elaine.
I am sorry.
I am keeping you from the ball.
Goodnight.
Hello?
Circle 1-6-3-3.
Hotel Metropole?
Mr Darricott please.
Yes. Mr James Darricott.
Norma.
- Darling. What's happened?
I'm sorry I had to phone you to come
here but I couldn't very well go to you.
I understand, dear. I came as
soon as I could. What is it?
Mrs Fendley phoned me a few minutes ago.
She had just had a
talk with her husband.
She thinks that he knows about ..
Everything.
Well?
Can't you see what that means?
It will be one of the nastiest scandals
that New York has seen in years.
Are you afraid?
Yes I am.
For you.
You'll be a target for every
dirty mind in New York.
Norma, I cannot let you in for that.
I can't let your name
be linked with mine.
I can't expect you to ..
To marry me.
But.
We still love each other. Don't we?
My darling.
If anything happens to you nobody
is going to keep me out of it.
What happens to you happens to me.
There's no-one who can hurt me, Jamie.
Except you.
There is nothing I want.
If you still love me?
More than anything in the world.
Well. That's all that matters then.
I expected to find you alone.
How do you do.
I think I had better go.
No.
Please stay.
I have something to discuss with you
that does not concern Miss Page.
You must know that.
But I've something to tell you, Elaine.
I had hoped to tell it to you under ..
Different circumstances.
But I feel it best to tell you now.
Miss Page and I ..
Are going to be married.
I don't believe you.
Jamie.
You can't do this to me.
You .. you cannot humiliate
me before the whole town.
I've no intention of
humiliating you, Elaine.
Oh.
Goodbye, dear.
Just this once.
And then it will never be goodbye again.
Darling.
What else could I expect
from a ladies' man?
The ladies' man is dead.
My Potemkin.
And I was worried about you
because I thought Horace knew.
Well.
If he does know.
He will divorce me.
And you will marry me.
Make no mistake about that.
You are going to marry me.
You are not going to marry that girl.
Before you do.
I will kill you.
Good evening.
Good evening, Mr Darricott.
Horace.
Your guests are waiting for you, Elaine.
The Grand March is about to begin.
But I can't go without Mr Darricott.
You will please go.
Now.
And to what do I owe
the honor of this visit?
These.
Don't worry.
I know you didn't steal them.
I am fully aware that my wife ..
Gave them to you.
Mr Darricott please.
I believe I heard my wife say just
now that she would kill you.
She didn't know what she was saying.
She knew perfectly well
what she was saying.
She was mistaken.
I am going to spare her that .. trouble.
Don't bother to answer that.
I can conceive of nothing.
Mister Darricott.
That could come to you
over the telephone ..
That would be of importance to you.
Now.
There you are, my dear.
So sorry to have kept you waiting.
Such a lovely party, Mrs Fendley.
- Do you think so, my dear?
It's almost time to
start the Grand March.
We'll start it just as soon as
Mr Darricott comes down.
He will only be a moment.
He is .. he's detained.
You really mean to go through with this?
If I don't kill you.
My wife will.
My wife or Rachel.
You see, Mr Darricott.
I know a good deal more
about you than you think I do.
Yes. Please try him again.
Mr Fendley.
I am not going to beg for my life.
You may be thoroughly
justified in killing me.
I only want to say that ..
Not only for me.
But for you.
You may be making a great .. mistake.
So that's your game, is it?
There's a fight up there.
- Where?
Up there on the balcony.
There's two men fighting.
Is Mr Darricott here yet?
No. That's who they're waiting for.
Oh? Thank you.
But, Mr Fendley.
That is, we ..
I will lead The Grand March.
With Mrs Fendley.
Mr Darricott has found
it impossible to appear.
Horace. You ..
You have ..?
- We had better start.
Stand back now. Stand back.
Has anything happened?
Plenty.
Mr Darricott?
Jamie Darricott himself.
Look.
That guy in the street clothes.
Wait.
Let him have his fun.
He can't get away.
What's the matter with you, sister?
Were you in love with him too?
I am sorry.
You don't have to be sorry for me.
He loved me.
They can't ever take that away from me.
FxMay22.