Close it.
It's not much, I know,
but there was nothing better.
People never die when you
need them, right doctor?
- It's an honour, Baron.
- There's no need to count it, it's 50.
Yes, of course.
When's the next one?
Lynch, I'll need you next week
for something special.
Sounds good to me,
that means lots of money.
I need a corpse no more
than six hours old.
- 200.
- 500.
- 300.
- Fine.
I don't mind doing my bit for science.
- But I can't promise.
- Results Lynch, not promises.
I don't understand why
you trust him so much.
Money, Charles. It's a wonderful
drug for people like Lynch.
Perhaps it's nothing more
than a splendid dream.
Or perhaps,
just an insane nightmare.
- Does it matter?
- N0, not if I give him life.
It's worth every risk.
Any risk...
- Even your life?
- Yes, of course.
The creation of life is the
greatest achievement.
To hesitate or have doubts...
to be scared now...
would mean all my work
up to now has been pointless.
This... is my life.
But creating life,
isn't that God's task alone?
Here on earth, man is God.
G0 to bed, Charles.
Tanya arrives tomorrow,
get some rest.
Goodnight.
What will you tell her?
Nothing.
But we must finish our work
immediately, don't you agree?
Yes, it's true.
Charles!
You're not saying hello?
I think I at least deserve that.
Forgive me, Tanya.
Forgive me, I'm confused.
Your father and I are happy
to have you with us.
- Come.
- Thank you.
Thomas.
Come here, Thomas.
Come, Thomas.
Take the lady's luggage
and bring it to her room.
From the carriage you'll
take it to her room.
Is that understood?
G0.
Poor Thomas, he's a good lad.
Except for his brain, he's quite normal.
It must have been a childhood illness.
- What a pity, such a handsome boy.
- Your father's getting dressed.
- He worked until late last night.
- As usual.
Is he still working on his animal
transplant experiments?
You know what he's like, he's been
working on them for twenty years...
and he'll work on them for
another twenty, and he'll continue.
Tell me about university.
Except for my studies,
it was rather boring...
but I didn't go there
for the social life.
Aren't you happy?
I'm like my father, stubborn.
When I want something, I get it.
And that's what happened, top of the
class, and now I'm a surgery graduate.
My compliments, doctor.
Daddy!
- My girl.
- It's great to see you again.
That's enough, is this the way
a surgery graduate behaves?
Yes, it is.
Yes, Jack Morgan.
Poor son of a bitch, they'll hang him.
They'll break his neck today.
Are you and Harry with me?
Poor son of a bitch that Jack
Morgan, I never liked him.
- Or you, right?
- Yes, sure, but I'm waiting.
- We can't do it any earlier.
- And Harry?
- He goes where I go.
- Perfect, to Jack Morgan.
To his death.
And when professor Muller wanted
to object to my theory...
I stood there like Sir Galahad
in front of the dragon.
Professor Muller was very much
the dragon, I assure you.
My colleagues retired to their places
thinking who knows what?
And I told that dumb intellectual
how narrow-minded his views were.
Professor, it's men like you,
with the imagination of an ostrich...
that bury their heads under
the sand of superstition.
Whenever someone comes along with a new idea,
they keep it under lock and key.
It's medicine ancl science in the
laboratory of the archivist.
Then I said, I won't set foot in your
class until you apologise...
for your entirely subjective
ancl insulting criticisms.
Good clay, Professor.
And I left.
I know, you've heard it a million times.
It doesn't matter.
It's a fascinating story.
You know, the Frankenstein name
still echoes around the university.
I'm not surprised, I haven't cared about
what those idiots think about me...
or my theories since I left them.
- Sit down Charles, your leg must be tired.
- N0, thank you, I'm fine.
Thank you.
Did you have any problems at university
because you were my daughter?
Sometimes.
But mainly because I was a woman.
Sadly, the professors still have their
prejudices about a woman's role.
- You'll be an excellent surgeon.
- Thank you, Charles.
But I don't just want to be
an excellent surgeon.
What do you want to do?
Assist you father, in your work.
Since I was a child, I've always been
interested in your experiments.
Every summer when I came here...
I went into your laboratory.
It was always locked.
Of course, but I found a way in.
A tunnel, in the wall in your room.
I wonder how you managed to find it.
I was very curious.
Now as well, I'm curious to know
what progress you've made.
I hope you won't keep any
secrets from me now.
I'll be very glad to discuss it,
doctor to doctor.
Good.
But I must confess that my
ideas are radical.
Much more than yours, father.
ReaHy?
Of course, I'm my father's daughter.
You're talking about the
transplant experiments on animals?
On men.
Thomas.
Easy, 685V!
You frightened me, Thomas.
It doesn't matter.
Does it have a name?
- What do you call it?
- N0 name, no.
D0 you like my father?
My father, the Baron,
do you like him?
Even when he takes your animals away?
Even then?
Your animals, do you feel very
sad when the Baron uses them?
- N0, not you.
- N0, not me! The Baron.
Does it upset you when he
takes your lambs?
No, he doesn't take them!
What is it?
Why are you scared of him?
Is he bad?
Bad.
- Did he do something to you?
- Bad.
- Why another £300?
- This is a delicate matter.
There are people who must
be paid in advance.
- Which people?
- Listen, Baron.
I can't say.
Professional ethics.
Don't talk about ethics.
I can get one but it will cost
you another £300.
The way things stand,
you don't have any other choice.
- I'll try to find it.
- Take your time, and don't worry...
I won't sit down, I wouldn't want
to ruin your lovely furniture.
Excuse me.
I was looking for my father.
- Would that be Doctor Marshall?
- No, the Baron.
I never thought the Baron
had it in him.
And Doctor Marshall does?
No, he'd have no hope!
- Something to drink?
- No, it's too early.
It's never too early,
for anything.
What are you doing here?
You're a detestable man,
extremely vulgar...
and I'm sure whatever
you're thinking is pure fantasy.
I'd say you spend too much time alone.
Be careful, that will rot
your brain faster than whiskey.
How could a person like you
think like a witch?
It depends on the company
I find myself in.
Excuse me, father.
I'm sorry, I didn't realise
you were there.
Mr Lynch.
Come, I'll show you out.
It was a real pleasure speaking to you.
Good clay.
Father.
- I said I'm sorry.
- I heard you.
£200 now,
another 200 on delivery.
- When will it be?
- Very soon.
- When?
- When they hang Jack Morgan.
- The clay after tomorrow.
- And then?
Then he's all yours.
Murderer!
You'll pay for your sins!
"I come to bury Caesar,
not to praise him."
Murderer!
You'll rot in Hell!
I'm guessing you're not going
to miss Jack Morgan.
Just like I won't miss you, Captain.
I find that most depressing, Lynch.
Because one clay you'll find yourself
shaking Morgan's hand in Hell.
You mean I'll keep
the other hand for you?
Your clays are numbered.
You'll slip up soon,
and that will be the clay I pay my debt.
N0, not prison my friend,
you're too smart for that.
It's the noose for you.
And I'll make sure you get it,
it's the least I can do.
You might, you might not.
I'll make sure.
I'll make sure, Lynch.
What are you doing here?
I was heading for the city
when I saw the crowd.
- What's going on?
- Something I'd rather you didn't see.
A hanging-
- I've never seen a hanging.
- Nor will you see this one.
Come on, I may be a woman
but above all I'm a doctor.
- Death is normal to me.
- This isn't death.
This is legalised murder.
Perhaps she should stay
to see the difference.
Yes, you're right Charles.
- Thank you, Charles.
- Don't thank him yet.
- Who is that?
- I don't know, I could find out.
It isn't necessary.
Are you ready?
It's easy now, just a few steps.
"And Jesus of Nazareth spoke..."
"Father, forgive them,
for they know not what they do."
"And they cast lots to divide
his garments."
It's time, Morgan.
Proceed.
One... tw0.. three...
They're coming.
- Tanya knows about the animals.
- But how?
I don't know, she asked me
why you still keep them.
Tanya must not find
out about the experiments.
Not now, Charles.
Very good, Lynch.
Excellent.
Thank you.
Charles...
Come on Turner,
earn your money.
Was it difficult?
As difficult as opening
a bottle of whiskey.
D0 you trust him?
I don't trust anyone.
Especially a man who drinks.
Don't worry Baron...
No one's going to shed a tear over
Jack Morgan's empty grave.
He killed the only person who would
have said a prayer for him.
And next week,
another special commission?
I don't know.
I may not need you anymore.
I'm sad to hear that.
I like your money.
- What will I do without it?
- You'll think of something.
I'm not so sure.
- How much blood?
- Two pints this time.
Good, we're ready.
I'm sorry,
but I couldn't...
I really hoped you wouldn't come.
That's why you don't use
animals anymore.
Human transplants.
Tanya, please go.
- I can help you.
- You wouldn't understand.
Yes, father.
YGS.
What are you going to do
with the brain?
Tanya, please.
Will you stop treating me like a child?
I'm a doctor, a surgeon.
Don't you understand,
I'm just like you?
N0.
That's impossible.
- Charles?
- It isn't impossible, Tanya.
But his heart and brain?
You have to keep them alive.
Of course, we've clone it before.
Inside another human body?
We don't need a body.
You're about to put Morgan's brain
and heart in that creature.
Tanya, no more questions.
N0, I don't want you involved
in this experiment.
If anything were to happen,
you'd be as guilty as me in the eyes of the law...
and I couldn't have that.
Soon I'll tell you everything.
Just have a little patience.
I'll try.
Good luck.
- Everything ready?
- Ready.
Pliers.
Start the timer, hurry.
We can begin.
It's moving.
I hope Morgan's brain
works just as well.
Let's hope so, Charles.
Ancl so, for almost twenty years
my animal transplant experiments...
have been leading up to this moment.
All the humiliations I received
from my colleagues.
The accusations against my
mental faculties, all the insults...
will be thrown right back
at their idiotic faces.
- Looking for something?
- Yes, clouds.
I need a storm for the final phase,
a magnetic storm.
Only lightning can give life
to the creature.
That's why I still haven't
transplanted the heart or the brain.
I can keep them alive indefinitely,
but once they're transplanted...
they won't last more than a few hours
if they're not activated by lightning.
- I want to see how you keep them alive.
- You will.
- You'll do it.
- I won't fail Tanya, I promise.
You should be proud of me,
we'll have the medical world at our feet.
I want this so much for you,
to see you realise your dream.
Something nobody can ever
take away from you.
There won't be any need,
I'll be glad to share it.
It's time.
Charles! Charles!
The brain, Charles.
Doctor, quick.
Below the cortex.
- In the white matter?
- No, lower, in the grey matter.
Look.
A lesion on the hypothalamus.
It's no good, we can't use it.
It won't work.
We need to find another one.
- There's no time.
- We must find the time.
We can't use a lesioned brain.
But the lesion might be insignificant.
And if it isn't?
The hypothalamus controls
the central nervous system.
It could paralyse an organ,
and then what benefit would there be?
To give him life and then leave
him paralysed like a corpse.
- It's a risk we must face.
- What about anger and pleasure?
The two emotions connected
to the lesioned part of the brain.
Two vital emotions.
One of the two in excess
would be disastrous.
- We must find another brain!
- I don't have time.
Every minute shortens
the life of that heart.
I can't throw away twenty years
of work in a few minutes.
- I'm begging you, think!
- Think?
No, it's instinct that changes
the world, not thoughts...
and my instinct is telling me to
transplant this brain immediately!
And I'll do it alone.
- I'm with you.
- Thank you, Charles.
The skylight.
Raise the platform.
We'll wait for the storm
to get stronger, Charles.
Man's will is clone.
He's electrified.
Curses!
Charles, close the skylight.
Close it!
Nothing.
- We must wait.
- His face?
To hell with it, I don't care what
he looks like as long as he lives.
I messed up, Charles.
You were right.
I should have repaired
the lesion on the brain.
It probably wouldn't
have changed anything.
The effects of the lesion would
only have been noticeable...
if the brain had been reactivated.
We'll never know, and not knowing
is more disappointing than failure.
Have a long rest,
then we can start again.
No Charles, it's too late.
It's too late for me.
Perhaps Tanya will take my place.
- Will you help her?
- Of course.
But let's see how you
feel in a couple of months.
- You might change your mind.
- I doubt that very much.
I'm not even sure I want Tanya
to attempt the experiment.
- A moment ago you asked me to help her.
- Yes, a moment ago I wanted you to.
- It was a selfish impulse.
- You mustn't say that.
You see Charles, perhaps there are some
things man should leave to God.
I'd never have thought...
He's alive!
Yes, he's alive.
It's beating.
Stand back, Charles.
Now we'll find out if this is
all just a figment of our imagination.
Get up.
Come on, get UP!
Come down.
Come down!
We've clone it, Charles.
We've clone it!
Go on, Charles.
Call Tanya, I want her
to share this moment with us.
Come forward.
Take three steps.
Stop there.
Lower your arms.
I order you to lower...
Tanya.
He did it.
He's alive!
- He's alive.
- Oh, Charles!
How marvellous!
- Who is that in the hallway?
- Please, just keep calm.
My father!
What happened to my father?
Dad!
Tanya.
What do we do now, Charles?
We must call the police.
N0!
- Not yet.
- We must.
D0 you want to destroy
my father's reputation?
Of course not, but we can't
hide this from the police.
I said no.
- You don't understand.
- Tanya...
Listen to me, what will happen
if he kills again, and again?
No, Tanya.
We must tell Harris.
Yes, tell him.
- But tell him it was a thief.
- What about Morgan's body?
What did you do with the other cadavers?
The acid tank.
It's in the other room.
Let's put Morgan in it.
Please Charles, we must hurry.
I don't know.
What do you hope to gain?
Time.
Time to find a way
to save my father's name.
Charles, didn't you love him?
Of course.
D0 it for him.
And for me, Charles.
Just for me.
Please.
- Is this where you found him?
- Yes, exactly where you are now.
I SEE.
Very interesting.
Animal organs, I presume?
Of course, my father dedicated
himself to animal organ transplants.
Yes, very interesting.
And you saw the thief.
A giant, you said.
He must have been a real giant.
Strong enough to...
- What did he steal?
- Nothing, as far as I know.
- I haven't checked everything.
- My father must have surprised him.
I'd say it was your father
who was surprised.
But why would a thief enter
a laboratory?
Perhaps he didn't know
it was a laboratory.
He must have seen the light on
and came in to look around.
Perhaps.
A very tall man, you said.
- How tall?
- I don't know, I was asleep.
At least a foot taller than you, Captain.
Really? That would
make him around seven foot.
Are you sure, Doctor Marshall?
A bit more, a bit less, I was trying
to get away when I saw him.
You said you saw him with the Baron.
Yes, but all I remember is
that giant crushing the Baron.
I'd left him about an hour earlier.
I was exhausted and I couldn't sleep,
then I heard footsteps outside the door.
It could have been the Baron or Tanya.
No, they came from the stairs
that lead to the laboratory.
The Baron was in the laboratory and
Tanya would never have disturbed him.
S0 it must have been somebody
who was a stranger to the house.
Then you came down just moments
after this thief had killed the Baron?
I tried to stop him but he
threw me to the ground and...
- Nonetheless, you saw him escape.
- Yes.
- Were you injured?
- Stunned.
How lucky!
I won't keep you any longer.
I'm sure it's been quite
an ordeal for you.
- By the way, that young man...
- Thomas?
- Thomas... where was he?
- He doesn't live here.
- He comes early in the morning.
- Very good.
- He didn't believe us.
- Yes, he did.
He was just trying to frighten us.
You're marvellous, Charles.
Thank you.
- And now?
- Now we wait.
It isn't going well today.
Look!
Poor girl, she's dead.
Find a doctor.
Curses!
Who is it?
What do you want?
Nice place you've found, Lynch.
It's the height of fashion.
Reminds me of an asylum.
Yes, you know your stuff.
The taste of a man who truly knows
what is obscene and vulgar...
erotic or simply grotesque.
It's very smart
the way it all blends together.
The way in which
everything seems to match.
There isn't an object out of place,
not a centimetre wasted.
It's quite remarkable.
I'm impressed.
Lynch.
You're a foul individual.
Something wrong?
Are the prisons empty this morning?
Not at all, quite the opposite.
Some of your friends were kind enough
to spend the night with me.
- I don't have any friends.
- Yes, you do.
Simon Burke and Harry Morse.
Not to mention Jim Turner,
and that other one, the hunchback.
- Were they drunk?
- Very.
They made quite a racket in the tavern
near the sawmill, do you know the place?
Yes, but what do four drunks
have to do with me?
The fight was over which
one of them had to pay the bill...
which was quite substantial.
Your friends drink, as you know.
You haven't answered my question.
ReaHy?
I have one for you.
Where did four men like that
find enough money...
to spend the entire night partying?
- Work?
- Perhaps.
But what kind of work?
Simon and Harry can't earn much.
After all, how many hangings do we have?
- Not enough for you.
- You disappoint me.
I don't dish out sentences,
I limit myself to arresting people.
- Were you drinking alone, Lynch?
- No, not alone!
Are you in the mood, Captain?
Two of those men work for you.
I can't see you paying anyone enough
to afford a night on the tiles.
You're right, I wouldn't.
Perhaps they found something else
that undoubtedly pays a lot.
I'm notjoking, Lynch.
Tell me what kind of work
they do for you...
given that you don't concern
yourself with legitimate business.
I know you're very resourceful.
I hear you're a loan-shark now
but your helpers, what...
They're debt collectors.
They collect for me.
Yes, it couldn't be anything else.
I'll leave you to what a man
like you would call...
Exactly what a man like you
would call it.
Lynch, one clay you'll say the
wrong thing at the right moment.
Captain!
- What is it, Peter?
- Sarah Welles and Fred Benson are dead.
John Masters was with Sarah,
he saw the killer.
- He says it was a monster.
- What?
A monster, a huge being,
ugly, with one eye.
Question him, he'll confirm it.
I can't figure out where
this being came from.
You must intervene, I can't control
the crowd, they're very excited.
We need to calm them down,
but also put them on guard...
inviting them to work with us on
this unusual case.
I'll do my best.
Calm down, we're working
on a plan to catch this maniac.
Locked up in your office?
You've got your eyes closed!
We admit we were taken by surprise.
We're going to need your help
before reinforcements arrive.
- He thinks we're lying!
- We'll deal with him once and for all!
If we've got to move, let's do it.
Me first!
- Are you with me?
- Yes!
Go home and don't do anything foolish.
Let us do our work.
We'll call you if we need you.
Don't take matters into your own hands,
it might cost you clearly.
If you see him, tell us, but don't
confront him, you could get killed.
I must warn you, don't wander from
your homes, especially at night.
Now clear out.
Come in.
It's pointless.
You won't find the answer in there.
There is no answer anymore.
I know the answer.
I'm just looking for a way
to put it into practice.
Will you help me?
I don't know.
You'll help me.
I don't know,
I can't commit myself...
until I know what you think
the answer is?
Another creature.
Tanya, it took me and your father
three years to build the first one.
- Less than three weeks for mine.
- Even three hours, it's still too late.
- Then there's been another murder.
- Two!
I didn't want to tell you.
I went into town today.
Everyone's talking about that creature,
they call it the monster.
That's what they call your father's
lifetime's work, a monster!
- And they're right!
- They're not!
My father was a genius.
- His creature exists.
- All it does is kill.
You don't understand,
even without the lesion on the brain...
that creature has the mind of a killer,
it kills for the pleasure of killing.
It must be destroyed.
Harris will destroy it.
How can a man destroy it?
Charles, there's only one solution.
Create another creature.
- You'll create another monster.
- No, an executioner!
Our creature will kill my
father's murderer.
It's impossible, even if you
found the right brain...
Your creature, despite the superhuman
powers the lightning will give it...
will need a body physically
strong enough to handle it.
Where will you find a man like that?
If I find him, will you help me?
That's my offer.
£500 if you get me the right man.
What makes you think that?
My father told me.
It's all in his diary.
All of his business dealings with you.
- I don't want money from you.
- I understand.
I knew it.
Just for one night,
then you'll have your man.
He won't cost you a penny.
It will.
Your price is too high.
I don't care what you think of me,
I don't want your sympathy.
- You disgust me.
- Then spend your money elsewhere.
Captain Harris might find my
father's diary very interesting.
That I sell corpses wouldn't
surprise anyone...
but your father buying them would
certainly raise an eyebrow...
and you wouldn't want that, right?
Think about it.
No one else can help you.
No one.
Besides, I'm not asking much.
One night won't kill you.
Have a nice bath and everything
will be just like before.
I'll kill him.
I'll kill him!
You need a drink, Charles.
I don't understand why you're so upset.
You can't take a man
like Lynch seriously.
I still want to kill him!
How could he have thought...
Thank you, Charles.
I had no idea you were
so interested in my reputation.
I'm sorry, of course.
You're a gentleman.
And you think of me
as someone who's untouchable.
You're wrong.
Really? Have you ever thought
about touching me?
Tanya, please.
Does it upset you that much knowing
a man like Lynch wants me?
No, it's just that it was most
vulgar of him to say it.
You want me, Charles.
It's the only reason you stayed.
- And if it were true?
- Then why not tell me?
Because you were scared.
You've always been scared,
of everything.
Even now you're scared.
We don't need Lynch anymore.
I've found him... Thomas!
- Thomas?
- Yes, Thomas.
Physically he's perfect,
and you know what his body's like.
He's strong, handsome,
he can handle it.
- What does that have to do with...
- Everything, because you love me.
You love me, but you've never
clone anything about it.
Instead of letting your love for me
give you strength...
- Stop it.
- You've become a spineless old man.
You're so weak, all you can do is
undress me with those perverted eyes.
The eyes of an old man incapable of
even thinking that I could love him.
You could...
Could you love me?
Yes.
If you were like Thomas.
Then you love Thomas!
I can't love Thomas,
he doesn't have your mind.
Think about it.
Think of me.
Think about loving me.
I know you want me.
You want to make love to me.
YGS.
Yes! Yes!
You can, Charles.
I'll make it possible.
My brain and my heart,
in Thomas' body.
His heart is as kind as yours.
Thomas with your brain.
There's a man I could love.
N0.
I won't kill Thomas for you.
I'm not a murderer.
- You were ready to kill Lynch.
- That was different.
One's the same as the other.
I'll help you, Charles,
and I'll give you everything.
I'll be your wife, when you want.
- Tell Tanya Lynch is here.
- N0, no, no!
- Go and tell her...
- Go away!
Very well, I'll come back tomorrow.
They're not at home,
or you don't know where they've gone?
You're completely crazy!
G0!
D0 you like it?
- Yes, a lot.
- I've had that ring for a long time.
I never thought I'd
see it shine on your finger.
Good morning, Charles.
Stop thinking about Thomas.
Think about him later.
Come.
Over there.
Lynch, you fooled me.
Daddy, the monster!
Damn you!
Jack!
John Lynch is dead?
Last night, killed by the same man
who murdered his father.
Nothing was stolen there
either, Lady Frankenstein.
Lady Marshall now, Captain.
Congratulations.
This man, did anyone
see him who's still alive?
Yes, the young man who was
with Sarah Welles, John Masters.
My husband told me
everybody thinks it's a monster.
They can think what they like.
John Masters insists it wasn't a man,
but he was too scared to be believed.
- Do you believe him?
- No, I didn't say that.
The Atkins boy watched the murderer
kill his mother but he's in shock...
and I don't know
when I'll be able to talk to him.
Poor boy.
- Thank you for the tea.
- I'll accompany you.
I was wondering why you visited
Lynch at his home at night?
The Baron owed him money.
My wife went to pay him.
- Why didn't you ask him to come here?
- But how, Captain?
- A man like Lynch, here?
- No, of course.
- Then why didn't Doctor Marshall go?
- It my was father's debt, that's why.
- Is there a problem?
- Right.
But I don't understand why your
father had a debt with Lynch.
Captain, I find you impertinent!
I always am.
Thanks again, and excuse me.
One last thing, Mrs.
You don't believe
in monsters, do you?
- Of course not.
- I do.
Have you finished yet?
You're worse than Lynch.
Are you sure
Doctor Marshall will want it?
Of course I'm sure.
Whatever the Baron did with the corpses,
Doctor Marshall was helping him.
I'm sure he's doing what the Baron did
with them, and he'll be most grateful.
To hell with his gratitude.
As long as he pays us well.
This is no life,
I want women and good whiskey!
- I don't work for you.
- Quiet! I hear someone.
Who could it be?
This is how I found them, Captain.
I got here early, like I always do.
I like things tidy.
Every morning...
Yes, thank you, Mr Stone.
That's all for now.
I keep a clean ship Captain,
and quiet as well.
Grave robbers?
It doesn't make sense.
Actually, it's starting to make a lot
of sense, grab those shovels.
Dig here, then dig up all the graves
from the last two months.
What do you hope to find?
Not a damned thing.
Thank you, you can put them down.
No Thomas, I wasn't laughing at you.
- Don't be afraid of me.
- No, lady.
No, I'm not afraid.
Come on, let's put these away.
- There.
- One...
Go.
That's better, isn't it?
Sit down, Thomas.
Sit down.
Haven't you made love before?
Don't you want me?
D0 you want me?
You're handsome.
Tommy! Tommy!
Are you looking for someone?
Yes, I'm looking for...
- I'm looking for my brother.
- Your brother? You must be mistaken.
Tommy.
Thomas Stark.
He isn't here.
Have you tried his house?
I've just come from there.
He hasn't been here for a few clays.
Where could he have gone?
He's never left the county.
Who knows? Perhaps it has something
to do with the death of my father.
- I'm sorry, I didn't know.
- Thomas was very close to my father.
His death must have upset him greatly.
I imagine so.
I'm sorry you came all this way,
but I'm sure Thomas isn't far.
- Are you staying in the village?
- Yes, of course.
Then I'll tell him.
He'll be glad to see you.
Thank you.
Thank you, lady...
- Lady Marshall.
- Sorry if I disturbed you, Lady Marshall.
We're all very close to your brother.
I'm sure you are.
Good clay.
Julia, I've got enough to worry about
with this killer on the loose...
and now with Thomas' disappearance.
- Find Tom.
- I promise.
That Lady Marshall, I don't like her.
I know what those women are like.
She could destroy a man
and then...
- Julia, everything's fine, trust me.
- I'm trying as hard as I can.
Please, Julia.
She seems like a nice person.
She's nothing like Lady Marshall.
She makes me nervous.
Her ancl her father's experiments,
animal transplants...
That's what she said,
and Doctor Marshall didn't deny it.
- Why would he?
- Why did they need cadavers?
What do you do with a cadaver, Peter?
Let's go.
You'll need two pints of my blood
in order to fill this sack.
The blood is pumped from the sack
using these two batteries.
Very good.
With compliments from
Count Alessandro Volta.
Don't be surprised Charles,
I read my father's medical diary.
But I've known about
Volta for a number of years.
Ancl Luigi Galvani ancl his
experiments to produce electricity...
with methods employing electrochemistry.
Very simple but efficient.
The copper pipes carry a
magnetic pulse to the sack...
causing it to expand
and contract like bellows.
Then the blood is pumped from
the sack and comes down this tube...
and enters the brain.
Providing a continuous flow of blood
from the sack to the brain...
and vice versa.
- What about the oxygen for the brain?
- It's liquid.
First, fill the container with this.
Then connect the two tubes to the brain.
Then put the brain in the glass
container and preserve it.
- Can it stay like that indefinitely?
- Indefinitely.
In his diary, my father wrote
that he tried to help Thomas.
What went wrong?
Nothing, it's just that
Galvani's theory...
would have turned Thomas
into a vegetable.
How much current did you give him?
Enough to help him,
but not enough to hurt him.
Tonight, you and I will help Thomas
become a real human being.
And my father...
will live again.
But with the fame he deserved.
Charles.
I love you, Tanya.
Really.
Think of tonight, Charles.
Just tonight.
Zack, you damned fool, I should lock
you up and throw away the key!
- Someone had to do something.
- Yes, but you haven't clone a thing.
Someone could have died,
including you.
But I was right,
that's no human being.
We must have shot it twenty times
but it just kept coming!
Twenty times, Zack?
At least ten, well maybe not ten,
but four or five, yes.
- Four or five, then?
- It's true, Captain.
Men lose blood but that monster,
nothing, it didn't lose a drop!
Very well, Zack.
Go home, but ifl hear that you...
You've got to kill it,
I don't how, but you've got to!
But you must hurry!
You wouldn't happen
to be threatening me?
It isn't a threat, it's a fact.
People talk.
They're saying it's
Baron Frankenstein's fault.
- That thing killed him, don't forget.
- But it didn't kill his daughter.
What does she have to do with it?
You know what people are like,
especially when they're scared.
And right now they're so scared
they're capable of anything.
Something crazy, even.
For them, the name Frankenstein
is synonymous with the Devil.
Under any guise.
Let's go.
What is it?
S0mething's wrong.
It's late, Tanya.
I killed Thomas.
You must make sure the ends
justify the means, for me.
What if it doesn't work?
Charles, I...
Tanya, I'd rather give my life
to you than the hangman.
Is everything ready?
No questions?
No, no questions.
Tanya, remember that I love you.
I'll remember.
Now smile.
It's the last thing I want to see.
Thank you.
Now begin.
I don't like your sudden visits.
I'm trying to find your father's killer,
I don't see why it should upset you.
You're right.
Forgive me.
But I've been by my
husband's side all night.
- Then he's seriously ill.
- It's possible.
He's resting now,
and after breakfast so shall I.
- Is your investigation progressing?
- Not really, but the killer is.
Another two men have been killed,
Jim Turner and Bill Jessop.
They worked for Lynch.
You wouldn't know them, they weren't
the type you'd invite home for tea.
Why did you ask about Thomas earlier?
Only because a clear friend
asked me to say hello to him.
You mean his sister
asked you to look for him.
I thought I was quite clear yesterday.
- She obviously didn't believe me.
- Only she could tell you.
- Do you believe me?
- Why would you lie?
- Women never lie to you?
- Always, Lady Marshall.
Charles!
I can't wait for the storm.
It may not come in time.
I need to generate enough electricity
to reactivate your brain and Thomas' heart.
I can't wait for lightning.
I can create the same
type of energy artificially.
You and my father had
experimented on Thomas.
Only you were afraid you'd kill him
if the current was too strong.
Everything's ready, my clear.
Don't be afraid.
They laughed at my father, Charles.
But they won't laugh at me.
Thank you, dear.
Have faith.
It's working.
Now let's see how much current we need.
Get ready, Charles.
We've almost clone it this time, Charles.
Just a little longer, clear.
A little longer.
You're alive, clear.
You're alive.
- Tanya.
- I'm here.
I'm here.
I'm cold.
Dear!
You don't expect me to believe that?
It's true Julia, I saw it.
You think Tommy has something
to do with this monster?
Not of his own volition,
he may have been coerced into it.
Tommy doesn't shine with intelligence.
Then Lady Marshall's
mixed up in this as well?
You don't like her, do you?
I'm sure she lied to me
when I asked her about Tommy.
Paul, I'm scared, help me.
I'm scared they'll kill him.
- Now don't exaggerate.
- I'm scared I won't see him again.
The monster!
Shoot!
Again!
Let's get out of here!
Follow me, but be careful.
Don't take any unnecessary risks.
When I remove the stitches no one will
notice the difference, I'm sure of it.
Okay, let's see what you can do.
Come on, Thomas.
Get ready with your hands.
When I drop the paper,
try to catch it as soon as it falls.
Look at me.
Are you ready?
YES.
Good, Thomas!
Your reflexes are perfect,
your pulse is normal...
How could I have known the
storm would come in time?
You couldn't have.
There's one more thing.
Try lifting that desk.
- That one?
- G0 on.
Go on Thomas, lift it.
- I'd never have thought I could do it.
- Now you can, Thomas. You're young again.
A handsome, strong,
intelligent young man.
Lady Marshall!
What is it?
It's Captain Harris, he insists on
seeing you, he won't leave.
Tanya, you must see him immediately.
Don't be afraid.
Everything's going to be fine.
G0, hurry!
- I must see Doctor Marshall.
- Impossible, he's very sick.
- I'm not asking your permission!
- This is unlawful entry!
- Yes, you're quite right.
- I'll report you to your superiors.
- Go ahead.
- I will.
- Where's his room?
- Please leave this house!
Not until I've seen your husband.
Sorry, but my illness is very
contagious, don't come too close.
I need to speak to you alone.
Whatever you have to tell me,
I want my wife to hear it.
I came to warn you about the monster
you created with Baron Frankenstein.
I hold you responsible for the deaths
of eight people, including the Baron.
- Can you prove it?
- I'd be here to arrest you if I could.
I know you're responsible.
I want you to stay alive.
Why would someone want
to kill my husband?
Not someone, the monster
he helped create...
which has already killed the four
people responsible for giving it life...
and you, doctor,
are the fifth and last.
You're out of your mind.
How could they...
Supplying your father
and your husband with cadavers.
I don't need to tell you
how they were used.
We have no idea
what you're talking about.
Those vases in the laboratory.
It wouldn't be hard to prove that
they contain human organs.
N0, you never thought that your monster
may not appreciate your miracle.
That's why it killed the Baron
and the other three men.
That's why it will kill you as well.
Why didn't it kill my husband
after it killed my father?
Perhaps your husband wasn't
in the laboratory.
It's the most ridiculous story
I've ever heard.
You have quite an imagination.
It was a thief that killed the Baron.
As for Lynch and those
other two champions of honesty...
anyone would have had sufficient
reason to kill them.
Perhaps it's your incompetence that's
allowing your imagination to run riot.
- I recommend a long rest.
- Excellent.
But please don't forget that
I warned you in time.
Your concern comforts me greatly.
Goodnight, Captain.
Whatever you've clone to Thomas,
there isn't a hiding place that I won't find.
- My best wishes to the doctor.
- Thank you.
- We must leave tonight, Thomas.
- No, Tanya.
Harris and his men will find the monster
and they'll destroy it.
They don't know how.
I do.
All available men, the place has
to be completely surrounded.
Make sure they don't tell anyone.
Hurry!
Let's go!
- D0 you know where to find him?
- He'll find me, tonight.
He'll come here tonight.
Oh, Thomas.
Monster!
Look out, Thomas!
Thomas, wait.
You don't have to kill it because
it doesn't need to kill anymore.
Now we can keep it at bay and show
the world my father hadn't failed.
That he wasn't a lunatic.
Think of us, Thomas.
The fame, the money!
N0, I must kill it!
You're right, kill it.
Why did you change your mind, Tanya?
Why?
Because you only need one of us to live,
then you'll have what you want.
- That's it!
- N0!
- It's the Captain!
- Is he dead?
- No, he's just passed out.
- Let him sleep, we can handle this.
This is unwise.
Be careful, Julia.
You, follow me!
Paul!
- Peter, why did you bring her here?
- Captain, I...
- The monster's inside the house!
- Zack's men are burning everything!
That lunatic!
Julia, wait here.
N0!
Spare me!
You love me!
I belong to you.
Yes, Thomas, kiss me!
Spread out!
Over here!
Everything!
Burn everything!
Who authorised you to do this?
Arrest him!
Take him away!
- Julia!
- Tommy!
- He's here!
- N0, you can't!
My 90d!
THE END
Subtitles © 2018 Nucleus Films Ltd
Translated by Anthony Baggaley.