Flash.
Michel Marnay, the French heart-crusher
sailed incog tonight from Naples
on board the Napoli.
Why?
Because Lois Clarke
and her 20 million smackers
will be at the dock palpitating for him.
And it's good news for us mere men,
because when he arrives
Michel Marnay goes out of circulation.
This time, it's marriage.
Well, here we are, ladies and gentlemen.
And a nice, crisp little tidbit
has just come in.
Oh, by the way, I might mention,
I am speaking from dear old London,
as usual.
Well, it's rumored that Michel Marnay
sails for America tonight
to enter into matrimony, at last,
with one of America's industrial nobility,
a Miss...
a Miss... Lois Clarke.
The rock and gravel heiress...
Stone and sand, you know.
Well, that seems to be all.
Good night.
- Signor Marnay?
- No.
Signor Marnay!
- Signor Marnay?
- No. Is he on board?
Yes.
Signor Marnay!
Signor Marnay! Signor Marnay?
Mr. Marnay,
will you autograph this picture of you?
Please?
Write something we could always remember.
Something sizzling.
Thank you.
It's in French. Isn't it wonderful?
I wonder what it means.
"You are very lovely girls,
but you have very bad manners."
I beg your pardon?
I said I believe you're reading
my radiogram.
Just a moment.
Well... how do I know it's yours?
Can you identify yourself?
Well... I am Michel Marnay.
Oh, don't tell me you're the fella.
Yeah.
Well, this is--
this is pretty personal.
Can you tell me what it says?
Well, it says...
"Remembering a warm, beautiful night,
"a thunderstorm over Lake Como,
"and you."
"And you."
- That's you?
- Yeah.
It was all right, huh?
Was nice?
Thank you.
Do you think it'll ever
take the place of baseball?
What's the matter? Did you lose it again?
Look.
I'm in trouble. Serious trouble.
Well, I could have told you,
playing around Lake Como.
- The poor thing.
- No, no. I must talk to someone.
Well, I'm really not very good
about that sort of thing. I talk a lot.
- I've tried to break myself of the habit--
- You have an honest face.
Oh, you--
I can trust you, can't I?
Yes, I guess so.
Come with me.
But, look,
the captain has an honest face too.
And the purser, I thought he had
a very honest type of face.
Shall we go to your cabin or mine?
Mine.
- Well, maybe mine is closer.
- Mine is here.
Not that I'm prudish.
It's just that my mother told me
never to enter a man's room
in any month ending in R.
Your mother must be
a very beautiful woman.
- What's your name?
- Terry McKay.
Terry McKay. And I'm traveling alone.
That wasn't, by any chance,
what was troubling you, was it?
Yes.
- Oh-- Oh, this is fine.
- I thought you'd like it.
You saved my life, you know.
I was bored to tears.
I haven't seen one attractive girl
on this boat since we left.
Can you imagine? Nine days like that?
This is terrible. That's not for me.
Life should be bright.
It should be beautiful and bubbling,
like pink champagne.
I got scared. I said to myself,
"Don't beautiful women travel anymore?"
Evidently not.
Then I saw you and it was all right.
I was saved. I hope.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
Have you been getting results
with a line like that?
Or would I be surprised?
But if you were surprised,
that would surprise me.
That sounds like a nasty crack.
- I could make a few too if I felt like it.
- I'm sure you could.
- I know I can.
- That's what I said.
I think I will. How's your fiancée?
She's got a cold.
Oh, that's too bad.
- Got it at Lake Como?
- No. No, she wasn't there.
Oh, you mean
the lady of the lake was not...
That was her best friend.
Chummy bunch.
Yeah.
Oh, this boat is going awfully fast.
Only eight and a half days till we get in.
Is there any reason why, from now on,
it shouldn't be pink champagne?
- Don't tell me he's the fellow.
- Mm-hmm.
He's all right, huh?
He's nice?
Where is he now?
Well, he's visiting his parents.
He sends me on a buying trip
every once in a while--
You see, he's my boss too.
You don't think he would approve
of pink champagne, do you?
- Oh, no, I don't...
- No...
Well, I think it's very touching,
you and him.
Very beautiful.
- I like that.
- Oh, I'm glad.
He must be a very fascinating fellow.
Oh, well,
you can just imagine how attractive he is
when I can resist
so charming a person as you.
Yes.
I think I'll go now.
After all, I still have deck tennis
and... keno,
and there is always shuffleboard.
- Don't tell me you're embarrassed.
- Oh, yes. Yes, I am.
So if you don't mind,
I think I'll take my pride for a walk.
- Unless, by chance you care to have--
- Dinner? Oh, I'd love that.
- Oh, that would be very nice.
- Don't you think?
Instead of Mother Goose, you were probably
brought up on the memoirs of Casanova.
Not at all.
But y-you've heard of the little fella,
haven't you?
I imagine you've known quite a few women,
Or maybe "few"
is the wrong word.
And I gather you haven't
very much respect for them.
But you've always been very fair
in your judgment.
I beg pardon, signora.
Would you like me to reserve
this table for you every night?
Why not?
You know... I--
Look, look.
Let's talk about you now.
Oh, no, not tonight.
- Let's talk about me some other night.
- All right.
Signor Marnay.
Another one.
- And your name, please?
- McKay.
Eh, where were we?
Oh, yes. What's the name of that...
strange place you came from?
Kansas.
And from there?
Well, then I went to New York
and got a job singing in a nightclub
from 10:00 to 3:00 in the morning,
and then the manager used to
chase me around his office till 4:00,
and then I went home.
And then one night he came along.
Oh, yes.
Yeah. He said I didn't belong
in a place like that.
He said that...
I didn't say anything.
He said that... I--
- That you should improve yourself.
- Yeah. So I studied hard.
So that someday
you would be a charming and lovely wife.
Yeah, that was the idea, more or--
Is there anything wrong with that?
- Oh, no, no, no.
- Well, that's what I thought.
But nothing happened.
Well, that just about
brings us up to date.
Now my life's an open book.
It's only one page.
That's the only page.
I beg your pardon.
Grazie. Thank you very much.
Oh, that's bad.
- That's a beautiful camera you've got.
- Oh, yes.
- Takes very clear pictures--
- Oh, please, monsieur!
I guess it isn't any good
for either one of us to be seen together.
Right or wrong, you know,
people like to talk.
- Better be goodbye.
- What's the matter?
- Afraid?
- Of you? No.
Well, after all, we're on the same ship.
We still have eight days, you know.
Well, you can take nice,
long walks out in the sunshine.
What shall I do if it rains?
- No. It's no good.
- I see.
- It's particularly no good for you.
- Yes, that's right.
Being seen with you is news and
I don't wanna get my picture in the paper.
So we better spread out.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, get me down from here, will ya?
I got up there and I couldn't get back.
- Can you do that?
- Sure.
- Good. You're quite a fellow.
- Hey.
You must be quite a guy yourself.
Yes. Why?
Well, everybody on the ship's
talking about ya.
No! What do they say about me?
Well, I don't know, on account of
every time they start talking about you,
they make me leave the room,
Is that so?
Oh! Be careful there, sonny.
You'll fall and hurt yourself.
When I was little like you,
I fell and broke my leg.
How is it now?
It's all right.
Then what are you crabbing about?
Well, I-I'm not crabbing.
I just thought that you...
I'm sorry.
- Give me a champagne cocktail, will you?
- Yes, sir.
- Got cigarettes?
- At the cigarette stand, sir.
- Pink champagne?
- Yes.
- Champagne cocktail, please.
- Yes, madam.
Have you any pink champagne?
Yes.
I changed my table to a table for one.
So did I.
It's too bad it had to be like that.
We had...
such a delightful dinner last night.
And...
Parlez-vous igpay atinlay?
- What was that?
- Well...
What is known as fooling the world.
Everybody's watching us.
- This is awful.
- What did you say?
I said this is awful
and I'm going to go.
- Don't you go too.
- I'm just watching you go.
I'll go.
Hello! Going my way?
- Calling on a lady.
- Oh, even in Madeira?
No, you're wrong this time.
My grandmother.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
She lives up on the hill.
Would you like to meet her?
Yes, I'd be very happy to.
Come on, get in.
Oh, what a divine place.
Oh, it's perfect.
- Oh, I wanna meet her.
- Yes?
Just a minute.
I'll see if she's there.
Janou?
She's not there.
Look.
She must be in the chapel.
Hello, Jacko.
Oh, hey. Still around?
What is it about this place?
There's something makes you feel
you ought to whisper.
Such peace.
It's like another world.
My grandmother's world.
Tell me a little more about her.
My grandfather
was in the diplomatic service.
They lived all over the world.
This was his last post.
He died here.
So she stayed on to be near him.
He's buried there near the chapel.
She must be waiting,
I think a little impatiently,
for the day she will join him.
Michel!
Oh, no. No, no.
May I present Miss Terry McKay.
She thought you were the girl
I'm going to marry.
- How do you do?
Oh, pardon.
I was only saying I liked you very much.
Oh. Thank you. I'm glad.
If you'll excuse me,
I'll sit down for a moment.
I'm longer with my prayers these days.
And my knees, well,
they are as old as I am.
- Are you English?
- No, I'm an American.
American?
Do you know, my dear,
I have a special fondness for America.
It was my husband's
first post after we married.
Really?
In fact, we went to Washington
on our honeymoon.
- You have a lovely place here.
- Thank you.
I'd like to stay on forever.
You are too young for that.
It's a good place to sit and remember.
But you still have to
create your memories.
Would you like to go inside the chapel?
May I?
How long has it been for you, Michel?
Oh, let me see.
Since you were an altar boy?
Yes.
Then you'd better go in too.
- It won't hurt you.
- I know.
- I'll prepare tea.
- Good.
Never seen such lovely colors.
- Everything's so vivid.
- Yes.
Even the green seems greener.
Yes, they...
they get a lot of rainfall here.
- Who takes care of this place?
- Hmm? Oh, an old gardener--
- There he is. Well!
- Oh, Michel.
He's got three children
since I have seen him.
Really? Well!
Emile says, "France needs men,"
so he has seven daughters.
Seven?
Oui!
Well, if you'll excuse me, I think
I'm going to see the rest of the family.
Tea will be ready any moment.
- May I help you?
- Thank you, my dear.
- Where are your cups?
- In there.
- I'll carry it.
- Oh, thank you.
I'm sorry. I had to let my maid go.
I have to watch my expenses.
You see, I planned on dying when I was 75.
And here I am, 77.
So, if I am not going to die,
I have to start saving my money.
You like it?
Yes, it's charming.
Who did that?
Michel.
- Michel?
- He painted it for me.
Wh-- Why, it's good!
He's very talented.
Oh, forgive me.
You see,
I wouldn't have any way of knowing.
Unfortunately, he is also very critical.
As a result,
he hasn't done anything since.
What a pity.
Besides, Michel is too busy, mmm...
Living?
Thank you.
Things come too easy to him.
And he's always alone.
By the art, he is not practicing.
The places he hasn't been.
The girl he hasn't met.
I don't mind confessing to you, my dear,
that I've been worried about him.
Why?
That one day
life will present a bill to Michel,
and that he will find it hard to pay.
But when I-I see him with you,
I feel better.
Well, I don't understand.
He's going to be married
and settled down, and...
Can't you just see him
with his slippers and his pipe?
No.
There is many a slip
betwixt the leap and the altar,
and anything could happen on a boat.
Believe me, my dear,
there is nothing wrong with Michel
that a good woman could not make right.
Well, I saw Emile's entire family.
Seven daughters.
I congratulated him
and I had a nice talk with his wife.
How have you two girls been getting along?
You'd be surprised.
- I bet she did all the talking.
- Mm-hmm.
She told me that
when you were a little boy,
if you didn't get your own way,
you used to lie on the floor
and kick and get red in the face.
And what did you say?
Well, I said you didn't do that anymore.
Now if you don't get your own way,
you just get embarrassed.
What have you two been discussing?
Seems a lot has been going on
that I know nothing about.
Well, I'm afraid we must be going.
Michel.
See?
Janou, you must play the piano for us
before we go.
- Oh, no.
- She was a great pianist, you know.
- Come on, come on.
- She's going to play right now.
But, Michel, look at my hands.
That's it.
That's good.
Remember, I was asked to do this.
♪ J'ai tout quitté ♪
♪ Pour l'ingrate Sylvie ♪
♪ Elle me quitte ♪
♪ Et prend ♪
♪ Un autre amant ♪
♪ Plaisir d'amour ♪
♪ Ne dure qu'un moment ♪
♪ Chagrin d'amour ♪
♪ Dure toute ♪
♪ La vie ♪
I don't like boat whistles.
I know. I know.
Here. Better have this around you.
Thank you.
Isn't it beautiful?
- You like it?
- Mmm, I do.
I'll send it to you someday.
This is as far as I can go.
This is the boundary of my small world.
It's a perfect world.
Thank you for letting me trespass.
Bye.
God bless you.
Well, Janou,
I'll come back to see you very soon.
I-I will.
And I shall write very often.
You'll see.
Please do.
Goodbye.
Bye, Janou.
Looks like stormy weather ahead.
We've changed our course today.
I want to thank you for a lovely evening.
I want to thank you
for what was undoubtedly
the loveliest day I've ever known.
You've been very sweet
to my little grandmother.
- I'm going to write to her.
- Oh, that'd be nice.
Well, good night.
Good night.
We're heading into a rough sea, Michel.
You say "A penny for your thoughts",
I'll jump overboard.
I thought you'd gone to bed.
What good would that do? I can't sleep.
Yes, I know.
All I seem to do is turn and toss.
Dreaming?
Wouldn't call that dreaming.
I'm awake.
I'd call it wishing.
My father used to say,
"Wishes are the dreams we dream
when we're awake."
Oh, your father said that?
He drank a lot.
I wrote a song once about wishing.
- It was nice.
- Oh, it was?
Oh, no, no.
I didn't mean-- I mean it was..
You mean it was not bad?
You know, one day I'm going to
learn your language
and be very funny too.
I'm sorry. How does it go?
Oh, I forget.
But it meant if you wish very hard
with your mind,
and if you wish very strong in your heart,
and if you keep on wishing long enough
and strong enough--
- You get what you want for Christmas?
- Yes.
Well...
we get in in the morning.
Will he be waiting?
- Mm-hmm. And she?
- Mm-hmm.
I suppose if we have something
in our minds, we'd better say it now.
Yes.
You know,
I've never worked in all my life.
In all my life, I've never worked.
I've been thinking about that.
- What did you say?
- Mmm? I didn't say anything.
You did too.
You said, "I was very fond
of expensive things.
"Furs and jewels and things."
D-Did I say that?
I guess you and I have been more or less
used to a life of pink champagne.
Maybe it'll be a little difficult to--
Do you like beer?
Yes, I do, but...
Oh, I know. It's bad for the figure.
My father used to say,
"It's a funny thing,
"but the things we like best
are either illegal, immoral or fattening."
I told you he drank like a fish.
I wonder what your father
would think of me.
Never working, not once.
Well, just because you haven't--
Oh, I didn't mean that I couldn't.
I know. Of course not.
But I couldn't find out all at once.
It would take me, oh,
at least six months to find out if...
- If what?
- Well, it's hard to say.
After all, it's unfair to ask you
to take a chance.
But... if I work hard enough
and long enough,
and if wishes came true,
where would you be?
What are you trying to say, Michel?
I'm trying to say that
it would take me six months to find out
if I'm worthy to say what's in my heart.
Oh, that's just about the nicest thing.
I think I'll turn in,
do a little more rolling and tossing and...
I'll think it over
and let you know in the morning.
- Going my way?
- No, I think I'll-- I'll walk a little.
Marriage is a very serious step
for a girl like me.
Yes, I know.
- You like children?
- Oh, yes, I do.
- I was so worried.
- I'm sorry. I didn't even know we were in.
I'm only half dressed.
Look, if everything turns out all right--
for both of us, I mean--
- In six months--
- Yes?
- That's July.
- July, yes.
I've written out these directions.
Read them carefully
so there won't be any mistake.
- "Darling, let's meet..."
- Mm-hmm.
"...July first, five o'clock, 102nd floor,
top of the Empire State Building."
Yes. That's it right there.
It's the tallest building in the world.
- You can't miss that.
- No.
It's the nearest thing to heaven
we have in New York.
Be sure you take the elevator.
Well, until we meet again...
take care of yourself.
Mr. Marnay,
any statement for the press?
Michael.
- So glad to see you.
- Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
- Did you have a nice crossing?
- I had a very nice crossing.
Miss Clarke?
Hold for a still, please.
Yes.
Thank you. One more, please.
Oh... yes.
That's it. That's fine.
One more, Miss Clarke, please.
- Will this do?
- That's fine, Miss Clarke.
- Thank you.
- I'm awfully sorry. I beg your pardon.
If you will excuse me,
I have an appointment.
Oh, Michael, I'm so glad you're back.
No more. No more.
Let me look at you.
Oh, it's wonderful to have you back.
Rough crossing?
Well, you wouldn't exactly call it smooth.
- I beg your pardon, sir.
- Oh, excuse us.
Really, darling,
it's great to have you back.
Well, it's great to be back, Ken.
Your trunk has arrived.
Where's the key?
Don't unpack, Annie.
I'm moving.
- Well, lots of good luck.
- Thanks.
I hope you'll be working here.
The terms are satisfactory,
but as I said before--
I know. It's not up to you,
it's up to the customer.
That's right.
You sing, then we'll talk further.
- And if I can't find you, I'll understand.
- That's right.
♪ Go on and sing, my heart ♪
♪ You know it's spring, my heart ♪
♪ So why not show it? ♪
♪ Pretend you're glad, my heart ♪
♪ Although you're sad, my heart ♪
♪ He mustn't know it ♪
♪ Remember, love is not an easy game ♪
♪ No two hearts ever beat ♪
♪ Quite the same ♪
♪ Go on and dance, my heart ♪
♪ This is romance, my heart ♪
♪ So keep pretending ♪
♪ Do not despair, my heart ♪
♪ We still may share, my heart ♪
♪ That happy ending ♪
♪ If it's to be, we soon shall see ♪
♪ And if it's not to be ♪
♪ No power on Earth ♪
♪ Can make it so ♪
♪ You know it's spring, my heart ♪
♪ Go on and sing, my heart ♪
♪ For if you sing ♪
♪ He'll never ♪
♪ Know ♪
How am I doing, Chief?
That noise is applause, isn't it?
Oh, well, maybe they're applauding
your two-dollar dinner.
I'd like to talk a long contract.
- Six months?
- That's not a long time.
Oh, yes, it is.
♪ Go on and dance, my heart ♪
♪ This is romance, my heart ♪
♪ So keep pretending ♪
♪ Do not despair, my heart ♪
♪ We still may share, my heart ♪
♪ That happy ending ♪
♪ If it's to be, we soon shall see ♪
♪ And if it's not to be ♪
♪ No power on Earth can make it so ♪
♪ You know it's spring, my heart ♪
♪ Go on and sing ♪
♪ Until we ♪
♪ Know ♪
Oh, I brought you something.
You're always so nice to me.
Nice? But you are my nicest boarder.
Well, no matter what you say,
I'm not going to pay you a cent more.
Who wants more money?
I am so happy you are here.
You're always happy. What's the secret?
Oh, I don't know. I don't know.
My place is half empty,
I have rheumatism,
and my husband left me with five children
and they're all ashamed of me.
I don't kn--
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, you shouldn't be sorry,
you should be happy.
There is no boyfriends calling on you
so you don't get married.
And if you don't get married,
your children won't be ashamed of you.
Well, good night. Don't you eat late,
because it's bad for you.
Good night.
I'm not going to worry about anything.
Oh, you know, I joke a lot about marriage,
but it can be a beautiful thing.
You know, you should get married
if you find the right man.
Well, of course I don't know
when you will find him, of course,
but don't you marry a loafer like I did.
It's just as easy to marry a man
with lots of money.
Maybe you don't love him at first,
but you can teach yourself
in six easy lessons.
Just don't you marry a loafer.
I married one. He was a prize-winner.
Yep.
I was hoping you would like one of...
Well, I suppose if I don't
sell my paintings, I'll get a job.
Oh, I wouldn't give up painting.
Why, painting--
I'm not going to give it up.
This is the only thing I know.
But I've got to make money.
A lot of money.
Of course, of course.
Well, in order to make money,
you must eat.
Even the new Marnay gets hungry,
you know.
Michel.
Michel!
I have good news for you.
What?
- I sold one.
- Which one?
The woman.
I got $100 for her.
- What are you so happy about?
- I'm a painter.
So am I, but I ain't happy.
Miss McKay, my dear, my favorite customer.
Welcome home.
- Thank you.
- How well you're looking.
Yes, I know. I didn't get it here.
- Where have you been all these months?
- Out of town.
My dear, we've missed you.
- Well, I've missed you too, Miss...
- Lane.
Miss Lane, I want to get
something so beautiful...
Simple, you understand, but breathtaking.
Oh, of course. Miss Webb,
look who's back.
Oh, Miss McKay. We were just saying,
"Whatever happened to Miss McKay?"
- And here you are.
- Isn't it wonderful?
Miss McKay is here,
and we were just wondering--
Miss McKay is there?
Well, give her anything in the shop,
but hold her till I get there, will ya?
You weren't worried
about her credit, were ya?
Yes.
Yes, that's what we were wondering.
I knew you'd understand, Mr. Bradley.
Thank you so much.
I don't think you could
make a mistake on either one.
Oh... excuse me, please.
Where shall we have this sent?
Well, I don't know at the moment.
I'll have to call back and let you know.
- I think that's right, isn't it?
- No-- no charge?
No, no.
- No?
- No, no. I know, I know.
No. No. No.
Oh, goodbye, Miss McKay!
- Do come back again soon.
- Yes, don't stay away so long, my dear.
- Thank you. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Bye, Miss Lane.
- Terry.
- Ken, what are you doing here?
How on Earth did you know I was here?
Oh. Oh, I see.
- What time is it, Ken? I'm late.
- Five minutes to 5:00.
- It's good to see you, Ken.
- It's wonderful to see you again.
I've got so much to talk to you about.
Can't we go someplace?
- I'm in a hurry.
- But I've got so much to say.
Well, call me up sometime.
No, you can't do that either
when I'm going to to be marri--
- Then you are going to--
- Yes, Ken, and I'm late.
- What time did you say it was?
- Four minutes of 5:00.
Looks like I came all the way down here
just to tell you what time it was.
Yes.
- Goodbye, Ken.
- Goodbye.
- Good luck.
- Thanks, Ken.
You can imagine how excited I am.
I thought 34th Street was that way
and it's down here.
I'll pay you more if I get out here.
I'm in a hurry.
There you are.
- What's the rush?
- I'm going to be married.
And I'd like you to be the first
to congratulate me.
Thank you so much.
- Going down?
- No.
What time have you got?
- Ten after 5:00.
- Okay.
Going down?
Yeah.
Doctor.
What do you think?
Her X-rays aren't very encouraging.
It's hard to say
if she'll ever walk again.
We can tell better in about six months.
Are you the fellow she was yelling about
under the anesthetic?
No, no. That's--
That's another chap.
She was on her way to marry him.
Has he been notified?
No. She--
She doesn't want that.
Because until she knows what you say
you won't know for six months,
she'd rather he didn't know.
That's being sensible. Nice girl.
I think so.
Excuse me.
Well, we weren't sure whether or not
we'd have you with us today.
Father, this is the man I....
- He and I--
- Yes. He explained.
Then you know I was on my way
to be married.
While I was on my way to be a good girl,
I got hit right in the intersection
of 34th and 5th.
Wasn't anybody's fault but my own.
I had an appointment way up.
I didn't wanna keep him waiting.
Oh, it could have been beautiful.
Marriage, I mean. Children.
Forgive me, Father. I'm a little weak.
I don't get a lot of exercise.
Janou?
Monsieur Michel,
she gave me this to send to you.
I was going to mail it today.
She said it was for the young lady
that was here with you.
♪ J'ai tout quitté ♪
♪ Pour l'ingrate Sylvie ♪
♪ Elle me quitte ♪
♪ Et prend un autre amant ♪
♪ Plaisir d'amour ♪
♪ Ne dure qu'un moment ♪
♪ Chagrin d'amour... ♪
Okay.
No, you can't go that way!
Hello, Miss McKay.
Oh, hello.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm all right. How are you?
- Fine.
- How are you, Patty Jane?
Fine.
- She's got on a red flannel pettiskirt.
- No.
- Oh.
- Well, it's warmer.
Oh, I bet it is.
Been practicing your song?
Know your parts today?
- Mm-hmm.
- Sure.
I knew mine yesterday.
- Is that so?
- Hey, don't.
Oh, come on, come on.
Come on, let's try it.
I've been practicing too.
Wait'll you hear me.
One, two.
♪ Wishing will make it so ♪
♪ Just keep on wishing ♪
♪ And care will go ♪
♪ Dreamers tell us dreams come true
It's no mistake ♪
♪ And wishes are the dreams we dream
When we 're awake ♪
♪ The curtain of night will part ♪
♪ If you are certain within your heart ♪
♪ So if you wish long enough
Wish strong enough ♪
♪ You will come to know ♪
♪ Wishing will make it so ♪
Come on!
Sing it again! Sing it again!
Sure, we'll sing it again.
One, two.
♪ Wishing will make it so ♪
♪ Just keep on wishing ♪
♪ And care will go ♪
♪ Dreamers tell us... ♪
- How long has this been going on?
- Only a few days.
- I hope you're not angry.
- Oh, no, no.
But when you have as many youngsters
on your hands as I have,
you have a problem.
Oh, I don't know. I like them.
I do too, but they don't like me.
They call me Picklepuss.
At heart, they're just little savages.
But music, you know, has the charms
to sooth the savage breast.
And if it has such an influence,
and if you can do so much
in a few days, I'm thinking...
I wonder if you're thinking
the same thing I am.
Music has charms, and I like children,
and children like me, and...
I'll be getting out of here pretty soon.
And when I do,
I'll be needing a job badly.
It will be only an experiment,
you understand.
- Yes, I know.
- We can't pay high.
Oh, I know, I know.
Just so you'll pay me enough
that I don't go around
calling you Picklepuss.
I'd like to give them a surprise.
So if you don't say anything,
I won't say anything.
I won't say a word.
We won't tell anybody!
We'll keep your secret!
I must say, you've become
a better painter, my friend.
Maybe you've become a better critic.
Six months of hard work.
Well, I'm glad you haven't
wasted your time, my friend.
I've sold everything but this.
I told them to take it out of the window
since you telephoned to me.
- This is the best, I think.
- Yes.
I'm not exactly ashamed of it myself.
You don't want to sell it, eh?
No, no, I don't want to sell it.
I wouldn't mind getting rid of it,
but... somehow I don't want to--
to take money for it.
I thought maybe you were keeping it
because... you were--
you were nursing a broken heart.
Oh, no. No.
Broken heart is not for me.
Life is what you make it, Colbert.
From now on,
I'm taking my fun where I find it.
- Oh.
- Well, I'll be seeing you soon again.
- Mm-hmm.
- Goodbye.
- Merry Christmas, Colbert.
- Merry Christmas to you, my friend.
Michael!
I heard you were in town.
I've had a terrible time running you down.
Ah, you've been gone a long time, mon ami,
and I've been thinking of you
morning, noon and night
and in-between times.
What?
I know you've been busy, but you could
make the theater tonight, couldn't you?
Well, I'll leave a ticket at your hotel.
Where shall we go from here?
Why, Michael...
That's up to you.
After all, this is your evening.
I don't know where to go anymore.
I just came back, you know.
Hello.
- Let me tell him. I'll go get him.
- No. No. No.
It's tough.
The first time you're able to get out
and you have to meet him.
All I could say was, "Hello."
Well, the show's over.
The boy got the girl.
Shall we go?
Seems terrible taking you home
with everybody going out.
I'm going to ask you once more.
Why don't you let me help you?
And I'm going to tell you once more.
If I let you finance my getting well,
he wouldn't like it.
And if he wouldn't like it, I wouldn't.
And if you did get me well
and I went to him, you wouldn't like it.
Well, then certainly he ought to know.
No, because if he found out,
he'd want to do something about it.
And then if I didn't get well,
he wouldn't like it and I wouldn't like it
and you wouldn't like it
and it would be awful.
No, unless I can walk to him one day--
and when I say "walk,"
I mean "run" — he'll never know.
But I've got my job now
and I'm on a budget
and if everything works out all right
and I'm a good little girl,
maybe I'll get what I want next Christmas.
Well, thank you, Lois.
Good night.
Sure you don't want to come with us?
The evening is so young and everything.
No, I think I'll turn in.
Some other time.
Merry Christmas, everybody.
Taking you to the theater
wasn't a very good idea, was it, Michael?
No.
Merry Christmas, Lois.
- Merry Christmas, Michael.
- Thank you.
What's the matter, buddy?
Feeling sorry for yourself?
Yeah.
You don't know what troubles are.
Look at me.
I live on 186th Street
and they won't let me on the subway.
Oh, excuse me, ladies.
- Oh, good morning.
- Good morning.
- She's not feeling very well.
- Oh, that's too bad.
- But she wants to see you. Go on in.
- Thank you.
- Merry Christmas.
- Oh, thanks!
- Well, good morning.
- Good morning, Miss McKay.
Hello. Hello.
I have bad news for you.
Doctor says I can't go.
Look, Doctor, I can be back
in a couple of hours.
This is a Christmas benefit.
It's their first public appearance.
This is my team.
She's our coach, Doc.
Doctor.
If it's gonna hurt her,
you wouldn't want her to go, would ya?
No.
You really don't need the piano.
Come on.
Go through it once without me.
The only place you might get stuck
is right at the beginning.
And Aloysius can sing an A in his sleep.
Can't ya, Al?
- Sure.
- Come on. Let's hear it.
See? Now ready. One, two.
♪ Wishing will make... ♪
Where's Patty Jane?
She's got a sore throat
and she won't be able to go on the stage.
Aw. Come here, darling.
Oh, a pretty new dress too.
- Hello, Miss McKay.
- Aw.
You really wanna go on the stage?
Then I tell you what you do.
You go right along with the rest of them
and you pretend to sing.
You know, make-believe.
Like this.
They'll never know
the difference.
Thank you, Miss McKay.
You're welcome.
Now, come on, pitch pipe. Give.
One, two-- Now, not too loud.
There's a baby upstairs.
One, two.
♪ Wishing ♪
♪ Will make it so ♪
♪ Just keep on wishing ♪
♪ And care will go ♪
♪ Dreamers tell us dreams come true ♪
♪ It's no mistake ♪
♪ And wishes are the dreams we dream ♪
♪ When we 're awake ♪
♪ The curtain of night ♪
♪ Will part ♪
♪ If you are certain ♪
♪ Within your heart ♪
♪ So if you wish long enough ♪
♪ Wish strong enough ♪
♪ You will come ♪
♪ To know ♪
♪ Wishing ♪
♪ Will make it ♪
♪ So ♪
Well, that's swell. That's keen.
You see? You don't need me.
Now go on. Go out here and fight
for good ol' Washington Heights.
Merry Christmas!
Goodbye. Goodbye. Good luck. Goodbye.
- Merry Christmas to you, Miss McKay.
- Thank you.
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas, Patty.
Well, this isn't going to be much
of a Christmas for you, is it?
No, I guess not.
Oh, wait.
There.
Thank you.
Are you comfortable?
Yes, I'm all right.
If you want anything, you just call.
I will.
Michel.
Hello.
How are you, Terry?
Good to see you.
Yes. It's good to see you too.
Feeling all right?
Oh, yes, I'm fine. I'm just resting.
It's been a long time.
Yes. Yes, that's right.
- Good to see you.
- Yes, you said that.
- May I?
- Oh, yes, yes. Sit down.
Thank you.
I will only be a minute.
You sure you don't mind that...
I bet you're wondering how I got here.
I was looking in the telephone book
for a man named McBride
when I saw the name of Terry McKay.
So I said to myself,
"Could that be Terry McKay, my old friend?"
And it was.
Yes.
Then I said to myself,
"I haven't been very nice to Miss McKay.
"After all, I had an appointment
with her one day at...
"And... I didn't keep it."
That wasn't a very nice way
to treat an old friend, was it?
No.
So I said to myself, "I must apologize."
And here I am.
- Well, that's sweet of you.
- Yes, I think so.
I often wondered about you, how you were.
Oh, you did? Really?
Well, I often wondered about you too.
So, you didn't get angry
because I wasn't there?
Oh, well, what do you think?
Well, you must have been at first.
- Well, yes, I-I was.
- Yeah, that's what I thought.
At first I was furious.
I said,
"He can't do a thing like this to me.
"Who does he think he is?"
And how long did you--
I mean, did you wait long?
Well, let's see,
I-I waited until about...
Midnight?
And then what did you do?
Oh, well, then I was really mad.
You can just imagine up there.
In a thunderstorm.
Yes.
And then what did you say to yourself?
Well, then I said,
"Why don't you go home and get tight?"
- You didn't do that.
- Didn't I?
Maybe you took a little one
every hour for about a month.
- Well, can you blame me?
- I should say not.
The least I could have done
was to send you a note.
Well, maybe when you thought about it,
you didn't know a way to reach me.
But you swore that
if you ever saw me again, you'd ask.
You didn't?
No.
No, I remembered we said
i-if we could make it, we'd be there.
And if one of us didn't show up,
there must have been a darn good reason.
Like what, for instance?
And the other one shouldn't ask questions.
Asking questions is--
Life must be bright.
We must keep it beautiful
and bubbling like pink champagne.
So there'll be no questions asked, I hope.
Cigarette?
Thank you.
Think of me walking all the way up here,
ten blocks to...
And instead, I promise not even
to ask you why you didn't show up.
You knew I was planning to.
- Doesn't seem fair somehow.
- I know.
I don't know what it is,
but when I'm with you, I--
Well...
Well, anyway...
No wedding ring?
No.
Well, I thought when I saw you at the...
At the theater last night?
No, he was-- No.
I didn't mean to offend you.
How's everything with you, Michel?
Oh, so you can ask questions.
Yeah.
Well, I thought everything was fine
until I saw you last night.
Then I knew there must be something
between us.
Even if only a notion.
So I bought myself a ticket.
Sailing?
Yes. Tonight.
Yep.
Well...
You're happy, aren't you?
Mm-hmm.
And you?
Well, I don't know.
I'm worried about the future,
what people will think of me.
They'll say,
"There he goes. The mad painter.
"There must be something
the matter with him.
"He doesn't like women."
You mean he won't even speak to them?
Oh, yes, yes, he sails the seven seas,
and to every woman he meets, he says,
"Where will you be in six months?"
- And they're there?
- Everywhere.
Eiffel Tower, Pyramids. Everywhere.
Waiting.
But he didn't? Where is he?
- You want to change the subject, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Well, six months ago,
who would have thought
we'd spend Christmas together?
- By the way, I have a present for you.
- A present?
Oh, well, I wish I had something for you.
Well, you didn't know I was going to...
Anyway, it's not really
a Christmas present.
So that's why my letters came back.
She wanted you to have it.
Remember?
Yes, I remember.
I would have sent it to you,
only I didn't know your address
until today, so...
Well, goodbye, Terry.
Goodbye, Michel.
Well...
You know, I painted you like that.
With the shawl. I wish you'd seen it.
Colbert says-- He's my dealer.
He says it's the best thing I've done.
I didn't think I would ever part with it,
but there was no reason
for keeping it anymore.
And then he told me about a girl
who came into his shop.
He told me she liked it very much.
I suppose she saw in it,
well, what I hoped you'd see.
So I told him to give it to her
because he said she was poor,
and not only that, he told me that she...
He told-- He said--
Yes?
Anyway, I-I told him to give it to her.
Yes, she couldn't afford it,
and it was Christmas season,
and you know me — bighearted Michel.
What time does your boat sail?
Boat?
Why didn't you tell me, Terry?
Darling.
If anything had to happen to one of us,
why did it have to be you?
Oh, don't look at me like that.
It wasn't anybody's fault but my own.
I was looking... up at the 102nd floor.
It was the nearest thing to heaven.
You see, you were there.
Don't worry.
It doesn't have to be a miracle.
If you can paint, I can walk.
- Anything can happen, don't you think?
- Yes, I think so.