GWAN DUNG, LAM FAI-WONG,
TONY LEUNG, CHIANG CHENG,
WAN FAT, FONG PING, GI GI
LEE CHUN-WA, WONG WING,
SHUM LO, WANG HAN-CHEN,
BENZ KONG, WONG MEI-MEI, KONG YUK-LAN
- What's your name?
- Wai Chung.
- How old are you?
- Twenty years old.
- What do you do?
- Jobless.
That's 'unemployed'.
- Where are you from?
- Canton, Toishan.
Ruthless enough!
Came all the way to the north
to kill someone?
That's nothing, just killed one.
I broke the law,
but I've got a chivalrous heart!
Sir, have you heard of
Wong Fei-Hung from Canton?
I've heard that he is a master
of Hung Fist.
He's my auntie's cousin's cousin.
So I'm a bit chivalrous like him.
When I see something I don't like,
I'LL beat them up!
Sir, I just said Wong Fei-Hung—
Take him in. The last one.
Sir, how long do I stay here?
The above sentenced you
to three years and eight months.
So long!
Hey! The last one.
- You've got to be kidding.
- Hey!
This kid's so bold to walk into that one.
Yeah. The old man
is really going to mess him up.
Yeah.
Damn old man.
You've got skill!
Charge!
What the hell's that?
That's really something!
This kid's got guts.
I ain't done!
Hey, you still wanna mess with him?
What if I do? Damn old man.
Don't be so loud, be careful.
Hey, I'm telling you,
this old guy is a lunatic.
He's already been sentenced to death.
Whoever lives here that provokes him
will be unlucky.
Why should I be afraid of him?
You don't know who you're dealing with.
It's because I couldn't stand
wicked folks bullying others.
I beat him to death with two punches,
so I'm in this prison.
Kid, aren't you afraid to die?
Afraid, my arse!
Fine. If you have the guts,
just go over and sit on those stools.
All over there.
He brought those stools in himself?
He didn't exactly bring it in.
But none of us guys
has ever dared to sit on those stools.
You're all unworthy.
Right, watch how 'uncle' does it.
Old man, no one here
dares to sit on this stool.
Uncle will, as you can see!
See! Both hands are steady!
Blow me, old man!
There is something else!
You broke my arse in half!
Charge!
What? Think I can't sit firmly? Watch!
Well?
So comfortable!
What's great about this? I can do it too!
Can't sit down?
Old man...! Have mercy on me!
Old man, I give up!
Mr Ma, what is it?
I'm letting you know
that I'm going to the execution ground
tomorrow morning.
You're really going there?
Don't be concerned, it was inevitable.
- I want to give you something now.
- What is it?
Here.
- This is—
- This piece of wood is only a half.
After you get out of prison,
you must do everything possible
to find the other half.
The other half?
Yes. Put the two pieces together
and you will understand the mystery.
I like your stubborn
and brave personality.
That's why I've no worries
about giving you this thing.
Young man, you must remember my words
and do this.
Can you find treasures in prison?
Hey! Slacking off?
When have I been slacking?
I saw you sit and look at a bit of wood!
Still denying it?
Hey! Don't hit me!
Bring out the bit of wood on you,
bring it out!
- Why?
- Bring it out!
- Don't take it! Damn it!
- Hey...!
Won't bring it out?
I won't!
Damn you!
- Damn you!
- Drop dead!
Damn you!
Damn you...!
Hey! Stop that...!
Stop! I'll shoot!
Hey! Go! Go quickly! Ignore him, go!
Come on, this way!
- Hey, have you managed it?
- No, how about you?
Of course not!
- Then let's keep moving.
- All right.
Hey...!
- Hey, why drag me into the water?
- You dragged me in!
- I'm going this way!
- I'm going that way!
So which way shall we go?
- I say go east.
- Then I say go west.
The west has a small path.
Those chasing us will know
that we'll take that one.
Then I'm sorry.
I've only ever taken the small paths
in my life, never the main ones.
All right, then let's go west.
Hey, you said to go west,
why won't you move?
Sorry, I've changed my mind now.
What?
I want to go back, to the east.
- Fine.
- Hey, don't keep following me.
- What about this thing?
- There's a way.
- What's that?
- Hey, watch out!
Hey, what are you doing?
Breaking that iron chain.
Hey, careful!
- Are you dead?
- My arse!
- Hey, think I'm a monkey?
- I want to turn you into a hairy crab!
Don't you look like a tied-up crab?
- Look like your daddy!
- So, I'm your bitch?
Trying to kill me? It hurts!
Come on!
Buddy, this is for real.
It's your own fault!
- So what should we do now?
- What do you mean?
- Think of a way to get rid of the chain!
- All right.
Right, let's go find a place now
and break this first.
Coach, is the old man
you're looking for named Ma?
Yes.
- Is he blind in one eye?
- Correct.
Coach, you're late.
He was shot the day before yesterday.
I don't know what business
Coach has with him?
The upper commander ordered us
to do our best for Coach.
Did he leave anything when he was dying?
- Leave something?
- Think hard.
Yes, Coach.
Is it the half piece of wood?
That's right,
this is what I'm looking for.
Then I know.
He gave it to a young prisoner.
Where is this prisoner now?
What a coincidence. He escaped yesterday.
That's right.
A new prisoner escaped with him.
Yes, there were still chains
on their feet at the time.
Okay. We'll pursue them separately.
Hey, this situation could use his help!
Aren't you scared of him reporting us?
Think of a way! Go!
- Hey, can you help us break a chain open?
- Money talks.
- What's the charge?
- Hammering a horseshoe is 15 coins.
Hammering a donkey's chain is 12 coins.
Okay, whatever price. Just break it.
Is it a horseshoe or a donkey chain?
So you dudes are the escaped prisoners.
It's okay to be a horseshoe,
and it's okay to be a donkey chain.
Just name your price.
Don't trouble me.
I, Dai Ngau-Bing, am a good
and law-abiding, first-class citizen.
- I don't do anything sketchy.
- Is this sketchy?
I let you go,
and the government will arrest me again.
Who are you kidding?
Hey, I'm giving you business now.
I refuse.
Hey! You see us suffering
but won't save us, what do you want?
Are you leaving?
You won't help us get this chain off,
we won't go.
You won't go?
Don't jump into the well!
Break our chain first!
Nose...!
- Chest...
- Nose...!
Foot!
On your knees!
Still not free!
Thanks!
Still not!
Strike.
Look!
Not been hit yet.
You held it for me!
I won't, then.
Catch!
- What is that?
- You know!
There! You almost got it!
That was a close one!
Not afraid of the heat?
This way!
My hand's here!
This is the real deal!
Hey!
Catch!
- Done!
- Go!
Don't run!
Go!
NGAU'S BLACKSMITH
Have you seen two fugitives
walking by here?
You've come now to catch them;
it's too late.
Did you see them?
Not only did I see them,
they messed up things here!
Look! See how I am now.
They also demolished my stall,
and ran off like horses!
- So where are they going now?
- How do I know?
Did you see where they went?
That way.
We'll go west.
Great...
Great!
- Hey buddy, we'll have a fight now!
- What do you mean?
You helped me break the chain
and I also broke yours.
So you don't owe me,
and I don't owe you either.
- Yeah.
- Then let's split up.
So which way are you going?
Anywhere besides your way. Goodbye!
Also, don't follow me.
I'm just going to ignore you.
Very impressive.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you...
Tips, please.
- Job done!
- Tips, please.
Thanks.
- Thanks, sir.
- Thank you...! Thanks, everyone.
- Thank you.
- Hold on!
What advice do you have, sir?
You think you can make a name for yourself
with a few lousy tricks?
Don't embarrass yourself.
We're a poor family
trying to make a living.
Please forgive us.
You mix in this place
without giving me a piece of the action?
You're in trouble!
Just leave your money
and get the hell out of here!
Well?
Hey, don't force a tiger
to jump off the wall.
Dare to fight me? Beat him!
Damn punk, go to hell!
Go to hell!
Hold it! I'm coming.
Master!
It's not about your small, lousy stall.
I'd do the same to the big restaurant.
You watch out!
- Get lost!
- Go away!
Master, you okay?
Damn, even the monkey ran away.
Pops, are you hurt badly?
I don't care, but—
This villain—
Don't be upset,
I'll vent your anger for you.
- Leave everything to me.
- What?
- You—
- That's right.
I despise such wicked folk the most
in my life.
I just escaped from prison.
That was because I killed a bad guy.
Brother, how can I trouble you?
- All those bad guys ran away.
- Don't worry, they can't run far.
- Call your boss out, quick!
- What for?
- None of your business!
- Call him quick. Didn't you hear?
Get your boss out now!
What do you want to eat?
I'll get it for you. Why call the boss?
- You— Why are you hitting people?
- So what if we're hitting?
- Don't let him hit you.
- What's the matter...?
Out of the way!
Sorry. Excuse us.
Please have some respect.
Please sit down...
Sit down...
It's okay, everyone. Please have some tea.
Young Master Ma,
if something's up, let's talk it through.
If you won't pay
this month's protection fee,
I'LL destroy your tea house.
- Here, pops, please come over.
- All right...
Sit down.
- Three? What would you like?
- A catty of dry wine.
- What else?
- Five-spice beef, drunken chicken,
poached meat, stir-fried
triple delicacies, 'a double crunch'.
Also ten steamed buns, right away.
Yes.
Right, I'LL have a full meal
with you today.
Brother, you've ordered so many dishes—
Don't you worry.
You don't need to pay, nor do I.
So who'll pay?
- Someone'll certainly pay.
- All right.
Young Master Ma, take your time.
I'LL give the money in a while.
Now, if you still don't give me ten taels
after we've eaten,
- don't blame me for being uncivil.
- Of course...
Cheers.
Thanks.
- Who are you?
- Your mum's bed buddy!
What?
Have another cup.
- Boss... no need to pay!
- What is it?
Look, some kid's beating that bastard up!
- What do you want?
- Take care of your little cock!
Easy!
That one!
Pops, take your time eating.
So you're helping them?
Your mum wants to marry;
the man's getting in there early!
This kid fights so brilliantly!
You'll save money this time, boss!
Yes, but my tea house
is about to be demolished!
Sorry...! It wasn't me!
Another noodle bowl of mine smashed!
Good hit!
Pops, drink up...! Come on...!
Flying saucer!
Catch!
Hey, wanna castrate me?
With a son like you,
you should've been aborted ages ago.
My tea leaves!
There goes another one!
We're on the same side...!
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
So many more things broken!
Hey...!
Even the waiter's been knocked dizzy!
I'm not dizzy!
Here!
- My wine!
- Take it back!
Pops, take it all!
You wanna rob me?
Not robbery,
it's so you accumulate secret virtue.
My Cock!
- Master, I think he's great!
- Bravo!
Hey, catch!
Bravo...!
Guest, your kung fu is superb!
Helped me knock him down!
That's nothing!
Here! My reward to you!
My shop!
Sure! All right, I'LL give you half
to renovate this shop. Fair?
Fair...
Thanks.
Follow him.
Pal, do you want money?
At most, we'll all share it.
Thanks, we're not asking for money.
Are you after my life?
No, not your life.
Then... what do you want?
To search your body.
What? No way.
Split and pursue!
- Why are you searching me?
- Let me ask you,
did the old man give you something?
So what?
- Give it quick!
- No way!
It's you?
Get them!
- What is your relationship?
- Relatives.
- What relatives?
- My bitch.
Your bitch?
Block fast!
- You handle these three pushovers!
- Hey, wait—
After him!
Smart arse, you abandoned me...
I really didn't accumulate virtue
in my last life, always running into you.
Hey, don't be so ungrateful.
I just saved you.
Really?
But you pass the toilet paper
when someone is peeing.
- A useless gesture!
- What?
To be honest,
even if you hadn't arrived just then,
I would've knocked them down!
- You...!
- Don't you agree?
Smart arse,
you think you can beat the world
with that one-and-a-half strokes?
Hang on! This young master
has his own magic weapon.
I have a bright future.
What's this special thing?
Can't tell you. I'll leave you itching.
Right. We'll split.
I warn you again,
stop stalking me like a ghost
all the time.
- Pops, where can I find an inn?
- Behind me.
'The wok steam smell permeates the air.'
'The roar of the cannons
inspires fear in all directions.'
- Come in...!
- Hey! What are you doing?
Don't be shy, young master.
Time for a midnight snack.
I'm full.
- Come on in!
- Hey...!
There!
This is true steaming!
- Come this way.
- What are you doing? Let go!
Come on, come this way.
What the hell?
Let gm!
- She's trying to steal him from me.
- He's mine!
Stop fighting...!
Let me take care of him.
- Young master, please come in.
- What?
Come in.
I said no.
I'm looking for an inn to rest.
Perfect! This is even better
than an inn for resting!
Young master, you're such a handsome boy!
Like a real gentleman!
Let me find you a true beauty!
- What do you mean?
- A pretty, young kung fu girl for you!
- Kung fu?
- First-class, but a bit more expensive.
- How much does it cost?
- Three taels.
- You gotta be kidding me!
- A trifle! Come on!
Come in.
Sweetie, a young man has come here.
Right, this girl is our royal best!
Not bad, right?
Look at you,
you feel dizzy when you look at her!
How will you handle it later?
Sweetie, you must take good care of him.
Please pay UP-
That quickly?
Here.
This is one tael,
two are missing.
How are you worth three, sweetheart?
You agreed on the price
before you came in.
Yes, but the old witch said
you're excellent in kung fu.
In fact, it's far from it!
I don't know how my kung fu is.
But people who don't give enough money
never get out of my bed.
God damn girl, stop bluffing.
Hold it.
Hey, don't make me angry,
I'll slap you a couple of times.
- Where will you slap me?
- You bitch!
- I said you'll never get out of bed.
- Make me show you my skill?
Have a taste of this.
As I said: no pay, no leaving the bed.
The old witch said your kung fu was great.
- So, she was just referring to this?
- How kind.
Bloody bitch.
- I've never fought in bed.
- I'll give you a taste.
See what tricks you have!
Have you tried this trick?
- Is it 'Buddha Sitting on the Lotus'?
- So you have tried it?
- Still missing two taels, will you pay?
- I won't!
Can't get out of bed yet. Come back!
- Do you still want it again?
- Go to hell!
Still wanna escape?
You resemble a steamed rice dumpling!
You look like a rice dumpling now!
Incoming!
You bastard!
Trying to freeload?
The kung fu chick really took care of you!
Still not enough!
Hey, my tables and chairs are all broken!
You better pay!
- Pay what? I'm out of money.
- What's that?
How dare you come to a brothel
with no money!
Then you better frickin' make up for it.
Stand up straight, everyone!
Hurry up! Here!
So what is this?
To get out of the door,
you must go via these crotches.
- How can I live with that?
- Who told you not to bring enough money?
Then I—
Wait and see!
- It'll be a good show this time!
- Yeah!
Won't you crawl?
If not, I'll ask them to kick your arse.
You bastard, let me tell you.
All my girls know two sets of kung fu!
You scared now?
So... I have no choice.
'The tiger falls to Ping yang.'
I'LL do it.
Come on.
- Are you for real?
- That's right...!
Can't I crawl like this?
- That won't do!
- How about it?
Crawl like a dog!
I don't believe in these superstitions.
I follow no forbidden rules.
Serves you right!
Damned fat cow, wanna kill me?
Let me tell you,
business has been bad lately.
I'll let you have a taste of my bad luck!
Hey, my back!
- It hurts!
- Transfer it to you...!
Go now, son!
Go away, quickly!
- Fucking bitches!
- Get out! Get out now!
- Never seen anyone like him before.
- Yeah!
Fucking bitches!
Damn! I'm in deep shit.
Hey pal, you're blocking my way.
Unless you take out
the piece of wood on you.
What? Bring it out for you?
- If not, don't think you can leave town.
- Fight if you've the guts!
More fighting? No way!
I had my kicks in there. I'm all swollen!
Then my men won't have to work too hard.
- My arse!
- Smart arse, soft feet, yeah?
Soft feet? I'll be looking
for your sister in a while!
Hey, watch out!
Got it!
Pat the pig's head!
Stewed trotters!
Let me handle it.
Your Nine-Pass Flower Stick's
pretty powerful.
You deserved that!
Who told you to constantly pester me?
You nobodies dare to oppose me?
Buy your coffins first!
I have no beef with you!
You took that piece of wood,
so that makes you my enemy.
Countless people have died under my stick,
but I don't want you to die here today.
I'LL beat you up like a dog now.
After him!
They couldn't have gone far. Split up!
Right!
Talk quick! Why do you always follow him
in want of that piece of wood?
- I can't say.
- Why not?
Why are you always following me?
Talk...
- If you don't talk, I'LL tear you apart!
- I'LL gouge your eyes out!
I'LL talk. 25 years ago, Black Tiger clan
and Tongbei school were rivals.
In fighting for their reputations,
Tung Gam-Hong of the Black Tiger gang
and Ma Siu-Tin of the Tongbei school
both met on the Changbai Mountain edge,
in a fight to the death.
Our master of the Black Tiger gang
killed that of the Tongbei school.
The master of the Tongbei school
was blinded in one eye by him.
The only son of the Gang — Tung Hak-Fung —
wants to avenge his father.
All these years,
he's been practising and getting ready.
I'm not from Tongbei.
Why drag me into this?
Our big brother was looking
for Old Man Ma because he had a rare book.
Old Man Ma died in the prison.
- But he gave it to you.
- Hence you're on this pursuit to kill me!
I'LL catch you one day
and get the half piece of wood.
Wait! Don't do anything to him.
Stand up! Get lost!
- What? You're letting him go?
- That's right.
Because I want him to deliver a message
to Tung Hak-Fung.
Right! Tell Tung Hak-Fung,
our Tongbei school
may have been beaten by yours,
but we'll crush you scum eventually.
Get going now!
Move!
How about you?
Why do you keep pestering me?
Maybe I'm the same as Tung Hak-Fung,
interested in the half piece on you.
What? So you also mean me harm?
- No.
- What, then?
- Because I have the other half on me.
- What did you say?
Really? Old Ma told me to search the world
to find the other half piece of wood.
So it's in your hands.
So now you know
why I pester you all the time.
I set it!
Bring out that half now.
- What are the words?
- Changbai Peak, Tiger Ridge.
Hey, what are you doing sleeping here?
I'm so tired.
What? So you're tired?
Pal, it's been three days
and three nights.
How can I not be tired?
Hey, what do you want now?
Keep going, find the destination first.
Hey, I have steamed buns in it.
- Hungry again?
- Of course.
Sure.
Right. Eat whilst walking.
- Eat before leaving.
- No.
Come on...!
Come on...! Hey, eat it...!
This is Black Tiger Ridge.
Hey!
- Look, that hole over there!
- Let's go in!
Sin Ha Cave!
They said there was something here.
Not a damn thing!
Stop blaming, kiddo.
I'm not blaming,
I've walked such a long way.
We'll stay here tonight.
It's here!
Oh yeah, I haven't asked you yet,
where did you get the half of your wood?
It was given to me
when my master was dying.
Your master? Who is he?
He was the brother of the old man
in the prison.
I see. So you...
That's right.
I deliberately broke the law
and went to prison.
The purpose was to take the half piece
to Old Man Ma.
But I didn't expect that he'd be shot
the day I went in.
It was unexpected and coincidental the day
at the mine when I saw it in your hands.
So I kept pestering you.
What was the use of pestering?
I thought I was lucky.
Now, just plain unlucky.
Hey, look.
The founder of the Tongbei school
was Wong Yau-San.
Devoting a lifetime, he lived in seclusion
in Changbai Mountain for six years,
extracting the essence of an ape
and studied the power of Eight Extremes
in order to create this.
To practice Tongbei Fist,
we must first start with wrist strength
and arm strength.
Waist strength.
Keen eyesight.
Abdominal muscles.
Neck strength.
Leg strength.
Consolidate the foundation
of internal and external kung fu.
Having the will to guide the air,
use the air to exert strength.
Emphasise softness and rigidity
with long arms.
When you move,
you can change your arms.
Look at you, eating so fast.
You aren't as diligent when practising.
What? You say I'm lazy when practising?
Are you not wrong?
Not wrong at all.
How much have you learn now?
Right. Tongbei water and fire,
Tongbei link,
Tongbei arms, Tongbei—
Tongbei drunken ape,
have you learn that?
I haven't learn this technique yet.
You haven't learnt...
Unless you did?
A little bit.
If you did, show me see a few moves.
Well?
Don't know, or haven't learn it?
'The white drunken ape descends the hill.'
'Dances around the flowers
and shakes about'.
'The white drunken ape descends the hill.'
The white... drunken ape... descends the hill.
'Dances around the flowers
and shakes about, drinking and singing.'
Dances around the flowers
and shakes about, drinking and singing.
'Jumping tiger and flying swallows
shake their fans gently.'
Jumping tiger and flying swallows
shake their fans gently.
'Shaking your head.
Fool around in the human world.'
Shaking your head.
Fool around in the human world.
'Born to spread flowers
and steal peaches.'
'Sleepwalk in the King's Pond.
Stand straight like an Immortal.'
'Flying between clouds in the sky,
reaching nirvana.'
'Rolling body and chopping the drunken man
from the Tang dynasty.'
'Golden hook hanging upside down
in the Immortal style.'
'The smart Tongbei ape
hides the water and fire.'
'The hungry ape hunts
like a tiger in the mountain.'
'Spreading arms and legs
like a phoenix spreading her wings.'
'Like winds and anchors,
or a needle in the ocean.'
'White ape guards the Nine Provinces
with water and fire.'
Wai Chung!
Where has that guy gone so early?
- One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight, nine,
ten,
eleven,
twelve,
thirteen,
fourteen,
fifteen.
Sixteen,
seventeen,
eighteen,
nineteen,
twenty.
Twenty-one,
twenty-two,
twenty-three,
twenty-four,
Twenty-five,
- Hey, what are you standing there for?
- No reason.
If no reason, get the hell out!
- Can't I look?
- No.
Hey punk,
what the hell are you doing here?
This is a martial arts school.
Yeah, I didn't say
that you were a funeral home here.
So insolent.
Are you not afraid to die?
If I were, would I be standing here?
- Fool.
- You...
Coach, he must be an enemy.
Yes, he must be here to rob Master.
Damn, all my stuff was stolen by him.
- Stop him immediately.
- Right!
You can't leave yet!
What's this?
You want me to stay here for dinner?
Hey, punk.
Let me ask you,
how long had you been standing here?
How many things have you learn here?
I stood there for a long time, but...
didn't learn anything.
Why didn't you learn?
Don't you know I'm a descendant
of the Five Tigers of the North?
That means
someone with some special skills.
There is a bit of skill, but it's useless.
Coach, let me take care of that punk.
Coach, we've been learning so long,
it's a chance for us to try it out.
Sure!
That's right!
I just came down from the mountain
and want to find someone to spar with.
I hadn't expected such a good place!
You want a fight? Beat him!
Out of the way!
Hey, which school or clan are you from?
Tongbei Fist. 'White ape
pulls curtains through the mountain gate.'
Hold on!
Right. Don't shame yourself.
One on one.
Get 'im.
Don't move.
Whose turn is it?
Wai.
Let me!
Hey!
Don't worry, you didn't split into two.
- What?
Several teaching assistants
have been knocked out, it's your turn!
I —
Hey...! If someone has a weapon,
you should as well!
No need! Here, I'll give it to you.
Thanks.
I poke. I push.
'Mad chicken's kick.'
- Hey, keep on!
- Surely not, me again?
If not you, who'll go?
Jump...!
Broom kick! Right into your tummy.
Go on. Go on!
Hey"
- Hey! Come back!
- Leave me alone!
Hey, it's your turn this time.
Of course!
Damn imp. Give you a taste of
my Five-Poison Spider Hand!
'Tongbei water and fire'!
Aren't spiders good at spinning silk?
'Spider spirit'!
Sting...!
My 'smart ape kicks mountain gate' trick...
is strong, right?
You watch out! 'Spider catches an insect'!
Go to hell!
You got me!
'Tongbei continuous punch'.
I've also found a girl.
Not bad.
Master, this smart arse is here
to challenge the school.
Step aside.
Your Chicken Foot isn't bad!
You handle the challenger!
Nice!
- Sorry! Sorry for the trouble!
- Hey, I haven't finished!
- Let's go, it's their place.
- I need to beat her up.
CHOU'S RESTAURANT
Here, cheers.
Why did you do that?
Leaving early to make trouble
at a martial arts school?
I wasn't. They asked me to fight.
I don't believe they'd ask you
into the martial arts school to fight.
But it's true that I want
to find someone to compete with.
- Why?
- To be honest,
our Tongbei Fist is just deadly kung fu
from books and school.
How can I know if I don't fight with them?
If you want to fight,
you'll have chances, kiddo.
You mean Tung Hak-Fung
of the Black Tiger gang?
You think they'll let us go?
True.
They can't find us,
so they must think we're practising hard.
Of course.
To eliminate the Tongbei school,
they'll pursue us all the way.
But, Jau,
I really don't want to die at their hands.
You're riding a tiger you can't get off.
Think you can walk away?
That's not what I said.
As the saying goes,
'Each has its own brilliant moves;
each teacher has their own method.'
- I don't get what you mean.
- You don't have to get it. Here.
Have a good drink today.
Jau, let's not go home till we're drunk.
Jau!
Jau...!
Long time no see.
That's right.
I've always missed you!
You escaped before,
but it won't be so easy this time.
Today? You wanna get me?
It's going to be really tough today.
- Hey, this punk's different from before!
- Different? There's more to come!
Wai Chung!
'Tongbei chops the Bagua'.
'Tongbei continuous punch'.
'Tongbei water and fire'!
- Drunken ape?
- You know it!
That's the drunken ape?
A bit drunk, but it's not finished yet.
I'll finish you off today!
Hang in there! No need to shake your head!
- Hey, don't be scared...
- Only you're scared, kiddo!
'Tongbei chops the Bagua'.
Chops the Bagua...!
'Chops the Bagua', your arse!
Tongbei...!
I'LL make your feet soft!
Die...
- I'm all numb!
- See if you can fight more!
There's another move! Deadly clingy fight.
Deadly clingy fight?
Won't you fight?
You hit me!
Hey, let me ask you, why were you here?
Smart arse,
you really thought I was drunk.
I guessed that you'd leave me behind!
Right, now that the enemy's
been wiped out, let's split up.
Hold it! Bring out the rare book!
Rare book?