Yeah, D.B.?
Oh, just cleaning out the dead wood.
Okay.
Look, Mr. Connell,
I just can't afford to be
without work right now,
not even for a day.
I've got a mother and two kid sisters--
More good luck telegrams.
Well, you know how it is. I...
I've just got to keep on working, see?
Sorry, sister.
I was sent down here to clean house.
I told you I can't use
your column anymore.
It's lavender and no lace.
- Sir?
- Send those other people in.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I get 30 dollars a week.
I'll take 25, 20 if necessary.
I'll do anything you say.
It isn't the money.
We're after circulation.
What we need is fireworks.
People that can hit with
sledgehammers, start arguments.
Oh, I can do that.
I know this town inside and out.
Oh, give me a chance, please.
All right, come in, come in, come in.
Cashier's got your check.
Who are these people?
Gibbs, Foley, Cunningham, Giles.
Hey you, sister!
Don't forget to get out your last column
before you pick up your check.
You're a couple of sticks
shy on your column, Ann.
Big rich slob like
D.B. Norton buys a paper
and 40 heads are chopped off.
- Did you get it too?
- Yeah.
You too?
Aw, Joe.
Oh, I'm sorry darling.
Why don't we tear the building down?
Before you do, Ann,
perhaps you better finish this column.
Yeah, lavender and no lace.
Wait, Joe.
Wait.
Wants fireworks, huh?
Okay.
Here.
"Below is a letter
which reached my desk this morning.
It's a commentary
on what we laughingly call
a civilized world.
'Dear Miss Mitchell,
four years ago I was fired out of my job.
Since then, I haven't
been able to get another one.
At first, I was sore
at the State Administration
because it's on account
of the slimy politics here
we have all this unemployment,
but in looking around,
it seems the whole world's going to pot.
So, in protest,
I'm going to commit suicide
by jumping off the City Hall roof.
Signed, a disgusted
American citizen, John Doe.'
Editor's note, if you ask this column,
the wrong people
are jumping off the roofs."
Hey, Ann, this is
the old fake-a-roo, isn't it?
Never mind that, Joe, go ahead.
"'And it's because of the slimy politics
that we have all this unemployment here.
There it is.
That's D.B. Norton's
opening attack on the Governor.
Why Jim, it's just
a letter sent into a column.
No, no, I can smell it.
That's Norton.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Good morning, Governor.
You're here rather early.
Governor, did you happen to see this
in The New Bulletin?
Mm, yes, I had it served with
my breakfast this morning.
Jim thinks it's D.B. Norton at work.
Of course it is.
Oh, come Jim, that little item?
D.B. Norton does things
in a much bigger way.
This is his opening
attack on you, Governor.
Take my word for it.
What did he buy a paper for?
Why did he engage a high
pressure editor like Come" for?
He's in the oil business.
I tell you, Governor,
he's after your scalp.
All right, Jim, all right.
Don't burst a blood vessel.
I'll look into it.
Yes, sir?
Get me Spencer of
the Daily Chronicle, please.
Yes, yes, I saw it, Governor.
If you ask me, that's a phony letter.
Why, that gag has got whiskers on it.
Hmm?
Okay, I'll get the Mayor and maybe
the Chamber of Commerce to go after them.
Get Mayor Loveett on the phone.
Sorry, the Mayor's busy
on the other phone.
Yes, I know, Mrs. Brewster.
It's a terrible reflection on our city.
I've had a dozen calls already.
Spencer at the Chronicle.
- Hold him.
- Just a minute.
Yes, Mrs. Brewster, I'm listening.
I insist that this John Doe man be found
and given a job at once.
Now if something isn't done about it,
I'll call out the whole Auxiliary.
Yes, and the Junior Auxiliary too.
We'll hold a meeting and see that it is.
Yes, Spencer?
Who?
The governor?
Well, what about me?
It's my building he jumping off of,
and I'm up for re-election too.
- Shh.
- What are you doing?
Get Connell at the Bulletin.
Why, why, he's liable to go
right past my win--
- Get me Connell.
- What was that?
- What?
- out the window.
Something just flew by.
- I didn't see anything.
- Well, don't stand there, you idiot.
Go and look. Open the window.
Oh, why did he have
to pick on my building?
- Is there a crowd in the street?
- No, sir.
Then maybe he's caught on a ledge.
Look again.
I think it must have been a seagull.
A seagull?
What's a seagull
doing around the City Hall?
That's a bad omen, isn't it?
Oh no sir, the seagull is a lovely bird.
It's all right, Mrs. Brewster.
It was just a seagull.
- Connell?
- Nothing's happened yet.
I'm watching.
Don't worry, Mrs. Brewster.
Just leave it all to me.
Spencer, I'll call you back.
Hello, Connell?
This is--what are you doing?
This is the Mayor.
Yes, Mayor Lovett.
How many times you gonna call me?
I've got everybody
and his brother and sister
out looking for him.
Did you see the box I'm running?
"An appeal to John Doe.
Think it over, John.
'Life can be beautiful, ' says Mayor.
If you need a job,
apply to the editor of this paper,"
and so forth and so forth.
Okay, Mayor, I'll let you know
as soon as I have something.
What?
Well, pull down the blinds.
Went up to Miss Mitchell's house, boss.
Boy, she's in a bad way.
- Where is she?
- Hey, do you know something?
She supports her mother and two kids.
What do you know about that?
- Did you find her?
- No.
Her mother's awful worried about her.
When she left the house, she said
she was going on a roaring drunk.
The girl, I mean.
- Go out and find her.
- Sure.
Hey, but the biggest thing
I didn't tell ya.
Her old man's Doc Mitchell, you know,
the doc who saved my mother's life
and wouldn't take any money for it.
You remember that.
Okay, boss, I'll go and look for her.
Holy smokes, Commissioner.
You've had 24 hours.
Okay, Hawkshaw, grab a pencil.
Here it is again.
About five-foot-five,
brown eyes, light chestnut hair,
and as fine a pair of legs as--
Ever walked into this office.
- Did you want to see me?
- No.
I've had the whole Army
and Navy out searching for you
because that's a game
we play here every day.
I remember distinctly being fired.
That's right,
but you have a piece of property
that still belongs to this newspaper,
and I'd like to have it.
- What's that?
- The letter.
- What letter?
- The letter from John Doe.
- Oh.
- The whole town's in an uproar.
We've got to find him,
and the letter's the only clue.
There is no letter.
We'll get a handwriting expert to--
What?
There is no letter.
Say that again.
There's no letter. I made it up.
You made it up.
Mm-hmm.
You said you wanted fireworks.
Don't you know there are
nine jobs waiting for this guy,
22 families want to board him free,
five women want to marry him,
and the Mayor's practically
ready to adopt him, and you--
Just called the morgue, boss.
- They say there's a girl there--
- Shut up!
- Ann! Say, why didn't you--
- Beany!
Only one thing to do, Hank.
Drop the whole business quickly.
- How?
- Run a story, say John Doe was in here,
and is sorry he wrote the letter and--
That's right. You've got it, sure.
He came in here and
I made him change his mind.
"Bulletin Editor Saves John Doe's Life."
Why, it's perfect.
I'll have Ned write it up.
Oh, Ned, I got a story I want you--
Wait a minute.
Listen, you great big, wonderful genius
of a newspaperman.
You came down here to shoot some life
into this dying paper, didn't you?
Well, the whole town's
curious about John Doe and boom!
Just like that, you're going to bury him.
There's enough circulation in that man
to start a shortage in the ink market.
- In what man?
- John Doe.
What John Doe?
Our John Doe, the one I made up.
Look, genius, now look.
Suppose there was a John Doe,
and he walked into this office,
what would you do?
Find him a job and
forget about the whole business,
I suppose, huh?
Not me, I'd make a deal with him.
- A deal?
- Sure, when you get ahold of a stunt
that sells papers,
you don't drop it like a hot potato.
Why, this is good for
at least a couple of months.
You know what I'd do?
Between now and let's say Christmas,
when he's gonna jump,
I'd run a daily yarn.
Starting with his boyhood,
his schooling, his first job.
A wide-eyed youngster
facing a chaotic world.
The problem of the average man,
of all the John Does in the world.
Now, then comes the drama.
He meets discouragement.
He finds the world has feet of clay,
his ideals crumble.
So, what does he do?
He decides to commit suicide in protest
against the state of civilization.
He thinks of the river, but no.
No, he has a better idea, the City Hall.
Why?
Because he wants to attract attention.
He wants to get a few things off his chest
and that's the only way
he can get himself heard.
- So?
So, he writes me a letter
and I dig him up.
He pours out his soul to me.
And from now on we quote,
"I Protest," by John Doe.
He protests against
all the evils in the world,
the greed, the lust, the hate, the fear,
all of man's inhumanity to man.
Arguments will start.
Should he commit suicide or should he not?
People will write in,
pleading with him, but no.
No, sir, John Doe will remain adamant.
On Christmas Eve,
hot or cold, he goes, see?
Very pretty, very pretty indeed,
Miss Mitchell,
but would you mind telling me
who goes on Christmas Eve?
- John Doe.
- What John Doe?!
The one we hire for the job, you lunkhead!
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Let me get this
through this lame brain of mine.
Are you suggesting we go out
and hire someone
to say he's gonna commit suicide
on Christmas Eve?
- Is that it?
- Why, you're catching on.
- Who for instance?
- Anybody.
- Beany'll do.
- Why, su--
Who, me?
Jump off a--
Oh no, anytime but Christmas.
I'm superstitious.
Miss Mitchell, do me a favor, will ya?
Go on out and get married,
and have a lot of babies,
but stay out of the newspaper business.
Better get that story in, Hank.
It's getting late.
You're supposed to be a smart guy.
If it was raining 100 dollar bills,
you'd be out looking for a dime
you lost someplace.
Holy smokes, wasting my time
listening to this mad woman.
Look, chief, look what
the Chronicle's running on John Doe.
They say it's a fake.
Why, the no-good, the...
"John Doe story, amateur journalism.
It's palpably phony, it's a wonder
anyone's taking it seriously.
- What do you think of those guys?
- That's fine, that's fine.
Now fall right into their laps, go ahead.
Say John Doe walked in
and called the whole thing off.
You know what that's gonna
sound like on top of this.
- That's all, Ned.
- Thank you.
All right.
Amateur journalism, huh?
Why, the bunch of sophomores.
I could teach them more about--
Hey, boss!
Get a load of this.
- What?
- Look.
What do they want?
They all say
they wrote the John Doe letter.
Yeah, I wrote it, boss.
- Oh, they all wrote the letter.
- Tell them all to wait.
Look, Mr. Connell,
one of those men is your John Doe.
They're desperate and will
do anything for a cup of coffee.
Pick one out and you can make
the Chronicle eat their words.
I'm beginning to like this.
If you ask me, Hank,
you're playing around with dynamite.
No, no, no, no, no, the girl's right.
We can't let
the Chronicle get the laugh on us.
We've got to produce a John Doe now.
Amateur journalism, huh?
I'll show those guys.
Sure, and there's no reason
for them to find out
the truth either, because
naturally [won't say anything.
Okay, sister, you get your job back.
Plus a bonus.
What bonus?
Oh, the bonus of 1,000 dollars
the Chronicle
was going to pay me
for this little document.
You'll find it says that,
"I, Ann Mitchell, hereby certify
that the John Doe
letter was created by me--"
- I can read, I can read.
- Sorry.
You think this is worth 1,000 dollars,
do ya?
Oh, the Chronicle
would consider it dirt cheap.
Packs everything including a gun.
Okay, sister, you got yourself a deal.
Now let's take a look at the candidates.
The one we pick has got
to be the typical, average man.
Typical American
that can keep his mouth shut.
Show me an American who can
keep his mouth shut and I'll eat him.
Okay, Beany, bring 'em in one at a time.
Did you write
that letter to Miss Mitchell?
No, I didn't.
What are you doing up here then?
Well, the paper says there
was some jobs around loose.
Thought there might be one left over.
Had any schooling?
Yeah, a little.
What do you do when you work?
- I used to pitch.
- Baseball?
Yeah, 'til my wing went bad.
Where'd you play?
Bush leagues, mostly.
How about family?
Got any family?
No.
Oh, just traveling through, huh?
Yeah, me and a friend of mine.
He's outside.
Looks all right.
He's perfect, a baseball player.
What could be more American?
Wish he had a family though.
Be less complicated without a family.
Look at that face, it's wonderful.
They'll believe him. Come on.
What's your name?
Willoughby, John Willoughby.
Long John Willoughby,
they called me in baseball.
Um, would you, uh, would you like
to make some money?
Yeah, maybe.
Would you be willing to say you
wrote that letter and stick by it?
Mm, I get the idea.
Yeah, maybe.
That's our man.
He's made to order.
I don't know.
He don't seem like
the kind of a guy that'd fall in line.
When you're desperate for money,
you do a lot of things, Mr. Connell.
He's our man, I tell you.
He's fainted!
Get some water, quickly!
Hurry up, Pop.
Right here, sit down.
You all right?
Yeah, I'm all right.
How many is that, six?
Pretty hungry, weren't you?
All this John Doe
business is batty, if you ask me.
Well, nobody asked you.
Trying to improve
the world by jumping off buildings.
You couldn't improve the world
if the buildings jumped on you.
Don't mind the Colonel.
He hates people.
He likes you enough to stick around.
Well, that's 'cause
we both play doohickeys.
I met him in a boxcar
a couple of years ago.
I was fooling around with my harmonica
and he comes over and joins in.
I haven't been able to shake him since.
All right boys, here he is.
No, no, no, you can't
take pictures of him like that,
eating a sandwich and with a beard.
- But he's gonna jump off a building.
- Yes, but not because he's out of a job.
That's not news.
This man's going to jump
as a matter of principle.
Maybe you're right.
We'll clean him up and put him
in a hotel room under bodyguards.
We'll make a mystery out of him.
Did you speak to Mr. Norton?
Thinks it's terrific.
Says for us to go the limit.
Wants us to build a bonfire
under every bigshot in the state.
- Oh, swell. Is that the contract?
- Yeah.
What's he doing here?
Friend of his. They play duets together.
Duets? But can we trust him?
- Oh.
- I trust him.
Oh, you trust him, eh?
Well, that's fine.
I suppose he trusts you too.
Oh, stop worrying. He's all right.
Okay, but we don't want more than
a couple of hundred
people in on this thing.
Now the first thing
I want is an exact copy
of the John Doe letter
in your own handwriting.
I've got it already, here.
That's fine.
Now I want you to sign this agreement.
It gives us
an exclusive story under your name,
day by day, from now until Christmas.
On December 26th,
you get one railroad ticket out of town,
and the Bulletin agrees
to pay to have your arm fixed.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Yeah, but it's got to
be by Bone-setter Brown.
Okay, Bone-setter Brown goes.
Here, sign it.
Meanwhile,
here's 50 dollars spending money.
That's fine. Beany?
- Yes, boss.
- Take charge of him.
Get him a suite at the Imperial
and hire some bodyguards.
And some new clothes, Beany.
Think we better have him deloused?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Both of them?
- Yes, both of them,
but don't let 'em out of your sight.
- Hey, Beany, gray suit, huh?
- Yeah.
Okay, fellas.
Take it easy, John Doe.
And you, start pounding that typewriter.
Oh boy, this is terrific.
No responsibilities on our part,
just statements from John Doe,
and we can blast our heads off.
Before you pop too many buttons,
don't forget to make
out that check for 1,000.
Yeah.
Okay, fellas, now let me see.
You sit outside the door
and nobody comes in, see?
You two fellas sit in here.
Hey, pretty nifty, huh?
You ain't gonna get me to stay here.
- Sure you are.
- No, sir.
That spot under the bridge where we slept
last night is good enough for me.
- Say, what'll I do with this baggage?
- Oh, stick 'em in the bedroom.
Give me mine, I ain't staying.
You know, we were headed
for the Columbia River country
before all this John Doe business came up.
You remember that, don't ya?
Sure, I remember.
Say, did your ears pop
coming up in the elevator?
Mine did.
Oh, Long John, I tell ya, it's no good.
You're gonna get used to a lot of stuff
that's gonna wreck you.
Why, that 50 bucks in your pocket
is beginning to show up on you already.
And don't pull that on me neither.
Stop worrying, Colonel.
I'm gonna get my arm fixed out of this.
Hey, here's some cigars the boss sent us.
- Have one.
- Hey, cigars!
- Help yourself.
- No.
Say, I'll bet you even the Major Leaguers
don't rate an outfit like this.
Here, make yourself comfortable. Paper?
I don't read no papers
and I don't listen to radios neither.
I know the world's been
shaved by a drunken barber
and I don't have to read it.
I've seen guys like you go under before.
Guys that never had a worry,
then they got ahold of some dough
and went goofy.
The first thing that happens to a guy--
- Hey, did you get a load of the bedroom?
- No.
The first thing
that happens to a guy like that,
he starts wanting to go into restaurants
and sit down at a table and
eat salad and cupcakes and tea.
Boy, what that kind of food
does to your system.
The next thing the dope wants is a room.
Yes sir, a room with steam heat
and curtains and rugs,
and before you know it,
he's all softened up
and he can't sleep unless he has a bed.
Hey, stop worrying, Colonel.
50 bucks ain't gonna ruin me.
I've seen plenty of fellas
start out with 50 bucks
and wind up with a bank account.
Hey, what's the matter
with a bank account, anyway?
And let me tell you, Long John,
when you become a guy
with a bank account,
they got ya!
Yes sir, they got ya.
- Who's got him?
- The heelots.
- Who?
- Hey
there's the City Hall tower
I'm supposed to jump off of.
It's even higher than this.
Who's got him?
The heelots.
- Woo!
- Hey, wait a minute.
You're not supposed to jump
'til Christmas Eve.
Do you want to get me in a jam?
If it's gonna get you in a jam,
I'll do you a favor.
I won't jump.
And when they got ya,
you got no more chance
than a road rabbit.
Hey, who'd you say was going to get him?
Say, is this one of those places where
you ring if you want something?
Yeah, just use the phone.
Boy, I've always wanted to do that.
Hey, Doc, look. Look, Doc.
Give me that again, will ya?
Who's gonna get him?
The heelots.
Who are they?
Listen, sucker, you ever been broke?
Sure, mostly often.
All right.
You're walking along,
not a nickel in your jeans,
you're free as the wind,
nobody bothers you.
Hundreds of people pass you by
in every line of business,
shoes, hats, automobiles,
radios, furniture, everything.
They're all nice,
lovable people and they let you alone.
Now, is that right?
Then you get ahold of some dough,
and what happens?
All those nice, sweet,
lovable people become heelots,
a lot of heels!
They begin creepin' up on you,
trying to sell you something.
They get long claws and
they get a stranglehold on you,
and you squirm and you duck and you holler
and you try to push 'em away
but you haven't got a chance.
They got ya.
First thing you know, you own things.
A car, for instance.
Now your whole life
is messed up with a lot more stuff.
You got license fees and
number plates, and gas and oil,
and taxes and insurance,
and identification cards
and letters and bills
and flat tires and dents
and traffic tickets and
motorcycle cops and courtrooms
and lawyers and fines and
a million and one other things,
and what happens?
You're not the free and
happy guy you used to be.
You gotta have money
to pay for all those things.
So you go after
what the other fella's got,
and there you are.
You're a heelot yourself.
You win, Colonel.
Here, take the 50.
Go out and get rid of it.
You bet I will, just as fast as I can.
I'm gonna get some
canned goods, a fishing rod,
and the rest I'm gonna give away.
Give away?
Hey, get me a pitcher's glove.
I gotta get some practice.
Say, he's giving it away,
I'm gonna get me some of that.
Hey, come back here, you heelot.
Will you send up five hamburgers
with all the trimmings,
five chocolate ice cream sodas,
and five pieces of apple pie?
No, apple, with cheese.
Yeah, thanks.
Hello there.
Well, well.
If it isn't the man about town.
All set, Miss Ann.
Hmm?
Oh, yes, let's go.
Um, let's see, we want
some action in these pictures.
Action?
Mm-hmm.
- That's good.
- No, no, no.
This man's going to jump off a roof.
- Oh.
- Here, wait a minute.
Let me comb your hair.
Sit down.
There, that's better.
You know, he's got a nice face, hasn't he?
Yeah, he's pretty.
Here, sit down.
Quiet, egghead.
All right, now a serious expression.
I can't. I'm feeling too good.
Oh come on now, this is serious.
You're a man disgusted
with all of civilization.
- With all of it?
- Yes, you're sore at the world.
Come on now.
Crabby guy, huh?
Yeah.
No, no.
No, look, you don't
have to smell the world.
With all those guys in the bleachers--
Never mind those guys.
All right, stand up.
Now, let's see what
you look like when you protest.
Against what?
Against anything, just protest.
You got me.
Oh. Look, I'm the umpire,
and you just cut the heart of the plate
with your fast one
and I called it a ball.
What would you do?
- Oh, you did, huh?
- Yeah.
Why can't you call it right,
you bone-headed, big-eared--
- Grab it, Eddie, grab it!
- ...pot-bellied...
Extra, extra!
Read all about it! Extra!
Read all about it!
I don't care
whose picture they're publishing.
I still say that
this John Doe person is a myth,
and you can quote me on that,
and I'm going to insist
on his being produced for questioning.
You know as well as I do
that this whole thing
is being engineered by a vicious man
with a vicious purpose, Mr. DB. Norton.
Mr. Connell and
Miss Mitchell are at the house, sir.
Oh, they are?
All right, come on.
Personally, I think it's just
plain stupidity to drop it now.
You should see his fan mail, thousands.
Why, it's going over like a house afire.
What are you afraid of, Connell?
It's doubled our circulation.
Yeah, but it's got everybody sore.
Ads are being pulled.
The governor's starting a libel suit.
What's more, they all
know John Doe's a phony
and they insist on seeing him.
Well, what about it? Let them see him.
We'll go 'em one better,
they can also hear him.
You own a radio station, Mr. Norton.
Why not put him on the air?
Watch out for this dame, D.B.
She'll drive you batty.
- Oh--
- Look, we can't let them
get to this bush league pitcher
and start pumping him.
Good night! No telling
what that screwball might do.
I walk in yesterday,
here he is standing on a table
with a fishing pole, fly-casting.
Take my advice and get him out of town
before this thing explodes in our faces.
If you do, Mr. Norton, you're just as much
of a dumb cluck as he is, excuse me.
Now you got yourself a meal ticket
and you hate to let it go.
Sure, he's a meal ticket for me,
I admit it,
but it's also a windfall
for somebody like Mr. Norton
who's trying to crash national politics.
That's what you bought
the newspaper for, isn't it?
You want to reach
a lot of people, don't you?
Well, put John Doe on the air
and you can reach 130 million of 'em.
He can say anything
he wants and they'll listen to him.
All right, we'll forget
the Governor and the Mayor
and all the small fry like that.
This can arouse national interest.
If he made a hit around here, he can do it
every place else in the country,
and you'll be pulling
the strings, Mr. Norton.
Go down to the office and
arrange for some radio time.
- But D.B., you're not gonna fall--
- I want it as soon as possible.
Okay, I just came in to get warm myself.
Come on, let's go.
Don't you go.
I want to talk to you.
Sit down.
This John Doe idea was yours, huh?
Yes, sir.
How much money do you get?
30 dollars.
Well, what are you after?
I mean, what do you want,
a journalistic career?
Money.
Well, I'm glad to hear somebody admit it.
Do you suppose
you could write a radio speech
that would put that fellow over?
Oh, I'm sure I can.
Do it and I'll give you
100 dollars a week.
- 100 dollars a--
- That's only the beginning.
You play your cards right
and you'll never have to worry
about money again.
Oh, I knew it.
- Hello.
Whenever there's a pretty woman around.
This is my nephew,
Ted Sheldon, Miss Mitchell.
- How do you do?
All right,
Casanova, I'll give you a break.
See that Miss Mitchell
gets a car to take her home.
Always reading my mind, aren't you?
Thank you very much for everything.
And Miss Mitchell, I think from now on,
you'd better work directly with me.
Yes, sir.
Ahh!
Hey!
Oh! I thought you were asleep.
Good night, sis!
We just wanted to say good night.
You little brats, you're just stalling.
I said good night.
Come, come, come, children.
It's past your bedtime.
- Now, go on.
- Go on.
- Oh, all right.
- Come on, come on. Come on, come on.
Stick a fork through me, I'm done.
I'll never get this speech right.
Oh yes you will, Ann dear.
You're very clever.
Yeah, I know.
What are you looking for?
Your purse. I need 10 dollars.
What for?
I gave you 50 just the other day.
Yes, I know, clear,
but Mrs. Burke had her baby yesterday.
Nine pounds, and there
wasn't a thing in the house,
and then the Community Chest lady came.
And the 50's all gone, huh?
Who's the 10 for?
- The Websters.
You remember, those lovely people
your father used to take care of?
I thought I'd buy them some groceries.
- Oh Ann, dear, it's a shame those poor--
- You're marvelous, Ma.
You're just like Father used to be.
Do you realize a couple of weeks ago,
we didn't have enough to eat ourselves?
Well, yes I know, dear,
but these people are in such need
and we have plenty now.
If you're thinking
of that thousand dollars, forget it.
It's practically all gone.
We owed everybody in town.
Now, you just gotta stop
giving all your money away.
Oh, Ann dear.
Oh, I'm sorry, Ma.
Oh, don't pay any attention to me.
I guess I'm just upset about all this.
Jeepers, here I am with
a great opportunity to get somewhere,
to give us security
for once in our lives, and I'm stuck.
If I could put this over,
your Mrs. Burke can have six babies.
You mean this speech you're writing?
Yeah, I don't know.
I simply can't get it to gel.
I created somebody who's going to give up
his life for a principle.
Hundreds of thousands of people
are going to listen to him over the radio,
and unless he says something that's,
well, that's sensational,
it's just no good.
Well, honey, of course
I don't know what kind of a speech
you're trying to write,
but judging from the samples I've read,
I don't think anybody'll listen.
What?
Darling, there are so many
complaining political speeches.
People are tired of hearing nothing
but doom and despair on the radio.
If you're going to have him say anything,
why don't you let him
say something simple and real,
something with hope in it?
Your father were alive,
he'd know what to say.
Oh, yeah.
Father certainly would.
- Wait a minute.
- Hm?
That's your father's diary, Ann.
Father's--?
I never knew he had a diary.
There's enough in it for 100 speeches,
things people ought to hear nowadays.
You be careful of it, won't you, dear?
It's always helped
to keep your father alive for me.
You bet I will, Ma.
Wait a minute.
John Doe don't want to sign no autographs.
Well, what does he do all day?
What does he do all day?
He's writing out his memories.
Sorry, lady, you can't see Mr. Doe.
He wants to be alone.
No. No, he just sits around all day
and commutes with himself.
Ball!
I don't know how you're gonna stand it
around here 'til after Christmas.
I'll bet you ain't heard
a train whistle in two weeks.
Stee-rike!
I know why you're hanging around.
You're stuck on the girl.
That's all a guy needs is
to get hooked up with a woman.
What was that, a single?
First baseman dropped the ball.
Butterfingers!
Tough luck, pal.
Guy has a woman on his hands,
first thing he knows,
his life is balled up
with a lot more things.
Furniture and...
Did you get him?
You're out!
Swell.
What's this, the end of the eighth?
Ninth.
Hey Beany, there's a couple of mugs from
the Chronicle snooping around out here.
Ha!
Come on, Angelface.
Gangway.
What's the score, Angelface?
Three to two, our favor.
Gee, that's great!
Hey, you got swell form there.
Must have been a pretty good pitcher.
Pretty good? Say, I was just about
ready for the major leagues
when I chipped a bone in my elbow.
I got it pitching a 19-inning game.
19?
Yeah.
There was a Major League scout
there watching me too,
and he came down
after the game with a contract.
You know what?
I couldn't lift my arm to sign it.
I'll be okay though,
soon as I get it fixed up.
Yeah, it's too bad.
What do you mean, too bad?
Huh?
Oh, that you'll never
be able to play again.
What are you talking about?
I just told you I was gonna get my--
You know how they are in baseball
if a guy's mixed up in a racket.
Racket? What do you mean?
Well, I was just thinking
about this John Doe business.
Why, as soon as
it comes out it's all a fake,
you'll be washed up in baseball,
won't you?
Yeah.
Doggone, I never thought about that.
- Gosh!
- And another thing,
what about all the kids in the country?
The kids that idolize ball players?
What are they gonna think about ya?
Yeah.
Hey, Colonel.
Did you hear that?
I gotta figure some way out of this thing.
Elevators are still running.
I know one way you can do it.
-[music 5 tops -How? 1
Well, when you get up there on the radio,
all you have to do is say
the whole thing's a frame-up.
Make you a hero, sure as you're born.
Yeah, but how am I gonna get my arm fixed?
That's a cinch.
I know somebody who'll give you
5,000 dollars just to get up on the radio
and tell the truth.
5,000 dollars?
Yeah, 5,000 dollars
and he gets it right away.
You don't have to wait 'til Christmas.
Look out, Long John,
they're closing in on you.
Say, who's putting up this dough?
Fella runs the Chronicle.
Here's the speech you make
and it's all written out for you.
5,000 dollars. Holy mackerel!
I can see the heelots coming,
the whole army of them.
It's on the level.
No, I'm sorry, tickets for
the broadcast are all gone.
Phone the Bulletin.
Sorry, no more tickets left.
Hello, John, all set for the big night?
- Swell!
- Turn around.
- One moment, Mr. Doe.
- Now stand still.
- Hold it, Mr. Doe.
- Big smile, Mr. Doe.
- That's swell.
- Okay, Beany, that's enough, take 'em out.
Now look, John, here's the speech.
It's in caps and double spaced.
You won't have any trouble reading it.
- Not nervous, are you?
- No.
Of course not. He wouldn't be.
- Who?
- John Doe, the one in there.
Hey, don't let your knees rattle.
It picks up on the mic.
Oh, Beany.
You needn't be nervous, John.
All you have to remember is to be sincere.
Pick up that phone, Miss Mitchell.
It's for you.
Okay. Hello?
Yes, Mother.
Oh, thank you, darling.
Oh, there he is, the poor dear man.
Oh, good luck to you, Mr. Doe.
We want you to know
that we're all for you.
The girls all decided--
...that you're not to jump off
any roof at all.
- You got the speech I gave ya?
- Yeah.
Now look, I'll give
this money to the Colonel
just as soon as you get started.
We'll have a car waiting
at the side entrance for you.
- Okay.
- How'd you get in here?
Huh? Oh, I just came in to wish him luck.
Come on, out, out!
Mother says good luck, too.
John, when you read that speech,
please, please believe every word of it.
He's turned out to be
a wonderful person, John.
- Who?
- John Doe, the one in the speech.
- Oh.
- You know something?
I... I've actually fallen in love with him.
All right, there he is, sister.
Now come on, plenty of oomph.
- What's the idea?
- No, no, no, that's too much.
That's not--that's not--
no, no, not so much.
Come on.
Oh, this is no time for
cheap publicity, Mr. Connell.
Listen, if that guy lays an egg,
I want to get something out of it.
I'm getting a Jane Doe ready.
Oh, come on, will you fellas?
Give me a chance.
That's fine honey, you go ahead.
How you doing?
All right, Beany, bring them in.
Holy smoke, a half a heelot.
There you are,
boss, just like you ordered.
Symbols of little people.
Okay, get 'em up.
All right, little fella.
This is ridiculous, Mr. Connell.
Come on, give me a chance.
The man's on the air pretty soon.
I told you, you'll get
all the pictures you want after.
No, come on, after.
Come on, come on, that's right.
Afterwards, you can
get all the pictures you want.
- Thank you very much.
- Come on, will ya?
- That's right.
- Come on, Snooks, you better bail out.
Okay, goodbye, Mr. Doe.
- Beany!
- All right, all right.
Better get ready. One minute to go.
Wow, one minute to go,
and the score's nothing to nothing.
Now please, John,
you won't let me down, will ya?
Will ya?
Of course you won't.
If you'll just think of yourself
as the real John Doe.
Listen, everything
in that speech are things
a certain man believed in.
He was my father, John,
and when he talked, people listened,
and they'll listen to you, too.
Funny, you know what
my mother said the other night?
She said to look into your eyes,
that I'd see Father there.
Hey, what do you say?
Okay, we're coming. Come on.
Now, listen, John.
You're a pitcher.
Now get in there and pitch.
Good luck.
Give him room, let him through.
Come on.
Hey, let's get outta here.
There's the door right there.
Hey, what are you doing here?
That's what I'd like to know.
Come on, out, out!
Hey, he's a friend of mine.
Never mind, let him alone. He's all right.
I'll be right over there pulling for you.
No, John, over here.
Stand by.
Phone the Chronicle. Tell 'em to start
getting those extras out.
And good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
This is Kenneth Fry
speaking for The New Bulletin.
Tonight, we give you something
entirely new and different.
Standing beside me is the young man
who has declared publicly
that on Christmas Eve
he intends to commit suicide,
giving as his reason, quote,
"I protest against
the state of civilization."
End quote.
Ladies and gentlemen,
The New Bulletin takes pleasure
in presenting the man who is fast becoming
the most talked-up person
in the whole country, John Doe!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I am the man you all know as John Doe.
I took that name
because it seems to describe...
because it seems to describe the
average man, and that's me.
...and that's me.
Well, it was me before
I said I was going to jump off
the City Hall roof
at midnight on Christmas Eve.
Now I guess I'm not average anymore.
Now I'm getting all sorts
of attention from big shots too.
We've been double crossed.
- We have.
- The Mayor
and Governor, for instance,
they don't like those articles
I've been writing.
You're an impostor, young fella!
That's a pack of lies you're telling!
Who wrote that speech for you?
Beany, get that guy!
This is a publicity stunt
for the Bulletin!
Spencer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the disturbance you just heard
was caused by someone in the audience
who tried to heckle Mr. Doe.
The speech will continue.
Well, people like the Governor,
people like the Governor
and that fella there can stop worrying.
I'm not gonna talk about them.
I'm gonna talk about us,
the average guys, the John Does.
If anybody should ask you
what the average John Doe is like,
you couldn't tell him
because he's a million and one things.
He's Mr. Big and Mr. Small.
He's simple and he's wise.
He's inherently honest,
but he's got a streak
of larceny in his heart.
He seldom walks up to a public telephone
without shoving
his finger in the slot to see
if somebody left a nickel there.
He's the man the ads are written for,
he's the feller everybody sells things to.
He's Joe Dokes,
the world's greatest stooge,
and the world's greatest strength.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir,
we're a great family, the John Does.
We're the meek who are--who are
supposed to inherit the Earth.
You'll find us everywhere.
We raise the crops,
we dig the mines, work the factories,
keep the books,
fly the planes, and drive the buses,
and when a cop yells,
"Stand back there, you,"
he means us, the John Does.
What kind of a speech is that?
Didn't you read it?
We've existed since time began.
We built the pyramids,
we saw Christ crucified,
pulled the oars for Roman emperors,
sailed the boats for Columbus,
retreated from Moscow with Napoleon,
and froze with Washington at Valley Forge.
Yes, sir, we've been
in there dodging left hooks
since before history began to walk.
In our struggle for freedom,
we've hit the canvas many a time,
but we always bounce back
because we're the people and we're tough.
They've started a lot of talk
about free people going soft,
that we can't take it.
That's a lot of hooey!
A free people can beat
the world at anything from war
to tiddlywinks if we all
pull in the same direction.
I know a lot of you are saying,
"What can I do?
I'm just a little punk.
I don't count."
Well, you're dead wrong.
The little punks have always counted
because in the long run,
the character of a country
is the sum total of
the character of its little punks.
But we've all got to
get in there and pitch.
We can't win the old ball game
unless we have teamwork,
and that's where every John Doe comes in.
It's up to him to get together
with his teammate,
and your teammate, my friends,
is the guy next door to you.
Your neighbor,
he's a terribly important guy,
that guy next door.
You're gonna need him
and he's gonna need you,
so look him up.
If he's sick, call on him.
If he's hungry, feed him.
If he's out of a job, find him one.
To most of you,
your neighbor is a stranger,
a guy with a barking dog
and a high fence around him.
Now, you can't be a stranger to any guy
that's on your own team.
So tear down the fence that separates you.
Tear down the fence,
and you'll tear down a lot of hates
and prejudices.
Tear down all the fences in the country,
and you'll really have teamwork.
I know a lot of
you are saying to yourselves,
"He's asking for a miracle to happen.
He's expecting people
to change all of a sudden."
Well, you're wrong.
It's no miracle.
It's no miracle, because
I see it happen once every year
and so do you, at Christmas time.
There's something swell
about the spirit of Christmas,
to see what it does to people,
all kinds of people.
Now why can't that spirit,
that same warm Christmas spirit,
last the whole year round?
Gosh, if it ever did,
if each and every John Doe would make
that spirit last 365 days out of the year,
we'd develop such a strength,
we'd create such a tidal wave of goodwill
that no human force
could stand against it.
Yes sir, my friends,
the meek can only inherit the Earth
when the John Does
start loving their neighbors.
You better start right now.
Don't wait 'til the game is called
on account of darkness.
Wake up, John Doe,
you're the hope of the world.
John, you were wonderful.
- Let's get out of here.
- Now you're talking.
Gangway, you heelots!
I knew you'd wake up sooner or later.
Boy, am I glad we got out of that mess.
I had the 5,000 bucks sewed up.
Could've been on my way to 'ol Doc Brown.
"You're a pitcher, John," she says.
"Now go in there and pitch."
What a sucker!
Eh, she's a heelot
just like the rest of 'em.
It's lucky you got away from her.
What was I doing up there
making a speech, anyway?
Me, huh?
Geez, the more I think about it,
the more I could--
Tear down all the fences!
Why, if you tore one picket off of
your neighbor's fence, he'd sue you.
5,000 bucks, had it right in my hand.
What do you mean, he ran away?
Well, go after him, find him.
That man is terrific.
Columbia River, here we come!
Jitterbugs.
Yeah.
Say, how much money we got left?
Four bits.
Better make it doughnuts, huh?
Yeah.
What'll it be, gents?
Have you got a couple of steaks
about that big and that thick?
Yeah, with hash brown potatoes
and tomatoes
and apple pie and ice cream and coffee?
And doughnuts, I know.
Hey, Ma!
Sinkers, a pair.
Sinkers, a pair, comin' up.
Glad he took the "T" out of that.
Hey, look.
"Join the John Doe Club."
John Doe Club?
Uh-oh.
- Are you John Doe?
- Who?
- John Doe.
- Ah, you need glasses, buddy.
Ha! Well, gee--
It's the spitting image of John Doe.
Yeah, but his name is Willoughby.
Long John Willoughby.
I'm a baseball player.
Sure.
Oh no, I'd know that voice anywhere.
You can't kid me.
You're John Doe.
Hey, Ma, Ma!
That John Doe!
John Doe!
Yeah, sitting right there, big as life.
Who'd you say it was?
John Doe, the big guy there.
Hey operator, Dan's beanery.
Call everybody in town.
John Doe was just in my place.
Yeah, he ordered doughnuts.
You're all here to see
John Doe and you're all neighbors,
but my office is
packed like a sardine box.
What does John Doe look like, Mr. Mayor?
Oh, he's one of those
great, big, outdoor type men.
No, you can't see him,
you didn't vote for me the last time.
Shame on you, what are you doing here?
Get off my front porch anyhow.
Mr. Norton come yet?
I wonder where he's at,
what's keeping him?
He should've been here 15 minutes ago.
Oh, th--there he comes now.
Now everybody on your dignity.
Don't do anything to disgrace us,
a little town, but we gotta show off.
Better let me talk to him.
All right, but present it to him as
a great cause for the common man.
Oh, here he comes.
Give him room down there.
Give him room, folks.
Come on now, come on, here they come.
Here they come.
Here, Mr. Norton.
Here he comes.
How do you do, Mr. Norton?
I'm Mayor Hawkins.
Come back here!
Let me go, you darn fool.
I'm the Mayor.
Mr. Norton, Mr. Norton, Mr. Norton.
I'm Mayor Hawkins.
Your office telephoned me to hold him.
- That's fine. How is he?
- Oh, he's fine.
He's right in my office there.
You know, it's a big honor having
John Doe here, and you too.
Haven't had so much excitement
since the old City Hall burned down.
People so excited,
they nearly tore his clothes off.
Matilda, darling, phone the newspapers.
Tell them Mr. Norton's here.
Step right inside, Mr. Norton.
My office,
very comfortable here, Mr. Norton.
Just had it air-conditioned.
Gangway, please.
Make room for Mr. Norton.
Gangway, gangway.
Here he is,
Mr. Norton, well taken care of.
The neighbors are
serving him a light lunch.
Hello, John.
Hello.
Mr. Mayor, if you don't mind,
we'd like to talk to him alone.
Why, certainly, certainly.
All right, everybody, clear out.
Everybody, quickly now.
Come on. That's right.
That's right. That's right. Come on.
Don't argue with me here.
- Wait 'til we get home.
- Don't you push me around like that.
Even though I'm your wife,
you can't push me around!
Look, Mr. Norton,
I think you got a lot of nerve
having those people hold us here.
There's nobody holding you here, Mr. Doe.
It's only natural that you--
Well, if there's nobody
holding us here, let's get going.
Incidentally, my name isn't Doe.
It's Willoughby.
Look, John.
Something terribly important's happened.
They're forming John Doe Clubs.
We know of eight already
and they say that there's--
- John Doe Clubs? What for?
- Mm-hmm.
To carry out the principles
you talked about in your radio speech.
I don't care what they're forming.
I'm on my way and I don't like
the idea of being stopped, either.
Oh, but you don't know
how big this thing is.
You should see
the thousands of telegrams we've received,
and what they're saying about you.
Look, it started as
a circulation stunt, didn't it?
Well, you got your circulation.
Now, why don't you let me alone?
Oh, it started as a circulation stunt
but it isn't anymore.
Mr. Norton wants to get back of it
and sponsor John Doe
clubs all over the country.
He wants to send you on a lecture tour.
- Me?
- Uh-huh.
Well certainly.
With your ability to influence people,
it might grow into a glorious movement.
Say, let's get something straight here.
I don't want any part of this thing.
If you got an idea I'm going around
lecturing to people, why, you're crazy.
Baseball's my racket
and I'm sticking to it.
Come on, Colonel, let's get out of here.
John, please.
Please, please,
I just got rid of one crowd.
But please, Mr. Mayor, tell him
the John Doe Club wants to talk to him.
Let them in, Mr. Mayor, let them come in.
Okay, folks, but remember your manners.
No stampeding.
Walk slow, like you do
when you come to pay your taxes.
Okay, all right. Give me a chance.
Come right in.
My name's Bert Hansen, Mr. Doe.
I'm the head soda-jerker
at Schwabecker's drugstore.
Well, sir, you see, me and my wife,
we heard your broadcast
and we got quite a bang out of it,
especially my wife.
Kept me up half the night saying,
"That man's right, honey.
The trouble with the world is
nobody gives a hoot about his neighbor.
That's why everybody in town is
sore and cranky at each other."
And I kept saying, "Well, that's fine,
but how's a guy gonna go around
lovin' the kind of neighbors we got?"
Old Sourpuss, for instance.
You see, Sourpuss Smithers is a guy lives
all alone next door to us.
He's a cranky old man that runs
a second-hand furniture store.
We haven't spoken to him for years.
I always figured he was an ornery old gent
that hated the world
'cause he was always slamming
his garage door and
playing the radio so loud
he kept half the neighbors up.
Well, anyway, the next morning
I'm out watering the lawn
and I look over and
there's Sourpuss on the other side
of the hedge,
straightening out a dent in his fender,
and my wife yells to me
out the window, says,
"Go on, speak to him, Bert,"
and I figured,
well heck, I can't lose anything,
so I yelled over to him,
"Good morning, Mr. Smithers."
He went right on pounding his fender.
Was I burned,
so I turned around to give my wife
a dirty look and she said,
"Louder, louder, he didn't hear you."
So in a voice you could've heard
in the next county I yelled,
"Good morning, Mr. Smithers!"
Well, sir, you could have
knocked me over with a feather.
Old Sourpuss
turned around, surprised like,
and he put on a big smile,
came over and took my hand
like an old lodge brother and he said,
"Good morning, Hansen.
I've been wanting
to talk to you for years,
only I thought you didn't like me,"
and then he started
chatting away like a happy little kid,
and he got so excited his eyes...
Well, Mr. Doe, before
we got through I found out
Smithers is a swell egg,
only he's pretty deaf
and that accounts for all the noises.
He says it's a shame how
little we know about our neighbors,
and then he got an idea and he said,
"How's about inviting
everybody some place where we can all
get together and know
each other a little better?"
Well, I'm feeling so good by this time,
I'm ripe for anything,
so Smithers goes around
the neighborhood
inviting everybody to a meeting
at the schoolhouse and
I tell everybody that comes
into the store, including
Mr. Schwabecker, my boss.
Oh, I'm talking too much.
Well, I'll be doggone if
40 people don't show up.
Course, none of us knew
what to do, but we sure got a kick
out of seeing how glad everybody was
just to say hello to one another.
Tell him about making
Sourpuss chairman, honey.
Oh yeah, we made
Sourpuss chairman and decided
to call ourselves the John Doe Club.
And say, incidentally, this is my wife.
Come here, honey.
This is my wife, Mr. Doe.
How do you do, Mr. Doe?
Sourpuss is here, too.
Oh, is he?
This is Sourpuss, or
excuse me, Mr. Smithers, Mr. Doe.
That's all right.
If you didn't call me Sourpuss,
it wouldn't feel natural.
Well, anyway, I guess nearly
everybody in the neighborhood
came except the Delaney's,
and the Delaney's live in a big house
with an iron fence around it
and they always keep their blinds drawn,
and we always figured
that he was just an old miser
that sat back counting his money,
so why bother about inviting him,
until Grimes, the milkman,
spoke up, and he said,
"Say, you've got the Delaney's all wrong,"
and then he tells us about
how they canceled their milk last week,
and how when
he found a note on the bottle,
he got kinda curious-like
and he sort of peeked in under the blinds
and found the house was empty.
"If you ask me,"
he says, "they're starving."
Old man Delaney has
been bringing his furniture
over to my place at night,
one piece at a time, and selling it.
Yeah. And well sir,
a half a dozen of us ran over there
to fetch him and
we brought him to the meeting,
and what a reception they got.
Well, everybody shook hands with him
and made a fuss over them,
and well, finally,
Mr. and Mrs. Delaney
just sat right down and cried.
And then we started to find out
about a lot of other people.
Yeah sure.
Well, you know Grubbel, for instance.
Grubbel's here, see?
Yeah, that's him.
Of course, you don't know Grubbel,
but he's the man everybody figured
was the worst no-account
in the neighborhood
because he was living like a hermit,
and nobody would
have anything to do with him,
that is, until Murphy,
the postman, told us the truth.
Why, Grubbel, he says,
he lives out of garbage cans
because he won't take charity,
'cause it'd ruin his self-respect,
he says.
Just like you said on the radio, Mr. Doe.
Well, sir, about
a dozen families got together
and gave Grubbel
a job watering their lawns,
isn't that wonderful?
And then we found
jobs for six other people
and they've all gone off relief.
And my boss, Mr. Schwabecker, made a job
in his warehouse for old man Delaney.
And he gave you that five-dollar raise.
Yeah, wasn't that swell?
Why, Bert, I feel slighted.
I'd like to join, but nobody asked me.
I'm sorry, Mayor, but we voted that
no politician could join.
Just the John Does of the neighborhood,
'cause you know how politicians are.
Yeah.
Well, the reason
we wanted to tell you this, Mr. Doe,
was just to give you
an idea of what you started,
and from where I'm sitting,
I don't see any sense
in you jumping off any building.
No!
Well, thank you for listening.
Goodbye, Mr. Doe.
You're a wonderful man,
and it strikes me you can be mighty
useful walking around for a while.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Mr. Doe.
I'm Mrs. Delaney, Mr. Doe.
God bless you, my boy.
Gee whiz, I'm all mixed up.
I don't get it.
Look, all those swell people think
I'm gonna jump off
a building or something.
I never had any such idea.
Gosh, a fella would have to
be a mighty fine example himself
to go around telling other people
how to...
Say, look, what happened the other night
was on account of Miss Mitchell here.
She wrote the stuff.
Don't you see what
a wonderful thing this can be?
But we need you, John.
You're hooked.
I can see that right now, they got you.
Well, I'm through.
For three years I been trying to get you
up to the Columbia River country.
First it was your glass arm,
then it was the radio,
and now it's the John Doe Clubs.
Well, I ain't waiting another minute.
Gangway, you heelots!
Hey Colonel, wait a minute.
Hey, Colonel!
I want you personally
to go along with John Doe
and Miss Mitchell and
handle the press and the radio.
- Me?
- Yes.
I don't want to take
any chances, and Johnson?
Yes, D.B.?
Your crew will do the mop up job.
They'll follow John Doe into every town,
see that the clubs are properly organized
and the charters issued.
Right.
There are only eight flags up there now.
I want to see that map
covered before we get through.
This has been growing like wildfire.
If they made demands, I'd understand it,
but the John Does ask for nothing.
People are going off relief.
If this keeps up, I'll be out of a job.
Soon as he gets strong enough,
we'll find out what John Doe wants.
30 every Thursday,
60 at 60, who knows what?
I'm sorry, boss, they just won't let
anybody talk politics with him.
It's crazy.
We've got to get to him.
They represent millions of voters.
[0.3.1 I tell you, ladies and gentlemen,
this thing has been
nothing short of a prairie fire.
We've received so
many applications for charters
to the John Doe clubs,
we haven't been able to take care of them.
I'd hate to have
that many pins stuck in me.
This John Doe
convention is a natural.
It's going to put our city on the map.
Why, over 2,400 John Doe Clubs
are sending delegates.
Can you imagine that?
You, Mr. Mayor, will be the official host.
You will make
the arrangements for decorating the city,
parades, and a reception
for John Doe when he gets home,
and don't wear your high hat.
No high hat?
No high hat, and from you, Connell,
I want a special
John Doe edition every day
until the convention is over,
and now, if you will please,
step into the outer office
and look your prettiest because there are
photographers there to
take pictures of this committee.
Don't worry, D.B.
Everything'll be taken care of.
- Sure.
- Isn't it all too wonderful?
Mr. Mayor, would you
step down in front, please?
You ladies get close to him. That's it.
- Well, I don't get it.
- Get what?
Look, D.B., I'm supposed to
know my way around.
This John Doe movement's
cost you a fortune.
Now, this convention is gonna cost plenty.
Well?
Well, I'm stuck with two and two and
I'm a sucker if I can make four out of it.
Where do you come in?
I have the satisfaction
of knowing that my money
has been spent for a worthy cause.
I see.
I better stick to running the paper, huh?
I think maybe you better had.
Connell, I'd like to
have the John Doe contract,
all the receipts for the money
we advanced for the letter
Miss Mitchell wrote
for which I gave her 1,000 dollars.
Yes, sure.
Well, we leave for
the airport in half an hour.
Is that Johnny boy's room?
Better hustle him up.
- He'll be ready on time. He's packing.
- Oh, good.
Did you see his picture
on the cover of Time?
Yeah.
I gotta give you credit, Annie, girl.
I've handled a good many
big promotions in my time,
everything from
the World's Fair to a channel swimmer,
but this one has
certainly got me spinning,
and now, a John Doe convention, wow.
Say, if you could only get him to jump off
the City Hall roof on Christmas Eve,
I'd guarantee you
half a million people there.
- Charlie?
- Hmm?
What do you make of him?
Who, Johnny boy?
Well, I don't know what angle you want
but I'll give it to you quick.
Number one, he's got great yokel appeal,
but he's a nice guy.
Number two, he's beginning
to believe he really wrote
that original suicide
letter that you made up.
Number three, he thinks that
you're Joan of Arc or something.
Yeah, I know.
Number four, well,
you know what number four is.
He's nuts about you.
It's runnin' out of his ears.
You left out number five.
We're all heels, me especially.
Holy smoke.
Come in.
I'm all packed.
Good, I'll go and get Beany boy.
Okay, Charlie boy.
Can I help you pack?
No, thank you.
You care if I sit down, out here?
No.
You know, I had a crazy dream last night.
It was about you.
About me?
Yeah, sure was crazy.
I dreamt I was your father.
There was something
I was trying to stop you from doing.
So, I got up out of bed
and I walked right through the wall here,
right straight into your room.
You know how dreams are.
And there you were in bed,
but you were a little girl,
you know, about 10, and very pretty, too.
So I shook you, and
the moment you opened your eyes,
you hopped out of bed and
started running like the devil.
In your nightgown,
you ran right out the window there,
and you ran out over the tops of buildings
and roofs and everything
for miles and I was chasing you,
and all the time you were running,
you kept growing
bigger and bigger and bigger, and
pretty soon you were
as big as you are now, you know,
grown up, and all
the time I kept asking myself,
"What am I chasing her for?"
And I didn't know.
Isn't that a hot one?
Well, anyway, you ran into some place
and then I ran in after you
and when I got there,
there you were, getting married,
and the nightgown had changed
into a beautiful wedding gown.
You sure looked pretty, too,
and then I knew what it was I was
trying to stop you from doing.
Dreams are sure crazy, aren't they?
Well,
would you like to know
who it was you were marrying?
Oh, a tall handsome Ubangi, I suppose.
No, not that bad.
It was the fella
that sends you flowers every day.
What's his name, Mr. Norton's nephew?
Ted Sheldon.
Yeah, that's the one.
But here's the funniest part of it all.
I was the fella up there
doing the marrying, you know,
the Justice of the Peace or something.
You were?
I thought you were chasing me.
Well, yes I was,
but I was your father then, you see,
but the real me, John Doe, that is,
Long John Willoughby,
I was the fella up there with a book.
You know what I mean?
I guess so.
Then what happened?
Well, I took you across my knee
and I started spankin' ya.
That is, I didn't do it.
I mean, I did do it, but it wasn't me.
See, I was your father then.
Well, I had you across my knee and I said,
"Annie, I won't allow you to marry a man
that's... that's just rich
or that has his secretary
send you flowers.
The man you marry
has got to swim rivers for you.
He's got to climb high mountains for you.
He's got to slay dragons for you.
He's got to perform
wonderful deeds for you!"
Yes, sir, and all the time,
the guy up there,
you know, with the book,
me, just stood there
noddin' his head and he said,
"Go to it, Pop, whack her one for me,
because that's just
the way I feel about it too."
So he says,
"Come on down here
and whack her yourself."
So I came down
and I whacked you a good one.
See, then he whacked you,
and I whacked you another one.
We both started whacking you like...
Well, if you're through whacking her,
come on, let's get going.
Okay, fellas, right in here.
You go out the side entrance.
There's a bunch of
autograph seekers out front.
We'll be down with the bags in a minute.
Come on, don't make
a government project out of this.
Hi, Beany.
When's our plane take off again?
Couple of minutes.
How many people do
you think we've talked to already,
outside the radio, I mean?
Oh, I don't know, about 300,000.
300,000.
What makes them do it, Ann?
What makes them come and listen and get up
their John Doe Clubs the way they do?
I've been trying to figure it out.
Look, John, what we're handing them
are platitudes,
things they've heard a million times.
Love thy neighbor,
clouds have silver linings,
turn the other cheek, it's just--
Oh yeah, I heard 'em a million times too,
but... there you are.
Maybe they're like me,
just beginning to get an idea
what those things mean.
I never thought much about people before.
They were always just
somebody to fill up the bleachers.
The only time I worried about them was
when they didn't come in to see me pitch.
You know, lately I've been watching them
when I talk to them.
I can see something in their faces.
I could feel that
they were hungry for something,
you know what I mean?
Maybe that's why they came.
Maybe they're just lonely and
wanted somebody to say hello to.
I know how they feel.
I've been lonely and hungry for something
practically all my life.
All aboard, folks.
We'll have the city behind us.
Yeah, that's true.
Oh, somebody else sitting here?
No, no, no, that's your seat.
And this is your coat.
Mine?
A little token of appreciation.
Oh!
Oh, it's beautiful, D.B.
I don't quite know what to say.
Oh, don't say anything at all.
Just sit down.
Oh!
Go ahead, open it, open it.
Oh. Oh, it's lovely.
And a new contract goes with it.
Well, come on, spring it.
You've got something on your mind.
Must be stupendous.
That's what I like about her.
Right to the point, like that.
All right, practical Annie, here it is.
Tomorrow night,
before a crowd of 15,000 people
and talking over a nationwide
radio hook-up,
John Doe will...
Announce the formation of a third party.
A third party?
Yes, the John Doe Party,
devoted entirely to the interests
of all the John Does all over the country,
which practically means...
90 percent of the voters.
He will also announce the third party's
candidate for the presidency,
a man whom he personally recommends,
a great humanitarian,
the best friend the John Does have.
Mr. D.B. Norton.
Yes.
Wow.
Glory, glory hallelujah
His truth is marching on
And although the opening of
the convention is hours off,
the delegates are already
pouring into the ball park
by the droves with lunch baskets,
banners, and petitions
asking John Doe not to jump off any roof.
No matter how you look at it,
it's still a phenomenal movement.
These John Does or the hoi polloi,
as you've heard people call them,
have been laughed at and ridiculed,
but here they are, gay and happy,
having traveled thousands of miles,
their expenses paid by their neighbors
to come here to pay homage
to their hero, John Doe.
And in these days of wars and bombings,
it's a hopeful sign
that a simple idea like this
can sweep the country,
an idea based on friendliness,
on giving and not taking,
on helping your neighbor
and asking nothing in return,
and if a thing like this can happen,
don't let any of your grumbling friends
tell you that humanity is falling apart.
This is John B. Hughes,
signing off now and returning you
to our main studio until nine o'clock,
when the convention will officially open.
Oh John, come in.
Say, I'm kinda...
It's raining out a little.
That's all right.
It's good to see you.
Sit down.
Thanks.
It's for Ann.
Oh, how nice.
- Thank you very much.
- Flowers.
I'm terribly sorry she isn't here.
- She isn't?
- No, she just left.
I'm surprised you didn't run into her.
She went over to Mr. Norton's house.
Oh.
Did you want to see her
about something important?
Yeah, well, no, it'll wait.
He's a nice man, isn't he?
Mr. Norton, I mean.
He's done an awful lot for the...
Well, say, my coat's pretty wet.
Afraid I might have
wet the couch a little.
Well, I guess I'll see her
at the convention later.
Yes, of course.
I'll see that she gets the flowers.
Thanks.
Good night, Mrs. Mitchell.
Good night, John.
Say, Mrs. Mitchell,
I... I'm kind of glad Ann isn't here.
You see, I came over here
hoping to see her alone
and kind of hoping I wouldn't,
too, you know what I mean?
There was something
I wanted to talk to her about.
Well, it can wait, I guess.
Good night.
Good night, John.
Hey, look, Mrs. Mitchell,
have you ever been married?
Well, sure you have.
Gosh, that's pretty silly.
Well, I guess
you must think I'm kinda batty.
Well, I guess I'd better be going at that.
John, my husband said,
"I love you. Will you marry me?"
He did?
What happened?
I married him.
Yeah, that's what I mean, see?
It was easy as all that, huh?
Uh-huh.
Yeah, but look, Mrs. Mitchell,
you know, I love Ann,
and it's gonna be awfully hard
for me to say it
'cause, well, you know, she's so wonderful
and, well, the best I ever was
was a bush league pitcher,
and you know, I think
she's in love with another man,
the one she made up,
you know, the real John Doe.
Well, that's pretty tough competition.
I bet you he'd know
how to say it all right,
but me, I get up to it
and around it and in back of it,
but I never get right to it,
you know what I mean?
So the only chance I've got is, well,
if somebody could
kinda give her a warning,
sort of, sort of prepare her
for the shock.
You mean, you'd like me to do it, hm?
Well, I was thinking, yeah, you know,
sort of break the ice.
Of course I will, John.
Gee whiz, thank you, Mrs. Mitchell.
Hey, you're okay.
This John Doe meeting is gonna be
one of the biggest
things that ever happened.
Why, they're coming from
all over, trains, boxcars, wagons.
- Look out!
- Hello, bodyguards.
Hey, had your dinner yet?
Not yet.
- That's all right.
- No, go ahead and have your dinner.
Wait a minute, John.
Hello, Mr. Connell.
How are you, John?
John, I want to
have a little talk with you.
What's--what's the matter,
are you falling?
Come here.
- Hey, boss.
- Oh, quiet, quiet, quiet.
Say, tell me something,
did you read the speech
you're going to make tonight?
No, I never read
the speeches before I make them.
I get more of a kick out of it that way.
Uh-huh, that's just
exactly what I thought.
Beany, go on down to the office,
tell Pop to give you the speech.
There's a copy on my desk.
Gee whiz, boss,
you know Mr. Norton told me
not to leave him, not even for a minute.
Go on, go on, go on, go on.
We'll be at Jim's Bar up the street.
You're a nice guy, John.
I like you.
You're gentle.
I always like gentle people.
Me, I'm hard, hard and tough.
I got no use for hard people.
Gotta be gentle to suit me.
Like you, for instance.
Yep, I'm hard,
but you want to know something?
I've got a weakness.
You'd never guess that, would you?
Well, I have.
Wanna know what it is?
"The Star-Spangled Banner."
Screwy, huh? Well, maybe it is,
but play "The Star-Spangled Banner,"
I'm a sucker for it.
Always gets me right here,
you know what I mean?
Yeah, it gets me right back here.
Oh, back there, huh?
Well, every man to his own taste.
You--you weren't old enough--
You weren't old enough for
the World War, were you, John?
No, no, of course not.
No, you must have been just a kid.
I was.
I was just ripe, and raring to go.
Know what my old man did when I joined up?
He joined up too.
Got to be a sergeant,
and here's the kick for you.
We were in the same outfit.
Funny, huh?
He was killed, John.
I saw him get it.
I was right there and
I saw it with my own eyes.
Me, I came out without a scratch.
That is, excepting my ulcers.
I should be drinking milk, you know.
This stuff is poison.
Hey, Tubby!
Yes, Mr. Connell?
- What do you say, huh?
- All right.
Yep, I'm a sucker for this country.
I'm a sucker for
"The Star-Spangled Banner"
and I'm a sucker for this country.
I like what we got here.
I like it!
A guy can say what
he wants and do what he wants
without having
a bayonet shoved through his belly,
and that's all right, isn't it?
You betcha.
Yeah, and we don't want anybody
coming around changing that, do we?
- No, sir.
When they do, I get mad.
I get boiling mad,
and right now, John, I'm sizzling.
I get mad for a lot of
other guys besides myself.
I get mad for a guy named Washington,
and a guy named Jefferson and Lincoln.
Lighthouses, John.
Lighthouses in a foggy world.
You know what I mean?
- Yeah, you bet.
- Hmm.
Listen, pal.
This fifth column stuff
is pretty rotten, isn't it?
Yeah, it certainly is.
And you'd feel like
an awful sucker if you found yourself
marching right
in the middle of it, wouldn't you?
You, 'cause you wouldn't
know it because you're gentle,
but that's what you're doing.
You're mixed up with a skunk, my boy,
a no-good, dangerous skunk.
Say, you're not talking
about Mr. Norton, are you?
I'm not talking about
his grandfather's pet poodle.
You must be wrong, Mr. Connell,
'cause he's been marvelous
about the John Doe Clubs.
Yeah?
Say, you're sold on this
John Doe idea, aren't you?
Sure.
Sure, I don't blame you, so am I.
It's a beautiful miracle,
a miracle that can only happen
right here in the good old USA,
and I think it's terrific.
What do you think of that?
Me, hard-boiled Connell,
and I think it's plenty terrific.
All right, now suppose
a certain unmentionable worm,
whose initials are D.B.,
was trying to use that
to shove his way into the White House,
so he could put the screws on,
so he could turn out
the lights in the lighthouses.
What would you say about that?
Nobody's gonna do that, Mr. Connell.
They can't use
the John Doe Clubs for politics.
That's the main idea.
Is that so?
Then what's a big political boss
like Hammett doing in town?
And a labor leader like Bennett,
and a lot of other big shots that are
up at D.B.'s house right now.
Wolves, John, wolves,
waiting to cut up the John Does.
Wait 'til you get a gander at that speech
you're gonna make tonight.
You're all wet.
Miss Mitchell writes the speeches.
Nobody can make
her write that kind of stuff.
They can't, huh?
Who do you think writes 'em, my aunt Emma?
What are you talk--I know she writes them
and gets a big bonus for doing them, too.
A mink coat and a diamond bracelet.
Don't write 'em?
Why, that gold-grabbing
dame would double cross
her own mother for
a handful of Chinese yen.
Shut up!
If you weren't drunk, I'd--
Hey, boss.
Here's the speech, boss.
Hey.
Go on and read it,
John, and then start sockin'.
Hey, wait a minute, Mr. Doe.
- Tubby.
- Yes, sir.
Better bring me a glass of milk.
I'm smoking too much.
Yes, Charlie?
Got everything all set?
Fine, John Doe been taken care of?
Good.
How many people
you think will be there, 15,000?
Oh my, that's fine.
Now listen, Charlie.
As soon as John Doe
stops talking about me,
I want you to start that demonstration,
and make it a big one, you understand?
Don't worry about that, 0.3.
My boys are there.
They'll take care of it.
What?
Yes, I'll be there 15 minutes
after I get your call.
Why, Mr. Doe!
Where are they?
In the dining room, sir.
Gentlemen, I think we're about ready
to throw that great big bombshell.
Yeah, well it's about time.
Even a conservative
estimate shows that we can count
on anywhere between
10 and 20 million John Doe votes.
Add to that the labor vote
that Mr. Bennett will throw in,
and the votes controlled
by Mr. Hammett and
the rest of you gentlemen
in your own territories,
and nothing can stop us.
As I said before, I'm with you, providing
you can guarantee the John Doe vote.
Don't worry about that.
You can count on me, on one condition.
Little Bennett's gotta be taken care of.
Didn't I tell you that everybody
in this room will be taken care of?
My agreement with you gentlemen stands.
I'm with you, D.B., but I still think
it's a very daring thing we're attempting.
These are daring times, Mr. Barrington.
We're coming to a new order of things.
There's too much talk
- been going on in this country.
- Certainly.
Too many concessions
have been made.
What the American
people need is an iron hand.
- You're right.
- That's true.
Quite right, D.B.
Discipline!
And now may I offer
a little toast to Miss Ann Mitchell,
the brilliant and beautiful lady
who is responsible for all this.
Miss Mitchell.
Mr. Norton, I'd like to
talk to you alone for a minute.
Oh, Miss Mitchell has
something to say to us.
Hello.
John, I'm so glad to see you.
I was terribly worried.
Did you write this?
Yes, I did, John,
but I had no idea what was going on.
- You didn't?
- No.
That's a swell bracelet you're wearing.
John, why aren't you
at the convention?
Is there anything wrong?
No, no, nothing's wrong.
Everything's fine.
So there's going to be
a new order of things, huh?
Everybody's gonna
cut himself a nice fat slice
of the John Does, eh?
You forgot one detail, Mr. Big Shot.
You forgot me,
the prize stooge of the world.
Why, if you or
anybody else thinks he's gonna use
the John Doe Clubs
for his own rotten purpose,
he's gonna have to
do it over my dead body.
Well, hold on a minute,
young man, hold on.
That's rather big talk.
I started
the John Doe Clubs with my money,
and I'll decide whether or
not they're being properly used.
No, you won't.
You're through deciding
anything and what's more,
I'm going down to
that convention and I'm gonna tell
those people exactly what you and all
your fine feathered friends here
are trying to cook up for them,
and I'm gonna say it
in my own words this time.
He'll ruin us, D.B.!
Wait a minute, wait a minute, fella.
My uncle wants to talk to you.
Listen to me, my son.
Before you lose your head completely,
may I remind you that I picked
you up out of the gutter,
and I can throw
you right back there again.
You've got a nerve
accusing people of things.
These gentlemen and I know what's best
for the John Does of America,
regardless of what tramps like you think.
Get off that righteous horse of yours
and come to your senses.
You're the fake.
We believe in what we're doing.
You're the one that was paid
the 30 pieces of silver.
Have you forgotten that?
Well, I haven't.
You're a fake,
John Doe, and I can prove it.
You're the big hero that's supposed
to jump off tall buildings and things.
You remember?
What do you suppose
your precious John Does will say
when they find out
that you never had any intention
of doing it,
that you were being paid to say so?
You're lucky they don't
run you out of the country.
With the newspapers and radio stations
that these gentlemen control,
we can kill the John Doe movement
deader than a doornail.
We'll do it too
the moment you step out of line.
Now, if you still want
to go to that convention
and shoot your trap off,
you go ahead and do it.
You mean to tell me you'd try to kill
the John Doe movement if you can't use it
to get what you want?
You bet your bottom dollar we would.
Well, that certainly is a new low.
Huh. I guess I've seen everything now.
You sit there back of
your big cigars and
think of deliberately
killing an idea that's made
millions of people a little bit happier,
an idea that's
brought thousands of 'em here
from all over
the country by bus and by freight
and jalopies and on foot so
they can pass on to each other
their own simple little experiences.
Why look, I'm just a mug and I know it,
but I'm beginning to understand
a lot of things.
Why, your type's as old as history.
If you can't lay
your dirty fingers on a decent idea
and twist it and squeeze it and stuff it
into your own pocket, you slap it down.
Like dogs, if you can't
eat something, you bury it.
Why, this is the one
worthwhile thing that's come along.
People are finally finding out that
the guy next door isn't a bad egg.
That's simple, isn't it?
And yet a thing like
that's got a chance of spreading
'til it touches every last
doggone human being in the world,
and you talk about killing it.
Well, when this fire dies down,
what's going to be left?
More misery, more hunger, and more hate,
and what's to prevent
that from starting all over again?
Nobody knows the answer
to that one, and certainly not you,
with those slimy,
bollixed up theories you got.
The John Doe idea
may be the answer, though.
It may be the one thing capable of saving
this cock-eyed world,
yet you sit back there
on your fat hulks
and tell me you'll kill it
if you can't use it.
Well, you go ahead and try.
You couldn't do it in a million years
with all your radio stations
and all your power because it's bigger
than whether I'm a fake,
it's bigger than your ambitions,
and it's bigger than all the bracelets
and fur coats in the world!
You bet it is, John.
And that's exactly what I'm going
down there to tell those people.
Wait a minute you ungrateful rat!
My uncle's been too good to--
He's getting away.
- John!
- Get me the Bulletin.
John!
I've always told you, D.B.,
you're playing with dynamite.
Don't let that girl get away.
Before he gets
through tonight, he'll ruin us all.
I'll stop him, I'll stop him cold.
Don't worry, I've been ready for this.
John!
Oh John, please listen to me.
Please, I can explain everything, John.
I didn't know what they were going to do.
Let me go with you, John.
John, please!
Go ahead, driver.
Ball park.
Let me explain it to you, John.
Please let me go with you.
Please, John.
Mr. Norton wants to see you.
Listen to me, Mayor Lovett.
You do as I say.
I want them both arrested.
You tell the police
department to pick up Connell.
- I've got the girl here.
- I've got the Bulletin.
I don't care what you charge them with.
If you're worried,
let them go in the morning,
but keep them in jail overnight.
Hello, Bulletin?
Put Pop Dwyer on.
With a banjo on my knee
I'm going to Louisiana
My true love for to see
It rained all night the day I left
The weather it was dry
The sun so hot, I froze to death
Susanna, don't you cry
Oh Susanna
Don't you cry for me
For I come from Alabama
With my banjo on my knee
Oh, Susanna
Don't you cry for me
For I come from Alabama
With my banjo on my knee
I'm going to Louisiana
My true love for to see
It rained all night the day I left
The weather it was dry
Three cheers for John Doe.
Hurray, hurray, hurray!
My country tis of thee
Sweet land of liberty
Of thee I sing
Land where my father died
Land of the pilgrims' pride
From every mountain side
Let freedom ring
Ladies and gentlemen.
One moment, John.
We'll begin with a short prayer.
Quiet, please.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let us have a moment of silent prayer
for the John Does all over the world,
many of whom are homeless and hungry.
Rise, please.
Everybody rise.
News boys, hundreds of yelling news boys
are swarming into the park like locusts.
- They're yelling, John Doe's a fake.
- Fake?
Federal investigation
urged by Chamber of Commerce.
How could he be a fake?
Must be some kind of a gag.
A what?
A gag, a gag!
Come on, come on, step on it!
Step on it, step on it!
You all know
your places now, so let's get going.
Wait for the signal.
Hey, mister, will
you autograph my balloon?
Sure.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is exactly what I came down here
to tell you about tonight.
Please, if you'll all just
be quiet for a few minutes,
I can explain this whole thing to you.
As you all know,
this paper is published by a man
by the name of DB. Norton.
Get back, you!
Wait a minute, everybody.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, ladies and gentlemen.
My name is D.B. Norton.
You all know me.
I accuse this man of being a faker.
We've been taken for a lot of suckers,
and I'm the biggest of the lot.
I spent a fortune
backing this man in what I believed
to be a sincere and
worthy cause, just as you all did,
and now I find out it's
nothing but a cheap racket,
cooked up by him and two of my employees
for the sole purpose of collecting dues
from John Does all over the country.
- That's a lie!
- It's not a lie!
Nickel and dimes to
stuff into their own pockets.
You can read all about
it in the newspapers there.
That's a lie!
- Listen, don't believe what he--
- Let go of me!
This man had no intention of jumping off
the top of a building.
He was paid to say so.
Do you deny that?
That's got nothing to do with it.
Were you paid for it or weren't you?
Yes, I was paid, but there has to be--
And what about the suicide note?
You didn't write that either.
- What difference does that make?
- Did you write it or didn't you?
- No, I didn't write it.
- Oh, you bet your life you didn't.
You look in your papers,
ladies and gentlemen,
and you'll find
Miss Mitchell's signed confession
that she was the one who wrote it.
Listen, folks, it's a fact that
I didn't write the letter.
Now you see, he admits it.
You're a fake, John Doe.
For what you have
done to all these good people,
they ought to run you out of the country,
and I hope they do it.
Speak up, John.
We believe you.
Please listen, folks.
Now that he's
through shooting off his face,
I got a couple of
things to tell you ab--
Come on, the rest of
you get in here and riot.
Break this crowd up, come on.
I'm sorry, folks,
but we can't hear him anymore.
Something's gone
wrong with the loudspeakers.
John Doe's a fake! Boo!
Say, they can't hear me.
This thing's not working.
Ladies and gentlemen.
This thing's bigger
than whether I'm a fake.
Look, Bert, you believe me, don't ya?
Sure, I believe you.
Walking my legs off picking up
5,000 signatures for a phony.
Well, there you are, Mr. Doe.
5,000 names asking
you not to jump off any roof.
Makes no difference, Bert.
The idea's still good.
We don't have to give up our club.
Yeah, well you can have it.
They're starting to throw things.
Somebody's going to get hurt.
I'm afraid it will be John Doe.
Listen to that mob.
I've got to go to him.
- Sorry, lady, I can't let you out.
- Oh, let me go!
I want to go to him!
Oh, please, please let me go!
- They're crucifying him. I can help him!
- Sorry, sister.
- We got orders to hold you.
- Orders from who?
Can't you see it's a frame-up?
- Ann, darling.
- Oh, Mother, they won't let me go.
They won't let me go.
Listen, folks.
You gotta listen to me, everybody.
Back to the jungle, you hobo.
Just another racket!
Stick to your clubs.
We've been fed baloney
so long we're getting used to it.
The idea is still good.
Believe me, folks.
Listen, John Does.
You're the hope of the world.
Police finally managed
to get him out of the park.
If that boy isn't hurt, it'd be a miracle.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this certainly looks like
the end of the John Doe movement.
Well, boys, you can chalk up
another one to the Pontius Pilates.
I should have been there.
I could have helped him.
He was so all alone.
A lot of us gonna be mighty ashamed
of ourselves after tonight.
We certainly didn't give
that man much of a chance.
Have some more coffee, Long John?
No thanks, Colonel.
Fake!
Racketeer!
Liar!
Cheat!
Impostor!
Why don't you jump?
Christmas Eve at midnight.
Goodbye, Mr. Doe.
You're a wonderful man.
God bless you, my boy.
Now get in there and pitch.
You're a fake,
John Doe, and I can prove it.
You're the big hero that's supposed
to jump off tall buildings and things.
You remember?
What do you suppose
your precious John Does will say
when they find out
that you never had any intention
of doing it,
that you were being paid to say so?
Christmas Eve, at midnight.
Silent night, holy night
Shepherds quake at the sight
Glories stream from heaven afar
Merry Christmas, sir.
Oh, Merry Christmas.
Christ the Savior is born
Who?
John Doe?
Is that screwball still around?
That dame's been calling all day.
Sure, sure, I know.
Yeah, at midnight, huh?
Okay, lady.
We'll have the place surrounded with nets.
They're laughing at me.
You're a sick girl, Ann.
You better take it easy.
Who are you calling now?
You called
that number not ten minutes ago.
Hello, Mr. Connell.
Have you seen him yet?
Now listen, Ann.
He can't possibly get
in without our seeing him.
I'm watching the side
door and the Colonel's out front,
so stop worrying.
Oh, thank you.
Why, Ann!
Ann, don't be foolish.
If this isn't the craziest, the battiest,
the looniest wild
goose chase I ever heard of.
Oh, shut up, Bert.
Sourpuss is right.
Yeah, well if he is, I'm a banana split.
That man's gonna be on that roof.
Don't ask me how I know, I just know,
and you know it as well as I do.
Sure, sure, I'd like
to believe in fairy tales,
but a guy that's a fake
isn't gonna jump off any roof.
I don't think he was
any fake, not with that face,
and any way,
what he stood for wasn't a fake.
Okay, honey, okay.
Elevators ain't runnin'.
Colonel.
You shouldn't've got out of bed, Miss.
Has he been here?
No.
Have you seen him?
I ain't seen him for a week.
Where's Connell?
He's watching the other door.
Oh, gee, you're swell.
No sense in going up there.
I been here for hours.
He ain't here.
Let me go, will ya?
Now, that's crazy.
It's 14 floors.
It's as far as the elevator goes.
We gotta walk up to the tower.
That tramp is
probably full of Christmas cheer
and asleep in some flophouse.
Let's go.
I've got to decorate my tree.
Well, I give up.
I don't what gave us the idea
he'd attempt anything like this.
I guess you're right.
I'm afraid the joke's on us.
Let's go.
I hope nobody finds out we've been here.
I wouldn't do that if I were you, John.
It'll do you no good.
The Mayor has policemen
downstairs with instructions
to remove all marks of identification
you may have on your person.
You'll be buried in Potter's Field,
and you'll have accomplished nothing.
I've taken care of that.
I've already mailed
a copy of this letter to Mr. Connell.
John, why don't
you forget this foolishness?
Stop right where you are, Mr. Norton,
if you don't want to go overboard with me.
I'm glad you gentlemen are here.
You killed
the John Doe movement, all right,
but you're gonna
see it born all over again.
Now, take a good look, Mr. Norton.
John!
Oh, John, don't do it!
I won't let you.
I love you, darling.
Oh, please, please don't give up.
We'll start all over again.
Just you and I.
It isn't too late.
The John Doe movement isn't dead yet.
You see, John, it isn't
dead or they wouldn't be here.
It's alive in them.
They kept it alive by being afraid of it.
That's why they came up here.
Oh, darling, sure
it should have been killed.
It was dishonest,
but we can start clean now,
just you and I.
It'll grow, John, and it'll grow big
because it'll be honest this time.
Oh, John, if it's worth
dying for, it's worth living for.
Oh, please, John!
Oh, oh please!
Please God, help me!
John!
John, look at me!
You want to be honest, don't you?
You don't have to die to
keep the John Doe idea alive.
Someone already died for
that once, the first John Doe,
and He's kept that idea
alive for nearly 2,000 years.
It was He who kept
it alive in them, and He'll go on
keeping it alive forever and always.
For every John Doe
movement these men kill,
a new one will be born.
That's why those bells are ringing, John.
They're calling to us.
Not to give up, but keep
on fighting, to keep on pitching.
Oh, don't you see, darling?
This is no time to give up.
You and I John, we, oh no!
Oh, no! No, John!
If you die, I want to die, too.
Oh. Oh, I love you.
Mr. Doe, you don't have to...
we're with you, Mr. Doe.
We just lost
our heads and acted like a mob.
What Bert's trying to say
is that we need you, Mr. Doe.
There were a lot of us
that didn't believe what that man said.
We were going to start
up our John Doe Club again,
whether we saw
you or not, weren't we, Bert?
And there were a lot of others
there were gonna do the same thing.
Well, Mr. Sourpuss even got a letter
from his cousin in Toledo.
I got it right here, Mr. Doe.
Only, it'd be a lot easier with you.
Please, please come with us, Mr. Doe.
Long John!
Mr. Doe!
Here, we'll help you with her.
She'll be all right.
Mr. Doe,
take her right down to the car.
We got a car right down there.
There you are, Norton, the people!
Try and lick that!