Compagnie, halte!
Compagnie, halte! Halte!
- Repos surplace!
- Repos surplace.
Whew.
Now listen here, fatheads.
We're back home again,
and just because you did a little fighting,
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking, "Well, here comes us.
Foreign Legion.
Each man a hero.
All the booze in the world made for us
and the women thrown in."
Well, you're wrong.
This time you're gonna behave yourselves
like gentlemen, even if it kills ya.
Yes, I'm talkin' to you.
You heard what I said.
Why don't you get in that line?
What are you doing with those fingers?
Nothing. Yet.
Get in there!
All packed up, sir. Ready to land.
Thank you, John.
There you are.
- I hope I haven't forgotten anything.
- Merci, monsieur.
You are very kind.
Your first voyage to Morocco?
Yes.
I make the trip quite often.
Perhaps I can be of some service.
I'd be happy to help you.
I won't need any help.
You can always reach me
at this address, mademoiselle.
Merci, monsieur.
- Good evening, Officer.
- Good evening.
Do you know who that woman is?
A vaudeville actress, probably.
Uh, just, uh, how do you know that?
Oh, we carry them every day.
We call them suicide passengers.
One-way tickets. They never return.
Well, the wanderer returns. How are you?
- When did you get back?
- Last night.
Alexander, I want you
to meet an old friend of mine.
Monsieur La Bessiere,
citizen of the world.
- Very happy.
- Citizen of the world.
- You're a Frenchman, aren't you?
- Yes.
- Uh, Miss Martin.
- Aren't you the painter La Bessiere?
- I paint when I find the time.
- He has all the time that he needs.
He would be a great painter
if he were not so rich.
Colonel Beauchard.
- Colonel.
- Charmed.
- Won't you join us?
- Please.
I'd love to, but, uh...
Isn't that Caesar and his wife?
Yes.
See you later.
Awfully nice to see you in Morocco again.
- I'm very happy to be here, even in this heat.
- Yes, it is hot.
And you, Madame Caesar.
- How have you been?
- I've been lonely.
We've missed you.
I feel greatly flattered.
Your rich friend is very democratic.
He can afford to be.
He's always chosen his own friends.
Adjutant Caesar was a captain
in the German Air Service
before joining the Legion.
Then perhaps you can give me
the history of his wife.
The less said about that the better.
The house is packed.
This is a great night for you.
If you make a hit,
you can stay here as long as you like.
Now, you may have heard of me
in Europe or not.
My house is patronized
by the finest society in Morocco.
Now, what was I going to say?
Oh, yes. Pick yourself a protector.
It will give you prestige.
An officer in the Legion.
They will tell you that
the officers in the Legion are unimportant,
that the common legionnaire is the thing.
They will tell you that private so-and-so
is a Russian prince or an ex-general,
that he joined the Legion
to forget his past.
Don't believe it.
The private in the Legion is nobody
at 75 centimes per day.
Thank you.
Pick the officers. They have the money.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It is no small task, as you know,
to supply my establishment
with new talent.
For some reason,
the artists I engage don't last very long.
It may be the heat. I do my best.
I pay the highest wages in Africa.
Mille grazie, signore e signori.
Mille grazie.
Anyway, I open the program tonight
with Mademoiselle Amy Jolly, a newcomer,
whom I hope you will receive
with your usual discriminating kindness.
If I remember correctly, Adjutant,
this audience shows
its "usual discriminating kindness"
by receiving its newcomers
rather unpleasantly.
What's the matter? You're late.
All right. Sit down. Go ahead.
Boo! Get off!
Aah!
May I offer you this glass
of champagne, mademoiselle?
Thank you.
À votre santé!
- May I have this?
- Of course.
Sing your number once,
and then sell the apples.
That's the most important thing.
Sell the apples.
Ten percent is yours, 90 percent is mine.
You'll make a fortune.
Yeah.
- Dame la flor.
- Over my dead body.
Dame la flor o me voy a casa.
Well, what's keepin' ya, baby?
We meet once more, monsieur.
I didn't anticipate this pleasure so soon.
Can I also have an apple?
- But I have no change for that.
- I hardly expected you'd have.
You are, again, very kind.
Mademoiselle, may I have the honor
of your company after the performance?
I'm sorry. I have disposed
of the balance of the evening.
- Some other time, perhaps?
- Of course.
An apple, sir? Madame?
Don't waste your time down there.
There's no money in the pit.
Isn't there?
Thanks for the flower, mademoiselle.
Can I offer you an apple too?
Lend me 20 francs, Barney.
That makes 60.
Two weeks' pay
is a lot of money for an apple.
You can have it for nothing, if you like.
Nothing doing.
I always pay for what I get.
I'd sit down if I were you.
You are pretty brave.
With women.
- What's the matter? Don't you like brave men?
- Perhaps.
Your change...
soldier.
Tom!
Hello.
Well, if it isn't Madame Caesar.
Tom, I must see you tonight.
See me tonight?
What if your husband sees you tonight?
He isn't going to see me.
Isn't he? What if he does?
Caesar's wife is above suspicion.
Yeah?
You may know something
about ancient history,
but I know something about husbands.
Tom.
Oh. It's you.
What's the matter?
Were you expecting someone else?
Can I offer you something?
- Cognac?
- Too hot.
Got any gin?
Yes.
- Cigarette?
- Thanks.
You've made this place look pretty nice.
It looks different now.
How do you know?
Have you been here before?
Well, I've been stationed in this town
for a long time.
Aren't you drinking?
No.
Well, salud.
You can smell the desert tonight.
Hot, isn't it?
Faded.
You can go now, soldier.
All right, lady. You won't have
any trouble getting rid of me.
Nothing like independence, is there?
Well, maybe I am independent with women.
You evidently don't think much of women.
I tell you, lady, it's their fault, not mine.
Been in the Legion very long?
Almost three years.
Three years? Seems like 300.
You sound tired of life.
I don't know whether I am or not.
I was when I joined this outfit.
How about you, mademoiselle?
Been on the stage very long?
Long enough.
- Tired of it?
- No.
You've got a lot of pictures with that man.
Your husband?
Husband? I never found
a man good enough for that.
That's just the way I feel about women.
How long ago was that picture taken?
Why?
That looks like Russian sable.
That coat's worth a load of shekels.
You still got it?
Don't be absurd.
If I still had that coat, I wouldn't be here.
What in the name of 10,000 corporals
did you come to a country
like this for, anyway?
I understand that men are never asked
why they enter the Foreign Legion.
That's right.
They never asked me,
and if they had I wouldn't have told.
When I crashed the Legion,
I ditched the past.
There's a foreign legion of women too.
But we have no uniforms, no flags.
And no medals...
when we are brave.
No wound stripes when we are hurt.
Look here.
Is there anything I can do to help you?
No.
I've heard that before.
Or do you think you can
restore my faith in men?
Not me.
You've got the wrong man for that.
Anybody who has faith in me is a sucker.
You better go now.
I'm... beginning to like you.
I've told women
about everything a man can say.
I'm gonna tell you something
I've never told a woman before.
I wish I'd met you ten years ago.
- Good night.
And thanks.
Well, the night's still young.
There's your key, lady.
If I were you, I wouldn't hand it around.
Tom.
I hear something.
Taking a walk?
Out for some fresh air?
No. I was looking for you.
It's a good thing you found me.
This quarter isn't safe at night.
I'd better take you home.
A hundred and twenty?
No. I wish I were.
I only feel so light to you
because your arms are so powerful.
Well, we're gonna get along
better this time.
Look out!
You'd better beat it.
There's gonna be trouble.
I'll give you one more chance.
Who were those two women?
Get your knee outta my hip.
Do you think the two women
you are trying to protect are worth it?
Well, I think one of them is.
Mon adjudant, Monsieur La Bessiere
is here to take you to his club.
Ask him to wait.
I'll be through in a minute.
- No, let him come in.
- Yes, sir.
Entrez, monsieur.
I didn't know that the military
was quite so busy.
Oh, yes, we are busy.
Sit down.
Perhaps you can learn something
about this country
which you think is so marvelous.
Got a match?
This little matter also involves
someone you're interested in.
I'm properly curious.
Bring in that woman.
Mademoiselle,
I think you know Monsieur La Bessiere.
- Very happy to meet you again, mademoiselle.
- Sit down.
I'm happy to meet you again.
Nice of you to have come, mademoiselle.
You were present at this affray
in which the prisoner,
with his customary bravery,
severely wounded two helpless natives.
Those natives were not helpless.
They attacked us.
Who was the other woman?
I don't know.
I'd like to know too.
Uh, do sit down.
The curious part of this is,
I am the only one
that really seems to know
who this other woman...
is.
If you do know,
you'd better keep it to yourself.
Careful, Caesar. Don't lose your temper.
Return the prisoner to the guardhouse.
Allez.
I appreciate your attempt...
to keep the name of my wife out of this.
That's all right, sir.
You may go now, mademoiselle.
I'll join you in a minute.
You look charming this morning.
What will they do to him?
I don't know.
Personally, I shouldn't care
to have Adjutant Caesar as an enemy.
I seem to have the unhappy faculty
of causing trouble wherever I go.
Oh, nonsense.
You know, I carry some weight with Caesar.
Possibly I can help you.
Every time a man has helped me,
there's been a price.
What's yours?
My price?
A smile.
I haven't got much more.
Shall we go?
Here you are. There's your pass.
You're a free man.
The door's wide open.
You can do as you like.
Till 7:00 in the morning.
- What's the idea of this?
- You're leaving for Amalfa Pass tomorrow.
Not me. I'm beginning to like this town.
- Tell Caesar I'm not going.
- You tell him yourself.
He's going along this time.
Who's going along?
You heard what I said.
Caesar's going along this time.
So that's what it is. That's why he didn't
recommend a court-martial.
He's gonna get me out on the road
and face me in the proper direction...
Well, you've got it comin' to ya, haven't ya?
You can't get away with murder all your life.
That's right, Sergeant.
Your argument's perfectly sound.
But nobody's gonna use me
for target practice.
I'm through with the army anyway.
I've been lookin' for the right kind of woman
all my life, and I think I've found her.
So I quit.
Take this dame and spend a few weeks
somewhere along the blue Mediterranean.
So you quit, eh?
Well, nobody's stopping you.
By the way, do you happen to remember
what the penalty is for desertion?
There's a hundred ways of dyin', brother,
and I'm pickin' my own way.
Come on. Get outta here!
He's in there.
I never saw such luck in all my life.
He's rich enough to buy Morocco.
And don't forget me.
You met him in my theater.
Good evening.
Your flowers are wonderful.
Any news of him?
I did what I could.
They will not court-martial him.
They're going to transfer him,
which means, of course,
that he will have to leave town.
Do you love him?
I don't know.
I hope not.
I can't accept this.
It's worth a fortune.
Anything of less value
would be unworthy of you.
I've got to change.
I'd like to take you away from here.
Would you?
Exactly what do you offer now?
The conventional thing.
My offer is highly respectable...
marriage.
You're a strange man.
Do you find it so strange
that I should be fond of you?
Must I answer you now?
I'd sleep better tonight if you did.
I don't think I care to take advantage
of your tempting offer.
- Then you're in love?
- No, I don't think I am.
Supposing you had never met
a certain private in the Foreign Legion.
What would your answer have been?
Might have been the same. I don't know.
I'm sorry to intrude, but I am leaving
for the Sahara in the morning,
and I just came to say good-bye.
I think you two want to be alone.
I understand you're leaving
on a rather strenuous journey.
May I wish you good luck?
Thanks.
- À bientôt, mademoiselle.
- À bientôt.
Will you be gone long?
When will I see you again?
Maybe never.
Something tells me
I'm not coming back this time.
Don't go.
That's just what I was thinking.
I could desert and board a freighter
for Europe tonight.
Why don't you?
I would in a minute if you'd go with me.
Will ya?
Yes.
I'll be back. Wait for me.
If you can spare one of your hands,
I would like to say good-bye too.
- Good-bye, mademoiselle.
- Why didn't you stay last night?
I had a few other calls to make.
- Who are those women?
- Those women?
I would call them the rear guard.
How can they keep pace with the men?
Sometimes they catch up with them,
and sometimes they don't.
And very often when they do,
they find their men dead.
Those women must be mad.
I don't know.
You see, they love their men.
I don't see why we have to
keep gettin' down all day.
We only have to get up again.
Anyhow, those walking bed sheets
can't shoot straight.
If you don't like this war,
why don't ya quit?
Anyway,
I thought you were gonna desert.
I've turned decent, Sergeant. Decent.
What did you say?
Decent. I'm in love.
Garde-à-vous!
You'd better not go in.
- What's wrong, Lo Tinto?
- What's wrong?
She's been drinking like a fish.
And don't send any more flowers in pots.
She threw the last one at me an hour ago.
Hello there!
Bonsoir, mademoiselle.
How do you like me now?
You seem gay tonight.
Have you had good news?
Have you heard from Private Brown?
Not badly written for a soldier.
Perhaps it was for the best.
Give me a drink.
Call my chauffeur, Lo Tinto.
You're losing your headliner tonight.
Good. I'm not losing anything.
She's been no use to me for three weeks!
Envoyez une patrouille.
Legionnaire Brown.
Legionnaire Brown!
Well, I had the right hunch, didn't I?
That's too bad, Brown.
Wait a minute.
Give me those 20 francs you owe me.
You know, that lady-killer
wasn't a bad soldier at that.
Destroy that machine gun.
May I go too, sir?
You're not at all excited.
Reading on the night of our engagement dinner
while we're all waiting for you?
Everybody's here.
I didn't think they would come.
On the contrary, they're delighted
to witness the unconditional surrender
of the most exacting bachelor
in the world.
I know.
You want to thank me
for making you happy.
You want to thank me for giving you
those pearls this morning.
You want to thank me for this
and you want to thank me for that...
Shall we go down now?
Anything wrong?
Caesar was killed.
I received the news this morning.
Oh.
Legionnaire Tom Brown
will probably come back tonight.
Is his company returning?
What's left of it.
You don't need to be concerned
about him, dead or alive.
There's still time to tell me.
Do come. They are waiting.
Mohammed.
Pick up those pearls
and take them to my room, please.
Where's Tom Brown? Was he killed?
Not so rough, mademoiselle.
I'm liable to fall apart.
We left him at Amalfa.
You can't kill that long drink of water.
Is he badly hurt?
Well, we didn't go down there
for any entertainment.
I gotta get some sleep.
Alexander, don't you think it
unusually hot this month?
No, I don't think so.
Oh, you always disagree with me.
When I came to Morocco as a boy,
it snowed in the summer.
Have you heard that before,
Monsieur La Bessiere?
I wasn't listening, Colonel.
What did you say?
When I came to Morocco as a boy...
Uh, what did I say?
When you came to Morocco as a boy,
it rained or... or something.
That was it.
I must go to him.
They left him at Amalfa.
- Is he badly wounded?
- I hope not.
Please don't disturb yourselves.
Sit down.
I don't mind you hearing this.
Why not let me send a telegram
and learn the details?
If his condition is serious,
we can drive down tomorrow.
I'm going now.
Order the car and pack my bag.
You see, I love her.
I'd do anything to make her happy.
Is there a Legionnaire Brown here?
Brown?
No, there's no Legionnaire Brown here.
Are you sure?
Well, he might be
under some other name.
Have a look.
Hello, mademoiselle.
What are you doing down here?
I'm looking for Legionnaire Tom Brown.
Oh, you don't find him down here.
Diese verdammte Schweinehund!
He make believe
that he had been hurt very badly.
They find out
and put him in another company.
Is he still in town?
He's around the corner
at the Christine's.
And don't forget to tell him
to pay me the 60 francs that owes me!
Who is this girl?
Wouldn't do you any good if I told you.
You love her very much?
Yup.
Poor boy.
¿Es tu novia?
Cállate.
What are you doing
in this part of the world?
I heard you were wounded.
Not me. I never felt better in my life.
Are you married?
No.
Why didn't you return
with your company?
Aren't you going to marry
that rich friend of yours?
Of course.
Are you sure?
I don't change my mind.
Well, then I wish you all the luck
in the world, mademoiselle.
Rassemblement!
Back to the barracks!
Antreten. Ihr Schweinehunde, raus!
Gonna be a thirsty march.
Have you lost something?
Can I help you?
Go on. Beat it.
I forgot my knife.
You forgot to say good-bye too.
We leave at dawn.
Come and see us off, will you?
Maybe.
Good-bye, mademoiselle.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, sir.
Good luck, Legionnaire Brown.