How do you get into
this place, mr. Milton?
Around the back through
the mews in sladen street.
Eh, looks as
though it might do.
Let's go around.
What might you be
needing it for, mr. Martin?
We store antiques and
furniture in general.
Well, then it
ought to suit you.
It's fireproof and
thoroughly dry.
Come this way.
Not much left of the
booking office now.
Well, moran, mr.
Martin seems to have
done his work very
satisfactorily.
I carried out
your instructions
to the letter, professor.
Now, moran, let's
get our bearings.
That wall, I take it,
faces pelham street.
Exactly, originally the
main entrance to the station.
And the lift shaft?
Here on this side.
The lift's at the bottom.
Eighty feet below.
Quit a drop.
Eh, moran?
The power was
cut off, of course,
when they closed the station.
How about lunch, mr. Holmes?
What do you fancy?
A nice little bit of boiled cod?
My
Dear, mrs. Hudson,
life is sufficiently
dull at the moment
without adding boiled cod.
But there's nothing
better for an invalid.
Yes, but I object
to being referred to
as an invalid, mrs. Hudson.
I'm a little rundown possibly.
So I should think!
With all the tobacco you smoke,
you'll be getting
seccotine poisoning next.
Well, in that
case, mrs. Hudson,
I shall always stick to you.
Oh, mr. Holmes.
That'll be the doctor.
Dr. Watson.
- Hello, watson.
- Hello.
What's the
matter with you fellow
have you caught cold?
No it's this
infernal atmosphere.
I suppose
it is pretty thick.
Thick, my dear holmes
it's intolerable!
You could cut it with a knife.
Why you can open the window.
You walked here I perceive.
Yes.
And on the left-hand
side of the street.
Yes, that's right.
But how in the
world did you know?
My dear fellow,
it's simplicity itself.
You've got a little reddish
soil adhering to your shoe.
They're pulling
up the flagstones
in front of the wigmore
street post office,
and as the pavement is covered
with that reddish soil,
it's difficult to
avoid treading in it.
The post office is on the
left-hand side of the street.
Oh, of course, when
you put it like that,
it does sound simple.
Elementary, my dear watson.
- Elementary.
- By the way, holmes,
I hope you've decided to take
that holiday I
prescribed for you?
Well, up to nine
o'clock this morning,
I was distinctly
averse to the idea.
But I've received a letter
from an old friend of ours
which inclines me
to change my mind.
I'm delighted to hear it.
Who's it from?
Well, my dear fellow,
I'll read it to you.
"My dear holmes, I am
sending you and the doctor
"yet another invitation
to visit me here.
"Believe it or not it's 20 years
"since you disposed of the hound
"of the baskervilles for me."
Goodness, can you
believe that, watson?
Seems impossible to me.
Very good.
"My daughter diana is anxious
to make your acquaintance.”
Yes, but she's engaged, watson.
To young trevor, a
neighbor of theirs.
"I know you hate the country,
"just as I hate london,
"but stretch a
point and come down
"for a week or two with watson.
"Yours ever, henry baskerville."
Father's
asked sherlock holmes
to come here for a few days.
Why?
The family hound
come to life again?
Oh, don't be absurd.
Hello, you two youngsters.
Oh, dad do you really
think there's any chance
of mr. Holmes coming here?
Well, as you know
I haven't been able
to persuade him in the past.
For the post, sir?
Oh, thank you jack.
Holmes is a creature of habit.
He likes to bury
himself in baker street
and work out his
problems with the aid of
I don't know how many
ounces of tobacco a day.
I must say I'd
like to meet him.
He sounds a terribly
brainy sort of chap.
I wonder if he's any
good at spotting winners.
No, no.
Holmes's hobby is
spotting criminals, jack.
I don't think racing's
quit in his province.
Well, watson, what about it?
Could you get away
for a fortnight?
Yes, I think so.
The hope for an epidemic of
measles hasn't materialized.
Things are rather slack.
I could get a locum
to carry on for me.
Good, good, and I
will stretch a point
and write to baskerville.
Inspector lestrade, sir.
Good
morning, lestrade.
Anything important on hand?
Good morning, mr. Holmes.
- How are you, doctor?
- How do you do?
You've the air of something
unusual having occurred.
Well, yes, mr. Holmes
well, tell me about it.
Here you'll find a
cigar on the table.
Thank you.
I'm leaving london.
Well, god bless my soul,
this is a very sad
development, watson.
With professor moriarty,
that napoleon of
crime, still at large?
You and your professor
moriarty, mr. Holmes.
You seem to see his hand behind
every other crime
on the calendar.
The yard doesn't share
your views I'm afraid.
They think it's all moonshine.
Well, moonshine's a brighter
thing than fog, lestrade.
However, tell me
where you're going.
- Exeter.
- Exeter?
Promoted chief inspector.
Reorganizing the
traffic I presume.
No, no, barchester races.
Half the west country turn up,
and they make exeter
their headquarters.
I see, well, good
luck, lestrade.
If your talent for organization
is equal to your
flair for detection,
barchester races should be
something of a sensation.
Thank you, sir,
and in case it's any use to you,
the chief constable colonel ross
gave me something good
for the barchester cup.
Oh, what is it?
His own horse silver blaze.
Well, I'm afraid
I'm not much of a
betting man, lestrade,
but watson here thinks he
knows something about racing.
Silver blaze.
He was round about 10 to
one at the last call over.
You won't get anything like
that on him tomorrow, doctor.
It's an open secret that
he did a trial yesterday,
which puts him among the
greatest steers of all time.
You're becoming quite
a tipster, lestrade.
Yes, our
handy guide to the turf.
Well, anyway he
carries my money.
Better to be on a
certainty at short odds,
than down the course
to 100 to one, say I.
Well, there you are, watson.
Make a note of that.
As a matter of fact,
the doctor and I
are going down to
the west country
to stay with sir
henry baskerville,
so we may possibly see you.
I hope so, mr. Holmes,
and if you do feel like
having a flutter, doctor,
don't forget silver blaze.
Watson put a bet on for me.
What?
Looks fit enough, colonel.
Best horse I ever
owned, eh, straker?
You're right, sir.
It'll take a good
one to beat him.
You fancy lord merton's
horse, don't you?
Desborough, yes, I
have got a bet on him.
We'll see how they stand
in the betting tomorrow.
There's a call over today
at the victoria club.
We'll probably hear
all about it tonight.
Oh, before I go,
could I have a word
with you alone, colonel?
Certainly.
What is it?
Well, I want to
ask you a favor
I hope you won't mind.
Would you lend me...
Well, I really want 500 pounds.
Monkey!
That's pretty cruel, isn't it?
I'm in a devil of a hole
or I wouldn't ask for it.
Yeah, but why come to me?
Why not sir henry baskerville?
Well, it's to do
with racing debts,
and sir henry's
terribly down on racing.
Well, have you have
you tried your bank?
You've got security.
Mortgaged up to the hilt.
Well, what about what about
one of those financial firms?
No that's no good.
I've been dealing
with old bingham.
He won't spring another fiver.
What albert bingham
the money lender?
No, I'm sorry there's
nothing doing.
Well, thanks all the same.
Stay here, prince, I may
want you again shortly.
Those are the
instructions, barton.
Sure.
I'm expecting a
visitor in a few minutes.
You'd better stand by
with prince till he goes.
Very good, professor.
Bring him in.
Sit down, mr. Stanford.
I understand you
wish to consult me.
Yes, that's right.
What is your business?
Look here, professor.
I'm a commission
agent in a big way.
I am fully aware of
who and what you are.
Well, in that case
I'll come to the point.
I've laid bets amounting
to over 150,000 pounds
against silver blaze
at the barchester cup
when his price was
100 to six against.
You follow that?
Perfectly.
His trial yesterday
proves he's a smasher,
a world-beater.
At the call-over at the
victoria club tonight
he finished up a firm favorite
at seven to two against.
I can't lay off
anything to speak of,
so to cut a long story short,
if silver blaze wins the cup,
I go out of business.
I see, and you wish me to
arrange that silver blaze
does not come under
starter's orders, is that it?
Exactly.
Hmm, I must
confess that this is
a somewhat unusual
experience even for me.
I've had some little
association with the turf,
merely as a form of recreation,
and I have found in general
that bookmakers are an
honorable body of men.
See here, professor,
I haven't come here...
Sit down!
I presume you are aware
that what you're asking
is out of my usual
line of business.
I thought you were prepared
to take on anything
for a consideration.
Quite.
Depends on the size
of the consideration.
Well, I've told you
what I stand to lose.
What's your price?
Ten-thousand pounds.
Pretty
steep, isn't it?
It's not my custom to argue
about these matters,
mr. Stanford.
Take it or leave it.
- Very well.
- Then that settles it.
Now, mr. Stanford,
a few details.
Where is the horse trained?
King's pyland, dartmoor.
Colonel ross's training stables.
Ross.
Very good.
Now give me all the information
you can about the
colonel's employees
and their neighbors on the moor.
Do you know anything about them?
Yes, it so happens that I do.
As far as neighbors, there's
henry baskerville, jack trevor,
and silas brown who trains
for lord manston at capleton.
As to his employees,
there's straker his
trainer, mrs. Straker,
hunter, the head lad,
the usual stable boys.
Who's the bloke you
drove here to see the boss?
A fellow named
stanford, bookie.
Did he tell you anything?
No, don't suppose
he'd come around here
to hand out tips do you?
So he's pretty
deeply involved.
Up to his neck.
I know everything about him.
He's bet with me for years.
He owes a packet to albert
bingham the money lender.
Bingham?
Lots of racing
people deal with him.
That's the name, moran.
Buy up all his
debts from bingham
and from any other
quarters you can find.
Don't haggle about the price.
Buy it quickly.
I want to get the whip
hand over that gentleman
at the earliest possible moment.
Very good.
When that's done,
you be ready to leave
with me for dartmoor.
I'm going home now, straker.
I shall be there if you want me.
Take every precaution.
That's all right, sir.
Hunter here sleeps in
his box every night.
His bed's pushed
across the door,
and he bolts himself
in from the inside.
No one could even attempt
to enter without waking him.
Good.
I can trust you, straker.
Tell me, jack.
What is the matter?
Nothing the
matter, dear, really.
Oh, yes, there is.
I noticed it the
moment you arrived.
You're worried about
something, aren't you?
Really, darling, it's nothing.
Here's the car.
They're here, dad.
Arrived have they?
Good.
Well, here we are, watson.
Come along.
My dear holmes.
Delighted to see you.
And we're delighted to come.
And you too, doctor.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Again looking at you both,
I can't believe it's been years.
Oh, you flatter us.
Come along I want you
to meet my daughter.
Oh, thank you.
Delighted.
Diana.
This is mr. Holmes
and dr. Watson.
- How do you do?
- And mr. Trevor.
Now how about a whisky
and soda after your journey?
Oh, thank you.
I'm sure that's what dr.
Watson would prescribe.
Well, if I did, you
would automatically
refuse to take it.
He grows more obstinate
with the years, baskerville.
That's the way
with most of us.
Well, make yourselves
comfortable.
- Oh, thank you.
- Well, now baskerville,
tell me something
about yourself.
Oh, no, no, no,
holmes, that won't do.
You've got to do that.
Father's has been promising
us all a treat, mr. Holmes.
We shall see you in action.
Yes, with sir
henry as the victim.
I mean that we should see
mr. Holmes do his stuff.
His stuff?
That's a modern
expression, watson,
signifying to display
one's talents.
That's right!
I want mr. Holmes to tell
us what father's been doing
for the last 20 years
just by looking at him.
You evidently have great faith
in my abilities,
ms. Baskerville,
but I'm afraid there's
very little data.
I merely observe that
since we last met,
your father has
taken to billiards.
That he's recently played a
hundred up with mr. Trevor.
So, astutely correct,
holmes but how...
Oh, my dear fellow,
it's simplicity itself.
I observed that both you
and mr. Trevor have traces
of blue chalk between
the forefinger and thumb
of your left hands
put there, obviously,
to steady the cue.
There I hope that
satisfies you, diana.
Well, I expect you'd
like to see your rooms.
I'll show you, mr. Holmes.
You'll stay and dine, jack?
Well, thanks.
If you'll take me as I am
and don't mind my rushing
off immediately afterwards.
I've got to ride over the
moor to king's pyland.
I'm trying to get straker
to persuade colonel ross
to buy one of my ponies.
That's all right,
my boy, come along.
How's that curry
coming along, lizzie?
Just about ready,
mrs. Straker.
Leave some aside for
hunter when you've dished up.
Take it across to him
in silver blaze's box.
Very good, ma'am.
Everything all right, hunter?
Yes, thank you sir.
- I do hope mr.
- Straker isn't late.
He especially asked for curry.
He shouldn't be
long now, ma'am.
Dinner's ready, jim.
All right, I'll just
go and have a wash.
Lizzie, don't forget
hunter's supper.
Oh, no, ma'am, I'm
keeping it hot for him.
All right, then you
can bring ours in now.
Very good, ma'am.
- Dear.
- Hello.
Mm, smells good.
What?
Yes, you only just came in time.
Well, I've had
a lot to attend to.
Is the colonel coming
over again before the race?
He didn't say so.
He seemed quite satisfied
with the arrangements I made.
Who are you
sending in the horse box
with silver blaze?
Well, I'll
send hunter, of course,
and simpson will probably
follow along with him.
What's the betting
on silver blaze now?
Seventy-two, I think,
was the last call over.
Here's your supper, ted.
Thanks.
- Night, ted.
- Bye-bye, liz.
Is anybody about?
It's you, mr. Trevor.
Is straker at home?
Yes, sir.
Look after the mare
for me will you, simpson?
Very good sir.
Mr. Trevor.
I hope I'm not butting in.
Not a bit come in.
I just called around to
have a chat about that pony.
Well, sit down.
Will you have a drink?
Oh, please.
- A biscuit?
- No, thank you.
Whose horse is that, simpson?
Mr. Trevor's, ma'am.
Haven't you seen him?
He wanted the guv'nor.
I suppose he came while
I was in the kitchen.
Well, that's really
all I came about.
I want the colonel to
have the first refusal.
You might tell him
the price I've quoted,
and let me know what he says.
Very good, mr. Trevor.
Oh, er...
Oh, well nevermind.
Mary.
Where have you been?
Just for a turn
around the yard.
Did you have a look
at silver blaze?
No, I just went
for a breath of air.
By the way, is silver blaze
doing another trial tomorrow?
Yes, the last before the race.
Well, I'm for an early night.
There doesn't seem to
be much to stay up for.
Here, ted, wake up!
What the devil's happened?
Where's the guv'nor?
Why isn't he in the yard?
What's up?
Is anything wrong
with silver blaze?
He's gone.
Gone?
Yes.
And hunter's dead.
Dead.
You must have a round
this morning, holmes.
Thank you, I should like to.
There're a few improvements
since you were here last.
Yes.
Hello, why it's ross.
Who's that with him?
Well, unless
I'm much mistaken,
that's my old friend lestrade,
recently a member of
the london police force
now transferred to exeter.
- Hello, ross.
- Morning, baskerville.
This is an early visit.
Hello, lestrade.
I didn't expect to
see you so soon.
You are mr. Sherlock
holmes I presume?
- Yes.
- And this is dr. Watson.
How do you do?
I'm told I could
find mr. Trevor here.
Why, yes, here is mr. Trevor.
I want a
word with you, mr. Trevor.
Say, ross, what's happened?
There's a devil
to pay, baskerville!
Last night silver
blaze was stolen!
Hunter my head lad poisoned
and straker has vanished!
What's this got
to do with jack?
That's what I'm
here to find out.
Well, perhaps we'd
better go indoors.
Come along, ross.
Now, mr. Trevor,
I'm in charge of this case,
and I want to ask
you a few questions.
At the same time
I must warn you,
that anything you say
may be used in evidence.
You were at king's
pyland last night.
I rode over from
here after dinner, yes.
Why were you over at
king's pyland, mr. Trevor?
To see straker about
the sale of a polo pony.
- That all?
- Yes. Why?
You didn't make that an excuse
to try and get information
from the stable boys about
silver blaze for instance?
What the devil do you mean?
Not interested in
silver blaze perhaps?
I'm interested in
the race certainly,
so are thousands
of other people.
Now, mr. Trevor...
Just one moment, lestrade,
if you would allow me.
Mr. Trevor, you say
you've discussed
the sale of a polo
pony with mr. Straker.
Was anyone else present?
No.
What not even, mrs. Straker?
Quite.
Now, mr. Trevor, you said
just now that you weren't
particularly interested
in silver blaze.
You haven't by any chance to
have your betting book on you?
I think so. Why?
Do you mind if I see it?
It's my duty to tell you
that I can't demand to see it.
Not now that is but...
Here it is.
I see you bet desborough,
the second favorite
to the barchester cup,
to win you 5,000
pounds, mr. Trevor.
Five thousand!
But, jack, you told me you
only had a few pounds on it.
I'm sorry, dear.
I had my own reasons.
Before you go any
further, lestrade,
may I ask if it's your intention
to apply for a warrant
against, mr. Trevor?
Not at the moment, mr. Holmes.
It was my duty to warn him.
I'm in your hands, inspector.
I won't run away.
As a justice of the peace,
I will be answerable
for mr. Trevor.
You'd better stay here, jack,
while the
investigation's going on.
Well, thank you, sir henry.
Very well.
Now, mr. Holmes,
I may as well be frank with you.
There are things in this case
which completely baffle me.
Really, you surprise me.
I was saying to colonel ross
that I'd be glad of
your cooperation.
Well, the case certainly
has some points of interest,
but what does colonel ross say?
Personally, I should
prefer to leave the case
in the hands of the
official police force.
If you don't mind my
saying so, mr. Holmes,
I've not much use for
amateur detectives.
Oh, come, colonel, come.
Even they have their uses.
Of course I've heard
of you, mr. Holmes.
They say you've
never been beaten.
Well, it's true I've
been generally successful.
Well, I hope you
will be so with me.
I wish to leave
no stone unturned
to avenge straker
and recover my horse.
Very well, lestrade,
I am at your service.
Thank you, mr. Holmes,
I'll be getting along.
I'll see you later
at king's pyland.
Really, holmes,
I must protest.
You're down here to
recuperate you know.
Undoubtedly, my dear doctor,
but only last night
you suggested a tonic.
Well, here is one ready-made.
Yes, please, mr. Holmes,
for my sake and jack's.
Well, watson, that settles it.
Ms. Baskerville,
you may rely upon
my doing all I can.
I had to have the body taken
to the cottage to
make my examination.
But nothing else
has been disturbed.
Well, that hasn't
taken us long, colonel.
Oh, no, there are very
good roads in devonshire.
Mr. Holmes is coming
over from baskerville hall
to give us what help he can.
He's been some slight
assistance to me in the past,
and anyway he can't do any harm.
Here is mr. Holmes.
Dr solter,
mr. Sherlock holmes, dr. Watson.
How do you do?
This is silver blaze's box.
What in your opinion was
the cause of death, doctor?
An overdose of powdered opium.
In that case, he would
have died in his sleep.
That is so.
The remains of
the lad's supper I presume.
Yes,
curried mutton.
Oh, curry?
That significant, lestrade?
I don't know, mr. Holmes.
Any food containing
sufficient poison
could cause death.
Oh, would it really?
Really, I hadn't
thought of that.
You must read my
little monograph
on the whole art of poisoning.
Did the people of the house
partake of the same dish
without any ill effects?
Yes, mr. Holmes.
Well, then what
is your theory?
Mr. Trevor while standing
at the open window,
passed his hand through,
and placed the poison
in the curried mutton?
Exactly, and quite
easily as you can see.
Well, and then what?
He opened the door
with a duplicate key,
took out the horse,
and led it to some
secret hiding place?
The evidence against
him is very strong.
But, it's purely
circumstantial.
Well, it'd be equally
easy for the murderer
with the aid of a stick or
a hunting crop to pull back
the bolt of the door.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, quite easy as
you say, lestrade.
Where is the stable boy
who discovered the crime?
Somewhere outside in the yard.
Would you let me see him?
Certainly, I'll fetch him.
Your name, simpson?
Yes, sir.
Opium's a distinct
taste, is it not, doctor?
- Yes.
- Not unpleasant,
but quite distinct.
Oh, quite.
I thought so.
Is this the boy?
Yes.
Now my lad,
you say that mr. Trevor
dismounted at the gates
and asked you to
water his horse.
- Yes, sir.
- And then?
He went towards
the cottage, sir.
And in doing so,
he would, of course, have
to pass silver blaze's box.
Yes, sir, he went
along that side.
But you didn't actually
see him pass the box?
No, sir, I had my back to him.
Yes.
Thank you, that'll do.
You can go back
to your quarters.
Very good, sir.
Would you like to question
mrs. Straker, mr. Holmes?
Not at the moment.
By the way, colonel,
there's another training
stable quite close I believe.
Yes, capleton.
Silas brown trains lord
manston's horses there.
Lord manston's desborough
is second favorite.
Yes.
Then with the exception
of baskerville hall
and trevor's place,
your only neighbor
would be silas brown?
Yes, I phoned brown at once
on the discovery of the crime.
And he knows nothing?
No.
And there's nothing
to connect mr. Trevor
with the capleton stable?
Nothing.
By the way, colonel,
have you an old shoe
of silver blaze?
Yes, here.
- How about this one?
- Oh, yes.
Yeah, thank you.
Thank you, I'll put it
in my pocket for luck,
and have you a
photograph of the horse?
I think so.
Will this do?
Perfect.
Thank you.
Do you mind?
Not at all.
Now, watson, let us transfer
our activities to the moor.
That building on the skyline
I presume is capleton.
Yes.
Look there's an
imprint of a hoof here.
Slight but quite distinct.
An exact fit.
And here a foot mark.
Good lord!
What's that?
Watson.
It's straker!
Obviously, he followed the
thief, caught him up here,
there was a struggle, and
he paid with his life.
And here's the torch he
used to trace the horse.
This is a very singular knife.
Surely, this is something
in your line, watson.
Oh, yes, it's what we
call a cataract knife.
Yeah.
As I thought.
The price for very
delicate work.
It's a curious weapon
for defense, lestrade?
The best
he could lay hands on
at the moment I suppose.
Mm, yes.
Yes, very possible.
No trace of blood I perceive.
Why that's straker's coat.
This is curious, lestrade.
I What, mr. Holmes?
It looks as
though the murderer
let him take his coat
off before the struggle.
Couldn't he have
taken it off afterwards?
Well, that's one explanation.
Though it's difficult
to see with what motive.
However, take it, lestrade,
and make a careful inventory
of everything you
find in the pockets.
Very good, mr. Holmes.
And now I suggest that you
and the colonel return
to king's pyland
and arrange for the
removal there of the body,
and then perhaps you'd be good
enough to meet us with a car
by that bridge in
say an hour's time.
Dr. Watson and I are going
to take a little
walk over the moor.
Very good, mr. Holmes.
In an hour's time.
Now, watson, let
us leave the question
of who killed straker
for the moment,
and confine ourselves
to finding out
what has become of the horse.
Oh, how are you
going to set about it?
Well, a horse will
always herd with its kind.
Silver blaze, if
left to himself,
would either have
returned to king's pyland
or gone to capleton.
If my assumption is correct,
that is our direction.
Hoof prints again.
Let's carry on a little further.
Look, watson.
Here.
These are man's footprints
beside the horse's.
A man wearing square-toed boots.
But the horse
was alone before.
Precisely it was alone before.
Here we are here's
the same footprints.
This time they're
coming from capleton.
- From capleton?
- Yes, let's follow the trail.
Looks in the pink doesn't he?
Yes,
ready for anything.
Aren't you desborough?
Let's see what is
in the betting today?
Five to
one second favorite.
Look for anything, watson.
We don't want
any loiterers here.
I only want to ask a question.
Am I too early to
see mr. Silas brown?
Well, I don't know, sir.
He was up rather
late last night.
What's this, orson?
No gossiping!
Get on with your job!
Very good, sir.
And what the devil
do you want here?
Five minutes talk
with you my good, sir.
I've no time for talking!
And we don't want
no strangers here.
This is a matter
of vital importance.
It's a lie.
Very well.
Shall we talk it
over here or inside?
All right, come on.
I shan't keep you more
than a few minutes, watson.
Oh, that's
all right, holmes.
Now, mr. Brown,
I'm at your service.
Well, I'm glad you realize
that it's no use
trying to bluff me.
Yes, that's quite a clever
bit of faking, brown.
Don't give me away.
I'll return the horse.
Very well,
but providing you
do as I tell you.
Now, brown, no tricks.
You understand?
I understand, sir.
Your instructions shall
be carried out faithfully.
Very well, you'll
guard him night and day
and engage a special
detective escort
when you take him to barchester.
I will do everything
you say, sir.
The horse shall be there.
Very well.
But remember...
You may trust me, sir.
Yes.
Yes, I think can.
I'm sorry to keep you, watson.
Oh, it's all right.
Well, the more
perfect compound
of a bully and coward
than silas brown,
I've seldom met really.
The horse is there then?
Yes, of course he
tried to bluff it out,
but I described
to him so exactly
what his actions
had been last night,
that he's convinced
I was watching him.
Well, what actually
happened, holmes?
I'll tell you.
Now I must go and collect
mr. Holmes and dr. Watson.
I must say I haven't
had much hope
of their having found the horse.
I'll be here
when you come back.
But surely brown was
running a tremendous risk.
Oh, my dear watson, silas
is an old horse faker.
He left nothing to chance.
You actually saw the horse?
Yes.
Well, I must say this for silas,
he certainly made
a good job of it.
But aren't you afraid
to leave it with him?
No, my dear fellow,
he'd as guard it as
the apple of his eye.
He knows that his
only hope of mercy
is to produce it safe.
Horse stealing is
a serious crime.
Colonel ross doesn't
impress me as a man
who'd be likely to show
much mercy in any case.
Well, the matter doesn't
rest with colonel ross.
I follow my own methods,
and tell as much or
as little as I choose.
I don't know whether
you've observed it, watson,
but the colonel's manner to
me has been somewhat rude.
I'm inclined to keep
him in suspense.
Say nothing about the horse.
Of course not, holmes,
without your permission.
Good old watson.
Here's lestrade with the car.
Well, mr. Holmes,
seen anything?
Yes, we've seen some very
interesting things, lestrade.
Boots.
Boots?
Yes, square-toed boots.
Where
now, mr. Holmes?
Straker's cottage, please.
I hope mr. Holmes
won't be long.
I want to phone
the story through
in time for the six
o'clock edition.
Mr. Holmes,
I represent the western mail.
I understand you're
taking up this case.
No, no, certainly not.
I'm just holmes the busybody
retained by the police to
supply their deficiencies.
Oh, inspector.
There are several
points upon which
I should like to
ask your advice.
I must consider whether I
don't owe it to the public
to scratch the
horse immediately.
Certainly not.
I should let the name stand.
- My business with mr.
- Holmes now is private
- if you don't mind.
- Right you are.
I've got something
to go on with anyhow.
Good day, everybody.
I'm very glad to have
your heard opinion, sir.
Well, doctor, have you
made your examination?
Yes. Straker was
killed by a savage blow
from some blunt heavy instrument
delivered with enormous force.
Lestrade let me see his coat.
You have it there.
Yes, here it is.
Thank you.
I presume you made the
inventory I asked for.
Trust me, mr. Holmes.
Letter in envelope.
London postmark.
Pipe.
Briarwood pipe, lestrade.
Pouch.
Pouch of sealskin.
Matches.
They're fine.
Telegram.
Handed in at coombe tracey.
Let's see what the
letter says first.
"Bingham and co. Financier.
"52-a bond street, london w-1.
"J. Straker esquire king's
pyland stables devon.
"Dear sir, please receive
this as official notification
"that your commitments to us
secured by six promissory notes
"were today purchased
by mr. Leslie martin
"of 15 lamb street west to
whom you are now accountable.
"Yours faithfully,
bingham and co."
Our friend straker
seems to have been
somewhat financially
embarrassed.
Now for the telegram.
"For cup final
send instructions.
"Will meet you as we agreed.
"Martin."
I think mrs. Straker might
be able to help us here.
She's in her room.
- I'll fetch her.
- Thank you, doctor.
I don't think she'll be
much assistance, mr. Holmes.
Apparently, she and straker
went to bed about
the usual time.
When she woke up in the
morning, she found he'd gone.
Yet, still I'd like a word
or two with her, lestrade,
regarding her husband's habits.
No one like a wife
to tell you that.
Eh, watson?
Oh, yes, quite.
You remember I
have these, lestrade.
Pray don't think
it deliberately.
Not at all.
You're welcome.
I see nothing in them.
Mr. Lestrade, have
you discovered anything?
No, mrs. Straker,
but mr. Holmes has
come over to help us.
We shall do all that's possible.
I won't be taking you
a moment, mrs. Straker.
I realize what
you're going through.
I just want to ask you this.
Are you by any chance
a light sleeper?
Yes, mr. Holmes,
as it happens I am.
I noticed a dog in the yard.
Does he sleep out
there at night?
Yes, always.
He's a very good watchdog.
You didn't by any chance
hear him barking
during the night?
No, I didn't.
No.
Just one other thing.
Was your husband
interested in football?
Oh, no.
Racing was the only thing
that interested him.
There's just one further
question, mrs. Straker.
You had curry for
supper last night.
Did you mention that to
anyone outside the house?
Why no.
Oh, thank you, mrs. Straker.
I don't think I need
intrude upon your time
and patience any longer.
Thank you, mr. Holmes.
Colonel, you have a
few sheep in the paddock.
Have you had anything
wrong with them of late?
No, I don't think so.
Now you mention it I believe
that one of my stable lads
did report that three of
the sheep had gone lame.
Why do you ask?
It was just a
long shot, colonel.
A very long shot.
Lestrade, let me recommend
to your attention
the singular epidemic
among the sheep.
You consider it
important, mr. Holmes?
Oh, yes, yes, exceedingly so.
Is there any other point
to which you want to
draw my attention?
Well, to the curious incident
of the dog in the night time.
The dog was perfectly
quiet in the night.
No that was the
curious incident.
Well, I'm going to
baskerville hall.
Would you be following?
Yes, it's very
possible, lestrade.
Hello?
Hello, could you please give
me coombe tracey post office?
Yes.
Yes, I'll hold on.
Coombe tracey is a small
village, is it not?
Yes, just a hamlet.
Then the postmaster
would be likely to remember
any strangers who came into it.
I should think so.
Hello.
Hello, is that the
postmaster of coombe tracey?
Look I'm speaking for mr.
Straker of king's pyland.
He received a telegram
yesterday signed martin
dispatched from your office.
But he cannot recall
anybody of that name.
Could you kindly describe
the sender to me?
Yes.
Oh, there were two of them?
I see thank you.
Thank you.
I'm very much obliged to you.
You think the
telegram's important?
Very much so, watson.
Well, au revoir, colonel.
We've had a charming
little breath
of your beautiful dartmoor air.
Then you despair of arresting
the murderer of james straker?
Well, there are certainly
grave difficulties in the way,
but I've every hope that
your horse will start,
and I think you will have
your jockey in readiness.
And you've nothing
definite to tell me?
When we meet at
the races, colonel.
What do you make
of it all, holmes?
Hmm, it's easy as looking at
love at first sight, watson.
But the fact that straker was
not interested in football
persuaded me that this is not
to be taken at its face value.
You observed of course that
the name of martin appeared
in both the letter
and the telegram.
Yes, it struck me as curious.
Yes, highly
significant, watson.
This telegram is
peculiarly interesting.
You mean it's in code?
Yes, and a very
elementary one.
By simply crossing out
each alternate word,
the message assumes an
entirely different meaning.
Instead of a request it
becomes a peremptory order.
"Final instructions.
"Meet as agreed.
"Martin."
What did the postmaster
at coombe tracey tell you?
He described the senders.
Two strangers.
Unquestionably,
moriarty and moran.
Watson, the professor
is behind all this.
You mean he's responsible
for the deaths of
hunter and straker?
Of hunter, yes.
Of straker, no.
In fact, I fancy
that straker's death
was the most unfortunate thing
that could possibly happen
from moriarty's point of view.
All through the season
my luck was dead out.
I found myself in trouble
to the tune of 4,000 pounds.
I went to bingham and
raise what I could,
and as a last plunge I backed
desborough to win me 5,000.
Make or break.
Well, why didn't
you come to me my boy?
Well, you're not a
betting man, sir henry,
and I was afraid you
wouldn't understand.
That's why I kept it dark.
Even from diana.
And now that
loathsome, inspector...
Oh, come now it's no
use calling him names.
In view of these bets,
he'd every reason
to be suspicious.
I don't care he's a
foul and nasty person.
I disliked him from the
first moment I met him.
Inspector lestrade.
Any news, inspector?
Yes, very grave
news, sir henry.
We found straker's body.
Body do you mean he's...
Murdered.
On the moor about a
mile from king's pyland.
Sherlock holmes
takes up the case.
Sherlock holmes, moran!
Once again that man
is crossing my path!
What's this news
mean, professor?
What's gone wrong?
What does this man holmes know?
I tell you if silver blaze goes
to the post and he's fit...
There is a big
difference mr. Stanford
between a horse going to the
post and winning the race.
You have my assurance.
I am not in the habit
of failing my clients.
Moran, tell barton to
take mr. Stanford home.
Then come straight back.
Yes, sir.
Prince?
It's now four o'clock.
Have the car ready
in 15 minutes.
Very good, professor.
Are we out for a long run?
Er, yes.
We've got to be back in
devon well before midnight,
and, prince,
we'll need the gun.
Okay.
What have you
got there, prince?
Oh, you haven't
seen this little gadget
- before have you?
- No.
You hadn't joined us
when it was last used.
Let's have a look.
It's a magazine airgun.
Absolutely silent and
immensely powerful.
Made specially for
the, professor,
by a well-known
foreign gunsmith.
Hmm, seems you're
gonna use it again.
Oh, there you are, barton.
I want you to take
mr. Stanford home.
Yes, we're in deeper waters
than you think, lestrade.
But we must take the
case one step at a time.
Now our progress so
far I'm glad to say
is completely to
exonerate mr. Trevor.
You've got to
convince me, mr. Holmes.
I've every hope of doing so.
Now you will agree that hunter
was murdered in order that
the horse could be stolen.
Exactly, we all know that.
When I examined the
remains of hunter's supper,
I remarked on the fact
that it consisted of curry.
Yes, but I still don't see.
Well, perhaps I
could help you to see,
one or two other things as well.
That was the first link
in my chain of reasoning.
Hunter was poisoned
with powdered opium
and powdered opium is
by no means tasteless.
Well, then, mr. Holmes,
why didn't the boy notice it?
By no mean tasteless when
mixed with any ordinary dish.
Curry was exactly the medium
which would disguise that taste.
So?
You remember that
I asked mrs. Straker
if she'd told anyone
they were having curry
for supper that night,
and she replied no.
Yes, I remember you
putting that question.
Well, it's surely too
monstrous a coincidence
to suppose that trevor
happened to come along
with powdered opium
on the very night
when a dish was served which
would disguise its flavor.
Why it's unthinkable, lestrade.
That certainly
is a strong point.
And there's a further point.
Even more significant, lestrade.
The silence of the dog.
Though someone had
been in the stable
and fetched out the horse,
the dog had not barked enough
to arouse mrs. Straker
who is a light sleeper.
I mean obviously the visitor
was some member
of the household.
Then what do you
make of it, holmes?
One thing for certain.
Trevor becomes
eliminated from the case.
Well, I confess, mr. Holmes,
in view of what you say,
I don't know what move to make.
Make no move at the moment.
Except to assure mr. Trevor
that all suspicions
of him were unfounded.
We're old friends.
It's wrongful to arrest
the future son-in-law
of sir henry baskerville.
I appreciate that.
I'll speak to mr. Trevor.
Who's that taking
my name in vain?
Ah, mr. Trevor.
I just had a little
chat with, mr. Holmes.
I'm glad to say that he
sees eye to eye with me.
You quite understand that at
the commencement of this case
it was my duty to follow up
any clue, however slight.
I don't mind telling you now
that I never seriously
suspected you.
Well, he can't say
fairer than that, can he?
Well, I'm very glad you feel
that way about it, inspector.
Yes, I still don't
see how it helps us.
Who did put the
opium into the curry?
Who did steal the horse
and kill hunter and straker?
My dear lestrade,
it's a capital mistake
to theorize before you
have all the evidence.
It biases the judgment.
Then you're not going to
tell us anything, mr. Holmes?
Well, not at the
moment, ms. Baskerville.
There's one other link in
the chain to be tested,
and to do that I'm afraid we
must return to london tonight.
Tonight?
Yes, dr. Watson
and I are sorry
to have to run away like this.
Well, there's nothing before
the midnight train from exeter.
Dinner will be ready
in a few moments.
You have heaps of
time to dine here
in comfort before you go.
Well, thank you I
shall be delighted.
I hope you'll stay
and dine too, inspector.
Oh, thank you, sir.
That's quite a museum
piece, sir henry.
Well, we've had
it a long time.
Why it's nearly 11:00, holmes,
and if we're to catch that
midnight train from exeter...
I'll order the car.
Don't bother, sir henry.
I'll take mr. Holmes
and the doctor in mine.
Oh, thank you, lestrade.
It's a pity you've
got to leave us holmes,
and I'm sorry you
can't tell us anymore.
You are leaving three
very puzzled people.
Well, I hope to
solve the puzzle
for you all on cup day
in colonel ross's box.
What's happening?
I think he's going, moran.
Well, that can't be helped.
- No.
- Au revoir, holmes.
Safe journey.
Thank you so much.
Goodbye.
Quick back to the car.
Follow that car.
When you get clear of
the house overtake her.
I have the strongest
reasons for thinking that
professor moriarty is the
brains behind this crime.
You know he seems quite
an obsession with you.
You still don't
believe in the professor?
Frankly, mr. Holmes, I do not.
Another few yards, moran,
then let them have it.
Oh, no.
There's a car following us.
Quick down for your lives.
Help!
Dear.
What are you hurt, watson?
No only a few bruises,
but where's the driver?
Here I am, sir.
I'm all right.
Sure?
No bones broken?
My word this is a lucky escape.
Oh, but where's lestrade?
Watson, have you seen lestrade?
Lestrade?
Ah, there you are, lestrade.
Well, do you believe in
professor moriarty now?
Double price, silver blaze?
Six to one, sir.
I'll take 60 pounds to 10.
Silver blaze 60 pounds to 10.
Five, six, nine.
- Thank you.
- Silver blaze five to one.
May I borrow your
glass, mr. Holmes?
Thank you.
Did you hear anything
from the street, dudley?
Well, they told me
sunstroke has a good chance.
Oh, mr. Holmes.
You've assured me that my
horse would go to the post.
We are still waiting to know
who killed straker and hunter.
I promised you should know
everything today, colonel,
and you shall.
Oh, watson you've been having
a little flutter I see.
What?
Well, if you
want to conceal it,
I suggest you find a deeper
pocket for your betting ticket.
It's all very
well, mr. Holmes.
But we are waiting.
Yes, well, colonel,
in the first place,
it will come as a shock to
you to learn that straker
was a scoundrel utterly
unworthy of your confidence.
Are you serious, mr. Holmes?
Yes, acting under the orders
of a master criminal
who bought up his debts,
and so had it in his
power to ruin him.
He poisoned hunter,
and then took silver blaze
out on the moor in
the dead of night.
- Oh, thank you.
- I can hardly believe it.
Straker?
But to what purpose?
It was his intention to
use that singular knife,
you remember I found
it in his hand,
to nick one of the
tendons of the horse.
With your wide experience
of the turf, colonel,
you know it's possible
to do that subcutaneously
and leave no trace.
The result would be
a slight lameness,
which you would put
down to rheumatism
or a strain in exercise.
You say it was his intention?
You mean he didn't succeed?
No.
I examined the knife.
There was no trace of blood.
But why didn't he do
all this in the stable?
Why take him out on the moor?
Well, for the best of reasons.
When so spirited a
creature felt the nick
of the knife he
would certainly have
roused the soundest of sleepers.
But how did you arrive
at all this, mr. Holmes?
I found several clues.
Chief of which was the knife.
You remember my asking you
if you've found anything
wrong with your sheep?
Yes, I remember.
When you told me
that some of them
had suffered from lameness
that confirmed my theory.
That straker before tackling
the delicate
operation on the horse
had been practicing
on the sheep.
Good heavens!
But who interrupted the plot?
Who killed james straker?
I'll waive that question
for a few minutes, colonel.
Hello, the numbers are going up.
Oh, should we go?
What number is silver blaze?
- Nine.
- Number nine.
Two three.
Four five.
Six.
Merton number six?
Why my jockey's
riding another horse.
What silver blaze doesn't run.
Look holmes.
Silver blaze doesn't run.
There's been a mistake.
The six should've been a nine.
Mr. Holmes, I relied
on you implicitly.
Yes, and you may
still do so, colonel.
Yes, that's him?
- There he goes.
- Is that him?
That's my horse.
That's my horse!
Yes, and that's the
murderer of james straker.
- What?
It was a kick from silver
blaze that killed your trainer.
They're off.
Here they come.
Confound it, desborough leads.
Oh, here comes silver blaze.
Come on silver blaze.
They're neck and neck.
Silver blaze.
Come on, silver blaze, come on.
It's my race!
But he's off.
Oh, holmes.
Look desborough wins!
Desborough!
The bullet has
penetrated the shoulder
and lodged near the lung.
But we heard nothing.
You wouldn't.
It was fired from an airgun.
Noiseless with tremendous power.
How could it possibly
be concealed in the crowd?
In the interior of
a specially designed
kinematic-graph camera.
Good heavens.
But how on earth do you know?
Well, I observed
through the glasses
a group of cameramen lined
up near the winning post.
I fancied I knew one of them.
Mr. Holmes, what
does this all mean?
It means, colonel, that
you've been cheated of your race
by the most cunning and
dangerous criminal in london.
Is there nothing to be done?
Lestrade, who's
the most likely man
to give me some information
on the betting for the cup?
It's difficult to say.
Old sam silver's a member
of the victoria club
- and a good friend of mine.
- Where can we find him?
It's a 100 to one he's in the
champagne bar at this moment.
I'll stay here with
muffin if you don't mind.
There's no question about it.
Stanford had laid over 100,000
pounds against silver blaze
and got left with it.
Point him out to me.
There he is mr. Holmes in
the dark suit and the bowler.
Thank
you, mr. Silver.
Watson, I want you to take
particular note of that man.
Not a word sam.
Trust me.
Excuse me, mr. Holmes.
You can rely on me
to look after this.
Yes, yes, but I think you need
a little unofficial help.
Just to supplement your usual
happy mixture of
cunning and audacity.
Is there anything I can do?
Yes, my dear watson.
A job that involves
tenacity of purpose
of which, my dear fellow,
you've given me so many proofs.
I want you to remain here
and never lose
sight of stanford.
Lestrade, and I will drive
straight back to baker street.
- Yes.
- Lestrade, will you
give instructions for your car
to be at dr. Watson's disposal?
Certainly, mr. Holmes.
And you might tell you
chauffeur to get into muffin.
As soon as stanford
leaves follow him.
When he arrives at
his destination,
send the car back
to baker street.
Then go to the nearest phone box
and tell me where you
are and wait for me.
- Is that clear?
- Perfectly.
Watson's
a long time phoning.
Oh, patience,
lestrade, patience.
Concentrate on the game.
Yes, come in.
Mr. Holmes, it's
nearly midnight.
You really must eat something.
Can't I tempt you to
a nice bit of haddock?
My dear mrs. Hudson,
you've always been
a temptation to me,
but haddock at
this moment is not.
How about a nice sheepshead?
No, thank you, mrs. Hudson.
I suggest you go
to bed, mrs. Hudson.
Very well, sir.
Still
your move, lestrade.
My mind's not on
the game, mr. Holmes.
I wonder what has
happened to dr. Watson.
Well, now let's see.
It was five o'clock when we
left the course and it's now...
Oh, look now it's
nearly midnight.
We ought to hear something soon.
Tell me, mr. Holmes,
why did you leave dr.
Watson to do the trailing?
Why not yourself?
Because my dear, lestrade,
when you set out
to draw a badger
that's gone to earth you
send a ferret down after it
while the man with the
gun remains outside.
Professor moriarty
is the badger,
dr. Watson is the ferret,
and I my dear lestrade
am the man with the gun.
I see.
And stanford?
Well, stanford,
if he's a wise man,
will go straight to moriarty
with whatever price he's paying.
When you're finished
with the professor,
you'll be taken back to
where we picked you up.
You've got the necessary
on you I suppose.
Yes, of course.
Okay.
I want you to go straight
to mr. Holmes' rooms
in baker street.
Yes?
Is that you holmes?
Watson speaking
from sladen mews.
Watson!
Quick, lestrade,
there's something wrong!
They've got, watson!
Inspector lestrade's
chauffeur, sir.
Good, drive us to
where you dropped dr. Watson!
- Right.
- Oh, dear.
Quite correct, mr. Stanford.
I must say this case has proved
more intricate
than I anticipated.
It should have been
worth a trifle more.
However, perhaps next time.
You may go.
Barton.
Here.
Next to mr. Holmes himself,
I don't know anyone
who'd be more welcome.
Hello, professor?
Who do you think I've
got here of all people?
No.
Doctor watson.
Watson did you say?
Doctor watson?
- What's he doing here?
- Moran.
Yes.
Caught him prowling
around the yard.
Shall I bring him in?
No, not just yet, prince.
I'll leave him alone with
this thoughts for a while.
Nothing like a little suspense.
I imagine the three weeks'
wait for the hangman
is infinitely worse than
the final interview.
Eh, moran?
- You wait here.
- Right, sir.
Come, lestrade.
This is the mews.
This looks pretty
solid, lestrade.
- What building is it?
- This must be the back
of the old pelham
street tube station.
What are you going
to do, mr. Holmes?
Drive straight
to scotland yard.
- And then?
- The headquarters
of the london transport.
Now, moran, I think
we'll interview the doctor.
Is that you, prince?
Bring in dr. Watson.
Right now.
Now then, doctor.
This should be
most amusing moran.
Ah, come in, doctor.
I have had the pleasure
of several interviews
with mr. Holmes,
but never before with his
talented friend and colleague.
Would you sit down?
May I ask what you are
doing in this neighborhood?
I'd good reason to think
it was your
neighborhood, professor.
Really?
As a matter of curiosity may
I ask you how you got here?
- By following mr.
- Holmes' instructions.
Oh, I see.
I'm afraid it's going to prove
rather unfortunate
for you, doctor.
I have not taken the somewhat
elaborate precautions to
conceal my whereabouts
in order to have you report
on the subject to, mr. Holmes.
You mean...
I'm going to have some
difficulty in leaving?
Oh, no, my dear doctor.
Oh, dear no.
There will be no
difficulty about that.
But you will leave by
the way I shall indicate.
I will explain to you, doctor.
You are now in what was the
pelham street tube station.
Behind that panel
is the lift shaft.
It's a sheer drop of 80 feet.
If you have any last message
to send to mr. Holmes,
I will see that it is delivered.
Sherlock holmes will fall
a reckoning with you moriarty
without any reminder from me.
So that is your last word?
Very good.
I will now remove the panel
and wish you a swift journey.
Don't move any of you.
Except you my dear watson
who I'm sure would be
more comfortable with us.
You must excuse
me for trespassing
on your private property.
I've had the lift
put in order again.
You clever...
No compliments please.
I arrest
you robert moriarty.
On what charge?
For being concerned
in the murder
of the stable boy edward hunter.
And for an attempt on the life
of mr. Sherlock holmes
dr. Watson and...
That'll do to go
on with, lestrade.
When the professor has
answered to those charges,
there will doubtless
be a number of others
to occupy his attention.
Listen, holmes, there's
no prison can hold me.
You know I almost wish
that were true, professor.
Life would be very dull
without your activities.
Watson, might I trouble
you for a match?
I think our quiet
rest in the country
has been a great success.
Damn you, holmes.
Blast you.
Well, it's the
most amazing case
we've ever solved, holmes.
Elementary my dear, watson.
Elementary.