Hey, look here!
Who was on duty in my
neighborhood last night?
Why...
I was, sir.
You were?
Yes, sir.
I was down there all night.
Did you look at this morning's paper?
No.
No, I didn't see this morning's.
You didn't?
No.
Well, take a squint at this.
Well, what about it?
I'm just about fed up
with your kind of stuff.
Now listen to me.
If there's any more robberies in
that neighborhood and you don't
make an arrest, you're fired!
You get me?
Yes, sir.
Poor old Kennedy.
The only way that you'll ever
make an arrest is frame it yourself.
Frame it myself.
Come on, come on.
Come on.
Get up out of this.
Get up, get up.
Get up out of there.
I suppose you fellas know you can
get 90 days on the rock pile for this.
If I should let you go,
would you do... me a little favor?
We'd be glad to.
Kennedy's my name.
Mr. Hardy's mine.
This is Mr. Laurel, Mr. Kennedy.
How do you do, Mr. Laurel?
Now, here's the proposition.
The chief and I are on the outs,
and I want to get on
the good side of him.
Naturally.
Certainly.
What I want you boys to do is to
go up and rob the chief's house.
Why, we'd be arrested.
That's the idea.
And I will arrest you.
That will put me in
good with the chief.
But what's going to become of us?
Oh.
Don't let that worry you.
Kennedy will fix it.
We won't do it.
All right.
Then the rock pile for you.
Come on.
Just a moment.
Pardon me.
I'll speak with my friend.
Just a little conference.
Well, make it snappy.
No good will come of it, and
we'll be put in... put in jail.
Excuse me.
All right?
We'll do it.
I thought you would.
You looked like you had
intelligence, and so do...
Come on, and I'll show you where
that house is.
That's the house.
Now, be as quiet as you can.
I'll see you later.
It's the garbage men, sir.
Climb over the wall.
Oh!
Shhhh!
Don't shush me.
Pick those things up.
What's the matter?
I'm scared.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Kennedy will fix it.
Come on. Let's go.
Oh!
Shh!
Shhh!
Aah!
Hey!
Oh!
Shhh!
Shh!
See what that racket is out there.
Oh, it's the cats, sir.
Let's pretend we're cats.
Do something about it.
Will you quit your playing?
Shh!
Get in.
I'm afraid.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Kennedy will fix it.
Now come on.
Oh, shoot!
Get something, quick!
Oh!
Get your hands off of it.
Why don't you do something to help me?
What can I do?
It blew shut.
Oh, "blew."
Now we've got to go
through the window again.
Get on it.
Shh!
Oh...
Hey! Psst!
Oooh!
Oh!
Shhhh!
Will you get me the hammer, please?
Aah!
Shh!
Get me something to tie this with.
Did you ring, sir?
No, I didn't ring, sir!
Would you get out of here so I
can get some sleep?
I believe you're getting old
and nutty.
We'll wait here for Kennedy.
And don't make any noise.
I told you, keep quiet!
Meadows, quit playing
the piano this time of night!
Oh!
Meadows!
Yes, sir?
You go and phone the police.
- Me?
- Yes, you. Hurry up.
Aaah!
Kennedy!
So it's you that's been
robbing the neighborhood!
You'll get life for this!
There's the police now!
Hurry up, will you?
Give me a good pull!
I'm doing the best I can!