1
00:02:10,354 --> 00:02:13,914
Arretez au coin, s'il vous plait.

2
00:02:38,514 --> 00:02:41,234
Monsieur Foine. Yes, monsieur?

3
00:02:41,234 --> 00:02:43,834
Could I speak to you for a moment?

4
00:02:45,034 --> 00:02:49,514
Well, I've been studying painting
with you for some time now.

5
00:02:49,514 --> 00:02:53,674
Do you think it's worth my while
Why do you ask?

6
00:02:53,674 --> 00:02:56,954
There's no sense in staying
unless I have talent.

7
00:02:56,954 --> 00:03:01,194
If you are not certain about
your talent, why stay till now?

8
00:03:01,194 --> 00:03:04,274
Because all this
is so beautiful to me.

9
00:03:04,274 --> 00:03:07,634
In my youth,
it was also beautiful to me.

10
00:03:07,634 --> 00:03:10,833
But now,
it is the city of lost illusions.

11
00:03:10,833 --> 00:03:14,794
Is your studio very far?
No. Not very.

12
00:03:14,794 --> 00:03:19,114
Let us go there. You will show me
what you have done. Yes.

13
00:03:26,274 --> 00:03:30,474
Have you any money?
A little. Not enough to live on.

14
00:03:36,634 --> 00:03:38,714
Then, I must tell you.

15
00:03:38,714 --> 00:03:46,114
There is no talent here, merely
industry and intelligence. You will
never be anything but mediocre.

16
00:03:46,114 --> 00:03:53,114
And it is very cruel
to discover one's mediocrity only
when it is too late. I know.

17
00:03:55,434 --> 00:03:58,714
That name does not belong there.

18
00:03:58,714 --> 00:04:01,074
It belongs somewhere else.

19
00:04:01,074 --> 00:04:06,474
Take your courage in both your hands
and make something of your life.

20
00:04:14,354 --> 00:04:17,753
Have you anything in mind?
Well, you see...

21
00:04:19,154 --> 00:04:24,594
..I have my limitations. I've always
been interested in medicine.

22
00:04:24,594 --> 00:04:29,594
If one can't be great, at least
one can be of some use to people.

23
00:05:16,494 --> 00:05:21,334
I don't know why I should 'ave such
a thing. Upon my word, I don't!

24
00:05:21,334 --> 00:05:25,054
I've never had a day's illness
in my life.

25
00:05:25,054 --> 00:05:28,894
It's a winter cough.
Many middle-aged women have it.

26
00:05:28,894 --> 00:05:35,694
Well, I never! No-one's
ever called me middle-aged before.
It's time you got used to it.

27
00:05:35,694 --> 00:05:38,574
All the same.
You're a nice one, deerie.

28
00:05:38,574 --> 00:05:41,814
I can't say the same for you.
Good day, madam.

29
00:05:41,814 --> 00:05:45,733
The rest of you come back tomorrow.
Get him ready.

30
00:05:45,733 --> 00:05:47,734
All right, sir.

31
00:05:52,173 --> 00:05:54,894
Are you the boy's father?
Yes, sir.

32
00:05:56,774 --> 00:05:59,374
What's the matter with you now?

33
00:05:59,374 --> 00:06:03,654
You see what the matter is.
The boy has a club foot.

34
00:06:03,654 --> 00:06:06,853
Carey, you'd better take this case.

35
00:06:06,853 --> 00:06:10,693
It's a subject
you ought to know something about.

36
00:06:17,574 --> 00:06:22,014
It's only for the looks of the
thing. I don't find it no trouble.

37
00:06:22,014 --> 00:06:27,454
That's wonderful. I did. That's cos
you let them go on at you.

38
00:06:27,454 --> 00:06:31,214
You're a little slow, Carey.
I'll instruct the class.

39
00:06:31,214 --> 00:06:36,174
There are many varieties of
club feet. This is less interesting.

40
00:06:36,174 --> 00:06:42,334
Yours would prove more interesting.
Yes. I believe so.

41
00:06:42,334 --> 00:06:45,134
Mind taking off your sock, Carey?

42
00:06:48,534 --> 00:06:50,574
No. Not at all.

43
00:07:05,133 --> 00:07:08,814
Keeps his feet nice and clean,
doesn't he?

44
00:07:10,614 --> 00:07:17,534
Hm, yes. Talipes equinovarus -
malformation requiring you to walk
on the outside of the foot.

45
00:07:17,534 --> 00:07:20,854
A very interesting example,
I must say!

46
00:07:20,854 --> 00:07:23,254
Do you mind if I have a look?

47
00:07:23,254 --> 00:07:25,334
Congenital club foot.

48
00:07:25,334 --> 00:07:29,894
In simple language, a foot twisted
inward. The cause is not clear.

49
00:07:29,894 --> 00:07:32,293
Hereditary influence plays a part.

50
00:07:32,293 --> 00:07:36,454
Dr Little traces recurring deformity
through four generations.

51
00:07:36,454 --> 00:07:38,733
When you've quite finished...

52
00:07:42,254 --> 00:07:48,414
I say, old man, I like that!
French, isn't she?
Yes. She was a model in Paris.

53
00:07:48,414 --> 00:07:52,694
I can't, for the life of me,
understand why you gave up painting.

54
00:07:52,694 --> 00:07:57,854
I'd rather look at that all day
long, than at this! Woman, you know!

55
00:07:57,854 --> 00:08:02,814
You can tell by the, er, pelvis.
I like 'em with a little more...

56
00:08:04,334 --> 00:08:08,094
There's life in the old girl yet!

57
00:08:08,094 --> 00:08:10,134
Don't inhale, deerie!

58
00:08:10,134 --> 00:08:13,214
I say! I've got to be getting along!

59
00:08:13,214 --> 00:08:19,374
A little matter of a barmaid
at the Crown & Anchor.
Very nice, too! Cheerie-o!

60
00:08:19,374 --> 00:08:21,414
Funny fellow, isn't he?

61
00:08:21,414 --> 00:08:25,974
It must have been wonderful
It was.

62
00:08:25,974 --> 00:08:30,573
You really knew all those
Some of them.

63
00:08:30,573 --> 00:08:34,494
I wonder if you couldn't help me.
In what way?

64
00:08:34,494 --> 00:08:38,294
There's a girl
and I can't get anywhere with her.

65
00:08:38,294 --> 00:08:43,014
You've been to Paris and all that.
I'm sure you can give me a starter.

66
00:08:43,014 --> 00:08:47,934
I'd ask Griffiths, only he couldn't
remember whom he was doing it for.

67
00:08:47,934 --> 00:08:51,414
You know,
say something to make her laugh.

68
00:08:54,694 --> 00:08:59,014
What? You don't believe it?
You are too suspicious!

69
00:09:09,253 --> 00:09:13,694
I say, she's marvellous, isn't she?
No. She's anaemic.

70
00:09:23,814 --> 00:09:27,894
You don't suppose she likes
Of course.

71
00:09:27,894 --> 00:09:30,814
Now's your chance. Say something.

72
00:09:33,334 --> 00:09:36,094
Well, I see your friend's going.

73
00:09:36,094 --> 00:09:38,494
I don't know what you mean.

74
00:09:38,494 --> 00:09:42,054
The nobleman
with the sandy moustache.

75
00:09:42,054 --> 00:09:45,054
Has he left you for another?

76
00:09:46,374 --> 00:09:50,574
Some people would do better
to mind their own business.

77
00:09:50,574 --> 00:09:51,934
Why?

78
00:09:53,454 --> 00:09:59,094
You have a very nice back. Am I
on speaking terms with your back?

79
00:09:59,094 --> 00:10:03,294
Woman, you know.
You can tell by the pelvis.

80
00:10:03,294 --> 00:10:08,334
And that...calls himself
a gentleman!

81
00:10:08,334 --> 00:10:12,934
I apologise. What for?
I promised you something charming.

82
00:10:12,934 --> 00:10:16,614
She's turned out to be
ill-natured and contemptible.

83
00:10:16,614 --> 00:10:20,654
You don't suppose I care what
an anaemic waitress says to me?

84
00:10:20,654 --> 00:10:24,614
Well, I do. I must be going.

85
00:10:24,614 --> 00:10:26,534
Coming along?

86
00:10:26,534 --> 00:10:29,854
No, I think I'll have some more tea.

87
00:10:56,034 --> 00:10:59,394
Anything you want?
Yes, if you don't mind.

88
00:10:59,394 --> 00:11:03,794
I'd like to talk to you.
Filthy weather, isn't it?

89
00:11:03,794 --> 00:11:08,114
Makes no difference to me.
I have to be here all day.

90
00:11:08,114 --> 00:11:13,034
Oh, I only wanted to say
Well, say it.

91
00:11:13,034 --> 00:11:17,874
You know, you have a lovely smile.
You should use it more often.

92
00:11:17,874 --> 00:11:20,114
Now, don't go spoofing me.

93
00:11:20,114 --> 00:11:25,434
A girl that works hard all day
don't have much reason to smile.

94
00:11:25,434 --> 00:11:29,314
Perhaps I could find a reason.
Will you let me try?

95
00:11:29,314 --> 00:11:33,594
I don't know whether I will
or whether I won't.

96
00:11:33,594 --> 00:11:36,034
I hope you'll decide you will.

97
00:11:52,514 --> 00:11:54,314
Huh!

98
00:12:45,714 --> 00:12:49,353
Like that, unt that, like so!

99
00:13:17,834 --> 00:13:20,394
That is a nice little hand.

100
00:13:30,814 --> 00:13:33,214
Excuse me, won't you? Ja ja.

101
00:13:37,054 --> 00:13:40,294
How do you do?
You seem in a great hurry.

102
00:13:40,294 --> 00:13:42,694
I've been waiting ten minutes.

103
00:13:44,694 --> 00:13:47,434
I didn't know you could draw!
Didn't you?

104
00:13:47,734 --> 00:13:50,854
That meant to be me?
Looks like you.

105
00:13:51,874 --> 00:13:54,394
If you look at it that way. Tea?

106
00:13:56,394 --> 00:13:58,094
You are a strange sort.

107
00:13:59,914 --> 00:14:04,434
I say, will you dine with me
some time? We'll go to the theatre?

108
00:14:04,434 --> 00:14:07,554
I don't mind. When will you come?

109
00:14:07,554 --> 00:14:12,874
I'm off Thursdays. All right, Thursday,
seven o'clock Victoria Station?

110
00:14:17,394 --> 00:14:22,474
All right. I'll meet you at Victoria
in the second class waiting room.

111
00:14:26,594 --> 00:14:28,954
All tickets, please!

112
00:14:28,954 --> 00:14:30,514
Show your tickets.

113
00:14:31,014 --> 00:14:32,694
All tickets, please!

114
00:14:36,094 --> 00:14:37,694
All tickets, please!

115
00:14:38,294 --> 00:14:40,534
Show your tickets.
All tickets, please!

116
00:14:42,034 --> 00:14:44,594
Boat train, platform 19!

117
00:14:45,594 --> 00:14:47,874
All tickets, please...!

118
00:15:19,114 --> 00:15:21,134
I thought you were never coming.
I like that!

119
00:15:21,434 --> 00:15:24,194
After keeping ME waiting.
I almost went home.

120
00:15:24,194 --> 00:15:26,834
I was in the second class
waiting room.

121
00:15:28,434 --> 00:15:32,554
Is it likely I'd sit in the second
class when I could sit in the first?

122
00:15:32,954 --> 00:15:36,634
For a gentleman of brains,
you don't use 'em!

123
00:15:36,934 --> 00:15:40,934
Perhaps not. Anyway, you're here,
so it's all right, isn't it?

124
00:15:40,934 --> 00:15:43,334
You certainly do make a girl
feel important.

125
00:15:46,754 --> 00:15:48,794
I love that music.

126
00:15:50,574 --> 00:15:53,414
Whenever I hear it, I think of you.

127
00:15:56,254 --> 00:15:58,254
How pale you are.

128
00:15:58,254 --> 00:16:01,014
How strange, how cold.

129
00:16:05,294 --> 00:16:09,453
You ARE going it!
Do you always order champagne?

130
00:16:11,254 --> 00:16:13,734
No. Why did you do it now?

131
00:16:16,734 --> 00:16:20,334
I was hoping it would make you
more friendly.

132
00:16:22,134 --> 00:16:27,974
Do you think it will? Well,
there's one thing I can say for you.

133
00:16:27,974 --> 00:16:31,334
Gentleman,
in every sense of the word.

134
00:16:58,014 --> 00:17:00,174
May I see you again?

135
00:17:00,174 --> 00:17:04,014
I don't mind. Doesn't it make
any difference to you?

136
00:17:04,974 --> 00:17:09,774
No. If you don't take me out,
someone else will.

137
00:17:33,774 --> 00:17:36,014
I'll say good night here.

138
00:17:36,014 --> 00:17:39,374
Won't you stay for a moment? No.
Why not?

139
00:17:39,374 --> 00:17:42,494
People would think
I don't know what.

140
00:18:41,574 --> 00:18:43,733
I love that music.

141
00:18:43,733 --> 00:18:47,054
Whenever I hear it, I think of you.

142
00:18:47,054 --> 00:18:50,054
Whenever I hear it, I think of us.

143
00:19:22,214 --> 00:19:26,334
I've never danced with anyone
who danced like you.

144
00:19:28,334 --> 00:19:32,013
I've been looking for you
all my life.

145
00:19:50,934 --> 00:19:54,974
You don't have much to do with
your time. I should be studying.

146
00:19:54,974 --> 00:19:58,574
Then why don't you?
Well, I'd rather see you.

147
00:19:58,574 --> 00:20:02,094
Any of the girls noticed, you're
waiting for me? I don't know.

148
00:20:02,194 --> 00:20:06,474
What difference does it make?
They all laugh at you. Do they?

149
00:20:07,174 --> 00:20:09,734
Why? Say you're in love with me.

150
00:20:15,254 --> 00:20:17,174
May I call you Mildred?

151
00:20:17,174 --> 00:20:19,134
I don't mind.

152
00:20:20,574 --> 00:20:24,734
Look here, don't say that any more,
will you? Why not?

153
00:20:24,734 --> 00:20:29,134
Well, I'll call you Mildred
and you call me Philip, will you?

154
00:20:30,494 --> 00:20:32,654
I'll think on it.

155
00:20:32,654 --> 00:20:38,334
I, um...I'm a little awkward at this
but will you kiss me good night?

156
00:20:38,334 --> 00:20:39,974
No.

157
00:20:41,614 --> 00:20:46,014
Oh, Mildred. Will you come
to the theatre with me on Saturday?

158
00:20:46,014 --> 00:20:47,894
I don't mind.

159
00:20:56,054 --> 00:20:59,254
You're sure they're for Saturday?
Certainly.

160
00:21:17,534 --> 00:21:21,774
My name is Miller, Emile Miller.
We should know each other.

161
00:21:21,774 --> 00:21:26,774
Why? Well, we are both interested
in the same thing. Thing?

162
00:21:26,774 --> 00:21:31,174
My dear young man, you are so...
so... er...

163
00:21:31,174 --> 00:21:33,214
artistic.

164
00:21:33,214 --> 00:21:35,534
You, you should be more...

165
00:21:35,534 --> 00:21:37,334
Like so!

166
00:21:37,334 --> 00:21:39,614
Thanks. Thanks very much.

167
00:21:39,614 --> 00:21:42,494
That's all right.

168
00:21:42,494 --> 00:21:44,694
Keep the change.

169
00:21:48,534 --> 00:21:50,974
What time shall I see you?

170
00:21:50,974 --> 00:21:55,494
I forgot to tell you, Philip.
I can't go. W... Why not?

171
00:21:55,494 --> 00:21:56,774
Me aunt's ill.

172
00:22:00,014 --> 00:22:01,854
Oh.

173
00:22:04,734 --> 00:22:06,174
Well!

174
00:22:07,614 --> 00:22:12,934
What's the sense in that? You don't
suppose I want to go by myself?

175
00:22:12,934 --> 00:22:17,133
I only got them for your sake.
Well you needn't go on about it.

176
00:22:22,214 --> 00:22:25,334
Violets! Sweet violets!

177
00:22:25,334 --> 00:22:27,974
Sweet violets, tuppence a bunch.

178
00:22:27,974 --> 00:22:31,734
Violets! Sweet violets...

179
00:22:37,094 --> 00:22:39,054
You're spying on me.

180
00:22:39,054 --> 00:22:42,494
I thought you was a gentleman,
in every sense of the word.

181
00:22:42,494 --> 00:22:44,854
Are you going out with Miller? No.

182
00:22:47,573 --> 00:22:52,174
Well, what if I am? I can go out
with him if I want to, can't I?

183
00:22:54,293 --> 00:22:56,894
He's keeping you waiting, isn't he?

184
00:22:56,894 --> 00:23:01,534
I'd rather wait for him
than have you waiting for me.

185
00:23:05,214 --> 00:23:07,294
Won't you change your mind?

186
00:23:07,294 --> 00:23:09,974
I'll get some more tickets... No.

187
00:23:16,294 --> 00:23:20,094
You keep looking for him
the way I look for you.

188
00:23:22,614 --> 00:23:26,094
If you don't come out with me
tonight you'll never see me again.

189
00:23:26,094 --> 00:23:28,814
Good riddance to bad rubbish.

190
00:23:46,574 --> 00:23:48,254
Oh, drink?

191
00:23:51,934 --> 00:23:54,214
Desire?

192
00:26:34,454 --> 00:26:36,454
Sorry, old boy.

193
00:26:36,454 --> 00:26:39,854
How about a nice large beer, huh?

194
00:26:40,853 --> 00:26:43,374
Wouldn't help? What would?

195
00:27:04,694 --> 00:27:06,734
Oh, Phil. Leave it.

196
00:27:06,734 --> 00:27:10,214
Why? What for?
Shows the waiter who you are.

197
00:27:12,494 --> 00:27:15,334
He knows who YOU are.

198
00:27:16,694 --> 00:27:20,094
And so do I. What do you mean?

199
00:27:21,654 --> 00:27:23,934
I'm sorry. I...didn't mean.

200
00:27:23,934 --> 00:27:28,014
You're a bit too superior for me,
my fine young friend.

201
00:27:31,334 --> 00:27:33,094
Mildred!

202
00:27:37,814 --> 00:27:40,974
Of course you don't like me.
I'm a cripple.

203
00:27:40,974 --> 00:27:44,493
No, Phil. It isn't that.
I've felt it all along.

204
00:27:44,493 --> 00:27:46,534
Foolish.

205
00:27:49,054 --> 00:27:51,213
Mind my hat, silly!

206
00:27:51,213 --> 00:27:53,494
You ARE clumsy!

207
00:28:13,473 --> 00:28:18,314
Off your nut! What practice can you
expect with a wife like that?

208
00:28:18,314 --> 00:28:23,034
I don't know. Let me ask you something.
Why do you want to marry this girl?

209
00:28:24,354 --> 00:28:27,634
Because I'm so in love with her.
Aah!

210
00:28:34,994 --> 00:28:38,834
That ring with a little design
is very popular, sir.

211
00:28:38,834 --> 00:28:43,194
We sell a great many of them.
They're 30 shillings.

212
00:28:43,194 --> 00:28:45,234
Thank you, sir.

213
00:28:46,234 --> 00:28:51,314
Philip, were you surprised when
I asked you to take me to dinner?

214
00:28:51,314 --> 00:28:55,634
I was delighted.
Were you? Yeah. Why?

215
00:28:55,634 --> 00:29:00,434
You've been so sweet to me all day
and I've got something to ask you.

216
00:29:00,434 --> 00:29:04,674
It makes it so much easier for me.
Makes it easier for me, too.

217
00:29:04,674 --> 00:29:08,794
I've something to tell you.
No, no. Let me tell you first.

218
00:29:10,714 --> 00:29:12,794
There it is.

219
00:29:14,634 --> 00:29:16,714
I want you to marry me.

220
00:29:16,714 --> 00:29:21,034
I'm so sorry, Philip.
That's what I was about to tell you.

221
00:29:21,034 --> 00:29:23,674
You shouldn't have waited so long.

222
00:29:23,674 --> 00:29:28,034
The fact is,
I'm going to be married.

223
00:29:31,034 --> 00:29:32,954
Are you?

224
00:29:32,954 --> 00:29:34,554
To whom?

225
00:29:34,554 --> 00:29:36,594
A man I know.

226
00:29:36,594 --> 00:29:38,634
He earns very good money.

227
00:29:38,634 --> 00:29:42,434
Yes, I'm...I'm sure of it.

228
00:29:42,434 --> 00:29:46,394
Now, you won't go on about it,
will you, Philip?

229
00:29:47,394 --> 00:29:48,674
All right.

230
00:29:48,674 --> 00:29:52,954
I'm getting on.
I'm 24. Time I settled down.

231
00:29:52,954 --> 00:29:57,074
This gentleman earns Ã‚Â£7 a week.
He's got good prospects.

232
00:29:57,074 --> 00:30:00,954
Well, this is goodbye.
I hate to eat and run, Philip.

233
00:30:00,954 --> 00:30:06,354
I'm going to the theatre with the
gentleman that I'm going to marry.

234
00:30:23,814 --> 00:30:27,454
All the latest films
of the day...!

235
00:30:38,214 --> 00:30:40,134
Taxi.

236
00:31:44,494 --> 00:31:46,854
Have you seen her since?

237
00:31:47,034 --> 00:31:53,233
No. London is the largest city
in the world and you know the cure
for ONE woman.

238
00:31:53,733 --> 00:31:56,214
Another. Ha ha! Right, ho!

239
00:32:06,914 --> 00:32:10,554
Norah, you don't read such junk,
do you?

240
00:32:11,054 --> 00:32:13,454
No. I write it. What?

241
00:32:13,954 --> 00:32:17,514
That's how I earn my living.
I didn't know.

242
00:32:17,514 --> 00:32:21,754
Successful? Very. I have an immense
popularity amongst kitchen maids.

243
00:32:22,254 --> 00:32:24,314
They think me so refined.

244
00:32:28,634 --> 00:32:31,474
Let's not talk about that.

245
00:32:32,574 --> 00:32:34,774
Let's talk about us.

246
00:32:46,894 --> 00:32:51,254
Norah, y-you're not really
fond of me, are you?

247
00:32:52,854 --> 00:32:56,533
For a clever boy,
you ask such foolish questions.

248
00:32:56,533 --> 00:33:00,054
Oh, my dear. It never struck me
Pleased?

249
00:33:00,054 --> 00:33:04,174
Delighted. And so proud
and so happy and so...

250
00:33:04,774 --> 00:33:06,294
So grateful.

251
00:33:06,294 --> 00:33:10,854
I wish you hadn't been in love
with... What was her name?

252
00:33:10,854 --> 00:33:12,894
Mildred.

253
00:33:12,894 --> 00:33:16,614
Because if she hadn't treated you
so abominably

254
00:33:16,614 --> 00:33:21,374
it wouldn't have taken you so long
to understand how I feel.

255
00:33:38,173 --> 00:33:41,733
I saw you! I wasn't very quick!

256
00:33:43,294 --> 00:33:45,934
Let's go out and play.

257
00:33:46,894 --> 00:33:49,854
Not until you've passed that exam.

258
00:34:18,934 --> 00:34:22,094
Tell me, darling.
What do you get out of this?

259
00:34:22,094 --> 00:34:24,974
You'll never know.

260
00:34:24,974 --> 00:34:28,894
I'm afraid you don't get much fun
with me.

261
00:34:28,894 --> 00:34:30,973
I wish...

262
00:34:30,973 --> 00:34:35,974
If only I could take you dancing.
I know how you love it.

263
00:34:35,974 --> 00:34:40,294
Philip, it's very silly to be
so sensitive about your foot.

264
00:34:40,294 --> 00:34:43,974
Other people don't think about it
as much as you.

265
00:34:43,974 --> 00:34:48,614
They notice it when they first
see you then forget about it.

266
00:34:50,374 --> 00:34:54,174
You know, I only speak of it
because I love you.

267
00:34:54,174 --> 00:34:57,134
I don't want it to make you unhappy.

268
00:34:57,134 --> 00:35:02,414
Now, will you please stay here
and go on cramming for that exam?

269
00:35:14,214 --> 00:35:16,814
There's a lady to see you, sir.

270
00:35:16,814 --> 00:35:20,814
I shouldn't have let her in
but she was that upset...

271
00:35:20,814 --> 00:35:22,854
Norah!

272
00:35:29,174 --> 00:35:31,774
What do you want?

273
00:35:35,414 --> 00:35:39,374
I didn't think
I'd ever see you again.

274
00:35:45,614 --> 00:35:47,854
What's the matter?

275
00:35:48,934 --> 00:35:52,374
He's left me. Emile.

276
00:35:54,814 --> 00:35:56,934
Oh, has he?

277
00:35:57,974 --> 00:35:59,734
Yes.

278
00:35:59,734 --> 00:36:02,614
Cos I'm going to have a baby.

279
00:36:20,054 --> 00:36:22,214
Why don't you sit down?

280
00:36:31,014 --> 00:36:35,374
I suppose you want him back.
He'll never come back.

281
00:36:35,374 --> 00:36:38,414
Why not? He just won't, that's all.

282
00:36:38,414 --> 00:36:41,934
You're his wife.
He has to provide for you.

283
00:36:41,934 --> 00:36:44,014
He won't give me anything.

284
00:36:48,774 --> 00:36:52,093
Even if he did, I wouldn't take it.
Why not?

285
00:36:53,494 --> 00:36:56,934
No matter what's happened,
I've got me pride.

286
00:36:57,974 --> 00:37:01,054
That's something, isn't it(?)

287
00:37:01,054 --> 00:37:03,094
Have you got any money?

288
00:37:04,094 --> 00:37:06,294
No.

289
00:37:07,534 --> 00:37:11,094
You'd better get yourself
a place to live.

290
00:37:11,094 --> 00:37:14,214
After that,
we'll see what can be done.

291
00:37:14,214 --> 00:37:19,094
Philip, you were always so good
to me. I knew I could come to you.

292
00:37:25,293 --> 00:37:31,174
Look here, Mr Miller. I like to know what
you intend to do about Mildred.  I?

293
00:37:31,174 --> 00:37:35,094
What you expect me to do?
Take care of her. You married her.

294
00:37:35,094 --> 00:37:39,413
I? I married Mildred? Ach!

295
00:37:39,413 --> 00:37:41,454
I married...

296
00:37:43,494 --> 00:37:45,334
This one.

297
00:37:49,774 --> 00:37:53,214
I'd still like to know what
you intend to do about it.

298
00:37:53,214 --> 00:37:56,054
Me? I can do nothing.

299
00:37:56,054 --> 00:38:00,614
One man cannot solution the
problem of the unmarried mother.

300
00:38:07,714 --> 00:38:10,034
Why didn't you tell me?

301
00:38:11,574 --> 00:38:13,574
I just couldn't.

302
00:38:15,213 --> 00:38:17,414
Well, brace up.

303
00:38:17,414 --> 00:38:19,774
Everything will be all right.

304
00:38:38,734 --> 00:38:40,694
Philip...

305
00:38:42,574 --> 00:38:45,614
Do you still...like me?

306
00:38:49,654 --> 00:38:51,614
Really?

307
00:38:51,614 --> 00:38:55,134
Strange as it may seem,
I always have.

308
00:38:55,134 --> 00:38:57,534
I suppose I always shall.

309
00:38:57,534 --> 00:39:01,013
I did everything I could
to make you love me.

310
00:39:01,013 --> 00:39:04,534
I thought you were incapable
of loving anybody.

311
00:39:04,534 --> 00:39:10,294
It seems horrible to think
that you were willing to sacrifice
everything for that man.

312
00:39:10,294 --> 00:39:12,414
I'm awfully sorry, Philip.

313
00:39:13,493 --> 00:39:16,894
I shall never forget
you wanted to marry me.

314
00:39:30,694 --> 00:39:33,254
Philip? Yes?

315
00:39:35,214 --> 00:39:37,654
You've been so nice to me...

316
00:39:40,014 --> 00:39:42,454
..I'll do anything you want.

317
00:39:44,094 --> 00:39:46,174
Will you? Why?

318
00:39:46,174 --> 00:39:48,614
Why, I owe it to you.

319
00:39:49,854 --> 00:39:51,893
Oh. Do you?

320
00:39:57,054 --> 00:39:59,134
You're not angry.

321
00:39:59,134 --> 00:40:00,813
No.

322
00:40:05,814 --> 00:40:10,294
Then you'll stay and have
Yes, if you want me to.

323
00:40:11,414 --> 00:40:15,494
Of course, Philip.
Nothing could delight me more.

324
00:40:15,494 --> 00:40:19,053
Just a moment
and I'll have everything ready.

325
00:40:52,414 --> 00:40:54,494
Come in.

326
00:40:59,574 --> 00:41:01,454
Hello, darling.

327
00:41:01,454 --> 00:41:03,494
Norah!

328
00:41:03,494 --> 00:41:06,174
How did you happen to come?

329
00:41:06,174 --> 00:41:08,574
Just passing by.

330
00:41:10,974 --> 00:41:14,134
I wanted to rub my nose
against your door.

331
00:41:17,294 --> 00:41:20,774
Philip,
why haven't I heard from you?

332
00:41:20,774 --> 00:41:23,254
I was just going to write.

333
00:41:23,254 --> 00:41:25,973
Why haven't you come to see me?

334
00:41:25,973 --> 00:41:28,454
Well, I...I've been busy.

335
00:41:30,694 --> 00:41:32,693
Why so silent?

336
00:41:34,174 --> 00:41:36,734
Well, you see...

337
00:41:36,734 --> 00:41:41,094
Norah, I've got something strange
to tell you.

338
00:41:41,094 --> 00:41:45,453
You've been so good to me,
it only makes it harder.

339
00:41:45,453 --> 00:41:47,534
Philip, what's wrong?

340
00:41:49,094 --> 00:41:51,174
I'm sorry. It's just over.

341
00:41:51,174 --> 00:41:54,734
You mean you don't care for me
any more?

342
00:41:54,734 --> 00:41:58,094
I'm afraid so. What have I done?

343
00:41:58,094 --> 00:42:01,334
Nothing.
You've been wonderful to me.

344
00:42:01,334 --> 00:42:03,374
It's just that I...

345
00:42:07,374 --> 00:42:11,454
Of course, I knew you never loved me
as much as I loved you.

346
00:42:11,454 --> 00:42:14,694
Yes, I'm afraid
that's usually the case.

347
00:42:14,694 --> 00:42:18,534
There's usually one who loves
and one who is loved.

348
00:42:18,534 --> 00:42:21,494
Oh, it's always the same.

349
00:42:21,494 --> 00:42:26,214
You want a man to be nice to you,
you have to be rotten to him.

350
00:42:26,214 --> 00:42:29,254
If you treat a man honestly, you...

351
00:42:33,334 --> 00:42:36,894
Philip, there's someone else.

352
00:42:39,614 --> 00:42:42,054
Yes.

353
00:42:42,054 --> 00:42:44,334
Who is she?

354
00:42:44,334 --> 00:42:46,294
Mildred.

355
00:42:46,294 --> 00:42:48,254
She's come back.

356
00:42:49,414 --> 00:42:51,854
After all she's done.

357
00:42:53,094 --> 00:42:55,374
How could you?

358
00:42:55,374 --> 00:42:58,094
That's what I'd like to know.

359
00:42:58,094 --> 00:43:02,454
It's just as though
you're bound to her in some way.

360
00:43:02,454 --> 00:43:04,414
Yes.

361
00:43:04,414 --> 00:43:06,534
As I am to you.

362
00:43:07,654 --> 00:43:09,933
And she was to Miller.

363
00:43:09,933 --> 00:43:14,374
As every human being is
to something or other.

364
00:43:27,854 --> 00:43:32,574
Funny looking little thing,
isn't it? I can't believe it's mine.

365
00:43:32,574 --> 00:43:35,134
Now, if you'll excuse me.

366
00:43:42,974 --> 00:43:45,654
So glad it's over, darling.

367
00:43:45,654 --> 00:43:48,414
You've been so good to me, Philip.

368
00:43:48,414 --> 00:43:51,494
From now on,
things will be different.

369
00:43:56,734 --> 00:44:00,134
Now, you will take good care of her,
won't you?

370
00:44:00,134 --> 00:44:02,374
That I will, ma'am.

371
00:44:04,974 --> 00:44:06,894
Good day. Good day.

372
00:44:11,334 --> 00:44:13,814
I know you don't like it, Philip.

373
00:44:13,814 --> 00:44:18,773
I can't do anything else
I suppose not.

374
00:44:18,773 --> 00:44:23,654
Be sure and go over on Sundays
and see the baby's taken care of.

375
00:44:23,654 --> 00:44:25,734
I will.

376
00:44:27,014 --> 00:44:30,414
What are we going to do
this afternoon?

377
00:44:30,414 --> 00:44:32,774
I asked Griffiths to come over.

378
00:44:32,774 --> 00:44:35,214
Oh, did you?

379
00:44:35,214 --> 00:44:41,614
Why? I know you find him amusing
and I'm always afraid of boring you.

380
00:44:49,254 --> 00:44:51,374
Hello, hello, hello.

381
00:44:51,374 --> 00:44:54,894
Sorry I'm late.
Had to get rid of a girl.

382
00:44:54,894 --> 00:44:58,814
Why didn't you bring her?
I'm not interested in MY girl.

383
00:44:58,814 --> 00:45:03,014
I'm interested in other men's girls.
D'you like me?

384
00:45:09,094 --> 00:45:13,493
Really, I'm too hungry to know.
I think I like you lots.

385
00:45:13,493 --> 00:45:18,694
I'd like you more if he took us out
to dinner. I'd tell you stories.

386
00:45:18,694 --> 00:45:22,894
You'll have a wonderful time.
What would he do?

387
00:45:22,894 --> 00:45:25,134
Ooh, pay the bill.

388
00:45:36,813 --> 00:45:42,014
I said, "What's that? Your missus?
I thought it was your sister!"

389
00:45:52,574 --> 00:45:54,534
Oh, allez-up!

390
00:45:54,534 --> 00:45:56,574
Allez-up!

391
00:45:57,653 --> 00:46:00,174
"Thought it was your sister!"

392
00:46:08,694 --> 00:46:10,894
Good night, Philip.

393
00:46:13,013 --> 00:46:15,654
Good night.

394
00:46:24,854 --> 00:46:26,894
Just a moment.

395
00:46:26,894 --> 00:46:29,294
Are you in love with Mildred?

396
00:46:29,294 --> 00:46:31,774
I?

397
00:46:31,774 --> 00:46:35,694
That's what you've been
so funny about! My dear old boy...

398
00:46:35,694 --> 00:46:41,054
Look here. It doesn't matter to you,
Harry. You've got so many women.

399
00:46:41,054 --> 00:46:44,973
Don't take Mildred away from me.
My dear old boy!

400
00:46:44,973 --> 00:46:48,934
She's nothing to me at all!
Nothing at all!

401
00:47:04,534 --> 00:47:07,334
Do you like it, Philip? Very much.

402
00:47:07,334 --> 00:47:10,454
So nice of you to give it to me.

403
00:47:17,134 --> 00:47:19,194
What are you thinking about?

404
00:47:19,694 --> 00:47:22,954
You were having quite a flirtation
with Griffiths last night.

405
00:47:22,954 --> 00:47:24,614
Yes I was, wasn't I?

406
00:47:25,014 --> 00:47:29,894
Matter of fact, well...
I'm sort of in love with him.

407
00:47:30,294 --> 00:47:31,934
I'm not surprised!

408
00:47:31,934 --> 00:47:33,444
What do you mean?

409
00:47:33,444 --> 00:47:36,954
Well Griffiths is good looking,
he amusing, he says the  kind
things that make you laugh.

410
00:47:36,954 --> 00:47:40,474
I'll thank you not to make fun of me.
You are a bit too superior for
me you fine young friend.

411
00:47:40,474 --> 00:47:42,093
Oh for heavens sake Mildred,
I wasn't making fun of you.

412
00:47:42,093 --> 00:47:45,734
Well you certainly don't act as if it's
serious. I don't think it is. Why not?

413
00:47:45,934 --> 00:47:50,734
Griffiths isn't in love with you.
How do you know? I asked him.

414
00:47:52,654 --> 00:47:57,174
Would you like to read a letter
I got from him this morning?

415
00:48:01,974 --> 00:48:05,494
"I've been up all night
thinking about you.

416
00:48:05,494 --> 00:48:11,093
"I have just sent for a messenger
to take this to you in the dawn.

417
00:48:11,093 --> 00:48:16,173
"You've no notion of the time
I had with your friend last night.

418
00:48:16,173 --> 00:48:21,334
"He kept asking me if I love you
and of course what could I say?

419
00:48:21,334 --> 00:48:23,654
"He'll doubtless tell you all this,

420
00:48:23,654 --> 00:48:26,453
"so I'm making sure that you..."

421
00:48:33,314 --> 00:48:36,794
Well? Can't help it
if I love him, can I?

422
00:48:36,794 --> 00:48:41,234
No. I suppose not. Then what
is going on about? Nothing.

423
00:48:41,634 --> 00:48:46,313
Only I was fool enough to think
that you cared for me. I do, Philip.

424
00:48:46,313 --> 00:48:48,354
As a friend.

425
00:48:48,354 --> 00:48:50,554
Not in any other way.

426
00:48:50,554 --> 00:48:54,874
But you do care for Griffiths
in the other way.

427
00:48:56,714 --> 00:49:01,234
But you're cold. That sort of thing
doesn't mean anything to you.

428
00:49:03,114 --> 00:49:05,634
That's what YOU think.

429
00:49:14,394 --> 00:49:17,634
It's no use going on about it,
Philip.

430
00:49:17,634 --> 00:49:22,914
You said yourself that I couldn't
help it if I'm in love with him.

431
00:49:27,234 --> 00:49:30,514
If there's anything else
to be said, say it.

432
00:49:32,354 --> 00:49:35,694
That's a nice dress
you have on, Mildred.

433
00:49:35,794 --> 00:49:39,154
I couldn't afford it,
but I paid for it.

434
00:49:39,154 --> 00:49:42,314
You have a nice apartment.
I couldn't afford it but I...

435
00:49:42,314 --> 00:49:45,954
If you were a gentleman, would you
throw what you've done in my face?

436
00:49:46,354 --> 00:49:49,094
Do you think it matters to me
whether I'm a gentleman or not?

437
00:49:49,094 --> 00:49:52,114
If I were, you don't suppose
I'd care for a cheap vulgar...

438
00:49:54,453 --> 00:49:58,054
I'm sorry, Philip.
I didn't want to end this way.

439
00:50:02,774 --> 00:50:06,933
Harry's waiting for me.
What do you intend to do?

440
00:50:07,233 --> 00:50:10,154
We're going to Paris.

441
00:50:10,154 --> 00:50:12,194
Get out.

442
00:50:12,194 --> 00:50:13,834
Get out!

443
00:51:04,394 --> 00:51:10,034
I've moved three times and each time
this woman's hounded me down.

444
00:51:10,034 --> 00:51:12,474
I don't like to do this but...

445
00:51:12,474 --> 00:51:15,033
All right, sir. I'll move her on.

446
00:51:15,033 --> 00:51:18,873
Come on, young lady.
You can't stay here. Come on, now.

447
00:51:43,994 --> 00:51:48,154
Look here, Carey. Mildred and I
are all washed up... Too bad.

448
00:51:49,694 --> 00:51:52,614
Excuse me. I'm due in the ward.

449
00:52:10,094 --> 00:52:15,214
Anything interesting, Carey? I was just
thinking what an unusual name you have.

450
00:52:15,214 --> 00:52:19,313
An old Yorkshire name. Once took
a day's riding across our estates.

451
00:52:19,413 --> 00:52:21,974
And here I am in a charity hospital

452
00:52:21,974 --> 00:52:26,014
because my father loved fast
women and slow horses.

453
00:52:26,014 --> 00:52:28,574
How the mighty are fallen!

454
00:52:30,854 --> 00:52:33,374
Hello! Hello, Father.

455
00:52:37,774 --> 00:52:41,934
Carey, this is my daughter,
christened Maria del Sol.

456
00:52:41,934 --> 00:52:45,974
Her mother called her Sally.
This young man is a student here.

457
00:52:45,974 --> 00:52:50,374
He's been nice to me. With some
inducement, he might be nice to YOU.

458
00:52:50,374 --> 00:52:55,334
Now, Father. Father's particular
genius is saying the wrong thing.

459
00:52:55,334 --> 00:52:57,894
He thinks it's fun to embarrass me.

460
00:52:57,894 --> 00:53:01,454
It is. Try it some time, Carey.

461
00:53:01,454 --> 00:53:04,854
I will, if I get the chance.
You shall have it!

462
00:53:04,854 --> 00:53:08,373
You're coming to see us
the first Sunday I am home.

463
00:53:08,373 --> 00:53:11,494
Oh, yes. Please do.

464
00:53:35,294 --> 00:53:38,133
What a quaint house!

465
00:53:38,133 --> 00:53:43,613
Yes, but it's not very sanitary.
Sanitation be hanged! Give me art!

466
00:53:43,613 --> 00:53:47,694
I've got nine children
and they thrive on bad drains.

467
00:53:47,694 --> 00:53:51,454
Look at that, now.
I am, with great admiration.

468
00:53:54,974 --> 00:53:56,373
Shall I bring the ale, Father?

469
00:53:56,373 --> 00:53:59,494
Right, m'girl.
The sooner the better.

470
00:53:59,494 --> 00:54:03,214
I hope you didn't have the table
in here on my account.

471
00:54:03,214 --> 00:54:06,094
I'd be quiet happy to have had dinner
with Mrs. Athelny and the children.

472
00:54:06,094 --> 00:54:10,374
Oh, no. I always take meals by myself.
I like these antique customs.

473
00:54:10,374 --> 00:54:14,534
I don't think women ought
to sit down at table with men.

474
00:54:14,534 --> 00:54:17,493
Don't you? Why not?
It ruins conversation.

475
00:54:19,574 --> 00:54:25,934
It's bad for them. Puts ideas
in their heads! Women are never
at ease when they have ideas.

476
00:54:25,934 --> 00:54:29,934
You sound like the voice
of old England. I am, sir.

477
00:54:29,934 --> 00:54:34,174
This fine, old Yorkshire pudding
gives me strength to carry on.

478
00:54:34,174 --> 00:54:37,894
Now stop getting up and down like jumping
Jack every time she comes in the room.

479
00:54:37,894 --> 00:54:40,694
She doesn't want you to make
a fuss about it, do you Sally?

480
00:54:40,694 --> 00:54:47,734
She won't think it rude if
you sit still. She don't care a hang
for chivalry, do you, Sally?

481
00:54:47,734 --> 00:54:49,454
No, Father.

482
00:54:49,454 --> 00:54:54,054
You speak quietly while eyeing
the young man so boldly.

483
00:54:55,134 --> 00:54:57,533
Yes, Father.

484
00:54:57,533 --> 00:55:01,454
You know what I'm talking about Sally?
How could I, darling?

485
00:55:01,454 --> 00:55:03,494
You're so clever.

486
00:55:03,494 --> 00:55:07,094
Don't stand behind me
in order to make eyes at him.

487
00:55:07,094 --> 00:55:09,814
Better get Philip some more ale.

488
00:55:19,893 --> 00:55:23,894
My word! Is there anything better
than English ale?

489
00:55:23,894 --> 00:55:26,974
Let us thank God
for simple pleasures -

490
00:55:26,974 --> 00:55:30,254
a good appetite,
roast beef and beer.

491
00:55:30,254 --> 00:55:32,974
I was married to a lady once.

492
00:55:34,814 --> 00:55:39,974
Good heavens! Never marry a lady,
my boy! Oh, really? Why?

493
00:55:39,974 --> 00:55:46,734
Because a lady has a point of view,
a personality and an individuality
all the devil you with.

494
00:55:46,734 --> 00:55:52,574
You want a wife who can cook dinner
and look after your children.
Don't you think so, Sally?

495
00:55:52,574 --> 00:55:56,894
I think you'd talk the hind leg
of the donkey. It's clean fun.

496
00:55:56,894 --> 00:55:59,054
Now, Sally waited on me,
I'll wait on you.

497
00:55:59,054 --> 00:56:05,013
Take my chair while I fetch you
and the young man some cheese.
Thank you, Father.

498
00:56:05,013 --> 00:56:07,374
What do you think of us?

499
00:56:08,534 --> 00:56:13,254
You don't know what this means to
me. I practically never had family.

500
00:56:13,254 --> 00:56:18,094
This is the only place I've known
that's had the quality of...home.

501
00:56:20,413 --> 00:56:21,494
Thank you, Father.

502
00:56:28,534 --> 00:56:31,654
It's no use mooning over her, Carey.

503
00:56:32,893 --> 00:56:36,974
Sally never kisses a gentleman
until he's been here twice.

504
00:56:38,974 --> 00:56:42,493
Well, you must ask me again,
some time.

505
00:56:42,493 --> 00:56:44,494
Do it yourself!

506
00:56:44,894 --> 00:56:46,973
Why don't you come next Sunday?

507
00:57:35,894 --> 00:57:39,534
May I walk to the station with you?
No. Why not?

508
00:57:39,534 --> 00:57:43,054
It's too late and you're a child.
I'm 20.

509
00:57:43,054 --> 00:57:45,894
Let's talk it over when you're 30.

510
00:58:01,534 --> 00:58:04,014
Did you hear what I said, old man?

511
00:58:04,014 --> 00:58:08,494
Yes, I heard. Sorry if I brought
up a painful subject.

512
00:58:08,494 --> 00:58:14,914
I thought you'd be interested to hear
about Mildred. Sorry she's had a bad time.
I gave her all I could.

513
00:58:14,914 --> 00:58:19,994
But you know me, always stony broke.
I thought perhaps you'd want to...

514
00:58:20,494 --> 00:58:24,454
I can't do anything. Got another cigarette?

515
00:58:24,454 --> 00:58:26,494
I don't blame you.

516
00:58:26,494 --> 00:58:31,454
I wouldn't have told you. She asked
me to give you her address.

517
00:58:31,454 --> 00:58:36,894
Gave me a jolt, seeing her with that
baby, asking for something to eat.

518
00:58:36,894 --> 00:58:39,454
She had the baby with her? Yes.

519
00:58:39,454 --> 00:58:43,014
Not difficult to imagine
her next step.

520
00:59:33,414 --> 00:59:35,774
Baby all right?

521
00:59:35,774 --> 00:59:38,294
I'm very grateful to you, Philip.

522
00:59:39,214 --> 00:59:45,294
If I could afford it, I'd have given
you a place of your own. As it is,
you're welcome to my room.

523
00:59:45,694 --> 00:59:49,854
I don't know what would become
of me and...baby...

524
00:59:49,854 --> 00:59:52,134
if you hadn't taken us in.

525
00:59:52,134 --> 00:59:54,134
You'd have got on, I expect.

526
00:59:55,174 --> 01:00:01,574
You've always been much nicer
to me than I deserved. I'm beginning
to realise how silly I've been.

527
01:00:01,574 --> 01:00:06,814
You couldn't help how you felt.
Let's not talk about it, shall we?

528
01:00:06,814 --> 01:00:09,414
I don't feel like that now.

529
01:00:10,414 --> 01:00:14,734
Look here, Mildred. Let's have no
misunderstanding about this.

530
01:00:14,734 --> 01:00:17,534
The reason you're here is... I know.

531
01:00:17,534 --> 01:00:21,413
Because you once liked me
enough to want to marry me.

532
01:00:24,274 --> 01:00:25,754
Yes.

533
01:00:25,754 --> 01:00:30,834
Well, at least I can cook for you
and keep your flat clean.

534
01:00:33,514 --> 01:00:37,913
Maybe some day you'll...
you'll feel better about me

535
01:00:37,913 --> 01:00:41,594
and things will be like
they used to be.

536
01:00:45,474 --> 01:00:48,274
Oh, thanks. I'll smoke it later.

537
01:00:51,974 --> 01:00:55,734
Well, er... Good night.

538
01:00:58,014 --> 01:01:00,254
Good night.

539
01:01:51,214 --> 01:01:54,734
Landlady came upstairs
a little while ago.

540
01:01:54,734 --> 01:01:59,374
She said, "Mrs Carey," she said.
"How can you stand it?"

541
01:02:01,334 --> 01:02:06,294
What's the matter with them? They're
indecent. Disgusting, I calls it.

542
01:02:06,294 --> 01:02:09,693
To have drawings
of naked people about.

543
01:02:09,693 --> 01:02:14,414
If you want to know what I think,
I've half a mind to take them down.

544
01:02:14,414 --> 01:02:16,574
You'll do nothing of the kind.

545
01:02:18,014 --> 01:02:20,734
I love those pictures, Mildred.

546
01:02:20,734 --> 01:02:24,294
I love them for what
they were meant to be.

547
01:02:47,054 --> 01:02:49,414
What happened to it?

548
01:02:49,414 --> 01:02:51,334
Hm? What?

549
01:02:51,334 --> 01:02:54,054
The way you used to love me.

550
01:02:54,054 --> 01:02:56,054
Oh, I don't know.

551
01:02:56,054 --> 01:02:59,374
I was disappointed so often
and hurt so much.

552
01:02:59,374 --> 01:03:02,294
What difference does it make?

553
01:03:02,294 --> 01:03:07,094
Nothing. Only, remember how you got
when I was so cold to you?

554
01:03:08,614 --> 01:03:12,894
You're getting me that way
cos you're so cold to me.

555
01:03:12,894 --> 01:03:14,973
No-one else, is there?

556
01:03:57,934 --> 01:04:00,734
He's not in love with anybody.

557
01:04:41,974 --> 01:04:43,973
Where were you?

558
01:04:43,973 --> 01:04:46,014
Altherneys'.

559
01:04:46,014 --> 01:04:48,574
What are you doing up?

560
01:04:48,574 --> 01:04:50,734
I couldn't sleep.

561
01:04:53,654 --> 01:04:57,214
Hadn't you better put on
something warmer?

562
01:04:57,214 --> 01:04:59,574
Oh, I'll be all right.

563
01:05:02,054 --> 01:05:04,534
Just let me stay here.

564
01:05:07,974 --> 01:05:09,774
Phil...

565
01:05:11,854 --> 01:05:13,974
Phil, I love you so.

566
01:05:13,974 --> 01:05:17,974
Oh, nonsense. T'isn't.
I can't live without you.

567
01:05:17,974 --> 01:05:22,094
Please get up. You're making a fool
of yourself and a fool of me.

568
01:05:22,094 --> 01:05:24,254
Oh, Phil. Please.

569
01:05:38,374 --> 01:05:40,654
I can't go on like this.

570
01:05:42,134 --> 01:05:46,894
Nonsense. You haven't anywhere
to go. Stay as long as you like.

571
01:05:46,894 --> 01:05:50,014
But with the definite
understanding...

572
01:05:58,294 --> 01:06:00,534
You disgust me.

573
01:06:04,054 --> 01:06:06,054
Me?

574
01:06:06,054 --> 01:06:08,174
I disgust YOU?

575
01:06:09,294 --> 01:06:10,774
You.

576
01:06:10,774 --> 01:06:12,094
You!

577
01:06:12,094 --> 01:06:18,214
You're too fine!
You won't have me but you sit here all
night looking at your naked females!

578
01:06:18,214 --> 01:06:20,253
Mildred. You cad!

579
01:06:20,253 --> 01:06:22,294
You dirty swine!

580
01:06:22,294 --> 01:06:28,574
I never cared for you, not once.
I was always making a fool of you.
You bored me stiff.

581
01:06:28,574 --> 01:06:33,534
It made me sick when I let you kiss
me. I did it because you begged me.

582
01:06:33,534 --> 01:06:35,574
You drove me crazy!

583
01:06:35,574 --> 01:06:40,734
And after you kissed me,
I always use to wipe my mouth!

584
01:06:40,734 --> 01:06:45,374
Well, I made up for it.
For every kiss, we laughed at you.

585
01:06:45,374 --> 01:06:48,934
Miller and me, and Griffiths and me.
We laughed at you.

586
01:06:48,934 --> 01:06:51,574
Because you were such a
mug, a mug, a mug!

587
01:06:53,134 --> 01:06:55,614
You gippy-legged monster!

588
01:06:55,614 --> 01:06:58,574
You're a cripple! A cripple!

589
01:07:05,534 --> 01:07:09,694
You love these things.
You love what they were meant to be.

590
01:07:09,694 --> 01:07:14,534
Well, here's what
they were meant to be!

591
01:07:31,293 --> 01:07:33,534
You want to be a doctor!

592
01:08:00,054 --> 01:08:03,494
This will take care
of your medical school.

593
01:08:21,054 --> 01:08:23,813
You're leaving? ..Why?

594
01:08:23,813 --> 01:08:27,454
My money's gone.
What do you intend to do?

595
01:08:27,454 --> 01:08:30,533
Oh... Anything.

596
01:08:32,214 --> 01:08:38,854
Before you go out into the world,
don't you think we ought
to do something about that foot?

597
01:08:38,854 --> 01:08:41,014
Think it'll do any good?

598
01:08:41,014 --> 01:08:43,454
I'll know better tomorrow.

599
01:08:47,414 --> 01:08:50,574
How are you, Philip?
I'm all right, Sally.

600
01:08:50,574 --> 01:08:52,974
How's your foot? Well...

601
01:08:52,974 --> 01:08:55,254
Let's try it, shall we?

602
01:08:55,254 --> 01:08:57,294
All right.

603
01:08:59,294 --> 01:09:01,374
Careful now.

604
01:09:42,414 --> 01:09:45,974
No openings...
Sorry, nothing today...

605
01:09:45,974 --> 01:09:51,014
All situations filled...
No experience? Can't use you...

606
01:09:51,014 --> 01:09:54,374
Nothing today...
Sorry, no vacancies...

607
01:09:54,374 --> 01:09:57,094
No openings...
Nothing...

608
01:09:57,094 --> 01:09:59,894
Nothing... Nothing... Nothing...

609
01:09:59,894 --> 01:10:01,934
Nothing... Nothing...

610
01:10:51,754 --> 01:10:55,394
Why haven't you been to see us?
Oh, I don't know.

611
01:10:55,394 --> 01:10:57,434
I've had things to do.

612
01:10:58,634 --> 01:11:02,754
You've been putting on weight.
I'm sure you haven't!

613
01:11:02,754 --> 01:11:07,714
Why do you say that? The way
Oh! That's only my look!

614
01:11:07,714 --> 01:11:13,834
It's more than that. I sent you
a note and when you didn't answer
I went to your room.

615
01:11:13,834 --> 01:11:18,434
Your landlady said
she had to put you out.

616
01:11:19,793 --> 01:11:22,194
Hello, Philip!

617
01:11:31,034 --> 01:11:38,474
My dear fellow, by pre-arranged
signal, my daughter communicated to
me confirmation of our suspicions.

618
01:11:38,474 --> 01:11:42,274
As you know, I've been on the beach
most of my life.

619
01:11:42,274 --> 01:11:45,954
In Tahiti, I was President
of the Beachcombers' Union!

620
01:11:45,954 --> 01:11:49,833
I would like to enquire
into your amateur standing.

621
01:11:49,833 --> 01:11:52,194
Where have you been staying?

622
01:11:52,194 --> 01:11:55,714
Oh...anywhere.
Why didn't you come here?

623
01:11:55,714 --> 01:11:59,794
False modesty, I suppose.
Now, stop being an Englishman.

624
01:11:59,794 --> 01:12:04,034
When a man's on his uppers,
it's time he came down to Earth.

625
01:12:04,034 --> 01:12:06,874
We want you here with us. Well, I...

626
01:12:08,714 --> 01:12:13,994
Thanks very much, but... You're
to stay until you get your bearings.

627
01:12:13,994 --> 01:12:18,274
I want no more fine talk about it.
It's all arranged.

628
01:12:19,754 --> 01:12:21,594
Well...

629
01:12:22,954 --> 01:12:26,114
Well, here goes my amateur standing.

630
01:12:26,114 --> 01:12:28,874
I-I really have no place to go.

631
01:12:28,874 --> 01:12:33,754
It's awfully good of you. Nonsense!
The house is completely unsanitary.

632
01:12:33,754 --> 01:12:37,594
You'll wind up with some
foul disease! Let him alone, Father.

633
01:12:37,594 --> 01:12:41,554
I want to talk to him.
I suppose youth must be served.

634
01:12:41,554 --> 01:12:45,474
But I'm sick and tired
of serving it. Nine of them!

635
01:12:47,834 --> 01:12:49,874
Will that do?

636
01:12:49,874 --> 01:12:52,114
Looks as if it might.

637
01:12:55,994 --> 01:12:58,834
Wouldn't be a nice night to be out.

638
01:12:58,834 --> 01:13:03,234
Not really. No. It's going to be
jolly having you here.

639
01:13:03,234 --> 01:13:07,194
I hope I shan't have to stay
very long. Why?

640
01:13:07,194 --> 01:13:10,594
I can't go on like this, you know.
I need a job.

641
01:13:10,594 --> 01:13:14,674
Father and I discussed that.
There isn't much you've overlooked.

642
01:13:16,474 --> 01:13:21,074
I'll have to sew that on, too.
And Father has a job for you.

643
01:13:21,074 --> 01:13:23,594
Has he? Where? Where he works.

644
01:14:15,834 --> 01:14:18,353
You're walking all right now.

645
01:14:19,434 --> 01:14:21,594
I saw you in the window.

646
01:14:24,714 --> 01:14:27,674
I never thought you'd come to that.

647
01:14:30,434 --> 01:14:33,834
You're very hoarse. Throat sore?

648
01:14:36,394 --> 01:14:40,713
You haven't forgotten
your doctoring, have you? No.

649
01:14:40,713 --> 01:14:45,754
Because...that's what I want
to see you about.

650
01:14:45,754 --> 01:14:47,994
Why not go to a doctor?

651
01:14:51,754 --> 01:14:56,354
There's the Free Hospital.
All them students staring at me?

652
01:14:59,434 --> 01:15:04,314
What seems to be the trouble?
Well, I cough all the time.

653
01:15:06,394 --> 01:15:09,554
Let's have a look at your throat.

654
01:15:35,514 --> 01:15:37,194
Phil.

655
01:15:38,994 --> 01:15:42,194
It's not...me lungs, is it?

656
01:15:58,274 --> 01:16:00,354
Where's the baby?

657
01:16:01,954 --> 01:16:05,914
She died last summer.

658
01:16:05,914 --> 01:16:07,234
Oh.

659
01:16:07,234 --> 01:16:11,514
You might say you're sorry.
I'm not. I'm very glad.

660
01:16:16,754 --> 01:16:19,514
I'm afraid I can't help you much.

661
01:16:26,914 --> 01:16:30,754
Don't leave me, Philip.
I know I've treated you shocking.

662
01:16:30,754 --> 01:16:34,834
But don't leave me. Not yet, please.
There's no-one I can go to.

663
01:16:34,834 --> 01:16:38,793
You're the only one that treated me
like I was human.

664
01:16:38,793 --> 01:16:43,034
You're a gentleman, Philip.
The only one I've ever met.

665
01:16:49,514 --> 01:16:51,714
Some things you'll need.

666
01:17:41,234 --> 01:17:43,394
Our last day.

667
01:17:47,474 --> 01:17:49,754
Why, Sally!

668
01:17:49,754 --> 01:17:51,473
Darling.

669
01:17:51,473 --> 01:17:55,274
I was so determined
not to let you see.

670
01:17:55,274 --> 01:17:59,714
Well, that's sweet of you
to care because I'm going away.

671
01:18:01,994 --> 01:18:08,314
I suppose I'm a fool to care,
but it doesn't mean you have to do
anything about it.

672
01:18:08,314 --> 01:18:13,154
You can't help it because someone
loves you and you don't love back.

673
01:18:13,154 --> 01:18:15,394
Sally, look at me.

674
01:18:17,794 --> 01:18:22,274
Darling, do you think you'll always
feel like this about me?

675
01:18:22,274 --> 01:18:23,794
Yes.

676
01:18:25,194 --> 01:18:29,514
I've known it since the first time
you came to our house.

677
01:18:30,994 --> 01:18:34,874
I thought at first that
I meant something to you, too.

678
01:18:34,874 --> 01:18:36,914
Oh, but you did.

679
01:18:36,914 --> 01:18:38,793
You do.

680
01:18:39,874 --> 01:18:45,234
When I come back, if you feel the
same, will you marry me, darling?

681
01:18:49,714 --> 01:18:52,714
Don't you mean if YOU feel the same?

682
01:19:12,114 --> 01:19:15,714
This is what you might call
the irony of fate.

683
01:19:15,714 --> 01:19:19,314
Come on now. Be quick.
Get her out of here.

684
01:19:20,954 --> 01:19:24,114
I don't want the likes of her
on me hands.

685
01:19:29,994 --> 01:19:34,274
I understand there's an interesting
Don't go in there.

686
01:19:34,274 --> 01:19:36,314
Why not?

687
01:19:36,314 --> 01:19:38,714
If you please... It's no use.

688
01:20:07,274 --> 01:20:09,754
Philip, I'm sorry I'm late.

689
01:20:09,754 --> 01:20:12,234
You're not. I'm not going.

690
01:20:19,714 --> 01:20:21,714
What's that?

691
01:20:23,514 --> 01:20:26,274
My wedding present to my wife.

692
01:20:29,274 --> 01:20:32,314
When do you intend to marry me?

693
01:20:32,314 --> 01:20:34,194
Right away.

694
01:20:34,194 --> 01:20:36,154
Thank you, Philip.

695
01:20:36,154 --> 01:20:38,634
Oh, I beg your pardon.

696
01:20:38,634 --> 01:20:40,874
You don't seem very pleased.

697
01:20:40,874 --> 01:20:43,194
Well, I am and I'm not.

698
01:20:43,194 --> 01:20:47,153
Why? I'm afraid
it's only a noble gesture.

699
01:20:47,153 --> 01:20:51,953
That's not enough for marriage.
No, Sally. It isn't just that.

700
01:20:51,953 --> 01:20:55,554
I like you far too much
to stand in your way.

701
01:21:23,034 --> 01:21:28,354
Philip, you're free. Yes,
but suddenly there's nowhere to go.

702
01:21:28,354 --> 01:21:30,794
Taxi, sir? No, thanks.

703
01:21:30,794 --> 01:21:33,513
I had to be free to realise that,

704
01:21:33,513 --> 01:21:40,634
free to understand that all those
years I dreamed of escape was
because I was limping through life.

705
01:21:40,634 --> 01:21:42,994
Taxi, sir? No, thank you!

706
01:21:42,994 --> 01:21:48,474
And because I was bound up with
a person who was incredible to me.

707
01:21:48,474 --> 01:21:50,513
That's all over.

708
01:21:50,513 --> 01:21:55,593
I'm not limping any more. My life's
all right. Then why don't you go?

709
01:21:58,114 --> 01:22:02,194
Because everything that's beautiful
to me is right here.

710
01:22:02,194 --> 01:22:04,954
Won't you please marry me, Sally?

711
01:22:06,074 --> 01:22:09,713
If you like. But don't you want to?

712
01:22:11,554 --> 01:22:14,474
Well, there's no-one else I'd marry.

713
01:22:17,314 --> 01:22:19,354
How about a taxi, sir?

714
01:22:19,354 --> 01:22:22,314
What? How about a taxi?

715
01:22:22,314 --> 01:22:24,354
Yes.
