This day and age,
and we still have blackouts?
And there's no Wi-Fi either.
Who's there?
Hey, this isn't funny.
Help! Help!
Get ready!
One, two, three.
Is it deep?
Hey, it's just sand, there are no rocks.
Is it cold?
Cold, cold, cold.
Wah, ha ha ha.
You're so timid.
Can you be braver next time?
Moron! Come here.
Okay.
Scared, huh? Scared
Hey, sorry, sorry.
Hey!
My god, are you blind?
It's your fault.
Why leave things in the middle?
Luckily it didn't get too far.
Oh, is it my fault now?
Clean it up right now.
You're so stern.
Why would anyone
want to get engaged to you?
- Take this.
- Okay, okay, okay.
Look at that cousin of yours.
She thinks I am bad at repairing cars.
I am good at it!
You pushed me just now?
Sir, we lost the GPS signal.
Do I go straight?
Yes, just follow the road.
Yes, sir.
Where exactly is this college?
And aren't the students
on their semester break?
Do you teach there?
Yes.
Adli, Mom's calling. Adli.
Boboi!
Hey, don't you have another name?
That's the name of my cat back at home.
You don't want to answer Mum's call here.
While at home,
you cling to Mom all the time.
Alia, why did you call me Boboi?
I called your name because
you didn't respond. Mom's calling.
I'll return her call later.
What's there to call?
There's no coverage at the hostel.
Alia, there's Wi-Fi at the hostel.
Gang!
Let's pray before we head back.
I'll pray later at the hostel.
Liar.
Hey!
Assalamualaikum, Mom.
Yes, Adli's here.
He's bathing at the river.
I just thought of bringing him
and his friends to play by the river.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'll look after him. Kak Fiza is here too.
Okay, Mom.
Bye!
I'm not ready.
Stop taking my picture.
They won't turn out good!
You don't have to be ready.
You always look good.
Okay no, no, one more time!
Okay, one more!
One!
Two!
Three!
Look!
Isn't it nice?
Yes, it's nice.
Kak Yam, what are you doing here?
Delivering food supplies.
Otherwise, what will the kids
who didn't go home eat?
They're all grown up.
They can take care of themselves.
Hey! Farid.
Did you hear?
Hear what?
About the village right behind.
Last week there was a fuss.
Some villagers got possessed.
The Silat boys got possessed!
There were seven of them.
Those Silat guys always go overboard.
- They were too engrossed.
- Hey, I'm serious here!
Their eyes turned all black.
Their sclerae disappeared.
Their faces turned pale!
Perhaps due to drugs.
No!
Enough.
I have to deliver food to the canteen.
Okay, Kak.
In the name of God,
the merciful and compassionate.
Oh Allah, oh my God,
please forgive our sins.
The sins of our parents,
the sins of our teachers.
Protect us from calamities.
I beg you, oh Allah.
Please extend the lives of our parents.
Please extend the lives of our teachers.
Forgive our sins
and distance us from adultery.
And all kinds of sins, little or great.
Ya Allah.
Answer me, oh, God.
Hurry up!
Adli, the smoke has to go
further that way!
Be patient! If you want it fast,
cook it yourself.
No, the problem now is
I asked you guys to pray,
but you guys lied!
That's right!
Great.
This is lying.
Hey, seriously, is the chicken enough?
I don't think it's enough.
Done.
Wow!
Eating alone, huh?
I asleep from waiting so long.
How could you do this to me?
Blame them for late!
I cooked it myself.
Here, it's all done for you. I'm sorry.
Adli, you too.
Why you didn't learn to cook properly?
Sorry, Kak Fiza.
Now you're scared!
Hey, hey, where's Wari?
Wari.
I saw him over there just now.
- Wari.
- Huh?
Wari.
Wari!
Are you done?
Yes.
Tomorrow morning I'll come at 5:00.
Don't you forget to wake up.
Don't worry, I'm a professional.
Teacher?
Kak Yam.
- Is Warden Harris around?
- Yes, teacher.
In the office, probably.
What happened to his hand?
He got into an accident!
He's still on leave, isn't he?
All right. I'll make my move.
Stay safe, Kak.
Come in.
Nazmi!
Have a seat.
Sorry.
I had to ask you come work early today.
It's all right.
There's nothing left for me at home.
Don't say such things, Mi.
Allah is testing you because
He loves you.
There must be a reason behind it.
Right.
A reason
which I couldn't find.
I seek forgiveness from Allah.
There.
How's your arm?
It looks bad.
No.
Broken.
Hey. Here.
List of students
who will stay here tonight.
Only 27 of them?
This is what I managed to get.
Hey!
Sorry again.
If it wasn't for the emergency
I wouldn't have called.
No worries.
I really wanted to work.
This is the key to the warden's room.
Stay there.
I only left few things there.
- Just my clothes.
- Okay.
One more thing.
For tonight's maghrib prayers
you'll be the imam.
Ask someone else to do it.
Hey, hurry up.
I want to go home.
Let's go, let's go.
Quick!
Quit messing around, I want to go home.
Now, okay.
- I'm going back.
- Okay, boss.
Now the gate is closed.
We're done for.
Relax, Sam.
It's just a gate.
Then how are you guys going in?
How about this, Kak?
We'll go back to the main road.
Drive us to the back.
Okay?
This is too much.
Kak. Stop, Kak.
- Here?
- Yes, here.
Hey, get on out.
Get on out?
Where to?
Sam, you're such a nerd.
I asked you to hang out
but you didn't want to.
Let's go.
Hey.
You'll heading back to KL?
No, the day after tomorrow.
Kak Miza has to meet the caterer tomorrow.
Oh.
Do you have some money, Alia?
Now he's asking for money.
Where's your own money?
Kak, I've finished my money from PTPTN.
Did you spend it or did you waste it?
Of course I spent it,
what else could it be?
Here.
Thanks, Alia.
Oh dear.
Your brother is such a spoiled kid.
Kak, why are you being jealous?
Hey, when you guys are back in KL,
Give my regards to our parents and all.
- If God wills.
- Take care of yourself.
Take care, Kak.
Bye.
Bye, Boboi.
Hey, Wari.
What about the photos?
I'll email them later.
Send only the nice ones.
Otherwise, I don't want it.
Any photo with you in it is nice.
Go, they'll leave you behind.
Bye, Alia. Bye, Kak.
Bye.
All right, let's go.
I like Wari.
He's a sweet guy.
Hey,
What?
You like my sister, don't you?
What are you talking about?
Don't lie to me.
Even if I do like her,
what's your problem?
Big problem.
You would be my brother-in-law
out of nowhere, you know.
Bullshit.
Just open up.
Adli, help carry my bag.
Okay.
Right now.
We'll go past the teachers' office.
Wait.
Why don't we just walk along
the new block?
You're so dense.
Aren't we on semester break now?
The teachers have gone home.
Hey.
Hurry up.
Wari.
Hey.
- Are you okay?
- Okay.
Let's go.
Hey, one second.
Okay, let's go. It's nothing!
Just a prank.
How dare you prank me?
- Prank!
- One,
two, three, run!
Why are you guys leaving me behind?
Gang.
Whoever's the last is a monkey!
Sam is a monkey!
So, who's the monkey?
Sam.
He already looks like one.
Where are you coming from?
We came from…
We came from the surau.
Just finished prayers.
That's true, we came from the surau.
The student who was the imam
took attendance.
Your names weren't on it.
Maybe because there were too many of us.
He didn't notice us.
Many, huh?
Only seven people prayed at the surau.
Whose is this?
It's not ours, teacher.
Maybe belongs to someone else.
What other students?
They've all gone home.
You guys are the only ones here.
I don't know, teacher.
All I know is I don't smoke.
Neither do I.
Follow me.
See, I told you guys…
You guys are stubborn.
Ouch.
What's your problem?
Playing the blame game now?
You want to save yourself?
Chill, I got punished too, right?
Hey, gang.
Isn't Teacher Nazmi on a long break?
Why is he here working?
I saw his arm.
Did you notice there was a cast on it?
An accident?
Hey.
Forget about him. Why bother meddling in
other people's business?
Let's do our job.
Come on.
Wari.
Are you okay?
Okay.
I thought you had a fever.
Hey.
Clean this up, you guys.
You think I'm paying you guys for nothing?
Listen here.
I…
left a gift for you guys In the toilet.
The flush didn't work.
- What are you waiting for?
- Pick it up.
I ain't picking it up.
You.
Don't play with soap, okay?
Why are you laughing?
As if you have never played with it.
What soap do you use?
This one.
I'm done.
There's no Internet.
Blackout.
How to update my vlog?
- Wait.
- What?
Oh, no, my phone
is running out of battery.
Same here, my phone is dying out too.
I don't have coverage either.
How am I supposed to call my mom now?
Serves you right. You disobeyed Alia.
Good for you. Suit with your name, Boboi.
You…
Hey.
Teacher isn't around, is he? Let's leave.
Hey. Don't do that.
If teacher found out.
We would be done for.
Let's finish this. Just a bit more.
- Come on.
- You're playing rough.
Wari. Wari. Wari.
Wari!
Hey. Wari, are you okay?
Do you want some medicine?
I'm not feeling well.
Bring him to the dorm,
let him have some rest.
Let's go.
Get in.
Faster, get in.
Lie down.
Oh my!
It feels so hot.
Why is he so feverish?
- It's really hot.
- Hot.
I don't know what to do now.
Okay, never mind.
I'll go get some medicine from teacher.
You guys take care of him.
Okay.
Get some rest, Wari.
Hurry, Adli.
Wari.
What's wrong with you? You became so sick.
No idea. Could it be food poisoning?
It couldn't be.
Didn't we all eat the same thing?
Teacher.
You gave me a shock.
What's the matter?
Got notice about power outage?
No, there wasn't.
Probably a blown fuse due to lightning.
Even if we call the technician
they would only arrive tomorrow.
I personally don't mind.
I'm worried the students might escape.
Don't worry.
I'll help keep an eye later.
Hey.
Teacher.
Didn't I ask you to clean the washroom?
No, teacher,
I came looking for you, teacher.
Wari has a fever.
I'm here for some medicine.
Stop lying.
I swear, teacher, Wari is sick.
I'm not lying.
Where's he?
At the dorm.
Wari.
I seek forgiveness from Allah.
What happened?
Wari.
Wari!
Nik.
Wake up, Nik.
Hey., Nik!
Nik.
Place him over there.
Tell me what happened.
Actually, teacher.
While cleaning the washroom,
Wari suddenly had a fever.
We brought him back to the dorm.
When we reached the dorm,
he became weird, teacher.
His eyes.
His face.
I don't know how to put it, teacher.
What did your friend do
to become like this?
I don't know, teacher.
No idea.
Whose phone has got coverage?
I have a phone, teacher.
But there's no coverage here.
Go to new block to get coverage.
Even with that.
We can only get one bar.
We need to go there.
teacher.
What about Wari?
You are all my responsibility.
Let's deal with the phone first.
Look after him.
Why do we have to stay here?
We have to look after, Nik.
What if Wari comes?
What are you going to do?
Just let teacher handle everything.
This dorm right here?
Go get coverage.
Once you've made the call,
go to the warden's room.
Okay, teacher.
The students are still awake.
Where is the coverage?
What's going on?
Why are you still awake?
Hey.
What are you doing here?
What's wrong with you?
Hey, are you okay?
Teacher! Help, teacher!
Teacher!
What are you doing?
Open door for him.
You moron! It could be Wari!
You're the moron.
Wari doesn't sound like that.
Teacher!
What if he's pretending, Kechik?
Don't dig your own grave!
What then?
Just ignore him?
Teacher, help!
Food has been dealt with.
I only have one problem left.
Flowers.
Do you want roses or lilies, Alia?
Alia.
Hello, Alia.
What's wrong?
I have a bad feeling.
Adli?
Alia. Alia.
Alia, you've to get back here now.
Hello, Adli.
Alia. Alia, we're in danger.
You need to get back here, please.
Hello.
I can't hear you.
Alia, listen here.
Wari is sick.
Get back here right now!
Adli, what gibberish are you talking?
Alia.
Alia, please.
We're in danger, you have to come.
Danger?
What sort of danger?
Hello.
Alia. Alia.
Adli.
Hello.
Wari.
I couldn't get through.
Kak Fiza.
I feel that something's wrong.
What exactly is wrong?
Because Adli said Wari fell sick.
He was just talking nonsense.
But that's what Adli said.
Okay, so? What?
Whatever Adli says, you just believe?
He was just pulling your leg.
No.
I know Adli.
I know what he's like when lie,
or when he is serious.
Kak Fiza.
I think Adli is in danger.
We need to turn back right now.
It's me.
Adli.
Hey.
I seek forgiveness from Allah.
Are you okay?
Wari.
Wari changed.
I saw his face.
I don't know how to describe this.
I stabbed him.
Is he dead?
I'm not sure.
Where's teacher Nazmi?
He isn't back yet?
No.
We split up earlier.
He went to look around.
At the seniors' block.
Nik.
Where are we?
What happened?
Are you okay?
I don't know.
My head is pounding like a drum.
I feel dizzy.
We've to get Nik to the hospital.
Where's Wari?
Adli.
Did you call the ambulance?
I couldn't. My cellphone broke.
Then who's coming to save us?
But I was able to call Alia.
Let's wait here.
Maybe she'll arrive in a while.
Teacher.
What happened?
I was attacked.
By a student.
His face!
His face…
Kak Yam…
Kak Yam told me
the nearby village been possesed.
Possessed?
Possessed.
What do we do, teacher?
There are students in my room.
Let's meet up with them.
And we'll make a plan.
I thought of the students
who went hysterical.
The hysteria must have spread in some way.
How does it spread then?
I don't know.
But I don't think
it spreads through air or infection.
Because we wrestled with Wari earlier,
but nothing happened.
Wari bit you just now, didn't he?
How could it spread through biting?
Sir!
Where is the guard?
Why is the dorm pitch black?
I was right.
Adli called because something went wrong.
Kak Fiza, we must get inside.
Okay let's go.
Wait.
Does she have the key?
How is your sister going to enter here?
You're right.
It isn't that difficult. Just open it.
Where's the key?
Usually, the guard
puts it in the booth.
I think we've to open the gate now.
But isn't it dangerous out there?
It's okay, Sam, I can go alone.
Never mind, I will follow you.
Nik,
look after Sam.
Let's go.
Give me your phone.
My battery is low.
It's fine.
Let's go.
Look, there are lights!
Do you think it's Farid or…
It's okay, Kechik.
We'll go have a look.
Let's go.
Chik, Chik! Wait.
Do you see them?
No.
Adli.
Hey, are you okay?
Kechik.
I think I can't go back with you guys.
What are you talking about?
We're going back to the warden's room now
and we'll treat you.
You know, don't you…
what will happen to me?
Adli. Come in, come in.
Kechik.
Once my sister arrives…
you take Nik to the hospital.
What about you?
Adli!
Hey, hey!
Adli! Adli!
Close the door!
Teacher.
Did you ask for anyone's help?
Earlier I asked the students
to call for help.
How long does the power outage
last usually?
I don't know.
There must be something that we can do.
This place used to be powered
by a generator.
It's still there.
But I don't know if it is still working.
We have to try starting the generator.
How? I don't know how. I'm not good at it.
Kak Fiza!
Blood.
Kak Fiza, look.
There's someone over there.
Hey, kid.
We're looking for a student here.
His name is Adli. Do you know him?
Who's that, Kak Fiza?
- Kak Fiza!
- Alia! Alia! Alia!
Run, Alia! Go!
Alia!
Alia! Wake up! Wake up! Alia!
Run!
Run Alia!
Run! Run!
Alia! Alia!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Teacher.
Teacher! Let's go!
My bag! My bag! My bag! My bag!
What are you doing?
Run! Alia!
Hey!
Who are you people?
I…
am the sister of a student here, Adli.
He called for help just now.
Do you know him?
Yes.
He is already at the warden's room.
Wait! Wait!
What was wrong with that student just now?
Why?
We have no idea either.
But right now we've to go back
to the warden's room.
Let's go.
Hey, hurry up! Faster! Faster!
Alia.
Where's Kechik?
He couldn't have left me behind, could he?
Relax, Sam.
You make me depressed.
Teacher.
Kak Fiza! Alia!
Sam?
Where's Adli?
Adli and Kechik went to open the gate.
You didn't see them?
Hey, the gate key is with me.
Who's that?
Alia! Kak Fiza!
Kechik!
Where's Adli?
I asked where's Adli?
Tell us.
Tell us what happen.
Adli became just like Wari.
No!
Adli!
Alia. Alia. Look at Kak Fiza.
Didn't I tell you and Adli
not to leave the room?
Stubborn. Look what happened to Adli.
- You moron!
- Can you just shut up?
Shut up?
What I said is true.
- If he were careful…
- You're wrong!
Adli is our friend.
Be considerate of their feelings!
Earlier you saw a student asking for help.
Why didn't you help?
I had to ensure, Nik's safety.
Was it his safety or your safety
that you wanted to ensure?
Cut it out!
Fiza, where did you park?
I parked at the place
where I dropped you guys earlier.
Can we all fit in your van?
The key is in the bag.
Bag?
We've to get it from the student
at the football field.
Does anyone have a phone?
There's no coverage.
No coverage in this area.
So there's no internet either.
Go to a higher place.
What do we do now?
We need to learn
about the things out there.
They're savage, teacher.
I saw it with my own eyes.
When they were gathering at the field.
I think Wari is their leader.
They can seemingly communicate
with each other.
One more thing.
Their eyes.
They can't look at light.
Are you sure about the generator?
I'm sure!
But I don't know if it is still working.
Wait. There's a generator?
Yes.
Show it to me. Perhaps I can fix it.
Do we have a toolbox and petrol?
Yes, we do.
At the workshop.
- Let's go!
- Wait.
Let's split up.
Farid, bring Fiza to the generator.
Sam.
You and Kechik…
head to the workshop.
Look for some petrol,
take the toolbox and meet up
with them at the generator.
Teacher.
Hey, wait.
Is it okay to split up?
It will be easier for them to spot us
if we move in a big group.
Okay.
Cellhone.
What do you want to do?
I've to go get coverage
at the upper floor.
I want to tag along. I can help.
No way.
You have to stay here.
But this is my phone. I want to tag along.
Nik.
As long as it isn't done, don't go out,
you got it?
Wari.
I am sorry, Wari.
I am sorry.
I'm so glad you are still alive, Wari.
Don't worry, Adli, I'm fine.
Wari.
But I am in pain, Wari.
I'll bring you to a world
without suffering.
Close your eyes, Adli.
Trust me.
Follow me, Adli.
Hurry. We're almost there.
There, the generator shed.
Let's go.
Here! Here!
Come on! Come on!
Go! Go! Go!
Take this.
Faster.
Whiere is the key?
It's stuck! It's stuck!
Go inside
Come inside
You…
How is it going? Can you fix it?
Probably yes.
I learnt about this model back then.
Anyway we have to wait for Kechik.
All right.
You!
Here.
What's this?
I'll wait for Kechik.
Whatever happens, don't go out.
Sam! Take this.
Sam!
Let's go!
Here.
Nik! Open the door, Nik!
Nik!
Sam! What's the matter?
Where's Kechik?
Kechik died.
Are you serious?
Don't joke around with me.
It's true, Nik. I saw it with my own eyes.
He was trapped at the workshop.
I think that right now
we need to go to the secret entrance.
We've to get Kak Fiza's van.
Didn't they lose their keys at the field?
What do we do now?
We need to leave this place, Nik
We need to go to the highway.
Let's get to main road.
We must get help, Nik.
What about Teacher Nazmi, Alia, Kak Fiza?
Is that all?
We must get out of here, Nik.
Otherwise we will all die here, Nik.
Please, Nik. Let's get out, Nik.
Let's escape from here, Nik.
Handphone
Got a signal?
Adli
Adli.
Hey!
Are you all right?
Adli,
Teacher!
Adli. Adli, don't!
Adli! don't! Adli!
Adli.
Alia's here.
It's me, Alia! Adli!
Alia! Alia!
- Alia!
- Alia?
Alia!
Adli!
Adli! Adli! Adli!
Alia! Alia! Alia!
Please.
Take care of Mom and Dad.
Promise me, Alia.
I promise, I promise.
But you've to keep fighting, Adli.
Please keep fighting.
Adli!
We must go now.
Alia! We must go now!
Let's go!
Over here!
Okay, our secret entrance is there.
What now? What do we do?
I will count to three.
We run together, and don't ever stop.
Okay.
One,
two,
three!
Sam! Sam! Sam!
Sam! Help me, Sam! Sam!
Get lost! Get lost!
Teacher!
Adli!
Kechik!
Kechik! Run, Kechik!
Faster, Kechik! Faster!
Kechik!
Kechik, faster!
Hey, Farid!
Get in Kechik!
Kak Fiza!
Harder, Kak Fiza!
Harder, Kak Fiza! Harder!
Harder!
Let's go!
This way. Hold this.
Teacher!
Get in! Get in!
Help me!
Kak Fiza. How can I help?
Do you know
what a crank handle looks like?
Yes, I know.
Okay, Kechik, please help. Thank you.
What else should we do, teacher?
We've to wait for the generator.
Can we make it, teacher?
What if we can't make it?
I hope we can make it till dawn.
Nazmi.
Who are you?
It's me, Wari.
I'm here to help you.
Follow me, Nazmi.
Follow me.
You won't feel any pain.
Your suffering will end.
Follow me, Nazmi.
Hey.
My pain…
my life, what do you know about them?
I know about your children.
About your wife.
Isn't this world unfair?
What sins have you committed?
Why did he do this to you?
Follow me, Nazmi.
Teacher.
What happened to your family?
Dear, what do we do now?
You told me you would be coming back.
I was going to give you a surprise.
Surprise?
What surprise?
What surprise do you want?
Dad! Let's go to the zoo, shall we?
Let's watch movies.
I want to bring you to the funfair!
Yes.
Dear,
it'll be fun.
But won't you feel tired?
I'm not doing this all the time.
Every day I ask God.
Why?
Why it wasn't me who died that day?
Sarah.
Honey!
- Dear.
- Honey!
Honey! Sarah!
Forgive me. Forgive me.
My dear.
I am okay.
Don't worry.
Our kids are waiting for us.
Follow me, Nazmi.
Teacher! Teacher!
My dear, don't worry. Follow me, Nazmi
Our kids are waiting for us, my dear.
Follow me, Nazmi.
My dear.
The kids are waiting for you.
Dear.
Follow me, Nazmi.
Teacher! Teacher! Teacher!
Teacher. Teacher.
Teacher.
You go.
But we can leave together, teacher.
I…
Soon…
I will be like them.
Hey.
Remember your promise to Adli.
Thank you.
Please.
Wait, Kechik.
I'm trying.
Why is it acting this way?
Wait.
I don't know why.
Wait, wait.
Allah, there is no deity except Him
the Ever-Living, the Sustainer
of all existence.
Neither drowsiness
overtakes Him nor sleep.
To Him belongs whatever is in the heavens
and whatever is on the earth.
Who could possibly intercede with Him,
except by His permission.
He fully knows what is ahead of them
and what is behind them.
And they encompass not a thing
of His knowledge, except
for what He wills to reveal.
His Kursi encompasses
the heavens and the earth.
And it is not difficult for Him
to preserve them.
And He is the Highest
and the Greatest.
Follow me, Nazmi.
A fire that took place at a hostel
has killed more than 20 people.
The police are still
investigating the cause.
The public are advised
not to spread any false information
and false news on social media.
Three victims were saved
while another badly injured victim
is being treated at a hospital.
Nonetheless, their identities
have yet to be confirmed.