(patriotic music)
("Caissons Go Rolling
Along" by John Philip Sousa)
- [Narrator] Causes and events
leading up to our entry into the war.
Well, what are the causes?
Why are we Americans on the march?
Is it because of
(explosions booming)
Pearl Harbor?
Is that why we are fighting?
Or is it because of
(explosions booming)
Britain?
France?
(dramatic music)
(explosions booming)
China?
(plane engines humming)
(explosions booming)
Czechoslovakia?
Norway?
(plane engines humming)
(explosions booming)
(plane screeching)
Poland?
(explosion booming)
(explosions booming)
Holland?
(plane engines humming)
(explosion booming)
Greece?
(plane engines humming)
(explosions booming)
Belgium?
Albania?
(explosions booming)
Yugoslavia?
Or Russia?
(speaking Russian)
(plane engines humming)
Just what was it made us change
our way of living overnight?
What turned our resources, our machines,
our whole nation into one vast arsenal,
producing more and more weapons of war
instead of the old materials of peace?
(patriotic music)
What put us into uniform,
ready to engage the enemy
on every continent and every ocean?
What are these two worlds
of which Mr. Wallace spoke?
The free and the slave.
Let's take the free
world first, our world.
How did it become free?
Only through a long and unceasing struggle
inspired by men of vision.
Moses.
♪ Peace on Earth ♪
♪ Good will to men ♪
♪ From Heaven's ♪
- Muhammad.
♪ All gracious king ♪
- [Narrator] Confucius.
♪ The world in solemn stillness lay ♪
- Christ.
♪ To hear the angels sing ♪
- [Narrator] All believed
that in the sight of God,
all men were created equal.
And from that there
developed a spirit among men
and nations, which is best expressed
in our own declaration of freedom.
We hold these truths to be self-evident,
that all men are created equal.
It is the cornerstone
upon which our nation
was built and the ideal
of all the great liberators: Washington,
Jefferson, Garibaldi, Lafayette,
Kosciuszko, Bolivar, Lincoln.
♪ Glory, glory hallelujah ♪
- [Narrator] Lighthouses, lighting up
a dark and foggy world.
- [Narrator] That government
of the people, by the people,
for the people, shall not
perish from the Earth.
- [Narrator] Fighting,
living, dying, for what?
For freedom.
That for which men have
fought since time began.
To be free!
(bell tolling)
- [Narrator] Is life so
dear, or peace so sweet,
as to be purchased at the
price of chains and slavery?
Forbid it almighty God.
I know not what course others
may take, but as for me,
give me liberty or give me death.
(patriotic music)
- [Narrator] But what of this other world?
Here men insisted that progress
lay in killing freedom.
Here they were putting out
the lighthouses, one by one.
Here the march of history
was reversing itself.
In Italy it began when an
ambitious rabble-rouser
set his followers marching on Rome.
The country, like every other country
after the last war, was
torn by political unrest,
hard times, unemployment.
Two courses were available
to the Italian people.
They could solve their problems
in a free, democratic way,
or they could let someone
else do the solving for them.
They made the tragic mistake
of choosing the second course.
They put their trust and
faith in this one man.
They believed he represented them.
Actually he planned to betray
them for the selfish interest
of himself and the group back of him
just as he had earlier betrayed
those who first supported him.
In Germany another even
more forceful demagogue
sent his followers marching
from the Munich beer halls.
He too had the sinister
opportunity to take advantage
of post-war chaos.
But he also had certain
distinctive German characteristics
to play on.
To start with, the Germans
have an inborn national love
of regimentation and a harsh discipline.
He could give them that.
The German Army, and through them
the people, have never
acknowledged German defeat
in the last war and were
anxious for revenge.
That, too, he promised them.
The wealthy and powerful
industrialists were fearful
of losing any of their wealth and power,
and were ready to back anyone
who would retain it for them.
He promised to take care of them, too.
(crowd cheering)
This man cunningly played all
these ends against the middle,
and ruthlessly set out
(guns firing)
to murder the newborn German republic.
(crowd shouting)
In Japan you expect things to
be done a little differently.
They were.
(somber patriotic music)
Here, not one man, but a gang,
disguised their little schemes
as the will of the Emperor,
and to the Japanese
people, the Emperor is God.
Taking advantage of
their fanatical worship
of the God-Emperor, it was no great trick
to take away what little
freedom they had ever known.
Yes, in these lands the people
surrendered their liberties
and threw away their human dignity.
(shouting in Japanese)
They gave up their rights
as individual human beings
Sieg Heil!
And became a part of a mass, a human herd.
(shouting in Italian)
Although these countries
were far apart and different
in custom and in language,
the same poison made them much alike.
Each got a new uniform.
In Italy, the new bosses
wore black shirts.
In Germany, the shirts were brown.
In Japan, they hid behind
the uniform of the Army,
but really, they belonged to
a sinister secret society.
Their symbol was a black dragon.
(dramatic music)
The other fellows had
to have a symbol, too.
Germany, a swastika.
In Italy, the old Roman
symbol of the fasces.
In Germany they called the new order
national socialism, or Nazism.
(dramatic music)
In Italy, they had a
shorter word, fascism.
In Japan, they had lots of names for it.
The New Era of Enlightenment,
the New Order in Asia,
the Co-Prosperity Sphere.
But no matter how you slice it,
it was just plain old-fashioned
militaristic imperialism.
The Japs would get the Prosperity,
and the others would get the crow.
They say trouble always comes in threes.
(speaking German)
Take a good, close look at this trio.
Remember these faces,
remember them well.
If you ever meet them, don't hesitate.
(speaking German)
- [Narrator] "Stop thinking
and follow me!" cried Hitler.
I will make you masters of the world!
And the people answered
Sieg Heil!
(speaking Italian)
Stop thinking and believe
in me! bellowed Mussolini.
And I will restore the
glory that was Rome!
And the people answered
Il Duce, Il Duce!
(shouting in Italian)
(speaking Japanese)
Stop thinking and follow your God-Emperor!
cried the Japanese warlords.
And Japan will rule the world!
And the people answered
Banzai, Banzai!
Each system was alike in that
the constitutional lawmaking
bodies gave up their power.
The Reichstag in Berlin, the
House of Deputies in Rome,
the Diet in Tokyo.
And these elected representatives
became collections
of stooges, rubber stamp organizations.
Sieg Heil!
Applauding on cue the
words of the leaders.
(crowd applauding)
- [Narrator] Each system
did away with free speech
and free assembly.
Each system did away with a free press,
and substituted a press
controlled by the Party.
Through their ministries of propaganda,
each took complete control of the theater,
the movies, the radio.
Every cultural activity and
every channel of information
was controlled by the most
important members of the Party.
Each did away with free
courts and trial by jury,
and substituted courts and
judges run by the Party.
Each abolished labor unions and the rights
of bargaining for wages.
(officer whistling)
(speaking German)
Heil Hitler!
And under the pretext of patriotism
established a system of forced labor.
Each enforced its decrees
by an army of secret police
who held the power of life and death
over every individual.
And for the few who still
believed in freedom and said so,
there was a ready answer.
(speaking Italian)
The greatest intellect in the world
can be silenced with this.
That is an exact translation of the words
these black-shirts cheer so lustily.
(speaking German)
- [Narrator] Whenever
I hear anyone mention
the word culture, the first
thing I do is reach for my gun.
Yes, they had the answer,
the blackjack, and the gun.
(gun firing)
(dramatic music)
(guns firing)
In Italy, they did it different.
(gun firing)
(dramatic music)
While in Japan...
(guns firing)
To their names can be added
those of hundreds and thousands
of others who stood in
the way of the New Order.
Finally there was only one obstacle left.
(bells ringing)
(choral music)
The word of God and the word of fuhrers
cannot be reconciled.
Then God must go!
(glass shattering)
(dramatic music)
- [Translator] I am absolutely
clear in my own mind
and I think I can speak
for the Führer as well,
that both the Catholic
and Protestant churches
must vanish from the life of our people.
- [Narrator] Thus spoke
Doctor Alfred Rosenberg,
and if you have any doubt
that he spoke for his Führer,
here's what happened.
♪ O come, all ye faithful ♪
♪ Joyful and triumphant ♪
♪ O come ye ♪
♪ To Bethlehem ♪
♪ Come and ♪
- [Narrator] Thousands
of other men of God,
Protestant, Catholic, Jewish,
were persecuted, arrested,
confined in concentration camps.
- [Translator] Our Führer
is the intermediary
between his people and the throne of God.
Everything the Führer utters
is religion in the highest sense.
(speaking German)
It is only on one or
two exceptional points
that Christ and Hitler stand comparison,
for Hitler is far too
big a man to be compared
with one so petty.
- [Narrator] Every day in
all German classrooms...
(singing in German)
Yes, take children from
the faith of their fathers
and teach them the
State is the only church
and the head of the State
is the voice of God.
(chanting in Japanese)
(patriotic music)
That was the way of life,
or better, the way of death,
in that other world.
Now what of our world,
the democratic world?
What did we want?
(gentle music)
What did we do about it?
First of all we wanted peace and security.
And to prove our sincerity, in 1921,
we initiated the Washington
Disarmament Conference.
This resulted in two
vitally important treaties.
One to reduce the size
of the British, Japanese,
French, Italian, and American fleets.
And the other, The Nine-Power
Treaty, which guaranteed
the integrity of China, and incidentally,
one of the powers signing this was Japan.
Later on in 1929, we signed
the Kellogg-Briand Pact,
which was supposed to abolish war
as a means of settling
international disputes.
(audience applauding)
This pact was signed by 47 nations,
including Germany and Japan.
- Mr. President, I have
the honor of handing you
the London Naval Treaty.
- [Narrator] Faithful to
our treaty obligations
(explosion booming)
we scrapped more than
60% of our naval tonnage.
And our army was reduced to a
standing force of 136,000 men.
Smaller than that maintained
by the little state of Romania.
We let our hopes for
peace become so strong
that they grew into a determination
not to fight unless directly attacked.
We let ourselves be
influenced by those who said
that we could find
security through isolation.
(patriotic music)
The confusion in our way
of thinking is apparent
in the slice of public
opinion as it appeared
in Pathe News in 1939.
- Another war, not for me.
This time America should
keep out and I know I will.
- If war breaks out in Europe,
I think that this country
should heed the advice
of its first president, and
avoid all foreign entanglements.
- I haven't the slightest
idea of European affairs.
- In the event of war in Europe,
I think we should stay out of it entirely.
- And all our efforts
should be made to keep out
of the fight.
- Let Europe fight her own battles.
They mean nothing to us.
- We should mind our own business!
- By all means, no.
- Yes, fight!
- No.
- Yes.
- If my country calls, yes.
- No!
- [Narrator] We simply
did not want to understand
that our individual and
national problems were,
and always will be,
dependent upon the problems
of the whole world.
("America, The Beautiful")
And we had individual and
national problems to worry about.
Plenty of them,
just as Germany, Italy, and Japan had.
But we faced them in a democratic way.
We passed laws to give working men
a chance to improve their lot.
We established an insurance
program for those without jobs.
We began to give old folks protection
against want and hunger.
We organized the CCC to
provide our young men
with healthy and useful employment.
(saw buzzing)
A federal works program came
into being and changed the face
of our nation with new
roads, bridges, schools.
We built great new dams which brought
the miracle of electricity
to millions of our people.
These were some of our accomplishments,
but there were others not so creditable.
We turned our backs
(dark somber music)
on the League of Nations.
We passed The Tariff Act to set
a higher wall of isolation around us.
We encouraged lawlessness
with the farce of Prohibition.
But in spite of these mistakes,
we never had a thought
of losing our free institutions.
John Q. Public still ran the country.
He had his choice of
voting for Dewey, Willkie,
Roosevelt, or anybody else.
In Germany they had the choice of voting
for Hitler, Hitler, or Hitler.
(dark music)
Over here, John Q.
Still read what he pleased.
And although he heard
of books being burned
in other countries, he would've laughed
if anyone had told him his
books would ever be burned.
(dramatic music)
(bells ringing)
And on Sunday, if he felt
like it, John Q. went
to any church he pleased.
♪ Like a mighty army ♪
♪ Moves the Church of God ♪
♪ Brothers, we are treading ♪
♪ Where the Saints have trod ♪
♪ We are not divided ♪
♪ All one body we ♪
♪ One in hope and doctrine ♪
♪ One in charity ♪
♪ Onward, Christian soldiers ♪
♪ Marching as to war ♪
♪ With the cross of Jesus ♪
♪ Going on before ♪
(children chattering)
(lighthearted music)
- [Narrator] Most of all,
he got a kick out of seeing
his kids grow up.
(children shouting)
- [Boy] Run, Jerry!
(boys shouting)
(referee whistling)
- [Narrator] The average
American was quite unconscious
of the fact that some
people had this in mind
for the little John Qs.
(speaking German)
Yes, while their children
were being trained to kill,
John Q's kids were giving their pennies
to help them have life.
(patriotic music)
And when we saw these
men on the newsreels,
quite often, we laughed.
To us, they looked like
characters in a musical comedy.
(crowd cheering)
But they weren't comic.
They weren't funny.
They were deadly serious.
They were out for world conquest.
And what made it deadly serious was
that there were 70 million Japanese,
45 million Italians,
and 80 million Germans
all hopped up with the same idea.
(speaking German)
Their leaders told them
that they were supermen,
Herrenvolk the Nazis called it,
the master race, destined to rule
all other peoples on Earth.
Sieg Heil!
Take a good look at these humorless men.
These were to be the
rulers of the ruling race.
(speaking German)
Obey us blindly and you will attain
your rightful place in the world.
All other people will be your slaves.
That's what they promised them.
That Americans, Chinese,
Russian, South Americans,
all free peoples would work
for them and make them rich.
And how they ate it up.
(chanting in Japanese, German, Italian)
We shall restore the glory that was Rome.
(chanting in Italian)
Today we rule Germany, tomorrow the world.
(crowd cheering)
The Pacific is ours.
(chanting in Japanese)
It was inevitable that these
countries should gang up on us.
The little fella is our pal Kurusu,
who smiled his way into our
hearts in December 1941.
Here he and his friends are
busy carving up the world
in advance, staking out their claims.
Take a good look at these claims.
- [Narrator] Here was the Italy
that Mussolini took over in 1922.
And almost his first act
was to tell the Italians
they were the rightful owners of Corsica,
Nice, Savoie, Albania,
Tunisia, Ethiopia, and a land corridor
linking it with Libya.
Later on he had an even bigger dream,
the old Roman Empire as it
existed nearly 2000 years ago,
to dominate all the lands
adjoining the Mediterranean.
'Mare Nostra'
Our sea, they called it,
just as the ancient Romans did.
- [Narrator] As for the Japanese,
they had some ambitions too.
By 1920 they had grabbed
off Formosa, Korea,
and the southern half of
the island of Sakhalin.
Then Baron Giichi Tanaka,
the Prime Minister,
carefully set down
Japanese aims in a document
called The Tanaka Memorial.
It was presented to the
Emperor July 25th, 1927.
Here was their dream,
Manchuria for raw materials,
China for manpower,
Then a triumphant march through Indochina,
Siam, Burma, India, the East Indies,
then on through Australia and New Zealand.
And in the north all they claimed
was that part of Russia
east of Lake Baikal.
That was to be the new order in Asia.
(ominous music)
Then the Japs would move eastward to crush
the United States and really start
their Co-Prosperity Sphere.
Now take a look at the bite
the Nazis reserved for themselves.
Here's the Germany Hitler walked into.
And here is what he wanted.
First Europe under his complete political
or economic control,
leaving Mussolini a share
of the loot if he behaved himself.
Then the drive to the east
through the rich oil-lands
of Iran and Iraq into India.
Another push south through Africa.
Then from Dakar, jump off
to meet the honorary Aryans,
who were to move in on South
America through the Pacific.
At the same time, start across
from the Scandinavian countries to hook up
with his bucktooth pals
coming over from Siberia,
to join in the conquest
of the United States.
- [Narrator] There it is, gents.
All they left us was Shangri-La.
And they'd claim that too,
if they knew where it was.
And did they think they had a chance?
- [Narrator] Listen.
(Speaking Japanese)
- [Narrator] When war comes between Japan
and the United States,
I shall not be content
merely to occupy Guam, the Philippines,
Hawaii, and San Francisco.
I look forward to dictating the peace
to the United States in the
White House at Washington.
Yamamoto wrote those
words on January of 1941.
Yes, the conquering Jap Army
down Pennsylvania Avenue.
That was the final goal.
You will see what they did to
the men and women of Nanking,
Hong Kong, and Manila.
Imagine the field day they'd
enjoy if they'd marched
through the streets of Washington.
But before striking, a
preliminary step was necessary.
From Berlin, from Rome,
from Tokyo, the campaign started.
Propaganda, to confuse, divide,
soften up their intended victim.
Put them on the defensive.
Scream you're abused,
shout you're oppressed.
The world's wrong, you're right!
If you shriek it loud
enough and often enough,
they'll believe you.
Above all, use their free press
and their free speech to destroy them.
(speaking German)
'Lebensraum'
they demanded, living room.
Our lands are overcrowded.
(lighthearted music)
But at the same time they gave prizes
to mothers who bore the most sons.
(crowd cheering)
They brought together
large groups of young men
and young girls for human breeding.
Read what one of their leaders wrote.
(babies crying)
Of course, the children
from this assembly line
belonged to the State,
to be scientifically trained for conquest.
(babies crying)
Another howl was the lack of raw material.
They claimed they were the
have-nots and we were the haves.
But out of this supposed lack
they built up the greatest war machines
the world has ever known.
These are the published figures
from the German military budget.
Actually between 1933 and 1939,
Hitler's program of rearmament
cost more than $80 billion!
The Nazis alone assembled a striking force
of 30 panzer divisions,
70 motorized divisions,
140 infantry divisions,
plus the Luftwaffe,
the world's largest air force.
And they had no raw materials.
Think of the bread, the
automobiles, the good things of life
that the German, Italian, Japanese leaders
might have given their people
if they had spent this money
for peace instead of war.
You know what billions we are now spending
to match their military force.
No, no these arguments
were all smokescreens.
When war came, the democracies
proved to be the have-nots,
and our enemies the haves.
And when war came, where did it come?
(drumming music)
(thunder cracking)
Remember that date.
September 18th, 1931,
a date we should remember
as well as December 7, 1941.
For on that date in 1931,
the war we are now fighting began.
The place was Manchuria, the
northernmost province of China,
6,000 miles from San Francisco.
Manchuria, the first
objective in the Tanaka plan.
By September 18th the
Japanese, who by treaty
patrolled the Southern Manchurian Railway,
had secretly and illegally
increased their garrisons.
On the Korean-Manchurian border
an entire Japanese army was assembled,
conveniently equipped
for a winter campaign.
All they needed was an excuse.
They made their own.
At 10:30 that night, just
after The Mukden Express
had passed by, a section
of track was dynamited,
causing damage to one
rail and two fishplates.
Japan's honor had been violated.
(explosions booming)
Within half an hour, the
Japanese railroad garrison
launched a coordinated
attack on the barracks
of the sleeping Chinese Army at Mukden.
The slaughter was appalling.
(horses galloping)
By midnight, the conveniently
placed Japanese Army
poured across the Korean
border, and the first open act
of aggression, the invasion
of Manchuria, was on.
In four days they had occupied
the whole of southern Manchuria,
and shortly after, the whole country.
Manchuria became Manchukuo, a puppet state
with an obedient stooge on
the throne, Henry Pu Yi,
a weakling whom the Japanese
had prepared for the job
with seven years of women and song.
In Washington, Henry L. Stimson,
then Secretary of State,
now Secretary of War, sent
out a blistering denunciation
of the attack.
The League of Nations
sent a committee of five
headed by Lord Lytton
and including our own General Frank McCoy
to Manchuria to investigate.
In October of 1932, the
committee issued its report.
- We found that the Japanese occupation
of this large part of
China was not justified
on the ground of self defense,
and that the new state
which had been set up, was
a Japanese protectorate
rather than a genuine case of
Manchurian self-determination.
- [Narrator] Shortly after,
the League condemned Japan
as an aggressor nation.
(speaking French)
- [Translator] I call on His
Excellency, Mr. Matsuoka,
delegate of Japan.
(people chattering)
- It is a matter of common knowledge
that Japan's policy is
fundamentally inspired
by a genuine desire to guarantee peace
in the Far East
and to contribute to the maintenance
of peace throughout the world.
Japan, however, find it impossible
to accept the report
adopted by the assembly.
- [Narrator] In answer
the Japanese delegates,
knowing there were no guns
behind this condemnation,
smiled, took up their briefcases,
and marched out of the League.
Northern Manchuria was dead.
Collective security was dead.
The green light had been
given the aggressors.
We and the rest of the world
knew that these aggressors
should be stopped and punished,
but we were unwilling to
make the necessary sacrifices
to back up that opinion.
It was impossible to
convince a farm boy in Iowa,
or a driver of a London bus,
or a waiter in a Paris cafe,
that he should go to war
because of a mud hut in Manchuria.
(explosion booming)
Yet the subsequent course
of history makes it clear
that that incident, so many miles away,
is one of the main reasons that you
and millions of others
are in uniform today.
The Japs had Manchuria.
Phase number one of the
Tanaka plan was completed.
Phase number two, the conquest of China.
In 1932, without warning,
the Japs attacked
the Chinese city of Shanghai.
(explosions booming)
(plane engines humming)
(people shouting)
(bombs whistling)
(explosions booming)
(guns firing)
(bombs whistling)
(explosions booming)
(plane engines humming)
(bombs whistling )
(explosions booming)
(woman crying)
(plane engines humming)
(bombs whistling)
(explosions booming)
(woman crying)
(guns firing)
(plane engines humming)
(explosions booming)
Here they met such stubborn resistance,
they had to pour more than 75,000 troops
into the local battle
before capturing the city.
This resistance made them decide to shift
their campaign to the north, and in 1933,
they added the province
of Jehol to Manchuria.
Yes, the Japs launched the
second phase of the Tanaka plan.
But they had yet to finish it.
A united nation stands against them.
Under the inspired leadership
of General Chiang Kai-shek,
the Chinese people fought,
and still fight on.
Meantime, what of Japan's partners?
What helpless people were
they planning to bomb,
slaughter, drive into slavery?
Hitler was not yet
ready, but Mussolini was.
Mussolini had to be.
His people were growing restless.
Fascism hadn't produced
the heaven on Earth
that he had promised them.
So he pulled the old trick
of launching a foreign war
to divert attention from troubles at home.
So Mussolini beat his chest like Tarzan
and looked around for a worthy foe.
He found one, Ethiopia.
(drumming music)
A good country for the
beginning of a glorious empire.
Its army had no machine guns.
Its army had no tanks.
Its army did have an air force,
exactly one old airplane,
one airplane against a
nation which had developed
a new theory of total air war,
of the blitz which would wipe
out cities, destroy civilians,
man, woman, and child.
In October of 1935, following
the Japanese example,
an incident was provoked
at the little settlement
of Walwal near the border of Ethiopia
and Italian Somaliland.
Italy's honor had been violated.
Refusing any arbitration,
Mussolini moved the whole might
of his army through the
Suez Canal to overrun
the undefended country.
Ethiopia's Emperor Haile Selassie
appeared before the League of Nations.
(speaking Amharic)
I must still fight on until
my tardy allies appear,
and if they never come, I say to you
without bitterness, the West will perish.
(people chattering)
Members of the League
half-heartedly stopped trading
with Italy, but refused the only thing
that will stop any aggressor, force.
Ethiopia was left to herself.
Native leaders came to
pledge their allegiance.
(speaking foreign dialects)
The people of Ethiopia, with
their spears and bare hands,
faced the guns and the
tanks of the invaders,
fighting desperately and gallantly
to save their country from conquest.
(explosions booming)
(plane engines humming)
(bombs whistling)
(explosions booming)
They fought and they died.
But in the end, there
could be but one result.
Might triumphed.
Italy conquered Ethiopia.
Many of our elected leaders
warned us of danger.
- Without a declaration of war
and without warning or
justification of any kind,
civilians, including vast
numbers of women and children,
are being ruthlessly murdered
with bombs from the air.
- [Narrator] But we were
still hypnotized by the fact
that two broad oceans stood between us
and the rest of the world.
We didn't realize that the
time when months were needed
to span these oceans was ended,
that the steam ship had
cut these months to days,
and that now the whole Earth's surface
could be covered in the space of hours.
Yes, we were a nation that wanted peace.
But we hadn't yet
learned that peace for us
depends on peace for all.
Nobody would run the risk of war
because of some mud huts and
barren plains in Ethiopia,
any more than we would run the risk
for some similar huts
and plains in Manchuria.
Correctly interpreting our
attitude, the aggressors
were all the surer that they
could get what they wanted.
Japan had started on
her march of conquest.
Italy had begun her new empire.
And now the third
gangster, what about him?
We take him up in our next
film, and show how he joined
his partners and put in his bid.
For this is what we are
fighting, freedom's oldest enemy,
the passion of the few to rule the many.
This isn't just a war.
This is a common man's
♪ Glory, glory hallelujah ♪
Life-and-death struggle
against those who would put him
back into slavery.
♪ His truth goes marching on ♪
We lose it, and we lose everything.
Our homes,
the jobs we want to go back to,
the books we read, the very food we eat,
the hopes we have for our
kids, the kids themselves.
They won't be ours anymore.
That's what's at stake.
It's us or them.
The chips are down.
Two worlds stand against each other.
One must die.
One must live.
170 years of freedom
decrees our answer.
♪ Firm, united let us be ♪
♪ Rallying round our liberty ♪
♪ As a band of brothers joined ♪
♪ Peace and safety ♪
♪ We shall find ♪
♪ Ah ah ah ♪