(dramatic music)
(suspenseful music)
(high piercing whistling)
(dramatic music)
- Well, I guess this could
prove Professor Grogan's theory
that you could put a snake
to sleep with a high B flat,
but before any of you kids go and try it
on your neighborhood rattlers,
remember, it may only work
on snakes that like music.
This is Carrie Madison inviting
you to join me next week
for some more curiosities of
this weird and wacky world.
Well, I guess that wraps it up, Ronnie.
(telephone beeps)
Hello.
What?
No, I was just leaving.
I could be at professor
Hartmann's laboratory
in about two hours give or take it.
What do you mean the crew
is gonna be late, how late?
An hour, what am I supposed to do
with the mad scientist for an hour?
Ha, ha, ha, I'll pretend
that you didn't say that.
- [Announcer] This is KKZ Los Angeles,
the spot that's hot on your dial.
♪ Where you can crunch 'em ♪
♪ Munch 'em, chew a mean stew ♪
♪ There ain't nothing in this world ♪
♪ Like Mama Roland's Jerky Sticks ♪
Yes sir, Mama Roland's Jerky Sticks.
Try 'em soon, you hear?
There ain't nothing in this world
like Mama Roland's Jerky Stick.
Okay, it's 9:45 exactly.
We got a high of 75 in downtown L.A.,
so for you breathers
out there in the valley,
it's looking pretty good.
News and views coming at you on the hour
with an extended report
on those earth tremors
up Frisco way.
They're on their way here,
if they can beat the freeway traffic.
You heard it first here
where we make it happen.
It's all coming at you.
(radio crackling)
It's the first shock wave to hit the area
and this one reads 4.5
on the Richter scale.
This is KKZ Los Angeles news and views.
(road rumbling)
(tires screeching)
(horn blowing)
(truck crashing)
- Geez, what the hell
you trying to prove lady?
You wanna drive in a demolition derby
go do it on a track.
- Funny, very funny.
I suppose you didn't notice
the rest of the world
is having an earthquake.
- You got two feet one
for the accelerator,
and one for the God damned brake.
Oh God, this piece of equipment
has seen me through two
state championships,
the defense of the interstate trophy,
and cost me 40 bucks.
Now look at it.
- What is it?
It's a broken Kendo
sword, that's what it is.
- Looks like a bamboo stick.
Well, since you're all
right, I've gotta go.
- Hey, don't let me detain ya, lady.
I mean I'm fine, my truck is fine,
my broken Kendo stick is just fine.
Everything's just fine lady.
- Look, I'm sorry, uh here.
- [Dan] What's this?
- Well, it's for everything.
- Lady, I don't need your charity.
- Charity, this isn't charity,
and stop calling me lady.
I hate to be called lady.
It's insulting and patronizing.
- Believe me, I can think of better words.
- I bet you can.
It's because I'm a woman isn't?
I mean, if I were a man--
- If you were a man,
I'd break your God damned head.
- Typical, be violent.
- Wanna see a violent male?
If you want to be treated like a child
taken across my knee and
given a good spanking.
- You wouldn't dare.
- Try me, lady.
(truck hissing)
(car engine revving)
(doorbell ringing)
- [Carrie] Hi, I'm Carrie Madison.
- Yes, I recognize you, Miss
Madison, and I'm enchanted.
Won't you come in, please.
(engine loudly rumbling)
(man sighing)
I daresay you're wondering why I,
a serious dimensional physicist,
should waste my valuable
time on a television program
which sensationalizes science.
- Well, at least you're
brutally frank about it.
- I don't mean to be rude,
but your program is precisely what I need
to make those fools
in the halls of science
take my work seriously.
Sorry, I've become angry,
and I've become a very bad host.
Can I get you something?
- No, thanks.
Look, I'm sorry, but my
camera crew have been delayed.
Um, maybe you could go over exactly
what it is you want us to film.
Is this it?
- Oh please, Miss Madison,
the matter transport is a
finely calibrated instrument.
- And you say you can send things
through this machine
into another dimension?
- Precisely, perhaps if I
were to show you what I mean.
(wires crackling)
(truck booming)
- Oh!
And they said it was gonna be a nice day.
- Now, in case you think
there's some kind of magician,
an object, some personal
possession, if I may.
(machine beeping)
(machine whirring)
- I saw it, but I still don't believe it.
- The objects are still there,
but in another dimension,
another part of the
universe we cannot see.
(machine beeping)
(machine whirring)
- I don't understand this.
(earth rumbling)
Dr. Hartmann, are you sure this is safe
with all these tremors going on?
- Be quiet, look, fascinating.
Do you realize we are
looking at a parallel world,
another dimension for the first time?
- You mean a world like ours?
- Why not?
People are people wherever they exist.
Perhaps technologies differ.
My God, you realize what this means?
The ability to cross into another world.
(room rumbling)
(machine whirring)
- Dr. Hartmann, Dr. Hartmann?
(mysterious music)
(dramatic music)
(doorbell ringing)
- Hello, anybody home?
(mysterious music)
(phone clicking)
(dramatic music)
(bag thuds)
(Dan grunts)
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Oh my God, not you again.
- Well look, it was
your own fault creeping
around like that.
- My fault, I come here looking
for help and I get mugged.
What have I done to you, lady?
You wipe out my truck, you
cave in my skull, you--
- Break your bamboo stick.
Kendo sword, sorry.
(Dan chuckles)
I'm Carrie, Carrie Madison.
- Dan Roebuck, keep thinking
I know you from someplace.
- I do a TV show.
- The Weird and The Wacky.
- Mm hm.
- Now I know ya.
Hey, that show really is a pile
of garbage, but you're good.
Though you look thinner on the box.
What is this place?
- It belongs to a Dr. Hartmann.
- Where is he?
- He's gone and I mean he's really gone.
- What do you mean really gone?
- There's no point.
I know you won't believe me.
- Try me.
- Well, this machine transmits things
into another world, another dimension.
(Dan chuckles)
I told you you wouldn't believe me.
- Of course I believe you, please go on.
- There was this accident.
- An accident?
- And he was standing right there.
- Standing right here.
- And then all of a sudden he
just disappeared like that.
- (chuckles) Disappeared, just like that.
(room rumbling)
(machine whirring)
- Wait, not you!
(dramatic orchestral music)
Uh, Dr. Hartmann, Dr. Hartmann.
Oh!
Oh, oh, oh God.
Dan, Dan Roebuck, where are you?
(dramatic music)
Oh Dan, can you hear me?
Dan, Dr. Hartmann!
I'll tell ya, if somebody
doesn't answer me soon.
Dr. Hartmann, I swear to God,
I have an interview later this afternoon.
If I miss is because of
you, I'm gonna be furious.
Damn you, damn you!
(dramatic music)
I must be dreaming this or I'm dead,
and this is either heaven or hell.
Well, heaven it isn't, so it must be hell.
Only this doesn't look like Dallas.
Dan Roebuck!
(Dan Roebuck echoing)
(wind whooshing)
(loudly sighing)
(Qahhar growling)
(Carrie screaming)
(dramatic music)
(Qahhar grunting)
(gentle music)
(dramatic music)
Son of a bitch!
(gentle music)
(upbeat music)
(tribesmen grunting)
(dramatic music)
- Don't panic.
Now slowly back away.
(dramatic music)
- Now what?
- Run like hell.
(tribesmen growling)
Keep running!
- [Carrie] I'm running, I'm running!
(dramatic music)
(tribesmen growling)
(Carrie screaming)
- Hang on!
(screaming)
Hang on!
(tribesmen growling)
(Dan grunting)
(dramatic music)
(tribesmen babbling)
(both groaning)
(root snapping)
(dramatic music)
(tribesmen growling)
- Oh God.
I think you should know
I can't stand heights,
they give me headache.
- Want a headache?
Just look up.
(tribesman growling)
- Oh!
(body whooshing)
- What's going on.
- Maybe it's some sort of strange ritual.
(man grunting)
(men growling)
(body whooshing)
What are you doing?
- This is the damn rope
and grappling iron.
I'm going to pitch it up there
and with luck it will hook onto something
and then you and I can
shimmy up the Beanstalk.
- And what if the giant is up there
and chops down the Beanstalk what then?
- Ladies first.
- Oh no, I don't like the way
those pint-sized midgets
committed suicide in installments.
Besides whatever did it
could still be up there.
- Okay by me.
If the wire breaks I'll have you
to break my fall but if
that's the way you wanna--
- No, no, no, no on second
thought I think I'm gonna first.
(Dan chuckling)
- Relax, I gotcha.
- I am quite able to do this by myself
so if you don't mind, please
take your hand off my butt.
Thank you.
(dramatic music)
(Carrie grunting)
It's okay now.
You can come on up.
(rock rumbling)
(dramatic music)
- Oh God!
(rock whistling)
(rock crashing)
(dramatic music)
- Sorry.
(Dan grunting)
(dramatic music)
Hi.
- Hey.
what are you doing?
- I'm letting him go,
that's what I'd doing.
- Oh so all of a sudden you're
an expert on this place?
Up to now everything in this world
either wants to hunt ya or kill ya.
God knows what he wants to do.
- I want to thank you.
- Geez, it speaks.
- Speaks English.
- No I speak Vanyan.
We can't stay here.
The Varns will return.
- The Varns?
- I think he means those
pint-sized midgets.
- What do you think?
- I think we'd better get out of here.
- But he's green.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
(fruit popping)
- Uh thank you, thank you for helping us.
- You saved my life
therefore I'm in your debt.
We have more forest to
cross before we're safe.
(Carrie gasping)
(Dan groaning)
(dramatic music)
(Carrie crying)
- Hey.
(dramatic music)
- Hey guys!
(gentle music)
Whoa!
(upbeat music)
(Carrie groaning)
Water.
- Call me if you need me.
(gentle music)
- [Carrie] Ah!
(Dan groans)
(dramatic music)
- What is that?
- Amber light.
How else can you make a fire?
- Well where I come from we use matches,
sort of like, um, (laughs)
it'll take too long to explain.
(dramatic music)
- You are not from Vanya
but there is nowhere else except Vanya.
Yet you speak Vanyan.
I don't understand.
- I don't understand myself.
(water splashing)
(Carrie screaming)
- Dan!
(pod gun whooshing)
(dramatic music)
- Shit.
What was that!
- Water beast.
Bad way to die.
- [Dan] You okay?
- [Carrie] Yes I'm fine, thank you.
I think I'll just put some clothes on.
- [Dan] Remember if you need any help.
- Yes, um hm, thank you.
Guess we owe you now, if
it hadn't been for that,
just what is that?
- Pod gun.
(pod gun firing)
- I see these, these Pods
are full of a kind of gas.
Can I have look at that?
Okay don't pull apart.
- My debt to you is now paid.
- Hey wait!
Hey we need your help to
find a guy named Hartmann.
He's the guy that got us into this mess.
He's the only one that can get us out.
- Plumberry, food for when you travel.
- [Carrie] Hey what happened?
- He said he squared
his debt and he was off.
- Oh God.
Oh God, what is that?
(laughing)
- Dinner.
(gentle music)
- Hartman couldn't possibly
have gotten this far, could he?
- Before I answer that
answer me one question.
- Huh.
- How long had you been
here before I found you?
- Oh about day, why?
- Well I've been here for at least a week.
- A week.
That doesn't make any sense.
- I know it doesn't.
How long before you followed me
into that force field or whatever it was?
- A couple of seconds
I guess, I don't know.
It all happened so fast.
- Well, I hate to tell you
this but the way I figure it,
a split second in our world
takes a whole lot longer here.
And if Hartmann disappeared
sometime before we did,
he could have been in
this world for at least,
oh who knows maybe a year.
- A year!
- Well he could be anywhere.
- And it's a big place to
look for a kooky scientist.
- Wait.
- What?
- [Carrie] I've seen that before.
- Where?
- In the lab!
When Hartman disappeared
it was behind him.
Terrific!
(gentle music)
You could do with the shame.
- Sorry.
- I'm not complaining.
(gentle music)
(upbeat music)
(chains rattling)
(Carrie gasping)
- Gently.
(dramatic music)
To find such a wildflower
lost here in the wilderness.
Especially one with hair
the color of the sun.
- No!
(dramatic music)
- They didn't get far.
- You fools, did you really believe
that scum like you could
take these away from me
and replace me as warlord.
No one can kill Kleel.
No one!
- I beg you, he threatened me.
- Oh so you were less
guilty are you coward.
Very well.
Arack, you will be taken
to the fortress with us.
As for you, hang him, now.
(laughing)
- No, please!
I beg you!
No!
Don't shoot me please!
(man screaming)
- Skin of ivory, hair
the color of the sun.
- Don't touch me!
(screams)
- And she speaks, when
she should remain silent.
What other surprises do you
have for me, Wildflower.
- Let her go you son of
a bitch or I'll kill ya.
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
- No!
You killed him!
(dramatic music)
Oh you animal!
(hand smacking)
(Carrie groaning)
- Bring her.
(dramatic music)
Giddy up.
- Giddy up.
- Come on frig.
- Gung ho.
- Yeah!
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
- Who's attack!
- Where's Carrie?
- Yeah, you're chokin' me you great ox.
- I'll break your goddamn neck
if you don't give me some answers.
- If we're talking about the girl,
Kleel the war lord took her.
- Where's he taking her?
- Look, don't you know anything?
Back to his fortress in the Dead Mountains
but no one gets in there and
I know what I'm talking about.
- And who the hell are you?
- My name is Malachi.
Can I get up now?
- Oh.
(Dan groaning)
- Here.
(Dan moaning)
- Can you take me there?
- First you act like a corpse
now you want to be an idiot.
- I wouldn't expect you do it for nothing.
- What is that?
Is it gold?
- It's a watch, not only gold
but it's got magical powers,
it speaks, it warns the one who wears it
if a thief is about.
- The devil it does.
(watch merrily beeping)
It also tell you Pacific
time, Mountain time
and the exact hour and
minute in Hong Kong.
- By all that's smelly in my own shoe.
It's a deal,
- It's yours, once we
reach Kleel's fortress.
- First off you need a horse.
(upbeat music)
Talkin' of horses the best dealer
in these mountains is
my old friend, Treet.
Though you ought to know,
he's got the sort of charm
that would make a snake vomit
but he sells good horses.
(gentle music)
(men chattering)
(men laughing)
(dramatic music)
- Get up!
- No!
No!
- Move!
- No!
- Yes!
(man laughing)
- [Carrie] Oh God!
- No!
- Yes!
(Carrie groaning)
(dramatic music)
- Don't you touch me.
- Speak when you're spoken to.
- Agh!
(man screaming)
(dramatic music)
- You!
I'm gonna teach you--
(Qahhar grunting)
(man strangling)
(dramatic music)
(gun firing)
(Qahhar grunting)
(dramatic music)
(club thudding)
(man yelling)
- So you thought you'd
play the master, huh.
Don't you never try to
wear my boots again vermin.
This woman belongs to me.
Do you understand?
- I didn't know.
I swear I didn't know.
- Now you do.
(boot thudding)
(man groaning)
Had he touched you, the
skin would have been peeled
from his screaming flesh
because you would have been
tainted by his foul embrace.
I'd have crushed the petals
of my little wildflower.
(dramatic music)
(Qahhar grunting)
- [Dan] How far to Kleel's fortress
from where you pick up the horses?
- [Malachi] Oh about a day's ride
but the closer we get
to Kleel's stronghold,
the more your mind might change.
- Why?
- If the tales they tell are true,
Kleel has a mighty sorcerer in his power.
You felt the bite of
his double smoke stick.
How can you hope to beat a man
who has the dark powers on his side.
(upbeat music)
(Dan groaning)
- [Dan] Whew!
- Leave the talking to me.
(upbeat music)
(men laughing)
- Malachi, you spitball.
- Spitball.
- What dugout, you been hidin' in?
- Wasn't I just tellin' my
companion how we had to stop
and wish my old friend
Treet a very merry day.
- I'll give you that,
horseman, ya you curdled toad.
- Curdled toad.
- Is that horseman, here
you old horse thief?
- Hand made tools the like of
which you'll never see again.
Of course my friend,
and food and drink is all I ask in return.
(tooth crunching)
(Treet groaning)
- Little offering for the fairies.
- Hey!
Hang on a second there, those tools--
- Yes?
- Are of excellent value.
I want to word with you little man.
- Well I hope it's a thank you.
- What!
Do you know how much those tools cost?
You've just given away my livelihood!
- That's gratitude for you.
I bring you all this way introduce you
to my friends.
- Him?
- and all I'm getting for
my pains is the promise
of that watch which would be much safer
in my keeping knowing the type of thief
that drinks in this place.
Do you hear me?
What is it?
- That man at the table over there.
- That's a green man they're really weird.
The men with him are traders.
They're trying to learn how
he summons the wild horses.
That's why they're
filling him up with booze
but he won't tell them.
Where are you off to now?
- Oh excuse me.
Hi.
- Pour him another drink.
- I could still do with your help.
- What's going on?
- Now listen friend, we're
willing to pay for your secret.
- Look, the girl I was
with, she's in deep trouble.
- Listen scat head, you're in trouble.
I'm doing business with this
man, now you stay out of it.
- Look I only wanna quick word okay.
- Just what do you think you're doing?
- Look he helped me before,
I'd like his help again, okay.
- I'm helping you this time
and nobody gets to share my reward.
- The way you do business
I can't afford ya.
- Back slidin' on our deal is it.
- Friend, I hope your
skills as thick you're hide.
(head thuds)
- What are you feeding him?
- I'm getting upset and when I get upset--
- Aww, shut up.
- I told you not to intrude!
- Hey, hey, I'm sorry I'm outta line.
I hate people who interfere.
- Look, you ought to
know that my friend here
not only said you looked like hogs in heat
but you smell like pigs in the swill bin.
- [Man in Red] He did, did he!
(dramatic music)
(fists thudding)
- [Malachi] Here ya go!
(men yelling)
(dramatic music)
- Okay, call your men back.
- All right get back to your fun now, now!
- I'm going but first
my friend comes with me.
(dramatic music)
- This is Treet Sky, and Treet
says who goes and who stays.
- Let him have him.
He's drugged.
- He's drugged.
(dramatic music)
- Here, what about me?
- What about you, dimple.
(dramatic music)
- [Malachi] Wait!
Come back!
How much?
You owe me!
Wait, let me ride with you.
Kleel the warlord will
pay much for that one.
- Why?
- [Malachi] Why that's for me
to know and you to find out.
All I ask is the gold band
he wears around his wrists.
- Truly Warlord Kleel will
pay gold for that one?
So will the Nabu Fire Warriors
and they're a lot nearer.
(Malachi groaning)
(man laughing)
- [Malachi] A favor, Treet old friend.
- Oh, anything, as long as you ride
as far from here as possible.
- A short cut!
Is there a shortcut
through to the main trail?
- Keep the river on your right, now go.
You evil smelling shrimp.
- May you suffocate in your
own fat you tub of grease.
(Treet laughing)
(dramatic music)
- [Man] Raise the gate!
(men groaning)
(dramatic music)
- Only the dead know their way out.
(gentle music)
Shareen, always the little mother.
- My lord.
- Bosk bring the woman.
Carefully.
Our Hellcat might damage
your manhood again.
Don't dismiss the men,
I want them to see what happens
to those who plot against me.
Hair the color of the sun.
What would you give
to have hair the color
of the sun, Shareen.
I should have the scalp
off your pretty head.
But then Shareen would sell her soul
to be anything other than the
half-breed slave that she is.
Isn't that true Shareen?
(men chattering)
- Haw!
- Traitor!
I hope the hanging of your accomplice,
weighs heavily on your conscience.
You wanted me dead, now you have the means
in front of you to do it, coward.
Right here in the open
for everybody to see
that Kleel's law is just, hard but just.
(men laughing)
Do you still have the guts coward
or is that yellow streak down
your back just for decoration.
(dramatic music)
(spear clangs)
(spear thuds)
You had your chance.
And you threw them away.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
(gun fires)
(dramatic music)
Kleel's law is hard, hard but just.
- You call that justice?
I call it murder.
- Perhaps a few hours in
Bosk's degenerate arms
might teach you a little respect.
- I don't think you'd like that.
- Oh?
Bosk, cage her, no food no water.
(dramatic music)
- She has the mark of
evil in her eyes, lord.
She will bring you ill luck if she stays.
- No my dear if she stays
the ill luck will be yours.
(Kleel laughing)
- What a great trade,
shrunken green weirdo
for an undersized thief.
(twig snapping)
(upbeat music)
- Piddle.
- You, I thought I got rid of you.
- Hope springs eternal.
- You're not only a thief
but an assassin as well.
- It isn't as bad as it looks.
- No?
You can explain why
you're sneakin' up on me
with a dagger in your hand?
- I came to warn you.
- Ha, ha, ha, right.
- I did and this is all the thanks I get.
- I don't believe this, I
just don't believe this.
- I don't suppose you'd believe me
if I tell you there's someone behind you.
- Oh, come on.
(sword thunking)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
- Where are we?
- Don't ask, just don't ask.
- We're being sold to the Nabu
who worshiped that rock
of fire over there.
We're in great danger.
- Keep your opinions
to yourself you drunk.
- Well my friend it's your lucky day.
The Nabu honor you.
They invite you to a contest
with the Guardian of the Rock.
If you win, you and your
friends are free to go.
- No problem, start the contest.
- Hey hold on a goddamn minute.
What the hell am I getting myself into.
- Ah, and if you refuse their invitation,
they pull out your tongues by the roots,
boil them and then while
you watch, eat them.
- Er, that's disgusting.
- And finally you're given
to the God of a Rock.
(rock hissing)
(laughing)
And then you fry.
It's fun isn't it.
(Dan grunting)
You never learn do ya.
what do I tell them?
Do you accept?
- Nod your head you idiot.
- Ah shoot.
(laughing)
- He desires the contest.
- [Nabu] Hurrah!
(Dan grunting)
- Thanks a lot you little twit.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- Oh God.
(dramatic music)
Okay.
Just a minute.
(upbeat music)
Oh, God!
(dramatic music)
(fists thudding)
(foot thudding)
Ow!
(fists thudding)
(Dan grunting)
(laughing)
(fists thudding)
(dramatic music)
Ah?
- Go on, go on!
(dramatic music)
(fists thudding)
(arms smashing)
(Dan groaning)
(dramatic music)
(boot clanking)
- Holy shit!
(sword clanging)
(boot stomping)
(Guardian screaming)
(rock hissing)
(Malachi laughing)
(Nabu moaning)
- Hey, hey, I won, you guys, I won!
- Sorcerer, all I hear
from you are excuses.
I need more powder for my guns
and you swore to show me
an even greater power.
- [Sorcerer] Your Excellency,
the slaves are not getting
sufficient chemicals out of the mines
for me to purify and distill.
Get me enough and I'll show
you what real power is.
- Then we will drive them night and day
but Sorcerer do not disappoint me.
I tire of waiting.
Bosk!
- Say nothing I beg of you.
I'll find a way to see you.
- Drive the slaves even harder,
the work goes too slow
and bring the woman in.
(dramatic music)
Your meat.
Eat damn you!
(door knocking)
Come!
You see I am not the
barbarian you think I am.
Plenty of fine food, bath and, uh,
look frock of exquisite thread.
(dramatic music)
The water cools.
Bathe now.
- What do you take me for?
- Why do you defy me.
Do you enjoy making me angry?
Because only the very stupid have no fear.
- I am afraid.
- Oh, well then well fight me.
I mean you're very strange.
Unlike any in this land.
But you're the first woman
who could rule by my side.
- Go to hell.
(dramatic music)
- Do not threaten me!
Your life hangs by a thread!
I could take you any time I wish you.
You understand?
(dramatic music)
You will stay in the cage
without any food or water
until you crawl to me
on your hands and knees
and beg me to take you.
(Carrie groaning)
(dramatic music)
- No!
(fist thuds)
(dramatic music)
(Shareen screaming)
(monkey screeching)
- He won it isn't fair.
- True maggot, but then
the rules can change.
You win some, you lose some.
What can honest men do?
- What's going to happen now?
- Oh that I can tell you.
You're gonna endure the pit of flame.
Once the stone plug is removed,
the sacred liquid runs
down this channel and--
- Is set on fire by the rock.
Back it comes and poof we go up in smoke.
- Wha?
- We're sitting in a bath of oil.
So when does the entertainment begin?
- Oh, ah, now!
(dramatic music)
(laughs)
- Those pods, how many do you have left?
(dramatic music)
Quick!
The amber light.
(dramatic music)
Just hope this works.
Give or take a few seconds.
Malachi!
(watch beeping)
(lock bursting)
(dramatic music)
(fire hissing)
(log whistling)
(horses stampeding)
(dramatic music)
(men shouting)
(pod gun firing)
(sword whistling)
(dramatic music)
(men shouting)
I don't know who you are but--
(Dan strangling)
- Oop.
(Qahhar grunting)
(Dan coughing)
Wonderful guy.
(Qahhar grunting)
- The green man can talk to anything.
- His name is Qahhar.
Your woman saved his life some suns ago.
- You mean Carrie?
- I told him that you were her friend.
He will go with us.
- I wouldn't think of going without him.
Only trouble is we don't have horses.
(dramatic music)
- The sun is still high Shareen.
Time enough to burn out
your jealousy and pride.
You should have chosen me half-breed.
But before the day is done
you'll have the answer
to the riddle of this death pit.
Why is it that when we
leave our dead slaves here,
they're all gone by the morning.
You will be the only one
who knows what happens,
when night falls.
(dramatic music)
(Bosk clicking)
(eerie music)
- What the?
- He's calling the horses.
- You mean he really can do that?
- We'll soon find out.
(eerie music)
(horses clomping)
You know, I never really
believed it til now.
(eerie music)
(men chattering)
(gentle music)
(dramatic music)
- It saddens me to find
you this way Miss Madison.
- Well get me out of here then.
- Impossible.
Kleel is not the kind
of man to cross lightly.
You've no doubt already
encountered a particular brand
of megalomania.
But how did you get here?
- That damn machine of yours, how else.
I came through about a second after Dan.
Dan?
Who's Dan?
- A friend.
A friend Kleel murdered.
- I'm, I'm sorry to that.
Then that means
that the matter transmitter
is still functioning.
Then there is a way back.
- What are you doing here?
With Kleel?
- Survival.
This is a strange and violent land.
Kleel almost had me
slaving away in his mines
but with a few scientific tricks,
I persuaded him I was a sorcerer.
You've possibly seen the pistols.
- You son of a bitch!
Then it was your guns that killed Dan.
- No.
Kleel murdered your friend.
- And that let you off, huh?
So you can go and make more guns for them.
- Kleel is not a fool.
So long as he is the
only possessor of guns,
who can stand against him.
He was also wise enough
to know I can give an even greater power.
- What have you done Hartmann?
- You must understand I've had
to work with very primitive
means at my disposal.
Even so I've managed to create a primitive
but potent equivalent to nitroglycerin.
- You're a goddam maniac.
- You disappoint me.
I would have thought you'd
have been far more realistic.
Do as I have done.
Humor him and survive.
Kleel will rule this land
with the power I can give him.
- Let Kleel rule and the rest can go spit.
I said it to him and I'll say it to you.
Go to hell!
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
- What's wrong?
- He says he needs water.
- Water, where?
(mystical music)
(earth rumbling)
(water trickling)
(lips smacking)
(dramatic music)
- [Green Man] Over there in the trees.
- What do you see?
- There is something moving.
- Whoa.
- That son of a bitch!
(Dan grunting)
(dramatic music)
(horse snorting)
(Qahhar sniffing)
(Qahhar grunting)
- He senses something.
Evil, unclean.
- Subtle, I thought it was
something serious, ah, ah!
(Malachi screaming)
(Undead roaring)
(horses neighing)
- Here, quick!
(dramatic music)
(Undead hissing)
- Where the hell are we?
- We're lost, I know we're lost.
- These caves go under Kleel's fortress.
(dramatic music)
(eerie music)
(footsteps shuffling)
(dramatic music)
(Undead moaning)
(footsteps clattering)
- What was that?
- What?
- They're coming after us.
(dramatic music)
(Undead moaning)
- What was that?
(Undead screaming)
- Look out!
(fists thudding)
(all screaming)
(dramatic music)
(fists thudding)
- Ew!
(Qahhar roaring)
(dramatic music)
- Malachi!
Let's go.
(gentle music)
- You filthy beggars.
- Get the hell outta here.
(upbeat music)
(footsteps clicking)
- Your Excellency.
- What?
- If I may.
The liquid is still in
the highly volatile state.
- I swear I'd understand you better
if you didn't have a tongue.
- Forgive me Your Excellency.
Perhaps if I were to show you
what I've already created.
- Mm.
(liquid thundering)
- The power.
You already have it's source.
- What is it?
- Clean air.
This way.
There's a boulder.
Qahhar!
Push!
(Qahhar grunting)
- Ah, ah, those people, they're back!
(dramatic music)
(Malachi groaning)
- Push, push.
(Qahhar grunting)
(dramatic music)
(undead moaning)
(Undead moaning)
(boulder thuds)
(Undead screaming)
(Dan gasping)
(Qahhar grunting)
- Let's go.
(Dan grunting)
Where'd the big guy go?
- Who knows.
(dramatic music)
We'll never get in.
Look!
(dramatic music)
(Qahhar grunting)
(fist thudding)
(dramatic music)
(Qahhar grunting)
- Go.
Go.
(dramatic music)
(pod gun firing)
(Qahhar grunting)
(Malachi screaming)
(Qahhar screaming)
- Get it up!
- There's nothing we can do.
We must find your woman.
- Yes but where?
- I will show you the way.
(men laughing)
- Yeah.
(Bosk groaning)
(Bosk burping)
(footsteps thudding)
- To good for the likes of me, huh.
Nobody can hear you now woman.
Nobody!
(dramatic music)
- [Carrie] Get away from me!
(Carrie screaming)
(dramatic music)
No!
(Bosk laughing)
(Carrie screaming)
- You!
(dramatic music)
(body thudding)
(foot thudding)
- Try me son of a bitch.
(Bosk grunting)
(dramatic music)
(fists thudding)
(Carrie crying)
- God I thought you were dead.
- Yeah, well I though you were about
to suffer fate worse than death.
- We cannot stay here.
Come.
- Yeah.
- Wait Dan, Hartmann is here.
He's Kleel's sorcerer.
- He's what?
- He's made nitro.
If Kleel gets his hands on it.
- Where is he?
- [Shareen] I'll take you there.
- Let's get outta here.
(dramatic music)
- God how did you get here?
I don't understand.
Who are these people.
- There's no time for
question and answer games.
Carrie, tie him up.
And Hartmann any noise and I'll use this.
I wish you'd both listen to me.
Only a powerful ruler such as
Kleel can provide the means
to return to our own time.
Can't you see that?
- No, and I don't intend
to use Kleel for anything.
- No stop!
There's enough combustible material here
to blow us all sky-high!
- What's going on?
Does he bring some kind of magic?
- Where's all the nitro?
- It's not here.
- You're lying but I don't have the time
to beat it out of ya, so get
your miserable hide outta here.
Move it!
I don't think you girls
will give us any trouble.
(Bosk moaning)
- The woman.
(dramatic music)
- Down.
Ah Shareen.
Your life was already finished.
(gun firing)
- Bastard!
- I must have missed you before.
- Ah, hold it.
(dramatic music)
- No leave him be.
- That's better.
Begging your Excellencies pardon,
I'm just a humble thief who
would like to make a deal.
- I don't make bargains.
- Ah but this is just a little deal.
- Malachi, for pity's
sake just take it easy
with that thing.
- Safe passage out of here
and a little something
for my trouble.
Now that's not too much to ask, is it?
- For God's sake quit while you're ahead.
We'll just take the safe passage.
- What makes you think I'd
let you all out of here alive?
- Okay just me then.
- You little louse.
- And if I refuse?
- I let the magic out
of the bottle don't I?
- Then you'd simply be pouring
away a decent flask of wine.
- Wine?
- I'm afraid so.
I seem to recognize the
flask you're holding.
- She told me it was the magic potion.
Wine.
(flask booming)
(hand slapping)
It seemed like a really
good idea at the time.
I was gonna get help
and come back for you.
I swear it.
Cut out my heart if I tell a lie.
- Don't tempt me.
- I need you help.
- I have nothing to say to you.
- Well I have something to say to you.
And you'd better listen.
I'll blow the whistle on you Hartmann.
- You can't blackmail me.
- Oh!
But you forget he listens to me now,
how else would I have been able
to save Dan and the others.
The stories I could tell
would curl your toes.
Now just what do you think he'd do
if he found you plotting his death
with your powders and potions?
- Damn you!
What you want me to do?
- What do you want?
- Believe it or not I'm here to help you.
- What do you take me for Hartmann?
- You may not know it
but it was I who persuaded
Kleel to spare your lives.
(Dan scoffs)
I cannot have your
deaths on my conscience.
- I find that just a
little hard to believe.
- I have no time to persuade you now
but you must give me your
word that if I set you free,
all of you will leave
this place immediately.
- Yes he gives his word.
- Where's Carrie?
- She's decided to stay.
- You're lying.
- Who knows what goes
on in a woman's mind.
- We're all men of the world.
These things happen.
Now do I have your word?
If you can't think for
yourself think of your friends.
- Yes, think of your friends.
- All right.
All right you got it.
(Hartmann groaning)
- You, you gave me your word.
- This world has taught
me on thing Hartmann.
Trust no one and you and I have
a little unfinished business
to take care of.
- [Malachi] Whoop!
(dramatic music)
- Leave us, leave us.
I don't want to be disturbed.
(dramatic music)
This is for you.
Open it.
(dramatic music)
It's a gift, open it.
Open it damn you!
You and I have an agreement.
Don't forget your friends
are still in my power.
I gave you their lives in
return for your cooperation.
(dramatic music)
Open it, please.
(gentle music)
- It's very beautiful.
- Yes, isn't it.
It was a lucky charm
of a warrior chieftain.
He still believed that
it would save his life
even as I pushed my
sword between his ribs.
- You have a way of ruining everything.
- So I ruin everything do I?
Do not patronize me.
I've offered you more than
I've offered any woman
and you spit in my face
as if I were a beggar.
(dramatic music)
You go to far.
- I'm sorry.
(Kleel scoffs)
- Thank you.
- Now you will be careful
how you handle those flasks.
One slip and there's enough
nitro to open up the mountain
and blow entire fortress sky-high.
- Comes a time when you
have to live dangerously.
You know what to do.
Malachi.
- Yeah?
- The powder you make for
Kleel's guns, I need it.
Now!
We've gotta move while it's still dark.
I'll lay enough fuse to make
this place blow in about,
Malachi, give me back my watch!
(watch beeping)
Take him with ya.
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
(flask clanking)
- What was that?
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(horse neighing)
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
(dramatic music)
(fire sizzling)
- I told you I didn't
want to be disturbed!
- Please I'd like some more wine.
- Very well.
Quickly.
(fist thudding)
(body thudding)
(Dan groaning)
- Drop it!
I said drop it!
I'm warning you.
You take one more step
and I'll blow your goddamn head off.
(Carrie gasping)
You conceited bastard!
(fist thudding)
(gun firing)
- That's doin' it.
- Dan, Dan, come one.
(flask booming)
- Dan, please.
Get up, get the sword.
- Sword.
- The sword.
- Come on.
- Wait, wait I gotta get this off.
(dramatic music)
Okay.
(flasks booming)
(men shouting)
(dramatic music)
(fire sizzling)
(swords clanking)
(men shouting)
- Dan!
(dramatic music)
- [Dan] This way!
- Where are they?
I'm ready.
(arrow whooshing)
(pod gun whooshing)
(dramatic music)
(flasks exploding)
- Stop!
(Qahhar grunting)
(fire whooshing)
- Kleel's law is harsh.
(laughing)
- I need the gun.
- To be clear, I can't drive.
(Malachi moaning)
(pod gun whooshing)
(fortress crashing)
(dramatic music)
(Qahhar grunting)
- What about that invisible doorway, doc?
- It's hopeless.
Don't you understand.
The chances of our finding
the things I transmitted
are 10 million to one.
- Then I suggest we start lookin'.
- Gold!
(dramatic music)
- What have you found?
- Just some cast off bauble
with strange markings on it.
- Markings?
- Scribbling, how do I know I can't read.
- Thank you.
- That's it!
Goddamn it!
That's it!
- Where'd you find this?
(dramatic music)
(transmitter whirring)
- No, no!
Wait!
(transmitter whirring)
- Where have they gone?
(watch beeping)
What about the watch?
(upbeat music)