♪ I dream of not a ray of sun ♪
♪ A moment ♪
♪ And then the empty dawn ♪
♪ Awakens the lonely
heart broken ♪
♪ A warm embrace ♪
♪ A fleeting smile ♪
♪ A whisper ♪
♪ And then the dream has gone ♪
♪ With most of the
words left unspoken ♪
♪ Each lonely day
when I awaken ♪
♪ I could not face
the empty dawn ♪
♪ For I know ♪
♪ That my heart
has been forsaken ♪
♪ A dream of love
was all I knew ♪
♪ That moment before
the empty dawn ♪
♪ Awakened my lonely
heart broken ♪
Tequila.
Is he having a dance?
Five-ace card player.
Five dollars he doesn't
last another minute.
Cut him down.
You stay out of this, Yank.
We'll cut him down
when he quits kicking.
Billy.
Get in, boy!
Where have you been, Billy?
You'd better ride with us.
There ain't no Yellowleg
Yankee boy goin' with us!
I hear they got a new bank
and an old marshal
over at Gila City.
That beats cheatin'
at cards, don't it?
Let's go.
The town looks quiet.
Yeah, I bet the
marshal's asleep.
Ever shoot a man in
his sleep, Yellowlegs?
You bein' a Yankee?
He ain't very sociable, is he?
Been with us a week and
ain't lost his temper once.
I never did trust a man
who didn't lose his
temper once in a while.
Come on, let's go.
We ain't takin'
the bank today.
Uh, are you givin'
the orders now?
Looks that way, don't it?
Billy, get him in the back.
No, Turkey, that
ain't my style.
Come on, he's
askin' for it, boy.
Any man that'd
turn his back on you
is just a dag blame fool.
I kinda like him.
I never know a Yankee before.
Hey, Mead!
Your horse needs a shoe.
There's a blacksmith's shop.
How long do you figure
that money's gonna keep?
Till I tell you when.
You know, I'm kinda
anxious to get my hands on it
and get over on old.
Take care of your horse first.
I was figurin' on
havin' a couple of drinks
with you fellas.
I sure hope,
sure hope this town
has some pretty girls in it.
When you get this
far out in the brush,
they're all pretty.
Billy, take the horses
round to the livery stables.
Uh.
Are you talkin' to me?
Your name's Billy, ain't it?
I'll take the horses
for you, mister.
Well, you look
like an honest man.
You know, some folks is
just born lucky, I guess.
Doggone it, you know,
don't push yours!
What's going on here?
These don't look
too pretty to me.
I told you, you ain't
been out here long enough.
Hey!
Hey, hey, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
Put that thing back up.
That'll have to wait, gents.
Wait, wait for what?
Church is about to start.
The parson don't like to
look at it during his sermon.
This ain't Sunday, is it?
That's a matter of
opinion in Gila City.
We haven't seen a
calendar in two years.
Some folks hold it's Monday,
but these folks
hold it's Sunday.
Are you gents
lookin' for a drink?
I'm lookin' right at it.
What's in that bottle?
Best we've got.
Even the Mayor drinks it.
That'll have to do.
Tell me somethin'.
How about the bank?
How they hold?
The bank's open,
they're Monday folks.
The bar's closed when
the parson walks in.
Howdy, mister!
Hello, boy.
Hey, that's what
I call pretty.
Psst.
Who's she, the redhead?
Works over at the dance
hall across the street.
Imagine comin' in here
like she was respectable
and bringin' her
woods colt with her!
Imagine!
She wouldn't know his
father if she saw him again.
Poor boy.
I imagine it's as close
as she ever was to a parson.
And her holding a prayer book
like she was respectable!
If they're going to heaven,
let's you and me not go!
Shh.
Gents, the bar is closed.
Number 23.
♪ Rock of ages, cleft for me ♪
♪ Let me hide myself in thee ♪
♪ Let the water and the blood ♪
♪ From thy wounded
side which flowed ♪
♪ Be of sin the double cure ♪
♪ Save from wrath
and make me pure ♪
♪ Could my tears forever flow ♪
♪ Could my zeal
no languor know ♪
♪ All for sin could not atone ♪
What are y'all drinkin'?
No drinkin'.
The bar's closed on account
of the church meeting.
Whisky.
I told them the bar's.
Billy, show 'em our
fancy six-shooters!
See how fast you can take
the cork out of that bottle.
I wanna tell you somethin'.
He's fast with
them six-shooters.
This boy's, the real comin' boy.
I wanna tell you I taught
him everythin' I know.
What's the matter?
I guess, you'll have to stand
and look at that bottle all
the way through the sermon.
♪ Let me hide myself in thee ♪
Lord, I see you sent
us some new faces today.
Male
and female.
Lord, I thank you,
and folks, I welcome you.
And I'll be dishin' out
the gospels in a minute.
But first, I've got to
say a word to you gents
with your hats on.
This here is a
preach-house, gents,
and you'll take your
hats off to the Lord.
Mister, I never met a man
who wouldn't take off
his hat to the Lord.
Let's get it off.
You get on with
your preachin'.
He's gonna touchy
about that hat, ain't he?
I've never seen
nothin' like it.
He don't even take
it off to sleep.
We'll have a moment
of silent prayer.
Yes.
All that money just sittin'
out there across the street.
I've never known a
man so hungry for money.
You know, I think you're
studyin' up to be a miser.
Studyin' up to buy us an army.
Don't you remember?
Still dreamin' about that?
It ain't such a
dream, Billy boy.
We could set up our own
republic on this country.
It's wide open,
nobody can stop us.
Take that bank money and the
Comancheros will sell us 100,
maybe 200 slave Indians.
We put uniforms on 'em.
Yeah, fix us up an army.
And I could drill 'em.
♪ When Johnny comes marching
home again, hooray, hooray ♪
♪ When Johnny comes
marching home again ♪
Left face, right face.
♪ Johnny comes marching ♪
Mm-hm.
Raise this arm.
Raise it.
Higher.
Mm-hm, all right.
It always pained you that way?
Almost always.
That ball ought to
come out of there.
That's
what I'm here for.
Have you ever
been in Springfield, Ohio?
No.
I'll swear I've seen
you someplace before.
Here.
How long will this lay me up?
Well, it's pretty
close to the collarbone.
A thing like that won't
heal overnight, you know.
What, a week?
More like a month.
Well, I got a little
business to attend to.
I don't think it
can wait that long.
Then stop wasting my time.
Wait a minute.
Missoura.
That's where it was.
A fella just about your
size, the Yellowleg sergeant.
Somebody had tried to scalp him.
A liquored-up Johnny
Reb with a Bowie knife.
He cut the sergeant
up pretty badly
before he was scared
off by something.
You know, if you
take off your hat,
you could make me out a liar.
It's you, all right.
You certainly went out of
your way to look me up,
didn't you?
Take off the hat.
I've kind of got
used to keeping it on.
Why?
You haven't got anything to
hide but a few battle scars.
A lot of the boys came
out with worse than that.
What did you do
after the war ended?
What would you do?
Well, I'd go after that Reb.
Well, I found him.
Is that Reb in town?
Well, what are you waiting for?
I'm waiting to get him alone.
You see, I want him
to know who I am.
I want him to know he's
gonna get what he gave me.
Are you sure you
found the right man?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I left my teeth marks
in his scalping hand.
And I'm askin'
you, my friends.
Any man, woman or
child that reckons
that he wants to go to hell,
I say let that man, woman or
child stand up and be counted!
What?
Start countin', Parson.
Get up, Turk.
Why, you white-livered coyote,
you mean to stand there,
and saying you intend
to go to that place?
I sure do, Parson.
I'll tell you somethin' else.
Any man in this room that
don't get on his feet right now
and join me is
goin' there pronto!
Well, nice to meet
you, ma'am.
My name's Billy.
Billy Keplinger.
Get out!
Come on, Turkey!
Sure is a pretty girl.
Ma'am, I wanna thank
you for your fortitude.
We'll all close
with a prayer now
for those poor, misguided men.
All that money
just sittin' there,
waitin' on a
Yellowlegged Yankee.
I never saw a man so patient
about robbin' a bank!
Oh, church meeting's over.
You have a nice afternoon.
Thank you again, ma'am.
Let me know when that
Yankee's patience runs out.
If his patience
ever does wear out.
That pretty redhead
that just went in,
I holds that today is Sunday.
What do you lovely
creatures feel about that?
I think it's Monday.
Get your horse.
Huh?
Get it.
Billy!
Hey, Billy!
Yellowleg's ready.
Somethin' wrong with that
Yankee's shootin' arm.
Somebody get the doc.
He's dead.
It was
them outlaws, Kit.
They did some wild shootin'.
No.
It was me.
Is she the
dance hall woman?
That's her.
Imagine comin' in here
like she was respectable,
bringin' her woods
colt with her!
Imagine!
She wouldn't know his
father if she saw him again.
Poor boy.
I imagine
it's as close
as she ever was to a parson.
And her holding the prayer
book like she was respectable!
That Yellowleg sure has been
tryin' to get hisself drunk.
He ain't quite makin' it though.
Some men are like that.
Give me two.
The boy's leanin'
awful hard on him.
You reckon the Mayor will
be able to talk that redhead
into changin' her mind?
Ain't nothin' gonna
change her mind.
She got Doc Acton to
take care of the body
and rented herself a wagon.
She's goin' tonight.
Goin' alone if she has to.
We've come to
change your mind, Kit.
We've decided to
have a nice funeral for the boy
right here in Gila City.
The whole town will come.
As Mayor, I'll see to it.
Mead will be buried in
Siringo, next to his father.
Now, Kit.
Bury him here?
You think I haven't
heard all the whispering?
You and your
gossiping little wives
with their pinched little faces
and their noses in the air!
Now, Miss Kit.
"That dance hall woman with
her freckle-faced woods colt.
No telling who the
father might be!"
They smell brimstone
every time I walk by.
They hated us both,
me and the boy.
Well, he's dead now
and you can tell your wives
that there was no sinning
and there'll be no funeral.
I'm taking him to Siringo.
You can't do that, Miss Kit.
It's smack in the
middle of Apache country
and there ain't nobody
willing to go with you.
Besides, there's not much
of it left but the weeds.
I've tried, Kit.
I've asked everybody.
I'm not asking
anybody to go with me.
Poor Kit.
She's trying mighty hard
to make folk believe
about the boy's pa.
Are you a single man?
Married.
I didn't know that, Cal.
Well, almost married.
Me and Emma.
She wouldn't let me go
with Kit, not that way.
Not to mention the Apaches.
I ain't never seen a
town so full of cowards.
town so scared of Indians.
You can take three.
Kit?
I hate to think what all that
sun will do to your face.
Will you take this?
No, thanks, Cal.
Take it.
I've got no use for it.
I can't sell it.
Imported all the
way from St. Louis.
Get down from there!
I said get down!
Somebody's got to
drive this for you.
Not you.
I'm askin' to.
I said get down!
Need any help, ma'am?
Get out of here, Billy.
I didn't mean to butt in.
Your place.
Get down.
I bet she don't get 20
miles before she turns around.
$50.
And a call.
What have you got?
You lose to four aces.
We're leaving town.
You're a little
premature, Yellowleg.
Get your horses.
Billy and me like this
town, got a homie place in.
We're stickin' around.
You'd better leave alone
'cause we ain't leavin'.
It wasn't me that shot that boy.
Get up.
Get up!
Turk, it's looks like you
and me is gonna go to Siringo.
Billy, you and I
ain't leavin' here.
I'm just backin' him up.
Yeah, I kinda like the
idea of going to Siringo
with that redhead.
Come on, what's the matter?
Come on!
I guess you don't mind the
Yellowleg orderin' you around,
but I don't like it.
But if I could handle
that six-shooter like you,
Billy boy.
His back's
pointin' right at ya.
What's the matter?
Scared?
Scared he might hear
your gun comin' out
of the holster and hoard on you?
No, that ain't no
fit way to kill a man.
Not even a Yankee.
There she is.
Yah, yah!
Good morning, ma'am.
You'll kill your horse
pushin' him like that.
Will you let me drive
that wagon for you?
I don't want your help!
Well, I'd be
mighty proud to ride
in that wagon with you, ma'am.
Leave me alone!
Both of you.
Well, now, you know it
ain't exactly safe out here
for a woman?
Well, it ain't exactly
safe for you either.
Any of you.
Now git!
Why don't you leave this
woman be and let's head back?
Yah!
Listen, that bank is
probably just now opening up.
Yeah, it probably
is, probably is.
We'll follow along and
see she gets through.
Turkey, that's a woman!
Come on, let's go.
Your dress is kinda wet.
I guess you're gonna
have to dry it out.
It shouldn't take
long in this heat.
I never did see
a dance-hall girl
so touchy about gettin'
kissed.
You stay away from me.
What's you gonna
do with that rock?
Use it on me?
Or a shotgun if I have to!
Well, ma'am, I always
did go for high stakes.
Apaches.
They scalped him.
Yeah.
It looks like they did.
Come on, let's get
back to that wagon.
Hey, the coffee's ready!
It's plain to see that woman
don't want us round here,
so why don't we
accommodate her by leaving?
Did you desert?
Hmm?
Did you desert the Rebel Army?
I don't remember telling
you I was in the army.
I figured you for a deserter.
How did you guess?
Maybe I ought to take
her a cup of coffee
before it gets cold.
Leave her alone.
Are you, are
you talkin' to me?
Hey, Billy, I think
Yellowleg's kinda taken a shine
to that woman.
All this time, we thought
he was feelin' sorry
about that boy.
Shut up!
Touchy too.
Yeah.
Like he is about that
hat he keeps wearin'.
You know what I think
he's got under it?
What's that?
Money.
Well, there's one
way we could find out.
We can ask him.
Take your hat off, Yellowlegs.
He's scared of you, Billy.
Yellowlegs.
Take your hat off or
I'll shoot it off.
You try it and I'll kill you.
You know, Yellowlegs,
there's something about
you I just gotta like.
Better mind your
thinkin', kid.
Yellowleg has done got
his claim staked out.
We could go back to that bank.
That posse would never follow
us out here, not to Siringo.
Or we could set up our
own little republic
like that Edward fella
did down in Texas.
You know, the
republic of Freedonia?
All this land out
here, just a-waitin'.
Think how you'd look in a
uniform with gold braid.
You're the kind of trigger-happy
young fella I can use.
You know, I'd make
you my military aide.
Then we'd start makin'
up a lot of laws,
but not one of them
would apply to us.
They don't now.
- They never did.
- I'll tell you something.
There's money in
a thing like this.
If it's run right.
But we've got to start first
with that bank
back in Gila City.
Turkey, don't
you ever shut up?
You nag
like an old woman!
It's sure quiet
out here, isn't it?
Look, I don't blame you
for feelin' the way you do,
but right now, it
might be a good idea
if you could kinda make out
like we were getting along.
Are you always that stubborn
or just hard to figure out?
Lady.
I'm just tryin' to help.
Who are you trying to help?
Riding shotgun on this wagon
isn't gonna buy you
a clean conscience!
I'm beginning to wonder
if you ever figured on
going to Siringo at all.
What are you trying to say?
I mean, right here is as
good as Siringo for the boy.
You don't have to
prove anything to me.
Damn you!
Look at 'em fightin'!
Yeah.
You don't know me well
enough to hate me that much.
Hating is a subject I know
a little something about.
You've got to be careful
it don't bite you back.
I know somebody
who spent five years
looking for a man he hated.
Hating and wanting revenge
was all that kept him alive.
He spent all them years
tracking that other man down,
and when he caught up with him,
it was the worst
day in his life.
He'd get his revenge all right,
but then he'd lose the one
thing he had to live for.
What was that for?
I was just checking my aim.
Nothing like letting the
Apaches know where we are!
That ain't no fit way to
kill a man, not even a Yankee.
You go on up ahead and
find us a place to camp.
There might be some
Apaches out there.
Then you go find out.
You know, you could
get the sun here.
I'll get used to it.
We'll be leaving
you in Siringo.
You can find your own way back.
Come on.
Turk, what are
you doin' out here?
This ain't your guard.
I wanna show you somethin'.
I've been carryin' this around
with me for a long while.
What's that?
It's a genuine general's cap.
I stole it over at San Antonio.
I never did show it
to anybody before.
A man sure really looks like
something wearin' one of these,
don't he, boy?
Huh?
Turk, if you're waitin'
for me to salute you,
you're gonna wait a long time.
Here, I wanna show
you something else.
Here.
Come here.
See that part right there?
It's not on a regular map.
A kind of a valley.
Not many people know it's there.
We're gonna buy ourselves
some slave Indians.
We're gonna put uniforms on
and we're gonna fill 'em good.
We'll be able to burn a fire
path through this country
from Tucson to Tucumcari.
What do you say, boy?
Huh?
What do you think of that, huh?
Oh, fine, Turk, fine.
Um.
Take over my guard
for me, will you?
I never, never traveled
with a lady before.
It kinda appeals to me.
Get out of my way.
Maybe I will
and maybe I won't.
I'm telling you
to leave me alone.
Oh, I don't wanna, I don't
wanna trouble you, Kit.
I just wanna be sociable.
And I never wear my guns
when I make a social call.
I always did like pretty things
and you're just about the
prettiest I've ever seen.
Saddle up.
Come on, get out of here.
I'm goin' with you, Billy.
You ain't goin' no place.
Huh?
You're stayin' right here.
He wouldn't stand a chance
in Apache country alone.
That's his lookout, ain't it?
Turk!
He's gone.
They'll be going back to
Gila City, both of them.
I'll drive you back in
the wagon if you want.
No, thanks.
You still going to Siringo?
You think you can stop me?
Lady, I wouldn't even try.
I, uh.
I'm sorry about
losing your horse.
Well, you don't have to
talk to me, you know!
It ain't worth the effort.
Five years is a long
time to turn your back on,
especially for a woman like me.
That's what you
thinking, isn't it?
Lady, I quit thinking when
I turned my horse around.
Oh, stop calling me Lady!
My name is Kit.
I don't know you well
enough to call you Kit.
Don't think you're fooling me.
You're not half as mad at
me as you are at yourself.
Gonna talk all
the way to Siringo?
Ha!
Grab that shotgun, come on!
Must have ambushed that
stage down at the border.
I sure wish I
could take a bath.
Well, nothing's stopping you.
Come on.
Want some more?
You know,
I can hardly remember what
my husband looked like.
We were only
married a few weeks.
We were on our way to
Gila City when he was,
he was killed in Siringo.
When Mead was born, they
wouldn't believe me.
Gila City put a
brand on both of us.
With their jokes and their talk
and their ugly little smiles.
Getting dark.
We've got to have another horse.
Them Apaches can't be far off.
They've got plenty of horses.
Now, you wait right
here until I get back.
Whoa.
Kit!
Pack up, we're moving out.
Whoa.
That's far enough.
I don't think I can
stay awake another minute.
You'll have to.
Start digging.
What?
We're gonna bury the wagon.
From here on, our trail's
got to look Indian.
If we're lucky, those
Apaches might still be out
trying to find their stagecoach.
Getting tired?
I didn't ask for any help.
I wasn't offering any.
I just asked if you
were getting tired.
Is Yellowleg a name?
Well, it'll do.
Where are you from?
Ohio.
Is it pretty back there?
Used to be.
What are you doing?
Do and I'll kill you.
What is it?
Apache.
How could he miss?
He didn't.
Well, why didn't he kill us?
Oh, he's got a little score
to settle up with me first.
Start packing up.
Can't forgive me for making
you give up those five years,
can you?
I'll pick up his trail again.
Hardly seemed
worth the trouble.
There you go.
He broke it.
What is he waiting for?
Why doesn't he kill us?
He will when he's ready.
Why don't you kill us
- and get it over with?
- Stop it!
Come on!
- Stop, leave me alone!
- Shut up!
Shut up!
Why do you let him torture us?
Our Apache friend's
been awful quiet.
Maybe he got bit by a snake.
Do you think
it's much further?
What?
Siringo.
Siringo what?
Do you think?
Strange.
I feel I know you better
than any man I've ever known.
Yet I hardly know you at all.
What are you trying to do?
You're hurting me!
What did you expect to find?
I was only trying to
make you more comfortable.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
There's some things about
me you don't understand.
You killed the only person
I loved in this whole world.
That's all I need
to know about you.
Next time I'll
be waiting for him.
Inside.
Go on.
This'll do.
Here.
You've got enough buckshot
in there to stop an army.
He ought to be on top
of the bluff by sundown,
so I'll wait for him.
If I'm not back by morning,
you're on your own.
Wait.
I just wanted to say
thank you.
Where is it, by the mission?
What was your husband's name?
Mead Tildon.
My son was named after him.
I
couldn't find it.
It's there.
No, there ain't nobody
named Tildon buried there.
You're just the same
as all the rest of them.
Here it is.
It must be one of the others.
Kit!
Kit.
I found it!
I found it.
Yellowleg.
Where's Turk?
Right behind you.
When Billy gets
hold of an idea,
he just won't let go of it.
Especially with the
red-headed woman.
Well, there's no need
to keep the lady out here
in the sunshine.
Let's step inside
and talk things over.
Sorry I can't offer
you folks a drink.
What did you do
with the money?
This money?
What money are
you talking about?
There's only one thing
would bring him down here
that's keeping ones up
here ahead of a posse.
I never saw folks
so scared of Injuns.
I tell you, she
sure is pretty.
Turkey, go get that money.
Are you crazy?
Now, go on, do what I told
you to do, go get the money.
You know, I, I just ain't
got the heart to kill him.
Huh?
How would you like
to have your gun back?
You want me to do it?
I'll be much obliged.
Just the minute he walks
back through this door.
What about her?
We'll decide that later.
You and me.
Well, I'm going
for a little walk.
And I'll be around.
The lady's got to
admit I got guts.
You'd
better get out of here.
You can't!
I've waited five years.
The waiting is over,
now keep out of it.
What happened to
Mead was an accident.
I know that now,
even though I thought that I
could never forgive you for it.
But I could never love a man
who was a cold-blooded killer.
Love?
You don't even know me.
I'm a face under a hat.
Did you ever wonder why
I won't take this off?
Wanna talk about love?
I've seen you
with your hat off.
What about my scars?
Do you know how many men
I've let kiss me and pinch me
just because their filthy
money gave them the right?
Men with dirty shirts,
smelly arms, money
in their pockets.
Can those scars be forgotten?
Can I ask you to love
a woman like that?
Now don't that make
a pretty picture?
Where's Billy?
Out of the way.
Don't do it!
All this shooting and he
ain't even touched him yet.
Turkey.
Billy, are you crazy?
All right, Yellowleg.
This is it.
You and me.
Move out, Billy.
Move out, Billy, I
ain't got time for you.
There ain't but two
horses in this town.
You know as good as me
that only two people are
gonna ride out of here alive.
You turned on me, Billy.
You turn coping on me and
I raised him from a puppy.
I'm not giving him this money.
No.
Get me some slave Indians,
I'll train them myself.
Take all this money.
Yellowleg, Yellowleg,
listen to me.
We can make ourselves a deal.
I don't want that Billy
with me, I want you!
Look at you, I put
you in that uniform.
Now come on, listen to reason.
Why can't a Yankee
join up with a Rebel?
We could do it.
Look at all this money here.
Look, I'll give it all to you.
I'll make a general out of you.
General Yellowleg.
Think of how you'd look
in one of these caps.
Listen, Yellowleg, like
I told you up there.
You're gonna be in my army.
I'll make a general out of
you with gold braid on you.
Remember that?
You know where you
left it, don't you?
Chickamauga.
Look at it.
No,
Oh, Yellowleg, listen to me,
I don't want that
Billy around here.
Look at me!
Yellowleg, I'll make
a general out of you.
I'll give you one
of general's camp.
You'll look good
in that gold braid.
Listen to me.
Don't!
Get out of here!
Don't do it!
Billy!
You tell Yellowleg it's
a fact I got soldiers!
Hi, Cap, we're trailing
a couple of bank robbers.
Looks like you got one of them.
Where's the other?
Inside.
Looks like they figured
you didn't have guts enough
to come here.
You know how people are.
As long as it's their money,
the gates of hell
wouldn't stop them.
Sure.
Parson, we're gonna need a few
of the right kind
of words from you.
We're burying a boy
alongside of his dad.
I'll say the
right kind of words.
This is a convoy.
Yes, sir.
Let go of me.
Gentlemen, you're gonna make
great officers in my army.
I'll soon have your
uniforms for you.
In gold braid and then
we'll start training.
Thank you, sir.
Well, Captain, if you'll
say, "Forward, yo!"
I guess these ranks, we'll go.
Forward, yo!
♪ When Johnny comes marching
home again, hurrah, hurrah ♪
Follow me, fill up those ranks!
Forward march!
Follow me, men!
We'll get us an army,
we know what to do.
We buy some slave Indians.
♪ Each day when I awaken ♪
♪ No more I face
the empty dawn ♪
♪ For I know that my
heart is not forsaken ♪
♪ The dream of love
that once I knew ♪
♪ Now lingers beyond
the empty dawn ♪
♪ No more is my
lonely heart broken ♪