Ah, Christmas Eve in London!
- Oh!
- Who in the world could resist it?
Whoo!
Yeah!
Kathy, the coin!
- Quick, Tim. Catch it!
- No.
I-I can't see it.
Oi, ratbag!
Why don't you watch where you're walking,
you great clumsy lump!
Sorry, Mr. Scrooge, sir.
Didn't realize it was you.
Good dog.
Prudence, stop licking that poor boy.
You've no idea where he's been.
Scrooge.
Come now, Prudence.
Bye.
Uncle?
Uncle Ebenezer, is that you?
That was close.
Uncle, it is you! I knew it.
Merry Christmas.
And where is she?
Where's the finest lady in all of London?
Prudence, girl.
You grow more beautiful
with every passing year.
Is Uncle Scrooge
taking good care of you, is he?
You don't miss
that rotten old Jacob Marley too much?
Why, I was just on my way
to your office, Uncle.
What luck to run into you.
Well, Harry, they say
a man makes his own luck.
So I suppose I only have myself
to blame for this encounter.
Out of time, Jenkins.
Good girl. Oh, yes.
There it is.
Yeah, there's a good girl. Yes.
- Care to make a donation?
- To the festive fund for the poor?
- Just enough to make Christmas merry.
- Or perhaps a little bit more?
Do you have a permit to perform here?
We didn't know we needed one.
Did you know we needed one?
I didn't know we needed one.
We didn't know we needed one.
Well, now you know you need one.
So pack up your trumpets,
before I call the police...
to throw you all in prison,
leaving me in peace.
Good day, ladies.
Scrooge...
How rude!
Uncle! Uncle!
Oh, splendid.
- Uh, here you go.
- Oh!
Thank you very much, sir. Such generosity.
Such generosity. Thank you very much, sir.
Think nothing of it.
Why, who would be
uncharitable at Christmas?
Who indeed.
Uncle. Wait for us!
I swear I had your money in hand
yesterday, Mr. Scrooge.
It's just that my mother, she got sick,
you see, and I had to pay for a doctor.
Another fascinating story, Jenkins.
But here's a better one.
Once upon a time,
Tom Jenkins, that's you,
owed me, Ebenezer Scrooge, 25 pounds.
Jenkins paid the money in full,
and Scrooge lived happily ever after.
The end.
Oh, come on now, Mr. Scrooge, sir.
I don't have it right now,
but I'm sure I can scrape it together
in another three, four days.
Five. A week.
Come on, it is Christmas after all.
Louder.
Faster!
He's rubbish.
Christmas? Really? If only I'd known.
This changes everything.
Very well, in the spirit of the season,
Mr. Tom Jenkins, you now have
until the end of Boxing Day to pay me.
Two extra days. How does that sound?
Two days is better than nothing,
I suppose.
Thank you very much, Mr. Scrooge.
Most charitable indeed.
Father Christmas has nothing on you.
Ho ho ho, yes, quite.
Now, let's see.
For the inconvenience you have caused me
and the extra two days,
shall we say another 25 pounds?
- That would mean I owe...
- Fifty pounds.
It's a good, round number,
wouldn't you agree?
Well, 30 is a round number too,
Mr. Scrooge.
You're right. But so is 60.
When you put it that way,
50 does have a better ring to it.
Do give my best to Mother Jenkins.
Oh, and Tom,
merry Christmas.
Fifty pounds. Two days.
Look out.
Merry Christmas.
- Scrooge.
- Hmm?
I say, Mr. Jenkins.
Do you deliver?
Mr. Jenkins?
Bah, humbug.
Left a bit. Right a bit. Left a bit again.
Up. No, up.
Left.
Your other left.
There, perfect. You're an artist, Mickey.
An artist would get paid more than a penny
for every thousand posters
he sticks up, Beryl.
You there. Yes, you. Who are you?
What do you think you're doing?
Who, us?
Sir, we is nothing
but a bunch of poor, homeless urchins
trying to make our way in the world.
Quick. Leg it!
Merry Christmas!
Blooming children.
Mr. Scrooge. Oh dear.
Welcome back, sir.
There's something I should tell you.
The cost of that ink
will be deducted from your pay.
What? The ink?
Oh. Oh, the ink. Of course, sir, yes.
Get on with your work, Cratchit.
- If it's not too much of an inconvenience.
- But, sir...
- I do not wish to be disturbed.
- Yes.
I've had more than my fill
of people for one...
day.
- We win!
- How in the world did you...?
Prudence knows a shortcut, don't you?
Very well, let's get this over with then,
shall we?
How does it go again?
Oh, yes, yes, the question.
"Uncle, won't you join me
for Christmas dinner tomorrow?"
The answer,
"No, Harry, I will not."
"Christmas is a humbug.
I despise it and all it stands for."
The same answer to the same question
you ask me every year.
I have no time to be merry.
Just because my partner is dead doesn't
mean I have no business to attend to.
Quite the opposite. Jacob Marley died
seven years ago this very night,
leaving me nothing but business.
Oh, yes, and you.
Oh, come now, Uncle.
Hela and I would just love to have you.
Hela? Who's Hela?
You know, Hela, my wife.
She was disappointed
you couldn't attend the wedding,
and simply can't wait to meet you.
So at least visit us this evening.
Some friends and I
are gathering to toast the season.
Good day, Harry.
Uncle, I'm all the family you have.
Why does it have to be this way?
I think Mother
would have been so disappointed
that you and I
spend every Christmas apart.
Harry, life is full of disappointments.
One such disappointment came
on the glorious Christmas Day
that you stumbled into this world.
The very same Christmas Day your mother,
my beloved sister, left it.
I will not be joining you
for Christmas dinner,
nor any other celebration
of this wretched season.
Now, please leave
before I say something you will regret.
Scrooge.
My offer still stands.
You are always welcome, Uncle.
- Goodbye!
- Merry Christmas, Prudence.
- Bob.
- Merry Christmas, sir.
Festive, ain't it?
Excuse me, sir,
but it's almost 6:00. Six o'clock.
Could I trouble you for my wages, please?
Cratchit, Cratchit, Cratchit...
you do nothing but trouble me.
Yeah.
Five, 10, 15 shillings.
- Thank you, sir.
- Take away five.
But I'm owed 15.
Consider the other five
your payment to me.
- For what, sir?
- The ink, of course.
And the day off
you insist on taking tomorrow.
Well, sir, it is Christmas.
Yes, as everyone is so fond of telling me.
Sir, this isn't enough.
My family, you see, my children...
My... My boy needs medicine.
You have children?
Of course you do.
Cratchit, times are hard.
And my financial burdens are considerable.
Now should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
- Scrooge...
- Does that sound fair to you?
No, sir.
No, sir, indeed.
Now, let's get you on your way, shall we?
- Merry Christmas, Mr. Scrooge.
- Yes, yes. Ding-dong, merrily.
I expect you
at half past seven on Boxing Day.
What? What have I done now?
Why, if it isn't the amazing
and wonderful Cratchit children!
Father!
- Tim!
- Father, help!
It's all right, my little man.
Just breathe, slowly.
He's getting worse.
That's it. There you go.
Right, you two.
That's it, no more busking tonight.
It's freezing out here,
and you need your rest, young man.
Aw.
- But we've only made ten pence ha'penny.
- Ten pence ha'penny? A bumper windfall!
If we add that to the ten shillings
I happen to have in my pocket
and throw in a bit of Cratchit magic,
I reckon we can have as fine a Christmas
as the Lord Mayor himself.
- Yay!
- Just wait and see.
Oh, don't be so dramatic.
I'll pick up a juicy bone for you
on the way home. How does that sound?
The butcher owes me seven pounds six...
so I'm sure he'll be happy to oblige.
Scrooge...
No?
No pleasing some people.
You there. What do you think
you're doing?
Oh, bravo!
There you go.
Merry Christmas.
You two!
Clear off!
Disgusting.
Ebenezer Scrooge...
Tell me.
There you go, sir.
Scrooge.
Tell me!
Ahh!
Ebenezer Scrooge.
J-J-J-Jacob Marley?
Impossible. You're dead.
Dead?
Dead tired!
Oh.
Oh, yeah. How embarrassing.
Prudence. Oh, how well you look.
I knew leaving you
in the care of Uncle Scrooge
was the right thing to do? Didn't I?
Hmm? Yes, I did. I did.
I do apologize
for the dramatic entrance, old boy.
Those in charge
insist on a touch of pageantry.
Goes with the territory, you see.
But I'm sure you and I can discuss
the rest like reasonable men.
Ah, I must have drifted off by the fire.
I'm dreaming.
Serves me right
for eating cheese so close to bedtime.
Well,
very well.
Ye gods!
Listen well, Scrooge.
This is no dream.
Look upon the chain that binds me.
In life, I forged it,
link by link, yard by yard.
It grew to match my greed.
In death, I will never be rid of it.
Nor will you yours.
Mine?
Yes, yours.
We were all like you.
Trapped in our own selfish worlds.
We never reached out
to our fellow men in life,
so are condemned to do so in death.
We have watched you many a day, Scrooge.
Watched your chain grow,
link by link, yard by yard.
But you may yet escape our fate.
I have pulled a few chains
and arranged for three visitors
to call on you before morning.
The first, when the bell tolls 1:00.
The second, at 2:00.
And the third, at...
Well, 3:00.
Listen to these visitors. Learn from them.
And heed my warning
before it's too late.
Jacob Marley
concerned for someone else's well-being?
Well, it must have been a dream.
Huh?
Humbug.
It's that nephew of mine. Interfering.
Bringing my blood to the boil.
Has me jumping at shadows.
Seeing things. Yes.
That's it. Yes.
The first, at 1:00.
Hmm.
Hello?
Oh, hello.
It's Scrooge, isn't it?
Yes, that's the one, Scrooge.
What a funny name.
Are you comfortable down there, Scrooge?
Uh, well...
Never mind that.
Who, or what, are you?
And it's "Mr. Scrooge," if you please.
Well, Mr. Scrooge-if-you-please, who am I?
I can be anyone you have ever known.
I can even be you.
Bah, humbugs.
Christmas is an outrage.
Grr, give me your money.
- Interest rates, and so on.
- Hmm.
You were not told of my coming?
No? No matter.
You have nothing to fear from me.
After all, your welfare is my business.
Miss, to be disturbed at this hour
is hardly conducive to my welfare.
Your redemption, then.
You see, an old friend of yours
asked me to illuminate
a thing or two for you. I...
Illuminate what, exactly?
I was getting to that.
You are an impatient one.
I will show you the past.
Christmas past.
Specifically, your Christmas past. Ahh!
There. Much better.
I've gone mad.
Mad, you say?
Jacob Marley floating in my sitting room.
Faces etched in frost.
Whispers in the wind.
A blizzard indoors.
Now you, a talking waxwork
with a wick for brains.
My dreams are never this... exciting.
And none of this can be real.
So, yes, I must be awake,
but quite insane.
Well, I may have wick for brains,
but I do think I'm real.
Here.
Oh, hush now.
There, did that feel real?
I-I suppose it did.
It hurt too.
Yes, the past can hurt.
Especially yours.
But it can also heal,
if you learn from it.
- Now, come with me.
- Absolutely not.
I refuse to go anywhere...
Whee!
Whoo!
Yeah!
No, no!
Whee!
Whoo!
Oh, baby Scrooge!
No!
Whoo-hoo!
Where? W-What? Who?
Get off!
Sorry, it does take its toll
going this far back.
- Did I not warn you?
- No, you certainly...
Wait, what do you mean by "back"?
Huh?
- What...?
- We're not quite there yet.
Almost.
Here we are.
The past.
Spooky!
I know this place.
It was demolished years ago.
I saw to that.
You there. What day is it?
I say...
Ah! Oh! Oh!
I wouldn't do that.
You can't interfere with anything here.
And nobody can hear you.
Or see you, for that matter.
- Don't fill it right to the top.
- Look!
Young Ebenezer Scrooge,
hard at work on Christmas Eve.
Not very festive, is it?
I...
I-I had no choice.
You see, without the modest income
I provided, my mother and sister,
th-they would have starved.
- Did your father not have any money?
- My father?
He was not a poor man,
but the fool spent his way
into debtors' prison.
Oh, I see.
Debtors' prison. Terrible, terrible thing,
a debtors' prison.
- What is a debtors' prison again?
- A debtors' prison is, uh...
None of your business.
You can't escape your past, mate.
Now, look here...
My dear little sister, Jen.
Jen. Come on, breathe.
Slowly.
In and out.
That's it.
What are you doing here alone?
- Does Mother know you're out?
- I wanted to give you this.
I made it all by myself.
- Merry Christmas, Ebenezer.
- Oh, Jen. It's Father Christmas.
He's really magnificent.
Maybe you could help me
make one for you in return.
Yes, please!
Shall we sing
that pretty song of yours as we walk?
Oh, such a sweet child.
Will she be all right?
She will be. For a while, at least,
the sickness will not take her.
My father paid his debts, eventually.
We found the right doctor
and she was saved. But...
But?
She remained a delicate soul,
whom a breath might have withered.
Jen died in childbirth.
My idiot nephew in exchange for my sister.
A sorry transaction in any currency.
And all on Christmas Day.
Christmas.
Oof. Humbug.
Oh, come now.
Is there not one Christmas
you remember fondly?
One buried, perhaps,
in a hole as deep as old Marley's grave?
- Hmm?
- Hmm.
Merry Christmas, sir.
Hello, Uncle.
Aha!
I do believe I've found one.
Mr. Fezziwig.
"Fizzywig?" Why, that's almost
as silly as "Scrooge."
Off we go.
- A little jump forward this time.
- Wait...
I'm home then.
And not before time.
Very well. You have a week and no more.
Or we shall both
have to find new employment.
- Good day.
- Thank you very much, Mr. Scrooge.
God bless ya.
And a merry Christmas when it comes.
It's still the past.
It is.
My word, you were
a handsome chap, Scrooge.
What went wrong?
Ebenezer?
Is that you, lad?
- Mr. Fezziwig?
- It is you!
Wonderful to see you, my boy.
So that's Mr. Wizzyfig.
Fezziwig. Yes, I used to work
in his warehouse before Marley took me on.
Why didn't you keep working for him?
Marley offered a position
with more security.
People will always need money.
If I'd stayed, I would only have been
Fezziwig's lowly apprentice.
I had to better myself
before even thinking of proposing to her.
Proposing?
Oh, I do like a wedding.
Who's her? Where's her?
Flora!
Isabel.
Yes, Father?
- Isabel.
Look who I found!
Ebenezer! How lovely to see you.
My, you look splendid in your suit.
- Although, do you mind?
- I... I...
- That is...
- There.
- You see...
- Perfect.
Thank you.
Oh, Isabel, how I love thee.
With thy big slobbery face
and stinking dog breath.
Oh! Oh.
Uh, Ebenezer, do you have
any plans for tomorrow?
- Tomorrow, sir?
- You know, Christmas Day, my boy!
No, sir. My sister
is with her husband in Kent.
They're expecting a child any day now.
She invited me to visit,
but I had to decline.
Then it's decided!
You'll join us
for Christmas lunch tomorrow.
I'm not sure I can.
Too much still to be done, and Mr. Marley
doesn't even take the day himself.
Say you'll come, Ebenezer.
It'll be such fun.
Oh, look away.
I, uh...
I'll talk to Mr. Marley.
- Did you go?
- Well, it would have been rude not to.
I felt obliged.
I see.
See you there.
But you didn't enjoy it?
No. Not one bit.
Oh my goodness.
You look like you're having an awful time.
Uh, yes.
A delightful woman.
Without her,
Jen's death would have taken
an even greater toll on me.
You married her, yes?
No. Not quite. I...
No?
- I would very much like to see why not.
- No!
I...
I do wish you would stop doing that.
Home. Finally.
Well, goodbye, whatever you are.
I would say it's been a pleasure,
but it hasn't.
Where's my name?
This is before Marley made me a partner.
Ebenezer? Hello?
- I'm still in the past.
- Hello?
Oh, you do catch on quickly, don't you?
Ebenezer? Are you there?
I brought some lunch.
I see so little of you these days,
so I thought...
I'm not sure what I thought.
Ah, lovely Isabel.
- But you said you didn't marry her?
- We are...
Were merely engaged. For quite some time.
I see. I thought you would have
gone back to work for Wiggyfiz?
Of course not!
His charity would have led to the same
ruination that befell my family.
"His charity would have led
to the same ruination
that befell my blah, blah, blah."
I needed more security
than he could offer. We needed it.
I saw them by the baker's
only a few minutes ago. Good day.
Lead on, Scrooge.
Lead on. Allons-y.
Please, Mr. Marley, sir.
This is my livelihood. My home.
My family will starve. Just one more week.
One more day,
and I'll have your money, I swear.
You've had three weeks already.
I am sorry.
No. No apologies, Ebenezer.
Times are hard,
and my financial burdens are considerable.
Should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
Does that sound fair to you?
- Sir, it's Christmas Eve.
- Come on.
Please, show some mercy.
- Where are you taking him?
- Clear off. Go on. On your way!
and my financial burdens
are considerable.
Now should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
Does that sound fair to you, Cratchit?
I... I don't recall this at all.
I'm not surprised.
As horrible as this situation is,
I'm sure it was of great financial benefit
to you and Marley.
Apart from the delightful Miss Fizzlejig,
you only seem to remember encounters
where you lose money.
You dwell on the bad things in life,
and then learn nothing from them.
Does Cratchit know?
Why would he choose to work for me?
After what I...
If his father had only paid his debts...
It's not my fault.
Isabel.
She saw all of this.
Ebenezer.
Can I talk to you?
Alone.
Not now, Isabel.
I have far too much work.
Later, later.
I'll, uh, leave you two lovebirds to it.
Come, Boris.
No.
Ebenezer?
Some assistance, please.
Yes, Jacob, coming.
Later, Isabel.
No!
There is no "later!"
Goodbye, Ebenezer.
Oh, look.
A wee glimpse into Isabel's future.
Oh, she looks so happy.
And her husband's gorgeous.
That... That could have been you, I suppose.
Oh, too bad, Scrooge. Too bad.
Why show me all of this now?
What's done is done. I can't go back.
When we were financially secure,
I would have married her...
eventually.
Wouldn't I?
I don't know.
Bye!
Take me back.
Take me back!
I'm afraid I can't.
There is no going back,
nor changing what has been.
You said so yourself.
You can't change the past,
but you can learn from it.
For your own sake, I hope you do, Scrooge.
- Ooh.
- No, no, no, no!
Whoo! It really is time to go.
Farewell, Scrooge.
Farewell.
No, please! Don't leave me here!
I must.
Ooh. I have shown you what was.
Now another will show you what is.
Oh. Ooh.
Remember what you have seen, Scrooge.
Remember. Learn.
Change while you still can!
The second, at 2:00.
Hello?
Is there anybody there?
Strange, annoying,
candle lady thing?
Hello?
Huh?
Who dares disturb my slumber?
State thy name and business, puny mortal.
I can't...
I can't... I can't keep it up.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It was her. She dared me.
Oh, we do like to have fun here.
Don't worry.
I know who you are.
Come on, bring it in,
Ebenezer Scrooge. Bring it in!
Welcome, my friend. Welcome.
Welcome where?
Where am I?
When am I?
Oh, you are in the here and now.
In the present!
Isn't it just fabulous?
It's fine, I suppose.
From here, I can go anywhere I please.
Just so long as it's happening right now.
And I do so love to visit
your teeny-tiny, tootsy-wootsy,
little planet at this time of year.
So much love, generosity, and good cheer!
Which, conversely, brings me to you.
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Squeezing, wrenching, grasping,
clutching, covetous you!
Secret and solitary as an oyster,
you edge along the crowded paths of life
keeping everyone at a distance.
Why, you stopped truly living your life
so long ago, you might as well be dead.
Do not presume
to tell me how to live my life.
I lead a good life.
I'm a good man.
Ha! "A good man," he says.
Uh, uh, uh.
Whoo!
Do you see the light?
Can you feel it, Scrooge?
Are you ready to live your life,
now, in the present,
unencumbered by the weight of the past?
I'm ready.
I'm ready to go home. Thank you very much.
Oh, really?
But the fireworks.
We did a whole song and everything.
Well, I'm not giving up on you yet,
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Come on. Let's hit the town.
Hit the town?
I'll hit something else in a minute.
Dragged from pillar to post
in the middle of the night. Huh.
My friends, please.
I-I would like to propose a toast.
My friends, please. Oh...
Oh, thank you.
He really is a buffoon, that boy.
There's no need to whisper.
No one can hear or see you.
Lucky them.
Please raise your glass
and drink to the good health and long life
of my celebrated uncle, Ebenezer Scrooge.
Boo.
I know. I know.
But I like old Scrooge.
- No, no, no. No. Come now. I do. I do.
- Why?
Why?
I never met my mother,
but my father spoke of her often.
Of her kindness. Her generosity.
It's hard to believe
that the woman he described
was that old stick-in-the-mud's
little sister.
But his sister she was.
And, by all accounts,
she and my uncle were inseparable.
She loved him without reservation,
and he, her.
So he can't be all bad.
I have to believe that somewhere
in that loathsome old carcass of his,
the man my mother loved
is fighting to get out.
I should like to meet him one day.
Which brings me to my next toast
of the evening, to my beloved mother.
As I entered the world, you departed.
Here's to the Christmases we never shared,
and the sad, short one we did.
Harry, my dear, sweet Harry,
let's not dwell
on the sadness in our past,
on those who cannot be with us.
Or refuse to be.
Instead, let us celebrate
those who are here.
Hear! Hear!
Everyone, let us honor the past
by toasting our present.
To each other. To Christmas.
- To friendship.
- Hear! Hear!
To friendship.
Bravo!
Oh, for goodness' sake,
where are we going now?
May I present to you
the beautiful home
of Robert Cratchit Esquire.
He owes these sumptuous surroundings
to the generosity of his employer.
I never knew
Cratchit had quite so many children.
No? Did you ever ask him?
Mmm. Pure nectar. An elixir
fit for Father Christmas himself.
The stuffing's ready, Father.
- And the birdie is plucked.
- Tremendous work, my dears.
Roast goose with sage and onion stuffing
à la Cratchit.
A legendary gourmet dish.
There's one problem. I'm not sure whether
to stuff the goose with the stuffing,
or stuff the stuffing with the goose.
Come now, my love.
It is a lean Christmas,
there's no denying that.
But we have each other
and we have the children.
We can still make the most of it.
In fact, I do believe this will be
the best Cratchit Christmas ever.
Hooray!
Not another toast.
If you please,
a toast to those whose generosity
have made possible
tomorrow's sumptuous Christmas feast.
Master Timothy and Miss Katherine,
the Christmas-caroling Cratchits,
of course.
And Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
Oh! Scrooge?
What are you trying to do,
spoil our Christmas?
But his money paid for the goose, my dear.
No, your money paid for the goose.
- If you can even call that a goose.
- But he paid me the money.
Because you earned it.
Believe me, you earned that money, Bob.
Mr. Scrooge assures me
that times are hard, my dear.
Times are hard. For us, not him.
Nonetheless, he is the founder
of our feast, and we should drink to him.
Hear! Hear!
The founder of our feast indeed.
I'd like to give him
something to feast on.
He'd have indigestion all January.
Children, we shall drink
to your father.
For the love and happiness he brings us.
And to our Tiny Tim,
for the health we wish him.
And, for the sake of your dear father,
I will even drink
to that old miser, Mr. Scrooge.
Long life to him and to us all.
And a merry Christmas to us all.
Merry Christmas!
God bless us.
God bless us, every one.
Merry Christmas!
I think Bob Cratchit's rather fond of me.
So is his wife.
Couldn't you tell?
And now, to the triumphant
musical climax of this celebration.
Master Timothy, Miss Katherine,
would you be so kind?
- No.
- Sing, sing!
Go on, love. Sing, sing!
It's embarrassing.
Sing!
I will if Kathy does.
Timmy.
Oh, just breathe. Slowly. That's it.
That's it.
There we go.
Slowly.
Bob's boy, Tim.
What will become of him?
The future is as much a mystery to me
as it is to you.
I can only show you what is.
What's to come if you do not change?
Well, that will soon be revealed
by... someone else.
Oh, excuse me.
Look, friend, there really is
no great secret to any of this.
You just have to do
the best you can with the time you have.
But you better get started soon.
Because before you know it,
all that time you think you have
will run out.
The third, at 3:00.
Well, goodbye, Ebenezer Scroo...
Ooh!
Would you look at that?
I, uh...
We are no longer in the present.
This is the future.
This is what is yet to come.
Are you still in there, giant?
The fellow in the green robes?
Liked life and so forth?
No.
You are something else entirely.
You don't speak?
Your colleagues were
rather fond of speaking.
More than I would have liked.
So you are the one that will show me
what awaits if I do not change my ways.
Yes?
So I should change, should I?
Why? Tell me.
I live my life as well as I can.
I have my faults, but who does not, truly?
Are all others
I've been shown this night without blame?
Am I the only one
with the power to change my life?
To change the lives of others?
Well? Am I?
Tell me!
Oh, very well.
Lead on.
Show me what bleak future
my wickedness has wrought.
And, yes, nobody can see
or hear me, I know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
good morning to you
on this joyous Christmas Day.
We are gathered here as a group,
united by a common bond.
Namely, our feelings of gratitude
to Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
I know that fellow.
Jenkins. Owes me 25... No, 50 pounds.
I must say he looks uncommonly happy
for a man so deep in debt.
In fact, most of this rabble
owes me money.
Shush. Shush.
While we are all deeply moved,
those of us who Mr. S was so kind
as to lend money to over the years
are particularly grateful
for what he has done for us today.
What have I done?
Certainly not forgiven their debts.
As your predecessor said,
you are showing me
what will happen if I do not change.
I did not change, yet I am celebrated.
And rightly so.
These creatures have finally
come to their senses. That's it. Ha!
It would seem the ordeal
to which I have been subjected
has been a complete waste of my time.
And yours, my silent friend.
No matter. All's well that ends well,
as they say.
That's right, Prudence.
They're cheering for me.
Yes.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much!
Ha, ha! Oh, yes, indeed.
This is far more agreeable
than what your predecessors had me endure.
So what's next, friend?
Tiny Tim.
- No.
- It's all right.
Cratchit, times are hard,
and my financial burdens are considerable.
- My boy needs medicine.
- It's Christmas Eve.
Cratchit,
you do nothing but trouble me.
Should I add to them by paying
for the upkeep of your entire family?
I must go now, my little man.
I promised your mother
I'd help with Christmas dinner, but...
I'll come and see you again tomorrow.
Same time, all right?
Oh, dear Tim.
Come on now, Father.
Till tomorrow then.
Sleep well, my love. Sweet dreams.
I...
I could have done more.
I could have done something.
Poor Tiny Tim.
Friend, you have shown me
a Christmas yet to come
that mixes great joy with greater sorrow.
Tell me, is this what will be,
or what may be?
If I were to change,
would all this still come to pass?
Here.
Gentlemen, please.
Sorry, Father. But you reap what you sow.
Is that not what your Good Book says?
I wouldn't hang about for any mourners.
Nobody's sorry to see this one go.
Nobody who doesn't walk
on all fours anyway.
Merry Christmas.
And thank you very much.
Come on.
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
Scrooge...
No.
Spare me.
Let me return.
I will not become this man
whose death is the cause
of such celebration.
Why show me this if I am past all hope?
Am I? Truly?
If... If I am beyond salvation,
then so be it.
But, please, the boy need not die.
Not when I have it in my power
to help him.
I beg of you, spare me for this reason,
if nothing more.
I swear to honor Christmas in my heart
and keep it there the whole year through.
I will learn from the past,
live only in the present,
and strive for a better future.
For all!
Tell me I may yet strike the writing
from the boy's cross.
Tell me
I may yet break this chain!
Please.
Please, tell me!
No!
No! No!
Please, no! No! Please, no!
Spare me! Spare me!
Please. Please!
Prudence?
Prudence!
I'm in my bedroom.
Oh, it's Prudence.
Well, was I... Was I merely dreaming?
- You there!
- Huh?
I-I say, what day is it, my fine fellow?
Um, Tuesday, I think.
Ha, no.
Is it Christmas Day?
Well, of course it is.
Takes all kinds, I suppose.
It's Christmas, Prudence!
It's Christmas, and I'm alive!
Wait, what time is it?
I'm glad Isabel found
the happiness she deserved.
Perhaps...
Perhaps it's not too late
for me to find my own.
I did. I swear. I said...
- Hello there.
- What?
What is it?
We didn't do nothing, Mr. Scrooge.
No, not yet, you haven't.
I have some errands for you to run.
I can make it worth your while.
Errands?
Thank you, Prudence. There's a good girl.
Ah, ah, ah, ahh!
Mind how you go.
Mr. Scrooge, sir.
Almost done.
Magnificent.
What wonderful children you all are.
And, well, sorry to ask again,
but you're sure
you managed to get everything on the list?
Yes, sir.
The butchers and the bakers
thought I was having a laugh.
But then I gave 'em the checks.
They'll be here soon.
Splendid. And you did deliver
the invitations? All of them?
Of course.
No guarantee they'll come, though.
It is very short notice.
Quite. Uh, you are
a clever young lady, aren't you?
As promised,
a gold sovereign for each of you.
Boys, since it's Christmas,
I ain't even gonna take my cut.
That's the spirit.
And you'll all stay for dinner, won't you?
Won't you?
Yay!
Ha! And help yourself to a gift.
- Come on.
- I get the biggest one.
Ready, Prudence?
- There we go. Comfortable enough, Ethel?
- Yes. Much obliged, Mr. Scrooge.
Good, good, good.
Oh, and please, call me Ebenezer.
- What's all this about then?
- Tom, your debt is canceled.
Merry Christmas, my friend.
Oh, and give my best
to your mother, won't you?
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Oh, my giddy aunt!
Ladies, 1,000 pounds for your fund,
this and every Christmas to come.
Oh, such generosity.
It's the doll from my mother's picture.
Uncle, I can't accept this.
You must.
It's a gift from an old fool who regrets
all the Christmases we never shared.
Oh, Uncle.
Thank you.
- "Business partners"?
- Yes, Bob. If you'll have me, that is.
Let's build a brighter future
for the Cratchits together.
- What do you say?
- I say yes!
God bless you, Mr. Scrooge.
God bless us, every one.
Uh! Here we go! Ha!
Come on!
Let's go!
Come on, get up, ha!
One more time, one more time!
Hey, listen to me now.
Stop.
Ow!
- Whoo!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hoo!
Merry Christmas!