&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;one last time&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I have to see this ground&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it's beautiful now&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; as if nothing had&lt;/font&gt;
happened here
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;soon they will tear down the main house&lt;/font&gt;
and then nothing will be left&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; nothing&lt;/font&gt;
except what&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i remember&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I grew up in the town nearby&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; when my&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;father was the man and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; where this house&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; waiting&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;it was built by wilfred&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Butler&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;we&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; have never seen him and he never&lt;/font&gt;
lived at home until the day before
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;christmas in 1950 he finally did come&lt;/font&gt;
back for the last time
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;all of us&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; believe that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; his death was an&lt;/font&gt;
accident
no one knew that another person had come
to&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; about&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the house&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; that Christmas&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;as deputy coroner of the county of&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;arlington&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; state of&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Massachusetts i&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;hereby find upon evidence of an autopsy&lt;/font&gt;
conducted by the medical examiner of
this&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; county that the deceased Wilfred&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Butler died as a result of&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; burns&lt;/font&gt;
inflicted&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; accidentally upon himself on&lt;/font&gt;
his own premises
during the afternoon of&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; december 24th&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;1950&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;no further inquiry shall be held over&lt;/font&gt;
the body of the deceased and this
inquest is officially closed
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Oh&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;all&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; right&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;yawn&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;nah&lt;/font&gt;
after the coroner's inquest on&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; New&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Year's Day a berry Wilfred but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; there was&lt;/font&gt;
no one there to mourn him&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it was the&lt;/font&gt;
funeral of a stranger
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I Wilfred Butler being a sound mind and&lt;/font&gt;
body
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;at least what the world considered sound&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;do hereby&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; leave my house and its grounds&lt;/font&gt;
and all personal effects within that
house to my only surviving&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; relation my&lt;/font&gt;
grandson&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jeff&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;and i solemnly charge him with one duty&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;let him leave the house as&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I left&lt;/font&gt;
standing untouched&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; remind the world of&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;its&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; inhumanity and cruel for&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; 20 years&lt;/font&gt;
that house lay empty&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; exactly as&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; wolford&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;lefted&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;and then last year&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; was beginning&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;was finally being sold the most&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; paper&lt;/font&gt;
story&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; traveled to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the county to a State&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Hospital for the criminally&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;the man who came to sell the house had&lt;/font&gt;
never seen it&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it was a lawyer in the&lt;/font&gt;
city&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; just&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; doing a job and enjoy&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;hopeless oh look&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;are you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; going&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; out the baby's gonna&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; have&lt;/font&gt;
a fit&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;what&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;hey there&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; i want together&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; w l IX boys&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; in&lt;/font&gt;
the&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Northeast this is Roger Fowler with&lt;/font&gt;
local story first today's&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; headlines a&lt;/font&gt;
warehouse&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; fires still rage and Elizabeth&lt;/font&gt;
police suspect&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; hearts&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; nasty invaded&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;market bill State&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Hospital large still&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;haunted by state&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; police and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; over roxbury&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;city past the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; controversial housing&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;well didn't I tell you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it's beautiful&lt;/font&gt;
can you see the money&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that was it&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;
think&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; mayor's waiting for me&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; my love&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;is such an important&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;right&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; are always says that&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;what&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;don't be&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;they actually get bored just look at the&lt;/font&gt;
view&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; sooner or later that by extracting&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;back home&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;mr.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Carter as&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the mayor&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;let me introduce you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; this&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; is&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Charlie&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;tolman who publishes our weekly&lt;/font&gt;
newspaper&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Patriot common and this is&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;test Howard&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; usually operates our&lt;/font&gt;
switchboard really&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; call her the&lt;/font&gt;
communications director&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and this is bill&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;mason&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; is an hour&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; sheriff won't you sit&lt;/font&gt;
there mr. Carter at the head to the
table
thank you&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i am I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; didn't expect me to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; all&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;together it's quite a reception&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;alright let's begin as you know I've&lt;/font&gt;
been retained by&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; jeffrey but I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; matter&lt;/font&gt;
concerns the house that he inherited
from his grandfather&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Wilfred&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;go on mr. Carter&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; III believe&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that you&lt;/font&gt;
offered to buy the house&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; for my client&lt;/font&gt;
offered&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; we&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; begged him&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; we wrote letters&lt;/font&gt;
and&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; selectors&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; well it's true&lt;/font&gt;
trouble&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; is always&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; trouble&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I can&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;sympathize&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i spent the last 20 years and&lt;/font&gt;
more driving people away from&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; their&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;prowlers burgers kids they're the worst&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;chasing for nothing cause of that will&lt;/font&gt;
that&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Gribble about humanity&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;no no&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; in humanity what the hell is that&lt;/font&gt;
up
yes well he was a better man
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;aight must&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; have been very hard it must&lt;/font&gt;
have been hate
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;that man hated&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; well some people are like&lt;/font&gt;
that
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;the question is&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; well do you still&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; want&lt;/font&gt;
the house&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; are you offering it to us mr.&lt;/font&gt;
Carter&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; exactly why now&lt;/font&gt;
well that's mr. Butler's business isn't
you know we're not rich
most of us came here during the
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Depression but we love this&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; time&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it's&lt;/font&gt;
our home&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and naturally you want to&lt;/font&gt;
improve&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; exactly my client understands&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;adding fully sympathizes and he's&lt;/font&gt;
willing to sacrifice the house&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; for fifty&lt;/font&gt;
thousand dollars in cash by noon
tomorrow
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;that's an awful lot of cash&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;it's also an awfully good bargain&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;
could go to&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; wilton&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you could go now to&lt;/font&gt;
the bank
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;am i clearly understood all that cash&lt;/font&gt;
perfect&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i'll wait&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; for your answer till&lt;/font&gt;
tomorrow
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;you're spending the night here yes may I&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;ask where&lt;/font&gt;
and the&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; mother house&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;we could put you up at the motel as our&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;guest&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; known&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; house&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the paradise motel&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;that's very kind of you but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I'm meeting&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;mr.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; but about some personal items you&lt;/font&gt;
want phone&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I can reconnect the line&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; that&lt;/font&gt;
don't trouble no trouble&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you need a&lt;/font&gt;
phone
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;don't want to be stuck out there well&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;you convinced me&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;by the way have you known mr. Butler&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;long time now&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I've never met him he&lt;/font&gt;
called me and asked me if I'd handle
this for myself yes&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; they had the key&lt;/font&gt;
delivered to my office&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; the mayor sheriff&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;common Howard see&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you all tomorrow&lt;/font&gt;
in fact&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i'm i'm&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; looking forward to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;like really slick he's a big lawyer bill&lt;/font&gt;
you've got to expect that don't tell me
about lawyers&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you see the way he looked&lt;/font&gt;
at us&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; as&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; he's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; close&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; doing his job&lt;/font&gt;
just don't&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; tell me about lawyers&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;
know what I like to see&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; toward them like&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; when talking to each other&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; even&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; one&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;of the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; one know what to believe&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I love you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; too&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; honey&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; when&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i get home&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and&lt;/font&gt;
have a nice nice surprise for you
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;oh I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; can&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; tell you what is now&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I would&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; be&lt;/font&gt;
surprised&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i would it&lt;/font&gt;
no no I can't come home now but&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it'll be&lt;/font&gt;
very&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; soon very soon&lt;/font&gt;
quote me&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; of course&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; miss you as&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; best&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; missed&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; me too&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;lion&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; how I get&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;so God call tomorrow&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I want to call&lt;/font&gt;
and talk to&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Jenny&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; yeah well it's not a&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;fact i'm i i'm&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; having a fine time the&lt;/font&gt;
same to you darling&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; what do&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you mean&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;hospital&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I was wondering if we get it&lt;/font&gt;
what&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; then&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; write down okay okay I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; better&lt;/font&gt;
get going
do me a&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; favor test called&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; tell her&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;i'm going to Wilton and i'll be&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; back&lt;/font&gt;
late
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it's fantastic isn't it&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; yeah you know&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Butler wasn't&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; getting nobody's lived&lt;/font&gt;
here for years&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; would be such a&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;waste&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it's his grandfather's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; monument you know&lt;/font&gt;
the caretaker who keeps this place just
the way he left it
what kind of&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; more human disease well&lt;/font&gt;
that's the trouble
nobody remembers anymore that's what
usually happens in&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; America remember this&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;and he walks with me and he talks with&lt;/font&gt;
me and he tells me&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I'm&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; his own&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;walk with me and he&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;is here that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; holds&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; the funeral I was a&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;kid and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jeffrey Georgia is also Chipley&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Florida but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; they're both been&lt;/font&gt;
subsequently eradicated from the map
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;the only thing open water&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; delicatessen&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;brought&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the strong&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; salami&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; potato salad&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;it only everything you have&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;bologna and macaroni no no not&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; some of&lt;/font&gt;
that potato salad&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; to pick the wine to&lt;/font&gt;
the delicatessen&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; man took&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; a personal&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;interesting selection&lt;/font&gt;
oh well we got lucky again that's early
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;1970s that's hard to come by&lt;/font&gt;
can&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I have some&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; to course question&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;mm&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; thank you&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;must have been wonderful what the people&lt;/font&gt;
lived here&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; must&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; have had a wonderful&lt;/font&gt;
life
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;well I hope&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;mr. believe something&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that stone&lt;/font&gt;
fireplace
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;okay for this table and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you probably&lt;/font&gt;
think this place has made a world right
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;well wrong&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; told&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; them underneath&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;is&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; two feet of&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; start the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; foundation is&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;eight breaks&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; while someday they're gonna&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;come in here and the content&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; of space&lt;/font&gt;
down and they're&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; gonna build little&lt;/font&gt;
tract houses all over this property on
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;quarter&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; acre and half a glass and that&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;bulldoze is&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; gonna come up that hill&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;toward this house and it's gonna get the&lt;/font&gt;
surprise of its life
build&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; kingdom&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;nobody's left know what&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; his grand&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I be like&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the rest of us wants money you&lt;/font&gt;
know he's asking&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; $50,000 cash for this&lt;/font&gt;
place and&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the only when he got all&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; can&lt;/font&gt;
get at least 250,000&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; but he won't take&lt;/font&gt;
his time
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;so you'll get screwed&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;do you want to go upstairs know so you&lt;/font&gt;
know&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; one of the great pleasures in life&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;the pleasure of anticipating pleasure&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;we are very close now&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;very close&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I don't see anybody here&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; looking&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; for&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;understanding&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it's furnished&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;anything doing&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;no sir&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; but look at this&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; more football&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok smooth and&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; quarterback got&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; a&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; timeout&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;protest&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; about&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that telephone up at the&lt;/font&gt;
butler house&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; isn't working well&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; tripower&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;wait&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;hello&lt;/font&gt;
oh yes&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it's hard&lt;/font&gt;
yeah&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the phones working fine&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;nationally&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; God thank you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; honey&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I'm going&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;down the car to get some cigarettes&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; back&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;in a minute&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; okay I'll&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; get lonely&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;did you get your cigarettes yes yes and&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;it&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; happened but the most&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; amazing thing&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;these cigarettes coming but small&lt;/font&gt;
packages&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; these days&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;oh that's for me&lt;/font&gt;
can&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; opened up the order&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; our&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Christmas&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Day After Tomorrow didn't&lt;/font&gt;
yes&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; ma'am that's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; annoying&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;mmm&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;a bill that someone's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; calling from&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;butler house&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; come on go ahead&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; now mr. Carter who&lt;/font&gt;
is this&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Butler very&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; cherished daughter's&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;not&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; here&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;speak up like that here you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; what is it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;what's wrong&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;cars here but he's gone&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok ok ok you stay&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; put in that house and&lt;/font&gt;
wait for you&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; please&lt;/font&gt;
sorry&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i I'm not&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; right now take it easy&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;i'm coming&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; mr. Butler you done&lt;/font&gt;
what's that&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; would see&lt;/font&gt;
hello who is this
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;merry dance&lt;/font&gt;
it's all down
hello hello hello
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;my God where is everybody&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Oh Maggie&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; thank goodness&lt;/font&gt;
something's come up something urgent&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; can&lt;/font&gt;
you start early
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Maggie Daley you get yourself over here&lt;/font&gt;
just get moving&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Maggie&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; just please hurry&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;come in&lt;/font&gt;
it's open
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok mr.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that's far enough&lt;/font&gt;
what do you want here&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; where&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; try again my&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;father's not home and don't move&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;
want&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; to put my&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; answer&lt;/font&gt;
no just stay there
what are you staring at&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I seem to&lt;/font&gt;
remember you&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; rode that's why I'm holding&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;a gun&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; scare me that makes sense&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;thanks&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;is everybody&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; carry one here you can ask&lt;/font&gt;
the sheriff when he gets here&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I'll call&lt;/font&gt;
him
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I'm sorry to disappoint you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; sheriff's&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;office is empty&lt;/font&gt;
how do you know&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; was&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; just there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;who are you Geoffrey Butler&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; oh you're&lt;/font&gt;
the one&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; who's selling&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the house&lt;/font&gt;
yes have you any ID
come on&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; don't laugh at me&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i want your ID&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;so many&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; xscape for Margaretville&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;put it on the table&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I'll go back&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;california license&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; lucky you would you&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;like to see my maniac card from the&lt;/font&gt;
silent&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; they give you when&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you escaped&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;has a big&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; scar&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; of that monitor people&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;won't get confused&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;okay look&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I'm sorry about the guy my&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;others will getting&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; your money all&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;
want to do is to get into my house&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; shows&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;deputy might have a key&lt;/font&gt;
he's about the only&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; 1i know where she&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;you go down the road about a mile and a&lt;/font&gt;
half to come to&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; white house of the white&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;fence and that you can't miss it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;thanks&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; ok we're Christmas same to&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;you&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;if&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I don't call back in an hour&lt;/font&gt;
why call&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the mayor or mr. tone and&lt;/font&gt;
nobody else
promise me you'll do that&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; well sure&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;market down honey&lt;/font&gt;
so you'll have it&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; 30 1&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; i'm heading west&lt;/font&gt;
on Route five&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; about the house&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; hear&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;from me&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;what&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; help&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;the light out there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;alright&lt;/font&gt;
did&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you find the deputy&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; alright wasn't&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;there i was thinking isn't your lawyer&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;is supposed to be at the house doors&lt;/font&gt;
locked
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;this car was&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; there so I borrowed it&lt;/font&gt;
you mean you stole&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; a car yeah&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; keeping&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;warm&lt;/font&gt;
what if he needs it&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; wouldn't find me&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;who's coming to dinner&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Oh daddy we always have dinner every&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Thursday&lt;/font&gt;
do you want something no I&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; paradise&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;motel&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;yeah&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I know&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it's awful what about a&lt;/font&gt;
drink
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;yeah it's cheap bourbon but it's a big&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;favorite around here&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;july's now string&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;look tired&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; am&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;well here's to a fast dollar&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;why did you decide to sell the house&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;with&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; cash&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; after&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; all these years&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;what's it like on the inside&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; know&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I've never seen the inside&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; when&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I was a child my father told me to stay&lt;/font&gt;
away from it&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; or something terrible might&lt;/font&gt;
happen
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;sort of like a haunted house&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; obviously&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;you're going&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; to sell it you've seen it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;yeah too bad&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; spot&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the only place to see&lt;/font&gt;
around here
oh&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I forgot&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; someone keeps calling with a&lt;/font&gt;
message for my father
she says that she's waiting at your
house in the reception room
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;what was waiting&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; in my&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; reception I don't&lt;/font&gt;
know&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; instead of&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; ways that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I'm gonna go on can I come too&lt;/font&gt;
pushy
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; supposed to be going back to&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;California soon&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;california you said you live there&lt;/font&gt;
remember&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; problem&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Jeff look&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; is a sheriff's car&lt;/font&gt;
there's a light&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; look at that tombstone&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;pretty cheerful&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; who bears the crossbar&lt;/font&gt;
where the crime&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; will freak but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; they're&lt;/font&gt;
my grandfather
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;someone that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; their sunglasses in the&lt;/font&gt;
snow&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; there the show's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; my&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; lawyers missing&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;so&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; the sheriff you've&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; got strange phone&lt;/font&gt;
calls and now&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; someone's fascinated by my&lt;/font&gt;
grandfather's grave
let's get out of here&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; you still&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; want to&lt;/font&gt;
go to my house
yes but I don't want to go alone
listen&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I'm not&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; nervous&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; of course you're&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;so cold i'm shaking from it&lt;/font&gt;
let's get out of here&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; okay&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; we'll get&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;help in town&lt;/font&gt;
it's 10 minutes drive
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;right mr. Tollman have a nice holiday&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;mm-hmm&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;mmm&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;deputies not here but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Tillman is&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; whose&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;tell me come on you'll see&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;mr.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Tollman&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; wait no please I have to&lt;/font&gt;
talk to you&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i'm sorry&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; this is Geoffrey&lt;/font&gt;
Butler&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; is the one&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; who's selling the&lt;/font&gt;
house&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; he can't get inside the place and&lt;/font&gt;
my&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; father's gone to Wilden so we&lt;/font&gt;
wondered
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;environment to tell&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; us&lt;/font&gt;
test
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;has gone to his&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; house why would you go&lt;/font&gt;
there
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I don't know anyway she won't get in&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;
say it's locked
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it says&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; she hates the place would you&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;like to drive&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Diana&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; can stay here&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; locker so I need a&lt;/font&gt;
key
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;oh&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; man this isn't my house&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; its&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; test test&lt;/font&gt;
is&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; in the air is satisfied&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; must&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; have&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;gotten my place&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;why&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; would&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you go there&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; she hates it&lt;/font&gt;
maybe she went to see the woman is there
someone called the mayor's house before
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;essentially be waiting&lt;/font&gt;
what is it
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;hello Jeff&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;hello is anybody there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I'm&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; dying Adams i&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; spoke to you before&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;tire waiting&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;who ru hello hello&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;sheriff I saw your car&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;bill is that you&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; can't remember&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; face&lt;/font&gt;
you're&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; older&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; now&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and but still&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;test your you don't be&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; i won't help&lt;/font&gt;
build&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; take it&lt;/font&gt;
test
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;the person on the telephone said 1935&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;christmas eve but that's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; not the&lt;/font&gt;
beginning in&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; 1997 butler house was&lt;/font&gt;
restored by&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; wilfred&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; butler&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; after&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; that I&lt;/font&gt;
find social&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; nodes parties&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; nothing&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;special&lt;/font&gt;
then in nineteen thirty&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; lose why&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Katherine dies at tuberculosis in August&lt;/font&gt;
1933&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it starts&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Wilfred Butler's daughter&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;is cruelly attacked and raped her name&lt;/font&gt;
is&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Marianne&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the same name as the caller&lt;/font&gt;
who left those messages tonight&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; she's 15&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I'm a second 1934 Marianne&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Butler gives&lt;/font&gt;
birth to a son Geoffrey Butler
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;early in 1935&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; butler house is turned&lt;/font&gt;
over to a&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; doctor&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Robinson&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; as an asylum&lt;/font&gt;
for mental patients
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;and then&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Butler goes on to say that he&lt;/font&gt;
has committed his own daughter&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Marianne&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;will live at the asylum&lt;/font&gt;
there's no end to&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; the story it's been&lt;/font&gt;
carefully cut out of all the papers
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;why&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; would&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; telemon&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; do that&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;and&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;you scared me what happened what&lt;/font&gt;
happened this test has&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; 40 birdcages&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Tommen&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; is hysterical&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;everybody's in my hospital me it's cold&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;outside you put lock the door&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jay&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; how&lt;/font&gt;
old are you how old&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; am I we want&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; to use&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;it&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i lived&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you know there's a lot&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; in the&lt;/font&gt;
paper about&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; your family&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I don't talk&lt;/font&gt;
about myself
wait a minute&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; there's a woman calling&lt;/font&gt;
and she says her name is&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; Mary Ann that&lt;/font&gt;
was&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; your mother's name wasn't&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it&lt;/font&gt;
my&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; mother died in childbirth that's why&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I started&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; traveling&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it's not what the&lt;/font&gt;
papers here&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; what's your point&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I just&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; thought that you should read&lt;/font&gt;
something&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; for your own good&lt;/font&gt;
nothing you could tell me about my past
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;the future would&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; be for my own good&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;where's the baby&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; some table&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;so stupid&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; to lie&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; miss the whole event&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;yeah maybe your&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; mother&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; still alive&lt;/font&gt;
maybe she's waiting for you at the house
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I don't know&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;one more side trips&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;let's go out there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;it&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; isn't&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;joblo&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;my god&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; table back&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;he's dead&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;his hands&lt;/font&gt;
somebody cut off his hands
you killed him you killed&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; told me&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;is asking for&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; help&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;you killed him&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;come&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Yuki&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;we took them&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;no mister&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; man&lt;/font&gt;
yes what time and where&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; you&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; want your&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;cock&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I write&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; is knowing that no one shall&lt;/font&gt;
ever&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; seeds&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; not my beloved daughter or&lt;/font&gt;
even my grandson&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jeffrey I write for&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;myself in the hope of forgiveness&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; if&lt;/font&gt;
that is still possible and&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I right for&lt;/font&gt;
you
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Marianne whose youth and innocence i&lt;/font&gt;
have destroyed
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I 1935 the doctors have treated my&lt;/font&gt;
daughter for a year&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I had believed they&lt;/font&gt;
could cure&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; child&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jeffrey was taken from&lt;/font&gt;
us and sent&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; California&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;i turn&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; my house into an asylum&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I brought&lt;/font&gt;
doctors to live there and welcome to
other patients use&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I remembered what she had been there was&lt;/font&gt;
never a lovely have happier child
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;please I am I posed toast&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;doctor please I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Christmas&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; of the first&lt;/font&gt;
year&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; news i must act not for&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; myself&lt;/font&gt;
but for my&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; helpless child&lt;/font&gt;
this&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; institute&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; our friend&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I had no plan&lt;/font&gt;
or I knew what I must take her from
these men with&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; their promises and lies&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;for he's a jolly good fellow&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; new record themselves and was stupid&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;this afternoon&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it was their celebration&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;expected list since they had come into&lt;/font&gt;
my house they had acted as if they owned
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;had&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; behaved like poor relations&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; of&lt;/font&gt;
guilty&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; finally on a control&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; its&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;after dinner they danced and drank as&lt;/font&gt;
they usually did all the time
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;Robinson would smile reassure me&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; they&lt;/font&gt;
expect me to believe&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; because I had no&lt;/font&gt;
choice
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Wilfred&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; trust me you really believe Mary&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;Ann&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; would be well he saw a light&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;is a light at the end of a long&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; talk&lt;/font&gt;
there is a light at the end
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;stay here&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; doctor&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I'll&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; get&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; more champagne he was ready&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I&lt;/font&gt;
knew&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; it&lt;/font&gt;
drunk and fat and full of his own
importance&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; left&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;my cruelty into&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Marianne was&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; inhuman&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i&lt;/font&gt;
know&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; i had loved I had fathered her&lt;/font&gt;
child&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Jeffrey I brought it up his dry&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;swear that on&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that afternoon&lt;/font&gt;
all&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I wanted was&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; to save my child&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I hope was to get her away from that&lt;/font&gt;
house&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; also wanted to set free those&lt;/font&gt;
other reps who had so long been abused
by the doctors
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I knew what they might do these inmates&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;were freed and this is my guilt I knew&lt;/font&gt;
and still&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I freedom&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;after the inmates started for the house&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;i went to&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; get a car to take&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Mary anyway&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I do not know exactly when she slept&lt;/font&gt;
away from&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I assume that when they saw&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; dining room the inmates believed her&lt;/font&gt;
to be part of that household which they
hate it&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; and so they killed later there&lt;/font&gt;
was a celebration and then most of the
inmates fled&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; I don't know where I shall&lt;/font&gt;
never forget&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; what they did to my child&lt;/font&gt;
since that&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Christmas i have learned in&lt;/font&gt;
prisons in the&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; silence lived anonymously&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;as an animal i have wanted in&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; business&lt;/font&gt;
until&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; all seasons have become as one and&lt;/font&gt;
that is a&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; season of vengeance&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;yeah yeah weapon but&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; still alive&lt;/font&gt;
this is still his house
your grandfather died in&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; 1915 he was&lt;/font&gt;
burned to death in&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; his house&lt;/font&gt;
my&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; grandmother poured gasoline over&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;squad found here but Tom&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; wanted to&lt;/font&gt;
believe he was dead&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; they still do&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;this house was an aside&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; that was a&lt;/font&gt;
massacre by the inmates&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; test&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; omen&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; the&lt;/font&gt;
sheriff&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; your father&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; know&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; all inmates&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;they killed&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; my mother in this room&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;ok&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;who's back&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;who's there&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;yeah yeah&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;no oh&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; why&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;area&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;please&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;I spent that night weeping by morning&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;there were&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; no&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; more tears&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt;I know&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; that my father&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; and Jeffrey both&lt;/font&gt;
thought they were shooting&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; it killers&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;but there was simply the last victims in&lt;/font&gt;
that house of victims
now a year later&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; they will tear down&lt;/font&gt;
Wilfred&lt;font color="#CCCCCC"&gt; Butler's&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt; monument but they can&lt;/font&gt;
never destroy
&lt;font color="#E5E5E5"&gt;what happened here&lt;/font&gt;