Hey...
Maybe you have to let it hurt.
- What?
- We've got to get going.
- What time is it?
- I don't know.
Erik?
Erik, come let me show you...
- Good morning.
Does anybody want eggs?
- ... daily average for an adult...
- Will you please finish eating?
- I'm not done reading. Thank you.
- Stop it.
I want them soft boiled.
"On a pipe..."
Dad, what is that? That one.
- What?
- What is "on a pipe"?
- Do you have to read out loud?
- Ten teaspoons of added sugar.
- For the average...
- Read quietly, if you have to read.
- The body needs energy...
- Thank you.
Please...
- Can you tell him?
- Eat up, so we can get going.
- Has anyone seen my gloves?
- Did you check on the shelf?
One second...
- Who put them here?
- I'll answer.
Don't. It's probably just Grandma.
Go to the car.
- Hurry up.
- Yeah, relax.
- Do you have the present?
- What? No!
- Jonas!
- What would you do without me?
Rock, scissors, paper.
Best of three.
- Come on, best of five!
- Okay, best of five.
Quit stalling. Get in the car!
Rock, scissors, paper...
- Let's go.
- Loser.
Shut up.
Take this.
- Can't you handle some music?
- No, not right now. Turn it off.
Did you hear that, Dad?
He can't handle some music.
But you can, right? You and me
are real men, unlike Jonas.
- Take it easy.
- You're full of smack.
Tell him to stop.
- Jonas can't handle some music.
- Shut up.
- You are so juvenile.
- Really?
Yes.
- Anyone voting against it?
- I do.
- Dad?
- What?
When you sit up front,
you control the radio, right?
- Yeah, but not all the time.
- Well, I think so anyway.
NINE MONTHS LATER
Jonas?
Hello? Hello?
Dad, we need to buy groceries.
Dad. Dad?
Dad? Dad!
Dad!
- Would you like one?
- No, I don't want any.
- And how did this happen?
- Well, I...
I really don't know.
Let me check your pupils.
I'm not actually sick.
Right. Try to rest a bit.
I'll be back in a while.
- Jonas. Jonas?
- What?
Are you sure
you don't want your pajamas?
No, that's okay, Grandma.
- We can stop by and pick them up.
- We'll pick up his things tomorrow.
You try to get some sleep now.
I read in your file that
you are an eye doctor.
How long
have you worked at St. Erik's?
Since 1995.
And you prescribed Citalopram
and Benzo for yourself?
Things kind of got to me...
Of course, you know to be careful
when mixing those two medicines.
The combination
can have an undesired effect.
- Can I sign you out today?
- Sure.
I recommend you take it easy.
Let yourself rest.
Get a change of scenery, take
a trip, visit your summer house?
Okay.
Take care of yourself.
- Have some more gravy.
- I've already taken some.
It's fine. This was delicious.
Really delicious.
We have apple pie
with vanilla sauce for dessert.
Oops.
Lasse! Come on in.
So, you're already up on your feet.
- Is Jonas awake?
- No. He's sleeping.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Pack your stuff, we're leaving.
Is that really wise?
I mean, in your condition.
Let's have coffee and discuss this.
That's very kind of you,
but we have a ferry to catch.
- Ingegerd, make some coffee.
- Tea's almost ready.
I appreciate your concern, Sven.
But I don't want to discuss this.
Jonas can stay with us
as long as necessary.
- I'm not here to discuss.
- So you can rest.
- Jonas. Get ready.
- Don't be unreasonable.
Jonas, get ready.
Here's the tea.
Is that Jonas?
I didn't recognize you.
You've grown.
Yes.
- Hello, Lasse!
- Hi, Lage.
- Welcome!
- Thanks.
- You want help with the bags?
- No, we're fine.
- Are you sure? I have a cart.
- No, no.
- Okay, we'll see you later. Bye.
- Bye.
- What's the matter?
- What?
Do you have everything?
There's clean sheets downstairs.
Okay.
Okay, good. Good.
Good.
Take the vacuum upstairs.
It's amazing how fast it gets dirty.
You should have seen the
dust bunnies behind the stove.
My, my...
Thanks for dinner.
That's it? You've barely tasted it!
I wasn't really that hungry.
We'll go shopping tomorrow, right?
What a morning.
- What are you doing?
- I'm going to fix the rowboat.
Do you know how to do that?
It just needs some scraping.
And a little paint.
Uh-huh...
Wouldn't that be fun?
Fixing the boat?
No. To go sailing. Or fishing.
- Wake up!
- Huh?
You could have
burned down the whole house!
What time is it?
- What are you reading?
- The Phantom.
Is it any good?
Mmm...
"The ghost who walks."At times
he travels like an ordinary man."
Didn't he have a dog?
Mmm... Devil.
Devil is a wolf.
That's right. Devil.
What a name for a dog.
Don't stay up too late reading.
Well, damn it.
I know I have one left.
- I'll have to look in the back again.
- Thanks.
Hey there, Doc!
- Well, hi!
- I had no idea you were here.
Yeah, we came... the other day.
I see. Is Jonas with you, too?
- Yes.
- Great!
Then he can play with Axel.
Well, not "play," but...
- I knew I had one left.
- Great.
Just remember one thing...
You need to scrape
all the crap off the boat first.
- He doesn't know this stuff.
- He does now!
Be thorough.
Make sure it's all gone.
Now he knows how to do it.
- Thanks.
- Hello.
Hello.
They arrived the other day.
Midsummer? Why don't you come
over and we'll do something?
Yeah, thanks.
- Are we having a barbecue?
- Yeah.
Yes, I'll go see if I can...
But...
- They've only got pork chops.
- I'll be right there.
We'll see you
on Midsummer's Eve.
Do you always swim
with your shirt on?
What?
Damn, it's so beautiful.
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
I thought I was the only one
who knew about this spot.
Oh...
God, this is so nice.
How old are you?
Seventeen.
So you're a junior this fall?
No, sophomore.
I kind of fell behind.
I see...
My friend had to repeat a grade.
She got meningitis or something.
Talk about bad luck.
- Damn it! Do you have a watch?
- No.
I have to work. Damn.
- Helena.
- Lena?
Helena. With an H.
Ah. Jonas, with a J.
Okay, Jonas with a J.
With a J.
See you.
"Hello. Jonas with a J."
Jonas with a J...
I'm such an idiot.
What did you do today?
What? Oh, nothing special.
Oh, I ran into Simon. Axel is here.
He'd like you to come over.
Okay.
About the other day...
Can't we try and make
the most of this summer?
Hello!
Hi!
You like fish?
Yeah. Thanks.
Good, isn't it?
Yeah.
- You're here with your dad, right?
- Yeah.
I'm renting a shack from my boss.
- But it's not that bad.
- Helena! The cash register!
- I'm on my lunch break!
- You can have it later.
- Helena!
- Yes, all right!
Want to go swimming some day?
- Yeah, sure.
- Cool.
- I thought you quit?
- No. Oh, hi!
I didn't hear you arrive.
- It's looking great.
- Yeah.
Would you like something?
- Cold drink, coffee?
- No.
- A beer?
- No, I'm fine.
- I'm not interrupting, am I?
- No.
It was really unexpected
to meet you the other day.
- I didn't know you were coming.
- No...
I hope you didn't think
I acted strangely.
- I don't know what got into me.
- No, that's okay.
- Jonas has gotten so big.
- Yes.
How's it going?
It was difficult at first, but I'm
getting the hang of it now.
No, I mean for you and Jonas.
Oh, that's just fine.
If you want to talk...
- Okay...
- Okay.
Simon is waiting.
- See you on Midsummer's.
- Yes.
- Say hi for me.
- I will.
Hold your breath, and feel the
tension in your hand and chest.
Feel the tension...
And breathe out,
relaxing your left hand completely
and the rest of your body.
Feel the pleasant contrast
of your body
relaxing and getting heavy.
Uh...
ERIK
MOTHER
- Hello.
- Hi!
- Have you been waiting long?
- No, I just got here.
Okay.
Come on!
It's really cold! Come on!
Yeah, I'm coming.
Okay...
Last one to that cliff is a... wimp.
Stop it!
Help!
- I let you win, you know!
- Yeah, right.
- Does it hurt?
- What?
- The knee.
- No. Sometimes.
Well, you swim like a fish.
I remember...
When I broke my arm I had to
wear a plastic bag over the cast.
I'd swim around with this
huge bag. I looked so stupid.
Hey...
Didn't you have a brother?
- I'm sorry. I didn't mean to pry.
- It's all right.
That's so like me.
I just say stuff without thinking.
He died in a car accident.
Maybe you already knew that.
No... Jonas.
Jonas, wait!
What's the matter?
What are you doing?
- I'm packing up.
- Stop it and listen to me!
We have to be able to
talk to each other, Jonas.
- I want to leave. I hate this place!
- I don't care.
Wait!
Jonas!
- Bye.
Are you going somewhere?
Going somewhere?
No...
About last time... I'm really sorry.
I mean... I apologize.
- Do you want some help?
- No, it's fine.
We used to rent a cottage here
when I was little.
I don't remember where, but...
My Mom used to say
that I took my first steps here.
I see...
You should have seen me then.
I was the world's chubbiest baby.
I was so fat they had to cut my
underwear around the legs
because my thighs were so fat.
- Hard to believe now, isn't it?
- Yeah.
I'll get it.
Hello, this is Jonas.
Hi!
- Playing backgammon with Dad.
- Who is it?
Nothing special.
I see...
Okay.
Okay, I will.
Good. Bye, bye.
- Who was that?
- That was Grandma.
They're coming tomorrow
on the ferry at 11.
Grandma said they're
bringing their own bed linen.
- Hi...
- Hi, Grandma.
- Hi, Grandpa!
- Hi...
Hello, welcome.
Happy Midsummer!
Thank you.
- Welcome.
- Thank you, Lars.
- We haven't inconvenienced you?
- Don't be silly.
We called,
but you never answered.
Jonas, grab Grandpa's bag.
- Have you been baking, Lasse?
- Yes, indeed.
- Sit down.
- Thanks.
I forgot the coffee!
- What have you two been doing?
- Nothing much.
Have you played with those boys?
Whatever they were called?
The ones on the cape.
- Kihlbom?
- That's right.
- No.
- Okay...
I have to ask you
to run down to Karlsson's store.
- Do I have to?
- There's no sour cream.
What do you think
Grandpa would say?
Herring without sour cream
for Midsummer's Eve?
There's still some work to do.
I'm gonna put a little varnish on it...
You need to tar it.
The hull. Plenty of tar
and it will float wonderfully.
Yes.
- Tar.
- Yes.
Thank you, that's enough.
Lars?
No, thanks. I'm good.
You can't celebrate Midsummer's
Eve without a schnapps.
- Maybe he doesn't want any.
- Of course he does, don't be silly.
It's Midsummer, everyone
wants schnapps. Right, Lars?
Of course. Thanks.
Midsummer without schnapps?
Well, I never...
Finally,
something to wet the whistle.
I have a bad headache
My eyes are stinging
Tummy is rumbling
The night is stumbling
And down the throat it goes
Moonshine, a drop or so
Praises to our spirits
Praise now our spirits
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
Damn, that's good.
That was beautiful, Grandpa.
- And one more time.
- Yes, indeed.
Erik hated herring.
To him, herring and potatoes
was the worst.
Mom always had to make sausage
for him. Remember that, Dad?
See the star in the blue?
Take a sip and you'll see two!
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- I look nice, right?
- Yeah.
- Are you here on your own?
- No.
"The little frogs..."
Hey.
Want to forget about this?
Come!
- There you are.
- Thanks.
- Cheers!
- Cheers.
Happy Midsummer.
- Shall we dance?
- Absolutely!
- Have you seen Jonas?
- Yes, he left with a girl.
Whoa!
Cut it out! Excuse me...
Sorry...
Nice.
- Hey?
- Yeah?
Do you believe in God?
That we go to heaven
when we die?
I don't know.
Maybe.
When I think about it,
I want to believe, but...
I don't know.
I believe in one God,
the Father Almighty!
Creator of Heaven and Earth!
- Are you confirmed?
- Yes.
I got a watch and a gift certificate
for a hardware store.
- Cool.
- Well, not really...
I am quite confirmed, too.
It shows, doesn't it?
- Do something!
- Lars!
Come on, Doc.
Time to go home.
- Come on.
- You are boring. So boring.
- Lasse...
- So boring...
Yes, I know.
I love you.
which would be... typical.
- This is where I live.
- Oh.
- Nice, isn't it?
- Yeah...
Bye! See you.
Yeah. Bye.
Jonas?
Come, sit down.
Well...
Grandma and I think you
should come with us tomorrow.
We feel it would be
better for everyone...
if you move in with us for a while.
I understand if you don't agree.
But we think it's best for you
and for your father's well-being.
This can't go on. Your father
isn't well. He needs help.
Go to bed now.
We're getting up early
in the morning.
Morning!
- Good morning.
- Anyone want some coffee?
- I'll make the coffee.
Not a problem.
Are you leaving so soon?
Aren't we taking a walk?
Lars...
Don't take this the wrong way,
but we have to talk.
Am I the only one eating now?
You need help.
Professional help, Lars.
Someone got up
on the wrong side of the bed.
We feel that
Jonas should come home with us.
It will give you time to rest
in peace and quiet.
Is that yours, Jonas?
Don't you see? You can't take
care of yourself or anyone else.
If I was still practicing medicine,
I'd commit you immediately.
- All right...
- Does anyone want some coffee?
We've already spoken with Jonas.
He'll gladly come with us.
Wait a minute...
Is that true, Jonas? Huh?
Jonas! Answer me, dammit!
- Leave him alone!
- Don't yell like that.
Listen, Sven...
You've never listened to
another person your whole life.
You only see and hear
exactly what you already know.
- The boy needs security.
- He needs his father.
He shouldn't need
to worry that...
you'll burn down the house
or slit your wrists.
Stop it, Sven.
Or overdose in a pathetic attempt
to numb your own self-pity.
And what good is it
to split up this family again?
Haven't we endured enough pain?
- The boy needs to rely on his dad.
- But he does!
We only want
what's best for the boy.
Let me tell you something, Sven.
I am Jonas' guardian.
I decide in this house.
No outsider is going to come here
and try to run my life
or Jonas' life! Is that clear?
We'll see about that.
- Are you threatening me?
- We both know how the law works.
The child's welfare comes first!
Stop it!
- Promise you'll call every day?
- I promise.
Take care of yourself.
Hello?
Hi!
Hi. I knocked, but no one...
I didn't even know there was a piano.
- You want coffee?
- No, thanks. I'm good.
Good, I didn't have any anyway.
Have you been playing long?
No, just for a few minutes.
- I didn't mean just now.
- Oh.
No. For a while.
I played a flute
in third grade, or something.
All that came out of it
was a lot of squeaking.
It was my mom
who taught me to play.
Was she talented?
Yes, she was.
You miss her, don't you?
Jonas?
- Wait, I'll check. Have you got it?
- Yes.
- Okay, let it down.
- Easy.
That's a damn leaky hulk...
Yes, yes...
- Smoke?
- No, thanks.
I was just saying that...
When you were expecting Jonas,
how happy we were for you.
And jealous, remember that?
You...
never really
think anything could happen.
I know I'm a prankster...
I've always been
the clown of the class.
But that's how I handle
my anxiety, my demons.
You have to find your way, Lasse.
This can't go on. It won't work.
You have to find a way
to move on.
Well!
What a crappy boat.
That's what it is.
Good luck with the rowboat!
Hi!
I brought lunch.
I've lost all feeling in my fingers.
Shit...
The palm of my hand
is completely numb.
You never think it'll happen to you.
You read it in the paper
and flip past it.
But I didn't stand a chance.
I know.
When my parents divorced,
I thought it was my fault.
That I had ruined it all.
I've forgotten my mom's cell-phone number.
I used to know it by heart,
but I can't remember it any more.
What do you remember?
I remember that Dad was driving.
We were on the way to
visit Grandma and Grandpa.
It was really cold that day.
Erik and I were fighting, as usual.
What did you fight about?
Who would get to ride shotgun.
I said it was my turn
on the way home when we...
when we crashed.
If I had been up front,
everything would have been...
Would have been what?
- Erik would have survived.
- But you would have died.
I should have won.
I always won.
You haven't told
this to anyone, have you?
No.
Not even your dad?
We don't talk to each other.
Not at all?
Not about this.
Why not?
You don't know my dad.
He wouldn't understand.
How can you know that
if you haven't even tried?
What do you want from me? Really?
Why do you ask so many questions?
Because I care about you.
That's bullshit, and you know it.
You just pity me!
- No, I don't!
- I can see how you look at me!
How everyone looks at me.
But nobody dares to say anything.
Jonas? Jonas!
Jonas!
- You sailed from Marstrand today?
- Yes, indeed.
I set the GPS and just...
- Hi.
Hi.
Well, hell! So you're upright today?
I'm sorry. Let me introduce you.
This is Lasse. These are
my friends Henrik and Karin.
And there's Lasse,
sitting there like a buffoon.
Huh?
He's about to give the wedding toast,
and he's sitting with
steak, gravy, and potatoes
all over his tuxedo.
Huh?
But cheers anyway.
Cheers.
I bet Simon didn't behave
any better at your wedding.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Everyone stares at me
when I'm in the store...
I smell their damned clothes
every single damned day!
Sorry...
Time doesn't heal all wounds.
That's just the way it is. Sorry.
I'll take care of it.
- You get the little one.
- Thanks.
A toast. To all the idiots...
May they rot in hell.
- Cheers.
That's tasty...
Especially with the bits of cork.
- Come!
- Where are we going?
Come.
- Your turn.
- You must be joking.
Yes!
Bravo.
That was nice, wasn't it?
Yeah, that was damn nice.
Help!
- Been swimming?
- No, no.
- He can't swim.
- Who?
Gunnarson. He can't swim.
A fisherman who can't swim...
- Dad?
- I guess he never learned.
Why don't we ever talk about Mom and Erik?
- What? We do, don't we?
- No.
We talk about them all the time.
No, we don't.
You never say Mom or mentions Erik's name.
It's as if they never existed.
Why did you do that, Dad?
Did what?
Jonas, it's...
It's hard to explain.
What did you think
would happen to me?
Did that cross your mind?
Please. Please, Jonas.
You don't understand.
You are a coward.
You only think about yourself.
How old was your brother?
Eleven. Almost twelve.
Did you get along well?
Yeah, sometimes.
No, actually. We fought all the time.
Weird how you can fight over nothing.
That's exactly what people fight over.
Nothing.
I wish I'd had someone
to fight with sometimes.
- Does that help?
- Yes, I think it does.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
I've always loved this house.
It's so still and quiet here.
And the sea...
No neighbors to stick their noses
in your business.
How are you and Simon
doing, really?
You know Simon. He can't
talk about anything of importance.
And he's a terrible dancer.
Well...
You can't blame yourself
for what happened.
It wasn't anyone's fault.
You know that.
Yeah, but Jonas thinks it is.
Stop blaming yourself.
That leads nowhere.
- I think he hates me.
- He doesn't hate you.
- He says he hates me.
- He says it, but he doesn't mean it.
He hates what happened, not you.
During the first World War, when
the men lay in their bunkers...
nearly all of them became
religious and prayed for survival.
Sometimes, I think that...
That it...
I think that maybe
it would help, sometimes.
I don't understand
a God damn thing of all this.
It's very, very empty.
That's the way it is.
Are you sad now?
I can't help it.
- What are you afraid of?
- I'm not afraid.
Come on, Jonas.
I can tell from looking at you.
You're about to fall apart.
- It's not so fucking easy.
- Who said it was supposed to be?
- You don't get it anyway.
- No...
Just that you feel like shit.
And that you aren't
doing anything about it.
You're a coward, Jonas.
Just like your Dad.
Go to hell! You don't know how
I feel! Nobody knows how I feel!
You don't know what it's like
to watch your little brother die.
You don't know what
it's like to lose your mom.
You don't know a damn thing.
Hey...
Maybe you have to let it hurt...
Here!
Want to hear a really great song?
Yeah, sure.
Have you heard this one?
- Loverboy!
- What?
Come on!
- I can't.
- This is nothing. Get a grip.
Come on!
- Come!
- Here?
- Yes!
- No, no... I can't even dance.
Stop! No excuses. Up with you!
Okay, stand here.
And move a little like this.
Dance! Do what you want!
You're driving me crazy!
- I can't...
- Get a grip! Shush!
Come on!
Where you can play football,
swim, and barbecue.
We remind you
that this is a smoke-free cabin.
If you'd like to smoke,
please go outside the cabin.
Please go out mid-air, that
makes it difficult to get there.
First mate Jonas wants to note
the emergency exits in the front,
in the back, and over the wings.
Back to you.
For lunch today we'll have
mashed potatoes, meatballs,
and some vegetables.
Shit...
Is that okay? We have a menu...
Dad!
where you
can buy some snacks.
Like sandwiches made by first mate Jonas.
Axel, come here.
- What's the matter, Mom?
- Come here...
Ouch, damn it!
Ow...
What happened?
- Let me see.
- I don't know.
But what happened...
Hi.
Ow! Damn it!
- Fuck...
- Lasse?
- Are you out of your mind?
- Shut the fuck up.
- Are you all right, Lasse?
- It hurts.
I've tried to talk to you
for 15 years, Simon.
But you can't.
You don't know how.
You just sweep
everything under the rug.
I needed someone...
who can touch me.
I need someone to talk with.
Can you understand that?
Every time a...
a patient...
asks the doctor how things are...
you're supposed to say
"One day at a time."
"One day at a time, Mrs. Larsson."
One more day...
And so this is what I think...
"Now, today will be a good day."
"I have to look ahead."
But I can't.
I can't do it.
I don't know how to do that.
Hey...
Explain it to me.
Please. Please, explain it
What's wrong? Jonas, listen!
What have I done wrong?
Tell me! What have I done wrong?
What did I do wrong?
Everything is your fault!
It's your fault Mom and Erik died!
What?
- Calm down!
- It's your fault I'm a cripple!
- I hate you!
- No!
- Yes!
- Jonas can't handle some music.
- You are so juvenile.
It's your fault!
What have I done wrong?
Rock, paper, scissors...
It wasn't my fault.
Dad!
It wasn't anyone's fault.
Jonas...
I love you.
I love you, too.
Come here...
There, there...
- Hi.
You forgot this.
Right, thanks.
- You take care, now.
- You too.
- See you.
- Yeah.
- Have you got everything?
- Yes.