I'm afraid you come too late, doctor.
Yeah?
We'll see .. we'll see.
The mother is dead.
I think I can save the baby.
Come along, I'll need your help.
I'll need some hot water right away.
Doctors shouldn't go
against the will of God.
Pray we should die too.
- No, no.
She is a pretty baby, Karl.
Your sister, she was pretty too.
And what did it bring her, but disgrace.
I tell him now.
Better the baby die too, maybe?
The mother, she didn't
have a wedding ring.
It's my business to save lives.
Helga.
Get to work there.
Helga .. pull off my boot.
Helga .. come here.
Helga.
You're going to marry Jeb Mondstrum.
I say you are ..
- But she don't hardly know him, Karl.
She had plenty time to get acquainted.
You're not going the way of your mother.
You start out just like her.
Reading novels.
Getting crazy notions in your head.
It ain't going to happen
in my family twice.
But, Karl.
- No.
What's in the blood is there.
No-one can change it.
When I see you married
with a wedding ring ..
Then I have done my duty.
You can't go out in this storm yet.
Better stay here.
Make yourself at home.
Ah, goodnight.
- Night.
Goodnight.
No.
You know .. you are a pretty girl.
Helga, you're as good as mine already.
Let me go.
Quiet, Major.
You're a girl, aren't you?
Yes.
What ..?
How did you ..?
Come on out.
Please let me stay here.
I won't make any trouble.
What's the idea? You can't stay in here.
Come out, I tell you.
But your dog will bite me.
Nonsense. Major doesn't bite girls.
Come on.
Say, hurry up will you.
It happens to be raining out here.
Where are we going?
Where?
Inside.
House.
You know: house.
Doors, windows, roof.
House.
I think I'd better not.
You're not afraid of a house, are you?
Alright. Stay here then.
Wait a minute.
Alright. I'll go with you.
Alright. Come on.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Hey, don't kid me.
You'd better take off your clothes.
No.
Oh, I didn't mean it that way.
I .. I mean you'd better
change your clothes.
You're soaking wet.
I'll get you something dry to put on.
I won't be a minute. Just get
warm there by the fire.
Here we are.
Say, what?
Here.
You can wear these.
Thank you.
Pants.
Yes. Of course.
I haven't worn petticoats for years.
You had ..
You'd better go in here and ..
Change.
Just throw out your wet clothes
and I'll hang them up to dry.
Well.
Say.
Who are you anyway?
Uhoh.
Never mind. Never mind.
We won't talk about you at all.
No, sir.
You know what we'll do?
We'll talk about me.
You know who I am?
No? Well, I'll tell you.
I'm Rodney. Mr Spencer's little boy.
I'm thirty, white and unmarried.
I'm really a very fine fellow.
Never unkind to animals
or kicked babies in the teeth.
Always courteous when drunk.
This is my old man's cabin.
He wanted me to be a lawyer.
So, obedient to his every word
I took a course in engineering.
Opportunity came to me in the guise of
a bridge to be constructed in Detroit.
A competition open to all.
I'm here now, working on my model.
After I win the competition I hope
to go on and on and on and ..
Carve a great career for myself.
Will you have cream or
sugar in your coffee?
Yes.
Alright.
There you are.
One?
Caviar?
Is that ..
To eat?
Sure.
Well.
It looks like ..
Like buckshot.
Well it isn't. It's fish eggs.
You know. Fish.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
We'll have to have a little port.
To warm us up.
Skol.
Here we go.
You poor kid.
You're all in, aren't you.
You'd better stay here
and get some sleep.
It's alright.
I'll take you home in the morning.
Well.
I had better go now.
Now listen. You're not going
out in that storm again.
No, sir.
You're going to stay here.
Look. This is my room.
You can sleep in there.
It's alright. I'll sleep out here.
See.
There you are.
Well.
Goodnight.
What are you thinking about?
I was just thinking how nice you are.
Okay. Goodnight.
Alright. Alright.
Hiya, Major. Hi, boy.
How are you, boy?
Well, good morning.
Good morning.
What are you doing?
Getting your breakfast.
What?
Getting my breakfast?
I should say not.
If there's any waiting-on to be done
around here, I'll do the waiting.
You sit down there.
You don't know what a good cook I am.
I'll take care of this thing.
What happened?
- I burnt myself.
Wait a minute.
Here.
This will fix it.
See.
It doesn't hurt now, does it?
No.
It doesn't hurt now.
Well.
It's morning. I ..
I guess I'd better be going soon.
It's much safer to travel at night.
Come on.
Stick around here with me today.
We'll just forget about everything.
We'll have a lot of fun.
Huh?
Ah, sure you will.
Tell you what we'll do.
We'll go fishing.
Have you ever been fishing?
- No.
What?
Say, you don't know what you've missed.
There's the grandest little spot
right down here with fish like ..
And do they bite?
Oh, come on.
Say you'll stay.
Will you?
Well.
Of course you will.
I don't know.
Don't shake it around like that.
You'll never catch one that way.
Hold it still.
Hey.
I've got a bite.
Alright, haul it in.
Where did he go?
Up in that tree.
Where?
- Here, here.
I'll get him for you.
Here.
Quiet, Major.
My fish.
You exaggerate.
- Let me hold him.
Wait a minute.
I'll get him off the hook for you.
Let me hold him.
Here you are.
He's gone. Where is he?
Here he is. Here he is.
There he is.
- Yes.
Little fish.
I'm going to cook him
for your supper tonight.
Hey, hurry up. We haven't much time.
Coming.
Did you bring my shaving things?
Come on.
Now the brush.
And the soap.
Did you bring the soap?
Soap?
You don't expect me to shave
without soap, do you?
You mean 'soap'?
Give me that soap.
Come on now. Give me that soap.
Hey, quit stalling. You'll
make me miss my train.
Give me that soap.
Now I've got you.
You bad girl.
Are you going to be good?
Are you?
Huh?
Yes.
Do you call that being good?
Huh?
Gee, I don't want to go, darling.
But I have to.
These drawings have to be in.
The competition closes in three days.
You understand that? Don't you?
And after all.
Six days isn't long to wait.
Is it?
No.
Not very.
Alright.
Come now, and help me finish packing.
You forgot these.
Oh yes.
You want these with you, don't you?
Sure.
Say.
Your father and mother.
Do you think they will like me?
Like you?
I should say they will.
I never had a picture of my mother.
I guess she never had one taken.
Just like.
Like she never had a ring.
Oh, Rodney.
I know now. It was untrue all the
things my uncle said about her.
About her not being good
because she didn't have a ring.
But you're going to have a ring, Helga.
I'm bringing one back with me.
Everything alright now?
Yes.
Say, I got to go.
Sure. But I'll be back
before you know it.
Yep.
You take good care of
yourself while I'm gone.
Eat lots.
Get plenty of good sleep.
Don't set fire to the house.
And don't take any wooden nickels.
Alright. Now we're ready. Come on.
Say, you forgot your bridge.
Yeah, the bridge. The most important
thing of all. Can you bring it?
Yes.
- Alright.
This is as far as you'd
better go, darling.
Goodbye.
Be good. It won't be long.
Goodbye, Major. Bye-bye boy.
Bye-bye, dear.
- Bye.
Come along, Major.
You're going back with us.
No.
I say you are.
No, no.
You're going back now.
Come with me.
- No.
Did you hear me? You're going back now.
I don't want to.
All aboard.
Say, shut that door.
I was trying to get out.
With the train going
thirty miles an hour?
Give me a cigarette.
And a match. And a match.
Come on, come on. What are you doing?
I'm out.
- I'm out.
Four more.
Yeah? Here's your four, and four better.
Come again.
- Yeah?
I'll just tap you.
What have you got?
- Four bones of fire.
That's good.
- I'll say it's good.
Hey Suzie, come here a minute.
Stick around. You brought me luck.
That's the best hand I've had
since Sitting Bull sat down.
Sit down.
It's alright kid, sit down.
What's your name, kid?
Never mind. Meet the joint.
Hello.
Hello, Frenchy.
- Hello, Coco.
Hello, Burly.
- Hiya, Burly.
Hello Eva.
- Hello, Burly.
Who's winning?
For a change.
Yeah?
Who are you?
This is Suzie.
Suzie?
- Yes.
Miss ..
Miss Lenox of Lenoxville.
She caught this train by mistake.
You can get off at the next stop.
How much does it cost to go to Detroit?
Thirty-three berries.
You broke, kid?
I understand. I ran away once myself.
Give me two.
Say, Burly.
- Huh?
You know the beauty that ditched Alf
this afternoon and married a bootlegger?
Why don't you let Suzie take her place?
I never thought of that.
Stand up. Let me see what you look like.
Not bad.
- Not bad? She's okay.
Think she'll work alright?
- Sure.
Alright, Pansy. Have the
wardrobe woman fix her up.
Uhoh, uncle. Come back with the ante.
I guess you got some that way once.
- You can never tell.
Hi, Suzie.
- Hello.
Where you been?
- To post something.
Oh?
I suppose you mailed
another letter to that guy?
Yes.
I told him I'll meet him at Marquette.
What makes you think he'll be there?
He'll be there.
Suzie.
Come here a minute, will you.
I want to talk to you.
Suzie.
Do you happen to know a
man by the name of ..
Jeb Mondstrum or Mardstrum?
No.
Okay.
Now don't worry, Suzie. I ..
I told him there wasn't anyone around
here who answered your description.
You had better not show today.
Just keep under cover until
we pull out of town tonight.
The ..
The Sheriff told me they're
watching all the outgoing trains.
Now, I can't stop them.
But I don't think they'll
search my private compartment.
So we'll fool them. You be
there when we leave tonight.
Oh, hello Sheriff.
Have any luck? Did you find her?
No, but we ain't finished
with them beauties yet.
Did you try looking in the wagon car?
We'll look alright.
Good luck.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
Right up this way folks,
for the dancing girls.
The show starts right away, folks.
Next, I present for your
approval, Major Crumb.
One of the strongest
people in the world.
Would you believe that when he was only
18 years old he was over six feet tall.
But later in life he got
married and settled down.
Just over here, the ladies from Arabia.
And then, from Arabia,
the tattooed lady.
Why, folks.
One tour of this little lady's anatomy
brings before your very eyes ..
Some of the most marvellous
features of the world.
For instance, on this limb here ..
We have the Eiffel Tower.
Get at eyeful of that and you
don't have to go to Paris.
On this limb right here we
have the Leaning Tower of Pisa.
Make it lean, madam.
I said lean, not fall.
Across the little lady's back.
We have a panoramic representation
of the Statue of Liberty.
But here's one statue you
cannot take liberties with.
Look at, but do not touch.
Across the little lady's torso.
I said, across her torso.
We find the Atlantic Fleet.
In action.
What's that? Show you Chicago?
Listen, brother. This is an
exhibition, not a Cook's tour.
That will be all, madam.
Now on the next platform here.
Right this way folks, can I draw
your special attention to this ..
Platform right here which has
the beauties of all nations.
Right here, folks.
On your toes, you canaries.
First I present for your approval.
Miss Hula from Bermuda.
From the sandy beaches of Waikiki.
Bombay Beulah from India.
Well?
If you don't like it, what do
you keep on looking for?
I'm sorry.
But they told me I
could find Miss .. Miss ..
You ain't ..?
- My name is Spencer.
Rodney Spencer.
I'm pleased to meet you, Mr Spencer.
My name is Madame Panoramia.
They call me 'Pansy' for short.
How do you do.
She may be a little dark, boys. But she
will be a bright spot in your memories.
Now folks.
For the sensation of all sensations.
And last but not least the
attraction of all attractions.
I wish to present for your approval.
The Belle Zedema.
The favorite of the Sultan of Turkey.
But she escaped and
his loss is your gain.
If he finds her I shudder to
think of the consequences.
For when she dances, every muscle ..
Every fibre in this
little lady's body ..
Sends out high voltage that
will more than electrify you.
I'll ask the little lady to retire and
prepare for her sensational dance.
As promised, folks.
I'm going to have the little lady
from Honolulu dance for you.
Alright Pop, let's have a little music.
Take it away, lady. Come on.
Rodney.
Well.
I'll be seeing you, Suzie.
Rodney.
It's nice to see you.
It's been so long.
I've been worried about you, Helga.
Sure you're alright?
Sure.
Sure I'm alright.
I'm so happy you've
come to take me away.
Let's get out of here quick.
I'll just get my things.
That won't take me long.
Just a minute.
Hello baby. Come on, snap into it.
The supper will be ready
in my tent in five minutes.
Hmm.
Who's your boyfriend?
What do you mean?
And I thought you were
just a little hick.
Get rid of him.
What did you say?
Don't try starting anything
around here, sap.
Please.
Give him the air.
Be in my tent in five minutes.
What did he mean?
What right has he to
talk to you like that?
What right?
He ..
He.
Oh.
No, Rodney. It wasn't my fault.
It wasn't my fault.
- Don't try to explain.
They came to take me back.
- You couldn't wait for me?
They were going to make
me marry Mondstrum.
And I'd have sworn you loved me.
Rodney.
I do love you.
- You've a swell way of showing it.
It would have killed me if I'd
had to go back to that man.
So you stayed and took this one?
He just called me a sap.
And he was right.
A sap not to realize how cheap you are.
Rodney, don't say that.
I couldn't wait to get back.
To marry you.
To marry .. that's funny.
I should have paid you off.
Thrown a few dollars on the bureau.
The kind of language you understand.
You don't know what you're saying.
- I even bought the ring.
Engraved with your initials and mine.
And the word 'always'.
You said you wanted a wedding ring
more than anything in the world.
Well. There it is.
Let me explain.
What will become of me if you leave me?
- I'll tell you what will become of you.
You'll go from one man to another just
like every other woman in the gutter.
Gutter?
- Yes.
Alright.
But I'll make it a worthwhile gutter.
I'd always hated men until I met you.
Hated them.
But from now on ..
It will be different.
So, you're on your way, sap?
Dinner is now ready in the dining car.
How about having a little
bite with me, lady?
Number 13. Maybe someone is hurt.
Let's get down there.
Spencer. I told you it would happen.
What is it, chief?
- A cave-in at Number 13.
Anybody killed?
You should have thought of that when
you forgot to put in the bolster.
I asked you if anybody was killed.
- It's no fault of yours they weren't.
A man can drink or work.
But he can't do both.
From now on you'd better
concentrate on the drinking.
You're through.
Oh Mike.
- Excuse me, judge.
Yes, dear?
Mike, dear.
Who is Friedman bringing tonight?
I believe he did mention his name but ..
The judge and I were talking
politics at that moment.
Uhoh.
The next time I'll have
Friedman phone me.
The table looks lovely, darling.
You go on with your blarney.
Marie, set two extra places.
I'll be back in a moment.
Hello?
Hiya, baby.
Is he really coming?
He ought to be here any minute.
I'm waiting for him now.
Swell.
New clothes and a little money
straightened him out okay.
And did he fall for that yarn about
Kelly slipping him a juicy contract.
That's wonderful.
And he hasn't the
faintest idea who I am?
Alright.
Oh, someday I'll tell you.
No, no. It's just a whim of mine.
I just want to pay back an old debt.
Would you mind explaining again
just what I'm doing here, Friedman.
You want the contract don't you?
Yes. But this mysterious lady ..
What has she to do with contracts?
My boy, the key to a big contract
is Commissioner Michael Kelly.
And the key to Michael
Kelly is Mrs Lenox.
Is there ..
Is there a mister Lenox?
Now, is there a mister Lenox?
Come on, Rodney. Here we are.
Good evening, Jane.
Take care of Mr Spencer.
Hiya, baby.
- Freddy. So glad you came.
Only, this is a very quiet party.
You won't enjoy it.
Don't worry, we'll suffer together.
- Yes.
Oh .. oh Rod.
Mrs Lenox - Mr Spencer.
What a pleasant surprise.
Mr Spencer.
You see.
One never knows what
Freddy is liable to bring in.
Well Benny.
Mike.
How are you?
- Here's that man I told you about.
Mr Spencer, I want you to meet Mr Kelly.
I've heard a lot about you, Spencer.
Thank you, Mr Kelly.
- Have a little cocktail?
Do, Mr Spencer.
Sure. I think a cocktail
will do you good.
You know the proposition I spoke about?
- Yes, Freddie.
I think it's going to go through.
- Good boy.
A Martini?
No?
Perhaps you'd rather have ..
Have a little port, huh?
No thank you.
Some hors d'oeuvres?
Maybe some caviar?
You know .. caviar?
Looks like buckshot.
But it isn't.
It's fish eggs.
You know, fish.
Come and meet some charming people.
Did you like that, George?
I think the most amusing thing about men
is they mistake cruelty for character.
They can't forgive.
They have no ..
No ..
- Tolerance?
Thank you.
I once knew a girl who went
through hell for the man she loved.
But he had no .. tolerance.
So he told her:
'You are a bad woman'.
'Go to the gutter where you belong'.
As a matter of fact she did
rather well for herself.
I knew an instance very similar.
Only being a man,
I learned both sides of the story.
Really?
I would love to hear you defend the
male sex, Mr Spencer. Please go on.
True. The man I knew was intolerant.
But only because he was
crazy about the woman.
How interesting, Mr Spencer.
Then he found out how
much he'd hurt himself.
Being a man, he was afraid it would hurt
his character if he went back, huh?
No. As soon as he cooled
off he did go back.
He did go back?
Sure. The sap went back.
As usually happens, he found the woman
who was burning him up had gone off.
Probably with someone else.
Those people usually meet
again sooner or later.
Surely he must have seen her?
Yes. He saw her alright.
She was sitting on top of the world.
Goody, goody, goody. I hope
she didn't even speak to him.
You see, she couldn't resist the
temptation to humiliate him again.
You know, women don't
forget very easily.
They resent being called .. gutter.
I think we'd better change the subject.
Ah, but you mustn't
miss the rest of the story.
That will interest you.
This woman.
Not content with
smashing one man's life.
Went merrily on.
To the highest bidder.
Always a parasite.
The last I heard of
her she'd sunk so low ..
She'd accepted protection
from a shady politician.
Mike.
I've had enough of this.
She'll treat you as she treated me.
When the next man comes along.
Only it won't hurt you because
you're used to her kind of woman.
I must talk to you.
I've nothing to say to you. If you were
younger I'd slam you into the table.
Spencer, what's the matter with you?
- That goes for you or anyone else.
Rodney.
Goodbye, Mrs Lenox.
Susan.
No use talking, Mike. I'm leaving.
So this is the fellow you told me about?
The first.
- Yes.
Now wait a minute.
Let's figure this out.
You can't run after him.
Why not?
If you leave here tonight.
There will be no coming back.
Do you realize that?
Yes.
But this man doesn't want you.
Of course he wants me.
All that bitterness and contempt.
It's only because he
is desperately hurt.
A man doesn't feel that
unless he loves you.
Well, it's a strange way.
I don't expect you to understand.
I didn't until tonight.
I wanted to hurt him as he hurt me.
And then ..
I don't know.
Think of your pride.
Didn't I tell you I love him?
I'll make him see me as I was.
Susan, don't you realize
what you're heading for?
What difference does it make?
As long as it's with him.
Saints alive, what's the
matter with this house.
People coming and
going and bells ringing.
Well?
I'd like to see Mr Spencer.
- That crazy egg?
Sure, he's gone.
When do you expect him back?
- He's never coming back.
He's gone for good.
Like a wild one, he was.
Threw twelve dollars down on the kitchen
table and rushed off with his grip.
Where did he go?
Maybe the big hotel at Timbuktu.
How should I be knowing?
Didn't he say anything?
Leave an address or something?
Didn't I tell you he was crazy?
Never a word did he say.
Susan.
Did you see him?
No.
He had gone.
Where?
I don't know.
Susan.
Come along with me.
Tomorrow you may feel
different about this.
No, Mike.
I'll never feel different.
I've got to find him.
New York is a pretty big place.
I know.
But I'll find him.
Where to, lady?
What?
- Where do you want to go?
I don't know.
Just keep on driving
until I tell you to stop.
Okay.
Goodnight, Pepe.
Do you think you should
go in there alone?
I've been in there
every night this week.
That's one of one of the
toughest places in these parts.
Come and have a drink with me.
- No thank you.
I'll be getting back to the yacht.
- Goodnight.
A table?
The American. He's here again.
Be nice to him.
He buys so much wine.
Big tips.
Oh baby. Come darling.
Come, darling.
Tired?
A little.
I've done the same dance
eight times tonight.
Why not come out on the yacht?
It'll be cool on deck.
- I'm not interested in yachts.
You know, I'm beginning to believe you.
Is that so hard to believe?
Yes and no.
I can see a little halo
around that head alright.
But it hardly fits in with this.
There is no halo, my friend.
Then why not sail with me?
Arabia.
Egypt.
Ceylon.
Sunshine. Pretty clothes.
Contentment.
When the cruise is over,
you won't find me ..
Well, how shall I say it?
Financially ungrateful.
What's the matter? Don't you like me?
Better than any man I've ever met.
With one exception.
You are very interesting.
Perhaps I'm in love with you.
Anyway, I find it hard
to leave this port.
All my life I wanted to
meet a man like you.
Understanding.
Now that I have met you.
I haven't anything to offer you.
Everything I have belongs to him.
Any news?
No.
But it can only be a question of hours.
They send him down for a
spell every three months.
He's a week overdue.
Of course I shouldn't say this really ..
But has it occurred to you that
he might never come down?
A lot of them don't, you know.
That swamp is a hotbed of fever.
Why did you have to say that?
I thought perhaps if you knew
definitely you would never ..
Don't, don't.
- Why not take me?
There wouldn't be a single
wish of yours I wouldn't ..
But I've told you what
I've been through.
Even to get this near to him.
A woman could go up
there and be with him now.
You don't think I would leave when ..
- A lot of women jump at the chance.
I know.
Each time I write.
Or phone.
Alone.
One room for tonight, baby.
Make it snappy.
Hey, Suzie. The boys are
here from up the river.
Rodney.
How are you?
Well, I'll be ..
Leave him alone. You know the
rules of the house. I saw him first.
What are you doing here?
I'm working.
Oh yeah?
Next stop Algiers and
then Port Said, eh?
Oh no.
- That's the route they all take.
You leave him alone. He belongs to me.
Let me speak to you alone.
Alone?
Sure, why not.
- Oh baby.
Beat it, beat it.
You're looking pretty
good, old playmate.
You don't understand why I came here.
No?
Penthouses and politicians
don't last forever, do they.
Alright.
Sit down and have a drink.
Why don't you sit down?
No thanks.
What have you got to say to me?
So many things.
But I'll say them.
Some other time.
Frightened little one,
or just being coy?
Now that we've said hello.
What kind of a toboggan
brought you down here?
I left Kelly after I saw you.
That night.
You took your time about
catching up with me.
It cost money. And I had to work.
Same old trade, huh?
Since I last saw you.
No man has had a minute from me.
Not even a second.
You lie.
No man since then.
Well.
What do you want?
Our love for each other has made
such a wreck of everything.
Your fault as well as mine.
I thought that we might try again.
You know.
You're the only woman I wanted to build
a fence around, and have all to myself.
You built the fence.
An army of men.
But I never wanted anyone but you.
But there never was a time that I
wouldn't have been as true as heaven.
If you'd only let me.
Rodney.
I'll do anything for you.
Go anywhere you like.
I'll share anything.
Or nothing.
We should forgive each other.
And try again.
We've got to forgive each other.
Rodney.
Ah, why talk about forgiveness?
Why ask anything different from me?
Every other man you knew
took you at your own price.
Nothing.
This time.
I'll take you as I find you.
No.
No, no.
Sorry.
I thought you might need me.
Oh.
One of your clients, eh?
No. She don't need you.
She's got a date with me.
Beat it.
- I don't take orders.
No?
- None of that, please.
I happen to know all about this.
I think you're making a great mistake.
I wish she'd marry me.
She's fine.
Marry?
Hey, listen.
All you need is the price
of a marriage license.
Just the price.
Not the wedding.
Did it ever strike you for a second
that you might be wrong?
What right have you
to take a stand like this?
What right?
Do you know why I
wallow up in the swamps?
Do you know why I never drew
a sober breath on the waterfront?
It's heat .. booze .. insects.
Damp-rot and sweat.
But it eats up the memory of you.
Come back. You come with me, yes?
Ah, get away.
Okay.
I'm all set.
Come in.
This is a surprise.
Yes, I'm on my way.
The barge is leaving for up river.
Nice of you to come and ..
Say goodbye.
So you're going to get married, eh?
Don't you care?
- Sure I care.
That's why it will be nice
to know that you're set.
And happy.
Wouldn't you like to go .. home?
There's a schooner sailing tonight.
Why don't we leave on her?
These hurts that we have
inflicted upon each other.
It's become a bond.
Nothing can break it.
We're just like .. like two cripples.
Twisted.
Only together can we ever become ..
Straight.
You've a queer way of looking at things.
Come on, Rodney. Shake a leg will
you, boy. That's the second whistle.
Go ahead. I'm coming.
Let me do that.
No. Please.
Let me.
So you're going to get
the ring at last, eh?
He seems like a pretty nice fellow.
I'm glad you're getting that ring.
You know what would
happen if you'd come with me?
You'd have to cook ..
Wash ..
Live in a dump.
- Yes, I know.
I'd drink.
- Not if you were happy.
Every time a man came along, I'd ..
I'd wonder.
I'll make you believe in me.
..t-g..