0
00:00:05,293 --> 00:00:10,294
Encoded by Judas
Enjoy!

1
00:02:06,293 --> 00:02:08,294
Holy mackerel!

2
00:02:08,378 --> 00:02:10,880
Call headquarters.
Get the lieutenant.

3
00:02:18,430 --> 00:02:20,973
Holy Christmas!
That thing's doing about 4,000!

4
00:02:21,058 --> 00:02:25,228
- But that's incredible, sir!
- That can't be aircraft. Must be a buzz bomb.

5
00:02:28,023 --> 00:02:30,233
This is Lieutenant Ferris
to Charlie Baker.

6
00:02:30,317 --> 00:02:33,236
l have a bogey
at 2-0-0 thousand feet.

7
00:02:33,320 --> 00:02:35,530
4-0-0-0 miles an hour.

10
00:02:52,089 --> 00:02:54,465
Reports are
coming in from all over the empire...

11
00:02:54,550 --> 00:02:56,509
from all over the world.

12
00:02:56,593 --> 00:02:59,762
The government
has not yet issued any statement,
but there seems to be no question...

13
00:02:59,847 --> 00:03:02,390
that there actually
is a large, unidentified object...

14
00:03:02,474 --> 00:03:04,684
circling the Earth at incredible speed.

15
00:03:04,768 --> 00:03:07,019
This is Elmer Davis again.

16
00:03:07,104 --> 00:03:09,689
We still don't know what it is
or where it comes from...

17
00:03:09,773 --> 00:03:11,691
but there's something there.

18
00:03:11,775 --> 00:03:14,110
lt's been tracked
around the earth by radar...

19
00:03:14,194 --> 00:03:16,863
traveling at a rate
of4,000 miles an hour.

20
00:03:16,947 --> 00:03:20,199
This is not another flying saucer scare.

21
00:03:20,284 --> 00:03:23,619
Scientists and military men
are already agreed on that.

22
00:03:23,704 --> 00:03:26,247
Whatever it is, it's something real.

23
00:03:26,331 --> 00:03:28,875
We interrupt
this program to give you a bulletin...

24
00:03:28,959 --> 00:03:30,960
just received from one
ofour naval units at sea.

25
00:03:31,044 --> 00:03:33,671
A large object traveling
at supersonic speed...

26
00:03:33,755 --> 00:03:37,091
is headed over the North Atlantic
toward the east coast ofthe United States.

27
00:03:37,175 --> 00:03:39,927
This is H.V. Kaltenborn speaking.

28
00:03:40,012 --> 00:03:43,723
Here in the nation's capital,
there is anxiety and concern...

29
00:03:43,807 --> 00:03:45,766
but no outward sign of panic.

30
00:03:45,851 --> 00:03:49,812
As a matter offact,
there are signs of normalcy―

31
00:03:49,897 --> 00:03:51,898
the beautiful spring weather...

32
00:03:51,982 --> 00:03:55,776
the tourist crowds around the public
monuments and other buildings.

39
00:04:55,963 --> 00:04:58,506
Hey!

41
00:05:24,616 --> 00:05:27,910
They're here!

42
00:05:28,912 --> 00:05:30,830
They're here!

43
00:05:30,914 --> 00:05:33,624
lt landed, over on the mall!
lt landed!

46
00:06:17,085 --> 00:06:19,837
- Get me the chiefofstaff.
- Thank you. Hold the line, please.

47
00:06:19,921 --> 00:06:22,548
Hold the line, please.

48
00:06:22,632 --> 00:06:26,135
Hello.
l want to speak to the president.

49
00:06:26,219 --> 00:06:29,346
l'm sorry,
but you'll have to interrupt him.

50
00:06:29,431 --> 00:06:31,724
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
This is Drew Pearson.

51
00:06:31,808 --> 00:06:34,435
We bring you this special
radio-television broadcast...

52
00:06:34,519 --> 00:06:38,898
in order to give you
the very latest information
on an amazing phenomenon―

53
00:06:38,982 --> 00:06:42,068
the arrival ofa spaceship in Washington.

54
00:06:42,152 --> 00:06:45,988
Government and defense department officials
are concerned by reports of panic...

55
00:06:46,073 --> 00:06:49,241
in several large eastern cities.

56
00:06:49,326 --> 00:06:51,368
l am authorized to assure you...

57
00:06:51,453 --> 00:06:54,997
that so far there is
no reasonable cause for alarm.

58
00:06:55,082 --> 00:06:58,125
The rumors of invading armies
and mass destruction...

59
00:06:58,210 --> 00:07:01,962
are based on hysteria
and are absolutely false.

60
00:07:02,047 --> 00:07:06,967
l repeat:
These rumors are absolutely false.

61
00:07:07,052 --> 00:07:11,305
The ship, designed for travel
outside the earth's atmosphere...

62
00:07:11,389 --> 00:07:16,602
landed in Washington today
at 3:47 p.m., Eastern Standard Time.

63
00:07:16,686 --> 00:07:18,979
We still do not know where it came from.

64
00:07:19,064 --> 00:07:22,942
The ship is now resting exactly
where it landed two hours ago...

65
00:07:23,026 --> 00:07:26,445
and so far there is
no sign of life from inside it.

66
00:07:26,530 --> 00:07:30,282
Troops have been rushed across
the Potomac River from Fort Myer...

67
00:07:30,367 --> 00:07:32,868
and have thrown a cordon
around the ship.

68
00:07:32,953 --> 00:07:35,746
They're supported by tanks,
artillery and machine guns.

69
00:07:35,831 --> 00:07:40,292
Behind the police lines, there's
a huge crowd ofcuriosity seekers.

70
00:07:40,377 --> 00:07:43,003
The army has taken every precaution...

71
00:07:43,088 --> 00:07:45,256
to meet any emergency
which may develop.

72
00:07:45,340 --> 00:07:49,051
every eye,
every weapon is trained on the ship.

73
00:07:49,136 --> 00:07:51,679
lt's been that way for two hours...

74
00:07:51,763 --> 00:07:54,431
and the tension isjust beginning―

75
00:07:54,516 --> 00:07:58,060
Just a minute, ladies and gentlemen.
l think something is happening.

77
00:09:01,208 --> 00:09:03,834
We have come to visit you in peace...

78
00:09:03,919 --> 00:09:06,587
and with goodwill.

79
00:09:55,762 --> 00:09:58,097
What's the matter with him?
He's hurt. Look!

80
00:09:58,181 --> 00:10:00,516
Boy!

83
00:11:55,965 --> 00:11:58,300
Gort! Deglet ovrosco!

84
00:12:18,238 --> 00:12:20,656
lt was a gift for your president.

85
00:12:20,740 --> 00:12:23,659
With this, he could have studied
life on the other planets.

86
00:12:30,750 --> 00:12:33,752
Get that ambulance over here.
Take him to Walter Reed Hospital right away.

87
00:12:33,837 --> 00:12:35,754
Yes, sir.

88
00:12:35,839 --> 00:12:37,756
Mr. Harley, sir, from the White House.

89
00:12:37,841 --> 00:12:40,843
- General?
- Right in there, Mr. Harley.

91
00:12:54,566 --> 00:12:58,694
My name is Harley,
secretary to the president.

92
00:12:58,778 --> 00:13:00,946
l've been told you speak our language...

93
00:13:01,030 --> 00:13:03,782
and that your name is Mr. Klaatu?

94
00:13:03,867 --> 00:13:05,784
Just Klaatu.

95
00:13:05,869 --> 00:13:09,329
The president asked me to convey
his deepest apologies forwhat has happened.

96
00:13:09,414 --> 00:13:11,331
Sit down, Mr. Harley.

97
00:13:11,416 --> 00:13:13,375
Thankyou.

98
00:13:16,588 --> 00:13:18,839
l'm sure l―
l need hardly point out...

99
00:13:18,923 --> 00:13:22,050
that your arrival
was something ofa surprise.

100
00:13:22,135 --> 00:13:24,219
Had you been traveling long?

101
00:13:24,304 --> 00:13:27,055
About five months―your months.

102
00:13:27,140 --> 00:13:29,308
You must have come a long way.

103
00:13:29,392 --> 00:13:32,561
About 250 million ofyour miles.

104
00:13:34,439 --> 00:13:37,191
Naturally, we are very curious
to know where it is you come from.

105
00:13:37,275 --> 00:13:39,276
From another planet.

106
00:13:39,360 --> 00:13:41,445
Let'sjust say that we're neighbors.

107
00:13:41,529 --> 00:13:45,032
lt's rather difficult for us to think
ofanother planet as a neighbor.

108
00:13:45,116 --> 00:13:48,827
l'm afraid, in the present situation,
you will have to learn to think that way.

109
00:13:48,912 --> 00:13:51,872
- The present situation?
- l mean the reason for my coming here.

110
00:13:51,956 --> 00:13:55,334
We're very curious about that too.

111
00:13:55,418 --> 00:13:58,086
- Would you care to talk about it?
- l'd be glad to.

112
00:14:00,131 --> 00:14:02,883
Not now, ofcourse, with you alone.

113
00:14:02,967 --> 00:14:05,469
Oh, perhaps you'd rather discuss it
personally with the president.

114
00:14:05,553 --> 00:14:08,013
This is not a personal matter,
Mr. Harley.

115
00:14:08,097 --> 00:14:10,390
lt concerns
all the people on your planet.

116
00:14:12,018 --> 00:14:14,478
l― l'm not sure l understand.

117
00:14:16,105 --> 00:14:18,941
l want to meet with representatives
from all the nations ofthe Earth.

118
00:14:21,110 --> 00:14:23,111
l'm afraid that would be
a little awkward.

119
00:14:23,196 --> 00:14:25,656
lt's completely without precedent.

120
00:14:25,740 --> 00:14:27,699
And there are practical considerations―

121
00:14:27,784 --> 00:14:31,411
the time involved,
the, uh, enormous distances.

122
00:14:31,496 --> 00:14:33,997
l traveled 250 million miles.

123
00:14:34,082 --> 00:14:36,458
l appreciate that, but...

124
00:14:37,835 --> 00:14:40,337
l want to be frank with you, Mr.―

125
00:14:40,421 --> 00:14:42,881
l mean, Klaatu.

126
00:14:42,966 --> 00:14:45,551
Our world, at the moment...

127
00:14:45,635 --> 00:14:49,388
is full oftensions
and, uh― and suspicions.

128
00:14:49,472 --> 00:14:51,932
ln the present international situation...

129
00:14:52,016 --> 00:14:54,142
such a meeting
would be quite impossible.

130
00:14:54,227 --> 00:14:56,436
What about your United Nations?

131
00:14:56,521 --> 00:14:58,730
You know about the United Nations?

132
00:14:58,815 --> 00:15:01,900
We've been monitoring your radio
broadcasts for a good manyyears.

133
00:15:01,985 --> 00:15:03,944
That's how we learned your languages.

134
00:15:04,028 --> 00:15:07,281
l'm sure you recognize
from our broadcasts...

135
00:15:07,365 --> 00:15:10,117
the evil forces that have produced
the trouble in our world.

136
00:15:10,201 --> 00:15:12,119
Now, surely you'll agree―

137
00:15:12,203 --> 00:15:14,413
l'm not concerned with
the internal affairs ofyour planet.

138
00:15:14,497 --> 00:15:18,292
My mission here is not
to solve your petty squabbles.

139
00:15:18,376 --> 00:15:21,295
lt concerns the existence
ofevery last creature on earth.

140
00:15:21,379 --> 00:15:24,715
Well, perhaps
ifyou could explain a little―

141
00:15:24,799 --> 00:15:28,885
l intend to explain
to all the nations at the same time.

142
00:15:30,263 --> 00:15:32,764
How do we proceed, Mr. Harley?

143
00:15:34,892 --> 00:15:39,271
Well, we, uh― We could call a special meeting
ofthe General Assembly.

144
00:15:39,355 --> 00:15:42,274
But, ofcourse, the United Nations
doesn't represent all the nations.

145
00:15:42,358 --> 00:15:45,861
Then l suggest a meeting
ofall the chiefs ofstate.

146
00:15:45,945 --> 00:15:48,238
Believe me, you don't understand.

147
00:15:48,323 --> 00:15:51,325
They wouldn't sit down at the same table.

148
00:15:51,409 --> 00:15:54,244
l don't want to resort to threats,
Mr. Harley.

149
00:15:54,329 --> 00:15:57,080
l merely tell you that the future
ofyour planet is at stake.

150
00:15:57,165 --> 00:16:01,376
l urge that you transmit that message
to the nations ofthe Earth.

151
00:16:08,176 --> 00:16:10,969
l will make that recommendation
to the president.

152
00:16:13,556 --> 00:16:15,682
But l must tell you in all honesty...

153
00:16:15,767 --> 00:16:17,768
l'm extremely dubious about the results.

154
00:16:17,852 --> 00:16:21,605
Apparently, l'm not as cynical
about Earth's people as you are.

155
00:16:21,689 --> 00:16:26,652
l've been dealing in Earth's politics
a good deal longer than you have.

156
00:16:26,736 --> 00:16:28,737
Good night, sir.

157
00:16:38,790 --> 00:16:43,377
lt is now 2:00 a.m.,
and the giant robot still hasn't moved.

158
00:16:43,461 --> 00:16:46,922
Engineers from nearby Fort Belvoir
have failed to budge him...

159
00:16:47,006 --> 00:16:51,218
and metallurgical experts
have found his huge body impregnable.

160
00:16:51,302 --> 00:16:55,305
They're now concentrating on the ship itself,
but so far with no results.

161
00:17:11,406 --> 00:17:13,365
Getting anyplace, Sergeant?

162
00:17:13,449 --> 00:17:16,368
Oh, no, sir.Just beats me, sir.

163
00:17:16,452 --> 00:17:21,248
l saw the ramp come through the side ofthe
ship right here. Now l can't even find a crack.

164
00:17:24,210 --> 00:17:26,753
Oh, Carlson. What's the report?

165
00:17:26,838 --> 00:17:28,755
No luck, sir.

166
00:17:28,840 --> 00:17:31,842
We've tried everything
from a blowtorch to a diamond drill.

167
00:17:33,970 --> 00:17:37,139
- What about him?
- He's made out ofthe same stuff.

168
00:17:37,223 --> 00:17:39,683
- Has he moved, Sergeant?
- No, sir, not an inch.

169
00:17:39,767 --> 00:17:43,019
This is the toughest material
l ever saw, General.

170
00:17:43,104 --> 00:17:45,897
For hardness and strength,
it's out ofthis world.

171
00:17:45,982 --> 00:17:49,151
l can tell you officially
that's where it came from.

172
00:17:51,028 --> 00:17:54,322
The skeletal structure
is completely normal.

173
00:17:54,407 --> 00:17:56,742
The tests show the same
for the major organs―

174
00:17:56,826 --> 00:17:58,994
the heart, liver, spleen, kidneys.

175
00:17:59,078 --> 00:18:01,663
And the lungs are the same as ours.

176
00:18:01,748 --> 00:18:05,000
That must mean a similar atmosphere,
similar pressure.

177
00:18:06,210 --> 00:18:10,255
- How old do you think he is?
- Oh, l'd say 35, 38.

178
00:18:10,339 --> 00:18:13,717
He told me this morning while l
was examining him. He's 78.

179
00:18:13,801 --> 00:18:17,387
- l don't believe it.
- Life expectancy's 1 30.

180
00:18:17,472 --> 00:18:21,600
- How does he explain that?
- Says their medicine is
that much more advanced.

181
00:18:21,684 --> 00:18:25,979
He was very nice about it, but he made me
feel like a third-class witch doctor.

182
00:18:31,819 --> 00:18:34,571
l removed a bullet
from that man's arm yesterday.

183
00:18:34,655 --> 00:18:38,575
- What about it?
- l just examined the wound,
and it's completely healed.

184
00:18:38,659 --> 00:18:43,205
- What does he say about it?
- Said he put some salve on it―
some stuff he had with him.

185
00:18:43,289 --> 00:18:47,626
- What are you gonna do with it?
- Take it downstairs and have it analyzed.

186
00:18:47,710 --> 00:18:52,255
And l don't know whether tojust get drunk
or give up the practice of medicine.

187
00:18:55,551 --> 00:18:57,886
- Afternoon, Mr. Harley.
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.

189
00:19:06,020 --> 00:19:09,481
Good afternoon.
l'm glad to see you up and around.

190
00:19:09,565 --> 00:19:11,566
Thank you. Have you any news?

191
00:19:11,651 --> 00:19:14,152
Not very good news, l'm afraid.

192
00:19:15,446 --> 00:19:18,114
The president accepted your suggestion...

193
00:19:18,199 --> 00:19:20,867
and cabled the invitations
for a meeting.

194
00:19:23,746 --> 00:19:27,207
Let me read you some ofthe replies.

195
00:19:29,544 --> 00:19:32,879
"The premierwishes to inform
the government ofthe United States...

196
00:19:32,964 --> 00:19:36,675
"that it will be impossible for him to attend
the meeting suggested by the president...

197
00:19:36,759 --> 00:19:40,387
unless the meeting is held in Moscow."

198
00:19:40,471 --> 00:19:44,683
"The suggestion ofthe president regarding
the possibility ofa meeting in Moscow...

199
00:19:44,767 --> 00:19:48,520
"would be unacceptable to His Majesty's
government at the present time.

200
00:19:48,604 --> 00:19:52,524
Representation could be sent only
ifthe meeting were held in Washington."

201
00:19:53,609 --> 00:19:56,319
Well, there you have it.

202
00:19:59,031 --> 00:20:02,117
Now that you understand
the situation more clearly...

203
00:20:02,201 --> 00:20:04,452
perhaps you'd like to discuss it
with the president.

204
00:20:04,537 --> 00:20:07,873
l will not speak with any one nation
or group of nations.

205
00:20:07,957 --> 00:20:11,835
l don't intend to add my contribution
to your childish jealousies and suspicions.

206
00:20:11,919 --> 00:20:15,964
Our problems are very complex, Klaatu.
You mustn'tjudge us too harshly.

207
00:20:16,048 --> 00:20:18,383
l can judge only by what l see.

208
00:20:18,467 --> 00:20:20,427
Your impatience is quite understandable.

209
00:20:20,511 --> 00:20:22,846
l'm impatient with stupidity.

210
00:20:22,930 --> 00:20:27,392
- My people have learned to live without it.
- l'm afraid my people haven't.

211
00:20:27,476 --> 00:20:30,186
l am very sorry.

212
00:20:30,271 --> 00:20:32,981
l wish it were otherwise.

213
00:20:46,787 --> 00:20:49,831
Before making any decisions...

214
00:20:49,916 --> 00:20:52,375
l think l should get out
among your people...

215
00:20:52,460 --> 00:20:57,255
and become familiar with the basis
for these strange, unreasoning attitudes.

216
00:20:57,340 --> 00:21:00,508
Under the circumstances,
l'm afraid that's impossible.

217
00:21:02,261 --> 00:21:05,180
l must ask that you don't attempt
to leave the hospital.

218
00:21:05,264 --> 00:21:08,808
Our military people have insisted on this.
l'm sure you understand.

222
00:21:49,558 --> 00:21:52,018
- Captain, sir! The man
from the spaceship got away!
- What?

223
00:21:52,103 --> 00:21:54,396
- Get every available man!
- Yes, sir.

225
00:22:29,557 --> 00:22:31,683
The authorities at Walter Reed Hospital...

226
00:22:31,767 --> 00:22:34,519
refuse to comment
on how he managed to escape...

227
00:22:34,603 --> 00:22:36,855
orwhat measures may be taken
to apprehend him.

228
00:22:36,939 --> 00:22:39,399
Descriptions of
the creature are denounced as rumor...

229
00:22:39,483 --> 00:22:41,401
by Police ChiefWalter Baxter.

230
00:22:41,485 --> 00:22:44,529
He's not eight feet tall as reported,
nor does he have tentacles―

231
00:22:44,613 --> 00:22:47,407
There's no denying
that there is a monster at large...

232
00:22:47,491 --> 00:22:51,536
that we are dealing with forces
beyond our knowledge and power.

233
00:22:51,620 --> 00:22:55,123
The public is advised
to take ordinary precautions...

234
00:22:55,207 --> 00:22:57,917
and to remain calm as we await further―

235
00:22:58,002 --> 00:23:01,129
Government officials
have come to the inescapable conclusion...

236
00:23:01,213 --> 00:23:03,673
that this ship and its occupants
come from some other planet.

237
00:23:03,758 --> 00:23:07,635
Thus far, scientists have refused
to speak officially on just which planet...

238
00:23:07,720 --> 00:23:10,430
until they've had an opportunity
to study the ship.

239
00:23:10,514 --> 00:23:13,558
They seem to agree, however,
that either Venus or Mars...

240
00:23:13,642 --> 00:23:15,643
is the most likely possibility.

241
00:23:15,728 --> 00:23:18,313
Not only are these
the closest planets to Earth...

242
00:23:18,397 --> 00:23:22,567
but all research to date indicates
that they are the only two planets...

243
00:23:22,651 --> 00:23:25,945
capable ofsustaining life as we know it.

244
00:23:26,030 --> 00:23:30,033
However, all reputable scientists warn
againstjumping to hasty conclusions.

245
00:23:30,117 --> 00:23:33,078
Professor Havermeyer of M.l.T,
for example...

246
00:23:33,162 --> 00:23:36,539
points out that it's entirely possible,
in light ofour meager knowledge―

247
00:23:36,624 --> 00:23:38,750
The president has urged all citizens...

248
00:23:38,834 --> 00:23:42,087
to be on the alert
for any information about this man...

249
00:23:42,171 --> 00:23:44,255
and to transmit such information
immediately...

250
00:23:44,340 --> 00:23:47,342
to the police, the army or the F.B.l.

251
00:23:47,426 --> 00:23:50,929
While the president made no effort
to minimize the crisis...

252
00:23:51,013 --> 00:23:54,349
he urged people
all over the country to remain calm.

253
00:23:54,433 --> 00:23:58,603
And l might add that though this man
may be our bitter enemy...

254
00:23:58,687 --> 00:24:01,564
he could be also a newfound friend.

255
00:24:01,649 --> 00:24:04,609
Unfortunately, for identification purposes,
the only photographs we have―

256
00:24:04,693 --> 00:24:06,778
- Mom, you think l could―
- are similar to this one.

257
00:24:06,862 --> 00:24:10,031
- Hey, who's that?
- and do not show the man's face.

258
00:24:10,116 --> 00:24:12,492
The president said
the entire facilities ofthe F.B.l....

259
00:24:12,576 --> 00:24:14,494
and every other federal agency...

260
00:24:14,578 --> 00:24:16,538
are being brought to bear.

261
00:24:16,622 --> 00:24:20,959
He pointed out, however,
that this is no ordinary manhunt.

262
00:24:21,043 --> 00:24:24,295
He warned we may be up against powers...

263
00:24:24,380 --> 00:24:26,714
that are beyond our control.

264
00:24:34,890 --> 00:24:39,310
- What is it you want?
- My name is Carpenter.
l'm looking for a room.

265
00:24:39,395 --> 00:24:42,272
- Oh, l see.
- Are you an F.B.l. man?

266
00:24:44,108 --> 00:24:46,359
- No, l'm afraid not.
- l'll bet he is, Mom.

267
00:24:46,443 --> 00:24:48,361
l bet he's looking for the spaceman.

268
00:24:48,445 --> 00:24:50,947
l think we've all been hearing
too much about spacemen.

269
00:24:51,031 --> 00:24:53,449
- This is Mrs. Benson, Mr. Carpenter.
- How do you do?

270
00:24:53,534 --> 00:24:55,451
And little Bobby.

271
00:24:55,536 --> 00:24:59,247
- Mr. and Mrs. Barley and Mr. Krull.
- How do you do?

272
00:24:59,331 --> 00:25:02,375
l'm Mrs. Crockett.

273
00:25:02,459 --> 00:25:05,086
l have a very nice room
on the second floor.

274
00:25:05,171 --> 00:25:08,089
lt has two large windows
and gets the sun all day long.

275
00:25:08,174 --> 00:25:10,425
Hey, mister! Can l help you
look for the spaceman?

276
00:25:10,509 --> 00:25:14,095
l knowjust what he looks like. He's got
a big square head with three great big eyes!

277
00:25:14,180 --> 00:25:17,473
That's enough, Bobby.
lt's late. Come on. excuse me.

278
00:25:17,558 --> 00:25:20,310
We mustn't annoy Mr. Carpenter,
or he won't want to stay here.

279
00:25:20,394 --> 00:25:22,353
Mom, l think he is an F.B.l. agent.

280
00:25:22,438 --> 00:25:26,024
He's really a dear little boy
and quiet as a mouse.

281
00:25:26,108 --> 00:25:28,109
And all the while
they're getting fingerprints―

282
00:25:28,194 --> 00:25:31,362
- You're a long way from home,
aren't you, Mr. Carpenter?
- How did you know?

283
00:25:31,447 --> 00:25:34,449
l can tell a New england accent
a mile away.

284
00:25:37,661 --> 00:25:40,121
And now we
take you to Miami Beach, Florida...

285
00:25:40,206 --> 00:25:42,207
for a report from Gabriel Heatter.

286
00:25:42,291 --> 00:25:44,209
Mr. Heatter.

287
00:25:44,293 --> 00:25:47,378
And now on this Sunday morning,
we ask some questions...

288
00:25:47,463 --> 00:25:51,007
that have been haunting
the entire nation for two whole days.

289
00:25:51,091 --> 00:25:53,843
This creature― Where is he?

290
00:25:53,928 --> 00:25:55,887
What is he up to?

291
00:25:55,971 --> 00:25:59,307
lf he can build a spaceship
that can fly to earth...

292
00:25:59,391 --> 00:26:02,977
and a robot that can destroy
our tanks and guns...

293
00:26:03,062 --> 00:26:06,689
what other terrors
can he unleash at will?

294
00:26:06,774 --> 00:26:09,359
Obviously,
the monster must be found.

295
00:26:09,443 --> 00:26:12,028
He must be tracked down
like a wild animal.

296
00:26:12,112 --> 00:26:14,364
He must be destroyed.

297
00:26:14,448 --> 00:26:17,033
But where would such a creature hide?

298
00:26:17,117 --> 00:26:19,827
Would he disappear
into the north woods?

299
00:26:19,912 --> 00:26:23,498
Would he crawl into the sewers
ofsome great city?

300
00:26:23,582 --> 00:26:27,418
Everybody agrees.
There is grave danger.

301
00:26:27,503 --> 00:26:31,631
The question remains,
what can we do to protect ourselves?

302
00:26:31,715 --> 00:26:34,676
What measures can we take
to neutralize...

303
00:26:34,760 --> 00:26:37,303
this menace from another world?

304
00:26:37,388 --> 00:26:39,931
Destroy it? Ofcourse! But how?

305
00:26:40,015 --> 00:26:42,267
And ifwe do destroy it...

306
00:26:42,351 --> 00:26:45,019
what do we face in retaliation?

307
00:26:45,104 --> 00:26:47,605
George, would you turn that radio off?

308
00:26:47,690 --> 00:26:49,983
l'm trying to concentrate.

309
00:26:50,067 --> 00:26:52,944
Why doesn't the government do something?
That's what l'd like to know.

310
00:26:53,028 --> 00:26:55,488
What can they do?
They're only peoplejust like us.

311
00:26:55,572 --> 00:26:58,032
People, my foot. They're Democrats.

312
00:26:58,117 --> 00:27:00,118
lt's enough to give you the shakes.

313
00:27:00,202 --> 00:27:03,746
He's got that robot standing there, eight
feet tall, waiting for orders to destroy us.

314
00:27:03,831 --> 00:27:06,457
This spaceman, or whatever he is―

315
00:27:06,542 --> 00:27:10,461
We automatically assume he's a menace.
Maybe he isn't at all.

316
00:27:10,546 --> 00:27:13,631
Then what's he hiding for?
Why doesn't he come out in the open?

317
00:27:13,716 --> 00:27:16,301
Yeah, like that Heatter fella says―
What's he up to?

318
00:27:16,385 --> 00:27:19,137
- Maybe he's afraid.
- He's afraid?

319
00:27:19,221 --> 00:27:22,473
After all, he was shot
the minute he landed here.

320
00:27:23,559 --> 00:27:26,227
l wasjust wondering what l would do.

321
00:27:26,312 --> 00:27:28,479
Perhaps before deciding
on a course ofaction...

322
00:27:28,564 --> 00:27:30,773
you'd want to know more
about the people here―

323
00:27:30,858 --> 00:27:32,942
to orient yourself in
a strange environment.

324
00:27:33,027 --> 00:27:35,945
There's nothing strange
about Washington, Mr. Carpenter.

325
00:27:36,030 --> 00:27:38,823
A person from another planet
might disagree with you.

326
00:27:38,907 --> 00:27:42,910
Well, ifyou want my opinion,
he comes from right here on earth.

327
00:27:42,995 --> 00:27:45,079
And you know where l mean.

328
00:27:45,164 --> 00:27:47,498
They wouldn't come in a spaceship.

329
00:27:47,583 --> 00:27:51,169
- They'd come in airplanes.
- l wouldn't be too sure about that.

330
00:27:51,253 --> 00:27:54,380
Stands to reason that fella wants something,
otherwise he wouldn't be here.

331
00:27:54,465 --> 00:27:56,716
That right, Mr. Carpenter?

332
00:27:56,800 --> 00:27:59,010
l must admit, l'm a little confused.

333
00:27:59,094 --> 00:28:02,722
Mrs. Benson,
Mr. Stevens is here to see you.

334
00:28:02,806 --> 00:28:05,224
Oh, thankyou. Excuse me.

335
00:28:05,309 --> 00:28:09,395
George, finish your coffee. l promised
the Carsons l'd be there at 1 1 :00.

336
00:28:11,231 --> 00:28:14,025
- Good morning.
- Good morning.

337
00:28:14,109 --> 00:28:17,403
We're all set. l picked up
some sandwiches and put gas in the car.

338
00:28:17,488 --> 00:28:20,531
The radio's still on the blink, so we can
forget about the spaceman for today.

339
00:28:20,616 --> 00:28:23,368
There's only one thing―
l haven't anyone to stay with Bobby.

340
00:28:23,452 --> 00:28:25,411
l don't suppose
we could take him with us.

341
00:28:25,496 --> 00:28:27,455
Well― Well, we could.

342
00:28:27,539 --> 00:28:30,833
There's always someone here, but today,
ofcourse, they've all got plans.

343
00:28:30,918 --> 00:28:33,920
l haven't any plans.

344
00:28:34,004 --> 00:28:37,173
l'd be happy to spend the day
with him, ifyou'd let me.

345
00:28:37,257 --> 00:28:40,510
Say, that would be great.
Wouldn't it?

346
00:28:40,594 --> 00:28:43,179
lt's awfully nice ofyou to suggest it.

347
00:28:43,263 --> 00:28:45,640
l'm sorry. Mr. Carpenter,
this is Tom Stevens.

348
00:28:45,724 --> 00:28:48,518
- How do you do, Mr. Carpenter?
- Hello.

349
00:28:48,602 --> 00:28:51,187
Bobby and l had a fine time
yesterday afternoon.

350
00:28:51,271 --> 00:28:53,314
We talked and listened to the radio.

351
00:28:53,399 --> 00:28:56,526
l thought today he might like
to show me around the city.

352
00:28:58,153 --> 00:29:01,322
- Well―
- Suppose l ask Bobby how he feels about it?

353
00:29:01,407 --> 00:29:03,324
Fine.

354
00:29:04,660 --> 00:29:06,994
- You think it's all right?
- Sure.

355
00:29:20,717 --> 00:29:23,678
That's my father. He was killed at Anzio.

356
00:29:40,737 --> 00:29:43,781
Did all those people die in wars?

357
00:29:43,866 --> 00:29:46,784
Most ofthem. Didn't you ever hear
ofthe Arlington Cemetery?

358
00:29:46,869 --> 00:29:48,786
No, l'm afraid not.

359
00:29:48,871 --> 00:29:52,081
You don't seem to know much about
anything, do you, Mr. Carpenter?

360
00:29:52,166 --> 00:29:56,627
Well, l'll tell you, Bobby―
l've been away a long time. Very far away.

361
00:29:56,712 --> 00:30:00,298
ls it different where you've been?
Don't they have places like this?

362
00:30:00,382 --> 00:30:02,967
They have cemeteries,
but not like this one.

363
00:30:03,051 --> 00:30:05,761
You see, they don't have any wars.

364
00:30:05,846 --> 00:30:07,847
Gee, that's a good idea.

365
00:30:09,141 --> 00:30:11,142
What would you
like to do this afternoon?

366
00:30:11,226 --> 00:30:13,144
- Go to the movies.
- All right.

367
00:30:13,228 --> 00:30:16,189
- No foolin'? Will ya?
- No foolin'.

368
00:30:16,273 --> 00:30:20,651
Bobby, tell me, do you have to
have money to go there?

369
00:30:20,736 --> 00:30:22,904
l've got two dollars.
Mom gave it to me.

370
00:30:22,988 --> 00:30:25,364
No. l want to take you to the movie.

371
00:30:25,449 --> 00:30:27,533
Do you think they'd accept these?

372
00:30:30,245 --> 00:30:32,622
Gee, they look like diamonds.

373
00:30:32,706 --> 00:30:35,458
ln some places, those are
what people use for money.

374
00:30:35,542 --> 00:30:37,793
They're easy to carry
and they don't wear out.

375
00:30:37,878 --> 00:30:40,421
l'll bet they're worth a million dollars.

376
00:30:40,506 --> 00:30:43,007
Would you give me your two dollars
for two ofthese?

377
00:30:43,091 --> 00:30:45,593
Well, sure.

378
00:30:46,595 --> 00:30:48,554
Okay.

379
00:30:50,224 --> 00:30:52,934
Let's not say anything to Mom
about this though, huh?

380
00:30:53,018 --> 00:30:56,854
- Why not, Bobby?
- She doesn't like me to steal from people.

381
00:30:59,650 --> 00:31:01,609
Golly.

382
00:31:20,837 --> 00:31:22,797
Those are great words.

383
00:31:24,800 --> 00:31:27,969
- He must have been a great man.
- Well, sure.

384
00:31:41,066 --> 00:31:43,734
That's the kind of man
l'd like to talk to.

385
00:31:45,487 --> 00:31:48,573
Bobby, who's the greatest man
in America today?

386
00:31:48,657 --> 00:31:51,033
Oh, l don't know.
Spaceman, l guess.

387
00:31:52,119 --> 00:31:54,078
No, l was speaking of earthmen.

388
00:31:54,162 --> 00:31:56,247
l meant the greatest philosopher,
the greatest thinker.

389
00:31:56,331 --> 00:31:58,666
Oh, you mean the smartest man
in the whole world.

390
00:31:58,750 --> 00:32:01,752
- Yes, that would do nicely.
- Professor Barnhardt, l guess.

391
00:32:01,837 --> 00:32:03,796
He's the greatest scientist
in the whole world.

392
00:32:03,880 --> 00:32:05,923
He lives right here in Washington,
doesn't he?

393
00:32:06,008 --> 00:32:07,967
- Right near where my mom works.
- Where's that?

394
00:32:08,051 --> 00:32:10,595
Department ofCommerce.
She's a secretary.

395
00:32:10,679 --> 00:32:12,763
That man they call the secretary
isn't at all.

396
00:32:12,848 --> 00:32:15,808
My mom's a real secretary.

397
00:32:15,892 --> 00:32:19,562
Mr. Carpenter,
now can we go see the spaceship?

398
00:32:19,646 --> 00:32:21,564
lfyou like.

399
00:32:35,370 --> 00:32:37,413
l'll bet that iron guy's strong.

400
00:32:37,497 --> 00:32:40,875
- l'll bet he could
knock down a whole building.
- l shouldn't be surprised.

401
00:32:40,959 --> 00:32:43,961
l'd like to get inside that ship,
see how it works.

402
00:32:44,046 --> 00:32:46,631
What do you think makes it go?

403
00:32:46,715 --> 00:32:50,635
Well, a highly developed form
ofatomic power, l should imagine.

404
00:32:50,719 --> 00:32:52,803
l thought that was only for bombs.

405
00:32:52,888 --> 00:32:56,015
No. No, it's for
lots ofother things too.

406
00:32:56,099 --> 00:32:58,976
You think it can go faster
than the F-86?

407
00:32:59,061 --> 00:33:01,812
- Yes, l should think so.
- About a thousand miles an hour?

408
00:33:01,897 --> 00:33:07,234
Maybe 4,000 miles an hour. And outside
the Earth's atmosphere, a good deal faster.

409
00:33:07,319 --> 00:33:09,320
How could they make a landing?

410
00:33:09,404 --> 00:33:11,781
Well, there are several ways
to reduce landing speed.

411
00:33:11,865 --> 00:33:15,242
You see, the basic problem
is to overcome the inertia and―

412
00:33:16,870 --> 00:33:19,955
Keep going, mister.
He was fallin' for it.

413
00:33:20,040 --> 00:33:21,957
Right.

414
00:33:24,086 --> 00:33:26,003
Thank you, Mrs. Robinson.

415
00:33:26,088 --> 00:33:29,173
l'm sure we've all shared your fears
during the past few days.

416
00:33:29,257 --> 00:33:31,342
l see a gentleman here
with his little boy.

417
00:33:31,426 --> 00:33:33,678
What do you think ofthe spaceship, son?

418
00:33:33,762 --> 00:33:36,722
lt's the biggest spaceship l ever saw.

419
00:33:36,807 --> 00:33:41,018
- And you, sir, mind telling us your name?
- My name is Carpenter.

420
00:33:41,103 --> 00:33:43,104
Would you care to say a few words,
Mr. Carpenter?

421
00:33:43,188 --> 00:33:45,523
l suppose you'rejust as scared
as the rest of us.

422
00:33:45,607 --> 00:33:50,986
ln a different way perhaps. l am fearful when
l see people substituting fear for reason.

423
00:33:51,071 --> 00:33:53,781
- ln fact, l would like―
- Uh, thankyou, Mr. Carpenter.

424
00:33:53,865 --> 00:33:56,826
Thankyou very much. l see another
gentleman over here in the crowd.

425
00:33:56,910 --> 00:33:59,286
Extra! Extra! Spaceman eludes police!

426
00:33:59,371 --> 00:34:01,997
Army put in charge!
Read all about it!

427
00:34:02,082 --> 00:34:05,334
Spaceman eludes police! extra! Extra!

428
00:34:05,419 --> 00:34:09,046
- Five new spaceman suspects!
- Get your paper here!

429
00:34:09,131 --> 00:34:13,050
Army put in charge!
Extra! Extra! Read all about it!

430
00:34:13,135 --> 00:34:16,220
- You think they'll ever find him?
- l don't know, Bobby.

431
00:34:16,304 --> 00:34:18,723
l'm inclined to doubt it.

432
00:34:18,807 --> 00:34:21,809
Mr. Carpenter,
what does "inertia" mean?

433
00:34:21,893 --> 00:34:25,020
lnertia is the property of matter
by which it remains in uniform motion...

434
00:34:25,105 --> 00:34:27,732
unless acted upon by external force.

435
00:34:27,816 --> 00:34:31,736
Oh. l'll bet that'sjust the way
Professor Barnhardt talks.

436
00:34:33,155 --> 00:34:35,114
Bobby, l have an idea.

437
00:34:35,198 --> 00:34:38,534
Let's go and see Professor Barnhardt
and find out how he talks.

438
00:34:38,618 --> 00:34:41,412
- You're kidding, aren't you?
- Wouldn't you like to meet him?

439
00:34:41,496 --> 00:34:44,874
Sure, l would, but―
Ah, l bet you'd be scared.

440
00:34:44,958 --> 00:34:48,377
Maybe we can scare him
more than he can scare us.

441
00:34:48,462 --> 00:34:51,464
l like you, Mr. Carpenter.
You're a real screwball.

442
00:34:54,801 --> 00:34:58,262
Extra! Extra! Spaceman still at large!

443
00:34:58,346 --> 00:35:02,016
Extra! Read all about it!
Get your paper here!

445
00:35:12,277 --> 00:35:14,278
Maybe he isn't home.

446
00:35:21,953 --> 00:35:24,288
Gee, l'll bet you this is where he works!

447
00:35:45,852 --> 00:35:48,229
What's that stuff
on the blackboard mean?

448
00:35:48,313 --> 00:35:50,815
lt's a problem in celestial mechanics.

449
00:35:50,899 --> 00:35:53,484
l'll bet he's the only one in the world
that knows the answer.

450
00:35:53,568 --> 00:35:56,737
He doesn't know the answer,
and he'll never get it that way.

451
00:36:00,700 --> 00:36:03,828
We probably couldn't get to see him
even if he was home.

453
00:36:09,793 --> 00:36:11,710
Hey, where are you goin'?

454
00:36:11,795 --> 00:36:15,297
lf he's that difficult to see,
perhaps we ought to leave a calling card.

455
00:36:30,355 --> 00:36:32,356
Did he do it wrong?

456
00:36:32,440 --> 00:36:34,441
Hejust needs a little help.

457
00:36:48,540 --> 00:36:51,292
What are you doing in here?

458
00:36:52,919 --> 00:36:56,088
How dare you write on that blackboard!

459
00:36:56,172 --> 00:36:59,550
Do you realize the professor's been
working on that problem for weeks?

460
00:36:59,634 --> 00:37:01,886
He'll solve it in no time now.

461
00:37:01,970 --> 00:37:04,305
How did you get in here,
and what do you want?

462
00:37:04,389 --> 00:37:06,307
We came to see Professor Barnhardt.

463
00:37:06,391 --> 00:37:09,143
He's not here,
and he won't be back till this evening.

464
00:37:14,316 --> 00:37:16,317
l thinkyou'd better leave now.

465
00:37:23,366 --> 00:37:26,619
Would you give this to the professor?

466
00:37:26,703 --> 00:37:29,038
l think he'll want to talk to me.

467
00:37:41,426 --> 00:37:45,429
l wouldn't erase that.
The professor needs it very badly.

469
00:38:17,963 --> 00:38:20,255
- Mr. Carpenter come home yet?
- Yeah. He's right inside.

470
00:38:20,340 --> 00:38:22,591
- Tell him l'd like to see him.
- Okay. Come on in.

471
00:38:28,264 --> 00:38:32,768
- Your name Carpenter?
- Yes. l suppose Professor Barnhardt's
been looking for me.

472
00:38:32,852 --> 00:38:35,104
l've been looking foryou all afternoon.

473
00:38:42,737 --> 00:38:44,697
Thankyou.

474
00:38:48,076 --> 00:38:51,996
- lt was a wonderful day.
- You still haven't answered my question.

475
00:38:52,080 --> 00:38:54,999
You know how l feel, Tom.

476
00:38:55,083 --> 00:38:57,376
But l just want to think it over.

477
00:38:57,460 --> 00:38:59,503
The boss is leaving for Chicago
tomorrow.

478
00:38:59,587 --> 00:39:03,007
lf l could tell him that l was getting married
and had two dependents―

479
00:39:03,091 --> 00:39:07,052
You're a good salesman.
But l've got to think about it.

480
00:39:07,137 --> 00:39:10,639
A good insurance salesman wouldn't
give you time to think about it.

481
00:39:12,934 --> 00:39:15,394
- Good night.
- Good night.

482
00:39:24,279 --> 00:39:26,196
- Oh, hiya, Mom.
- Hello, darling.

483
00:39:26,281 --> 00:39:29,116
- Good evening, Mr. Carpenter.
- Good evening.

484
00:39:29,200 --> 00:39:32,036
- Uh, Mrs. Benson, this is Mr. Brady.
- How do you do?

485
00:39:32,120 --> 00:39:35,122
- How do you do?
- Mr. Brady's a government agent.

486
00:39:37,292 --> 00:39:40,627
- Have a nice day, dear?
- We had a swell time!
Didn't we, Mr. Carpenter?

487
00:39:40,712 --> 00:39:44,048
- Yes, we did.
- We went to the movies
and had some ice cream cones.

488
00:39:44,132 --> 00:39:46,383
And then we went to see Daddy.

489
00:39:46,468 --> 00:39:48,385
l don't know how to thankyou.

490
00:39:48,470 --> 00:39:50,512
l enjoyed every minute of it.

491
00:39:50,597 --> 00:39:53,265
We, uh, better get going,
Mr. Carpenter.

492
00:39:54,559 --> 00:39:57,269
Aw, gee.
You didn't finish your story.

493
00:39:57,353 --> 00:40:00,022
l'll finish it tomorrow.
Good night, Bobby. Good night.

494
00:40:00,106 --> 00:40:02,107
- Good night.
- Good night.

495
00:40:10,575 --> 00:40:12,826
Come on, dear. Time to go to bed.

496
00:40:14,704 --> 00:40:17,915
Why did Mr. Carpenter
have to go with Mr. Brady?

497
00:40:17,999 --> 00:40:20,334
l don't know.
Maybe it was a mistake.

498
00:40:20,418 --> 00:40:24,171
Oh. We sure had fun today.

499
00:40:24,255 --> 00:40:27,299
We saw the spaceship,
and we went to see Professor Barnhardt.

500
00:40:27,383 --> 00:40:29,885
- Professor Barnhardt?
- Yeah, sure.

501
00:40:29,969 --> 00:40:34,473
- Mom, do l have to go to school tomorrow?
- Yes, ofcourse, dear.

502
00:40:34,557 --> 00:40:38,227
Gee. l was hoping l could go out
with Mr. Carpenter again.

504
00:40:46,820 --> 00:40:49,279
Oh, come in.
The professor's in his study.

505
00:40:49,364 --> 00:40:51,281
Thank you.

507
00:40:59,457 --> 00:41:02,709
This is the man you wanted to see,
Professor.

508
00:41:02,794 --> 00:41:05,420
- Thankyou, Captain.
- l'll wait outside.

509
00:41:06,923 --> 00:41:08,841
You wrote this?

510
00:41:08,925 --> 00:41:11,426
lt was a clumsy way
to introduce myself...

511
00:41:11,511 --> 00:41:14,555
but l understand
you're a difficult man to see.

512
00:41:14,639 --> 00:41:17,349
- l thought you'd have
the solution by this time.
- Not yet.

513
00:41:17,433 --> 00:41:19,351
That's why l wanted to see you.

514
00:41:19,435 --> 00:41:23,147
All you have to do now is to substitute
this expression at this point.

515
00:41:23,231 --> 00:41:25,816
Yes, that will reproduce
the first altered term.

516
00:41:25,900 --> 00:41:29,153
- But what about
the effect ofthe other terms?
- Almost negligible.

517
00:41:29,237 --> 00:41:32,072
With variation of parameters,
this is the answer.

518
00:41:32,157 --> 00:41:36,660
How can you be so sure?
Have you tested this theory?

519
00:41:36,744 --> 00:41:39,746
l find it works well enough to get me
from one planet to another.

520
00:41:43,960 --> 00:41:45,961
l am Klaatu.

521
00:41:47,297 --> 00:41:49,506
l spent two days
at your Walter Reed Hospital.

522
00:41:49,591 --> 00:41:51,842
Room 309.

523
00:41:51,926 --> 00:41:53,927
My doctor's name was Major White.

524
00:41:55,889 --> 00:41:59,099
And ifyou're not interested, or ifyou
intend to turn me over to your army...

525
00:41:59,184 --> 00:42:01,101
we needn't waste any more time.

526
00:42:11,613 --> 00:42:15,908
You may go now, Captain.
Please thank General Cutler and tell him―

527
00:42:15,992 --> 00:42:18,660
Tell him that l know this gentleman.

528
00:42:20,747 --> 00:42:22,706
You have faith, Professor Barnhardt.

529
00:42:22,790 --> 00:42:26,084
lt isn't faith that makes good science,
Mr. Klaatu. lt's curiosity.

530
00:42:26,169 --> 00:42:29,129
Sit down, please.

531
00:42:29,214 --> 00:42:33,592
There are several thousand questions
l'd like to ask you.

532
00:42:34,928 --> 00:42:37,179
l would like to explain something
of my mission here.

533
00:42:37,263 --> 00:42:39,223
That was my first question.

534
00:42:39,307 --> 00:42:42,100
We know from scientific observation
that your planet...

535
00:42:42,185 --> 00:42:45,437
has discovered a rudimentary
kind ofatomic energy.

536
00:42:45,521 --> 00:42:49,149
- We also know that you're
experimenting with rockets.
- Yes. That is true.

537
00:42:50,526 --> 00:42:53,028
So long as you were limited
to fighting among yourselves...

538
00:42:53,112 --> 00:42:55,697
with your primitive tanks
and aircraft...

539
00:42:55,782 --> 00:42:57,741
we were unconcerned.

540
00:42:57,825 --> 00:43:01,995
But soon, one ofyour nations
will apply atomic energy to spaceships.

541
00:43:02,080 --> 00:43:06,124
That will create a threat to the peace
and security ofother planets.

542
00:43:06,209 --> 00:43:08,210
That, ofcourse, we cannot tolerate.

543
00:43:08,294 --> 00:43:11,505
What exactly is the nature
ofyour mission, Mr. Klaatu?

544
00:43:12,757 --> 00:43:15,384
l came here to warn you
that by threatening danger...

545
00:43:15,468 --> 00:43:17,386
your planet faces danger.

546
00:43:17,470 --> 00:43:19,513
Very grave danger.

547
00:43:19,597 --> 00:43:21,890
l'm prepared, however,
to offer a solution.

548
00:43:21,975 --> 00:43:23,934
Would you care to be more specific?

549
00:43:24,018 --> 00:43:28,438
What l have to say
must be said to all concerned.

550
00:43:28,523 --> 00:43:32,067
lt is too important to be entrusted
to any individual.

551
00:43:38,533 --> 00:43:42,244
l gather that your efforts on the official level
were not entirely successful.

552
00:43:42,328 --> 00:43:44,288
l come to you as a last resort...

553
00:43:44,372 --> 00:43:46,790
and l confess my patience is wearing thin.

554
00:43:46,874 --> 00:43:49,710
Must l take drastic action
in order to get a hearing?

555
00:43:49,794 --> 00:43:52,337
What― What sort ofaction
do you mean?

556
00:43:52,422 --> 00:43:56,383
Violent action, since that seems to be
the only thing your people understand.

557
00:43:56,467 --> 00:43:58,802
Leveling New York City perhaps?

558
00:43:58,886 --> 00:44:01,138
Or sinking the Rock ofGibraltar.

559
00:44:09,397 --> 00:44:12,899
Would you be willing to meet with
a group ofscientists l'm calling together?

560
00:44:12,984 --> 00:44:16,153
Perhaps you could explain your mission
to them, and they, in turn...

561
00:44:16,237 --> 00:44:18,238
could present it to their various peoples.

562
00:44:18,323 --> 00:44:20,615
That's why l came to see you.

563
00:44:20,700 --> 00:44:23,452
lt is not enough to have men ofscience.

564
00:44:23,536 --> 00:44:26,955
We scientists are too often ignored
or misunderstood.

565
00:44:27,040 --> 00:44:29,666
We must get leaders from every field―

566
00:44:29,751 --> 00:44:31,960
the finest minds in the world.

567
00:44:32,045 --> 00:44:34,046
l leave that in your hands.

568
00:44:35,506 --> 00:44:37,716
One thing, Mr. Klaatu.

569
00:44:37,800 --> 00:44:41,303
Suppose this group
should reject your proposals.

570
00:44:41,387 --> 00:44:43,305
What is the alternative?

571
00:44:43,389 --> 00:44:45,640
l'm afraid there is no alternative.

572
00:44:45,725 --> 00:44:49,269
ln such a case, the planet Earth
would have to be... eliminated.

573
00:44:51,022 --> 00:44:53,648
Such power exists?

574
00:44:53,733 --> 00:44:56,610
l assure you, such power exists.

575
00:44:58,112 --> 00:45:02,449
The people who come to the meeting
must be made to realize this.

576
00:45:02,533 --> 00:45:05,035
They must understand what is at stake.

577
00:45:06,829 --> 00:45:09,373
- You mentioned a demonstration offorce.
- Yes.

578
00:45:09,457 --> 00:45:12,918
- Would such a demonstration
be possible before the meeting?
- Yes, ofcourse.

579
00:45:13,002 --> 00:45:15,545
Something that would dramatize
for them and for their people...

580
00:45:15,630 --> 00:45:17,881
the seriousness ofthe situation.

581
00:45:17,965 --> 00:45:21,760
- Something that would
affect the entire planet.
- That can easily be arranged.

582
00:45:21,844 --> 00:45:24,429
l wouldn't want you to harm anybody
or destroy anything.

583
00:45:24,514 --> 00:45:27,933
Why don't you leave it to me?
l'll think ofsomething.

584
00:45:28,017 --> 00:45:30,894
Maybe... a little demonstration.

585
00:45:30,978 --> 00:45:34,564
Something dramatic but not destructive.

586
00:45:36,484 --> 00:45:39,111
That's quite an interesting problem.

587
00:45:39,195 --> 00:45:41,446
Would the day after tomorrow
be all right?

588
00:45:41,531 --> 00:45:43,824
Say, about noon?

589
00:45:51,499 --> 00:45:53,792
There have actually
been no further developments...

590
00:45:53,876 --> 00:45:56,878
but police and the F.B.l.
are tracing every possible clue...

591
00:45:56,963 --> 00:45:58,880
and rounding up all possible suspects.

592
00:45:58,965 --> 00:46:01,299
- Rummy!
- This is the greatest manhunt
in the nation's history.

593
00:46:01,384 --> 00:46:04,261
- Did it again.
- Take a hand, Mr. Carpenter?

594
00:46:04,345 --> 00:46:07,347
Take a― Oh. No, thanks. We d―

595
00:46:07,432 --> 00:46:10,767
- Speculation was aroused today
when Professor Barnhardt―
- No, thanks.

596
00:46:10,852 --> 00:46:13,895
- Are you going out, dear?
- Yes. Tom's picking me up.

597
00:46:13,980 --> 00:46:17,524
Well, personally,
l wouldn't go out after dark these days...

598
00:46:17,608 --> 00:46:20,318
but, uh, then l'm not courting, am l?

599
00:46:20,403 --> 00:46:22,404
...the latest developments.

600
00:46:24,490 --> 00:46:28,160
Oh! Oh, Mr. Carpenter.

601
00:46:34,917 --> 00:46:36,918
Everyone seems so―

602
00:46:38,004 --> 00:46:40,589
"Jittery" is the word.

603
00:46:42,091 --> 00:46:45,260
Bobby's the only person
l know who isn't...jittery.

604
00:46:45,344 --> 00:46:47,804
Well, he has his homework
to keep him occupied.

605
00:46:47,889 --> 00:46:49,890
He's a fine boy, Mrs. Benson.

606
00:46:49,974 --> 00:46:53,602
- Naturally, l think so.
- Warm, friendly, intelligent.

607
00:46:55,563 --> 00:46:59,816
Mr. Carpenter,
this is none of my business...

608
00:46:59,901 --> 00:47:02,402
but why did that man
come here last night?

609
00:47:02,487 --> 00:47:05,238
Oh, theyjust wanted to
ask me a few questions.

610
00:47:05,323 --> 00:47:09,784
Bobby and l tried to see Professor Barnhardt
in the afternoon, and he wasn't in.

611
00:47:09,869 --> 00:47:13,497
Apparently, they thought l was
looking for secrets ofsome kind.

613
00:47:16,083 --> 00:47:18,001
Excuse me.

616
00:47:27,220 --> 00:47:29,262
- Hello.
- Hello. Are you ready?

617
00:47:29,347 --> 00:47:31,681
- l will be in a minute.
- The picture starts at 8:50.

618
00:47:31,766 --> 00:47:33,767
l wasjust talking to Mr. Carpenter.

619
00:47:33,851 --> 00:47:36,353
- Well, l hope Mr. Carpenter
won't think l'm intruding.
- Shh.

620
00:47:36,437 --> 00:47:38,605
What? Good evening.

621
00:47:38,689 --> 00:47:41,775
excuse me.
l wasjust going up to my room.

622
00:47:41,859 --> 00:47:43,860
Good night, Mr. Carpenter.

623
00:47:43,945 --> 00:47:45,904
Have a good time, both ofyou.

624
00:47:45,988 --> 00:47:48,031
- Thankyou.
- Thankyou.

625
00:47:48,115 --> 00:47:50,617
Why don't you wait in here
while l get my things?

626
00:47:50,701 --> 00:47:52,702
- Tom, that was awful.
- l'm sorry.

627
00:47:52,787 --> 00:47:55,205
- l guess l'm tired of hearing
about Mr. Carpenter.
- Tom!

628
00:47:55,289 --> 00:47:57,874
l don't like the way he's attached himself
to you and Bobby.

629
00:47:57,959 --> 00:48:00,460
After all,
what do you know about him?

630
00:48:02,296 --> 00:48:04,297
l'll go get my things.

631
00:48:18,396 --> 00:48:23,191
All you have to remember is first find
the common denominator and then divide.

632
00:48:23,276 --> 00:48:25,277
Thanks, Mr. Carpenter.

633
00:48:26,654 --> 00:48:29,447
- l'll say good night again.
- Mr. Carpenter―

634
00:48:29,532 --> 00:48:31,491
l―

635
00:48:33,286 --> 00:48:35,787
- Good night.
- Good night, Mrs. Benson.

636
00:48:37,498 --> 00:48:39,958
Go to bed now, darling.
You can finish that in the morning.

637
00:48:40,042 --> 00:48:42,002
Okay.

638
00:48:45,256 --> 00:48:47,507
Bobby.

639
00:48:47,592 --> 00:48:50,010
l think it would be better...

640
00:48:50,094 --> 00:48:52,637
ifwe didn't see quite so much
of Mr. Carpenter.

641
00:48:52,722 --> 00:48:55,181
Gee, why, Mom?
He's my best friend.

642
00:48:55,266 --> 00:48:59,269
And he's awful good in arithmetic.
He even helps Professor Barnhardt.

643
00:48:59,353 --> 00:49:01,938
Did you and Mr. Carpenter really
go see Professor Barnhardt?

644
00:49:02,023 --> 00:49:04,816
Sure we did. He wasn't there,
but we went to see him.

645
00:49:04,900 --> 00:49:07,902
Mr. Carpenter showed him
how to do his arithmetic.

646
00:49:10,197 --> 00:49:13,533
Mom? Something wrong
with Mr. Carpenter?

647
00:49:13,618 --> 00:49:16,286
- What do you mean, dear?
- On account of last night.

648
00:49:16,370 --> 00:49:19,956
You think he's a bank robber
or a gangster maybe?

649
00:49:20,041 --> 00:49:22,000
No, dear, ofcourse not.

650
00:49:22,084 --> 00:49:24,294
He's a very nice man.

651
00:49:24,378 --> 00:49:28,089
l just think that he might prefer
to be left alone, that's all.

652
00:49:28,174 --> 00:49:31,259
Now, you go to bed and forget about it.
Good night, darling.

653
00:49:31,344 --> 00:49:33,261
Good night.

654
00:49:34,347 --> 00:49:36,264
Mom?

655
00:49:37,767 --> 00:49:40,977
Why would he want to be left alone?

656
00:49:41,062 --> 00:49:43,563
Don't forget to brush your teeth.

658
00:50:11,300 --> 00:50:13,927
- Bobby, have you a flashlight?
- Yeah.

659
00:50:18,099 --> 00:50:20,517
- lt's a real Boy Scout one.
- Fine.

660
00:50:22,728 --> 00:50:25,814
- Here. All you gotta do is push up on it, see?
- Oh.

661
00:50:25,898 --> 00:50:27,816
What do you need it for?

662
00:50:27,900 --> 00:50:30,652
- l― Um, the lights in my room went out.
- Oh.

663
00:50:30,736 --> 00:50:33,154
l must tell you sometime
about another kind oftrain...

664
00:50:33,239 --> 00:50:35,156
the kind that doesn't need any tracks.

665
00:50:35,241 --> 00:50:37,158
- Really?
- Really.

666
00:50:37,243 --> 00:50:40,245
- Remind me in the morning.
l'll tell you all about them.
- Okay!

668
00:50:50,715 --> 00:50:52,632
No tracks?

670
00:54:58,212 --> 00:55:00,213
Gort! Berenga.

673
00:56:58,540 --> 00:57:01,501
Come in for a minute.

674
00:57:01,585 --> 00:57:04,587
Bobby, what are you doing
up at this hour?

675
00:57:04,671 --> 00:57:07,507
- l couldn't sleep, Mom. l had to tell you.
- Tell me what?

676
00:57:07,591 --> 00:57:11,052
Well, afteryou left, l followed Mr. Carpenter,
and where do you think he went?

677
00:57:11,136 --> 00:57:14,722
- Right into the spaceship.
- Now, Bobby, wait a minute.

678
00:57:14,807 --> 00:57:18,101
Honest, Mom. l saw him.
lt opened up, and he walked right in.

679
00:57:18,185 --> 00:57:20,645
And that big iron fella
was walkin' around too.

680
00:57:20,729 --> 00:57:23,898
- Bobby, you've been dreaming again.
- No, l haven't, Mom.

681
00:57:23,982 --> 00:57:27,110
Honest. l promise you, l saw him.

682
00:57:27,194 --> 00:57:29,195
Where'd you see all this, Bobby?

683
00:57:29,279 --> 00:57:32,615
On the lawn, down at the mall,
in that place with the soldiers out in front.

684
00:57:32,699 --> 00:57:34,700
Where were the soldiers all this time?

685
00:57:34,785 --> 00:57:37,495
That big iron guy grabbed 'em
and knocked 'em out.

686
00:57:37,579 --> 00:57:40,414
l like Mr. Carpenter, Mom.
l'm kind ofscared.

687
00:57:40,499 --> 00:57:43,376
Now, don't be frightened, darling.
lt was only a bad dream.

688
00:57:43,460 --> 00:57:47,338
We'll prove it to you. Tom, will you ask
Mr. Carpenter to come down for a minute?

689
00:57:47,422 --> 00:57:49,590
- Sure.
- He's in the room next to mine.

690
00:57:49,675 --> 00:57:53,219
- Okay.
- Now, think back hard.

691
00:57:53,303 --> 00:57:55,346
You didn't follow Mr. Carpenter at all,
did you?

692
00:57:55,430 --> 00:57:57,640
- You haven't even been out ofthe house.
- Yes, l have!

693
00:57:57,724 --> 00:58:00,893
Now, you didn't really see a spaceship,
but you thought you did.

694
00:58:00,978 --> 00:58:03,563
l'd never call you a liar.

695
00:58:51,403 --> 00:58:55,364
He's not there,
but look what l found in his room.

696
00:58:55,449 --> 00:58:57,408
- ls it real?
- Well, it looks real to me.

697
00:58:57,492 --> 00:58:59,493
Well, Mr. Carpenter's got
lots ofdiamonds.

698
00:58:59,578 --> 00:59:01,495
He gave me a couple ofthem.

699
00:59:02,915 --> 00:59:05,708
- He gave these to you?
- Well, not exactly.

700
00:59:05,792 --> 00:59:07,835
l gave him two dollars.

701
00:59:08,837 --> 00:59:10,880
This doesn't make sense.

702
00:59:10,964 --> 00:59:13,758
l think the guy's a crook.
l never did trust him.

703
00:59:13,842 --> 00:59:16,719
Gee, Mom. You think maybe
he's a diamond smuggler?

704
00:59:16,803 --> 00:59:18,846
Come on, darling.
You're going up to bed now.

705
00:59:18,931 --> 00:59:22,850
- l wonder ifwe ought to―
- Bobby and l have had enough
excitement for tonight.

706
00:59:22,935 --> 00:59:25,186
Do you think it's all right
foryou to stay here?

707
00:59:25,270 --> 00:59:27,188
Yeah.
l've got a good lock on my door.

708
00:59:27,272 --> 00:59:29,357
- Bobby's gonna sleep in my room tonight.
- Okay.

709
00:59:29,441 --> 00:59:31,525
Come on now. Up to bed with you.

710
00:59:31,610 --> 00:59:33,986
Bobby. Your shoes are soaking.

711
00:59:34,071 --> 00:59:36,739
Yeah. The grass was kind ofwet.

712
00:59:43,705 --> 00:59:46,290
- l'm going now, Helen.
- All right.

715
00:59:57,844 --> 00:59:59,762
Hello.

716
00:59:59,846 --> 01:00:01,764
May l see you for a minute?

717
01:00:01,848 --> 01:00:03,766
Well, l'm just going to lunch.

718
01:00:03,850 --> 01:00:05,768
- May l walk out with you?
- Well―

720
01:00:12,401 --> 01:00:14,568
Mrs. Benson speaking.

721
01:00:14,653 --> 01:00:18,114
- Oh, hello.
- l'm at Bleeker's to get an appraisal
on that diamond.

722
01:00:18,198 --> 01:00:21,367
- l thought we might have lunch together.
- Can l talk to you later?

723
01:00:22,452 --> 01:00:25,329
Oh, that'll be fine. Bye.

724
01:00:36,675 --> 01:00:39,302
l saw Bobby this morning
before he went to school.

725
01:00:39,386 --> 01:00:42,430
- Yes?
- l'd like to know what he told you last night.

726
01:00:42,514 --> 01:00:44,598
Oh, l really didn't pay much attention.

727
01:00:44,683 --> 01:00:46,642
Bobby has such an active imagination.

728
01:00:46,727 --> 01:00:49,895
Did you believe what he told you?

729
01:00:49,980 --> 01:00:53,232
l have a reason for asking this―
a very important reason.

730
01:00:56,320 --> 01:00:58,446
There's another elevator we can use.

731
01:01:09,499 --> 01:01:11,417
What is it you want?

732
01:01:11,501 --> 01:01:13,669
Before l askyou to be honest with me...

733
01:01:13,754 --> 01:01:16,130
perhaps l should be
completely honest with you.

734
01:01:17,758 --> 01:01:20,426
- What happened?
- What time is it?

735
01:01:21,720 --> 01:01:23,679
Just 1 2:00.

736
01:01:23,764 --> 01:01:27,391
We shall be here for a little while.
About 30 minutes.

737
01:01:29,770 --> 01:01:32,646
- Well, we can try pushing the other buttons.
- They won't work.

738
01:01:34,149 --> 01:01:38,819
- Why not?
- You see, the electricity's been neutralized―

739
01:01:38,904 --> 01:01:41,572
all over the world.

740
01:01:41,656 --> 01:01:43,783
Bobby was telling the truth, wasn't he?

741
01:01:45,494 --> 01:01:47,495
Yes.

742
01:02:14,648 --> 01:02:17,400
lt's that spaceman. That's what it is.

746
01:03:25,886 --> 01:03:29,305
You should see it, Professor Barnhardt.
You should go out and see it foryourself.

747
01:03:29,389 --> 01:03:31,557
Thanks. l am enjoying it right here.

748
01:03:31,641 --> 01:03:34,768
The whole city has stopped.
People are running around like ants.

749
01:03:34,853 --> 01:03:39,023
What a brilliant idea.
l never would have thought of it.

750
01:03:39,107 --> 01:03:41,734
What about the people
who are coming to the meeting tonight?

751
01:03:41,818 --> 01:03:43,777
- Have they all arrived?
- Yes. Here's the list.

752
01:03:43,862 --> 01:03:46,322
And l talked to most ofthem
on the phone this morning.

753
01:03:46,406 --> 01:03:48,616
- They're all very curious about the meeting.
- Good.

754
01:03:48,700 --> 01:03:52,536
- Did you speak to our friend Mr. Carpenter?
- He'll be there at 8:30.

755
01:03:52,621 --> 01:03:56,081
Tell me, Hilda.
Does all this frighten you?

756
01:03:56,166 --> 01:03:58,209
Does it make you feel insecure?

757
01:03:58,293 --> 01:04:00,211
Yes, sir, it certainly does.

758
01:04:00,295 --> 01:04:03,756
That's good, Hilda. l'm glad.

759
01:04:05,592 --> 01:04:08,385
As far as we can tell,
all power's been cut offeverywhere...

760
01:04:08,470 --> 01:04:11,263
with a few exceptions,
and even these exceptions are remarkable―

761
01:04:11,348 --> 01:04:15,017
Hospitals, planes in flight.
That sort ofthing.

762
01:04:15,101 --> 01:04:18,854
l wish l could give you more information, but
as you know, all communications are out―

763
01:04:18,939 --> 01:04:23,025
Telephones, radio, cable. Everything.

764
01:04:25,111 --> 01:04:27,613
Gentlemen,
l can tell you the president...

765
01:04:27,697 --> 01:04:29,907
is prepared to declare
a state of national emergency.

767
01:04:38,041 --> 01:04:40,042
Oh, Eleanor,
did you call the electrician?

768
01:04:40,126 --> 01:04:43,170
l tried, Mr. Bleeker,
but the phone doesn't work either.

769
01:04:43,255 --> 01:04:45,965
- Well, call the phone company.
- But the phone doesn't work.

770
01:04:46,049 --> 01:04:48,008
Oh.

772
01:04:50,470 --> 01:04:54,306
- ls it worth anything?
- l have never seen such a stone in all my life.

773
01:04:54,391 --> 01:04:56,350
Will you please tell me
where it came from?

774
01:04:56,434 --> 01:04:58,352
That's what l want you to tell me.

775
01:04:58,436 --> 01:05:02,273
But there are no diamonds like this
anyplace in the world that l know of.

776
01:05:02,357 --> 01:05:05,568
- Are you sure ofthat?
- Uh, would you like to sell it?

777
01:05:05,652 --> 01:05:09,280
- No. No, thanks.
- l-l'd give you a very good price.

778
01:05:09,364 --> 01:05:11,365
Thank you, no.

779
01:05:12,909 --> 01:05:15,286
l've already told you more
than l told Professor Barnhardt...

780
01:05:15,370 --> 01:05:18,914
because, in a sense,
my life is in your hands.

781
01:05:18,999 --> 01:05:21,417
l thought ifyou knew the facts,
you'd appreciate the importance...

782
01:05:21,501 --> 01:05:24,753
of my not being apprehended
before the meeting tonight.

783
01:05:24,838 --> 01:05:27,923
Ofcourse. Ofcourse l do.

784
01:05:29,009 --> 01:05:30,926
You hold great hope for this meeting.

785
01:05:31,011 --> 01:05:33,679
l can see no other hope foryour planet.

786
01:05:33,763 --> 01:05:37,141
lfthis meeting should fail,
then l'm afraid there is no hope.

787
01:05:38,810 --> 01:05:40,811
lt must be 1 2:30.

788
01:05:43,356 --> 01:05:45,274
Yes.

789
01:05:45,358 --> 01:05:47,985
Just exactly.

792
01:06:08,173 --> 01:06:10,466
- Where are you going now?
- Back to the boardinghouse.

793
01:06:10,550 --> 01:06:12,468
l'll be safe there for the afternoon.

794
01:06:12,552 --> 01:06:16,096
And l can keep an eye on Bobby. He's the only
other person who knows anything about―

795
01:06:16,181 --> 01:06:18,307
- No. Wait a minute. There's someone else.
- Who?

796
01:06:18,391 --> 01:06:21,393
Tom. He was there last night
when Bobby told me what he saw.

797
01:06:21,478 --> 01:06:23,395
Do you think he'd tell anyone?

798
01:06:23,480 --> 01:06:26,398
Well, l think he'd talk to me first
anyway, before―

799
01:06:27,734 --> 01:06:29,652
Well, we can't take any chance.

800
01:06:29,736 --> 01:06:32,571
l'll get in touch with him
right away to make sure.

801
01:06:34,783 --> 01:06:38,577
But l've got to talk to him. lt's terribly
important. When is he coming back?

802
01:06:38,662 --> 01:06:42,122
l don't know, Mrs. Benson.
He left before noon―

803
01:06:42,207 --> 01:06:44,249
before that awful electric business.

804
01:06:44,334 --> 01:06:47,002
l'm scared to death, Mrs. Benson. l―

805
01:06:47,087 --> 01:06:51,298
No. He wouldn't tell me where he was going.
Said it was something personal.

806
01:06:51,383 --> 01:06:54,510
Well, please ask him
to call me the minute he gets in.

807
01:06:54,594 --> 01:06:56,595
Thanks.

808
01:06:59,974 --> 01:07:02,518
Before we start discussing plans,
l want a report from Colonel Ryder.

809
01:07:02,602 --> 01:07:04,978
What about the robot, Colonel?

810
01:07:05,063 --> 01:07:07,606
When it was discovered last night
that the robot had moved...

811
01:07:07,691 --> 01:07:11,610
l was directed by theJoint Chiefs
to find a means of immobilizing him.

812
01:07:11,695 --> 01:07:16,323
We accomplished that this morning
by encasing him in a block of KL-93.

813
01:07:16,408 --> 01:07:18,701
lt's a new plastic material
stronger than steel.

814
01:07:18,785 --> 01:07:20,703
lsn't it possible
he's broken out ofthis stuff?

815
01:07:20,787 --> 01:07:23,622
No, sir. Wejust checked on that.
He's locked up tight as a drum.

816
01:07:23,707 --> 01:07:26,875
All right. That means
we concentrate on the man.

817
01:07:26,960 --> 01:07:30,796
Up till now, we've agreed upon
the desirability ofcapturing this man alive.

818
01:07:30,880 --> 01:07:33,882
We can no longer afford
to be so particular.

819
01:07:33,967 --> 01:07:37,553
We'll get him, alive if possible,
but we must get him.

820
01:07:37,637 --> 01:07:40,681
ls that clear?

822
01:08:16,468 --> 01:08:19,011
Honest, Mary, l'm so scared,
l can't sit still.

823
01:08:19,095 --> 01:08:21,972
l'd like to run someplace,
but l don't know where to go.

824
01:08:22,056 --> 01:08:23,974
Bye now.

825
01:08:24,058 --> 01:08:25,976
Margaret, call the Pentagon.

826
01:08:26,060 --> 01:08:29,730
Find out who's in charge ofthis spaceman
business. Whoever it is, l want to talk to him.

827
01:08:29,814 --> 01:08:33,400
Mrs. Benson's been trying to get you
all afternoon. She says it's important.

828
01:08:33,485 --> 01:08:35,486
Get this other call first.

829
01:08:40,283 --> 01:08:42,743
- Oh, Mrs. Benson, hejust walked in.
- Oh, fine.

830
01:08:42,827 --> 01:08:45,245
- Are you nervous too?
- Yes, l am, Margaret.

831
01:08:45,330 --> 01:08:48,582
- Oh, Helen. Come on in.
- Tom, l've been trying
to get you all afternoon.

832
01:08:50,084 --> 01:08:52,795
l have some terrific news
about your friend Mr. Carpenter.

833
01:08:52,879 --> 01:08:55,339
- What about him?
- Helen, he's the man from the spaceship.

834
01:08:55,423 --> 01:08:57,758
l had that diamond checked
at three different places.

835
01:08:57,842 --> 01:09:00,010
Nobody's ever seen a stone like that.

836
01:09:00,094 --> 01:09:02,805
After what Bobby told us,
that's enough for me.

837
01:09:02,889 --> 01:09:05,808
Why is it nobody knows anything about him?
Why hasn't he got any money?

838
01:09:05,892 --> 01:09:08,936
All right, Tom. lt's true. l know it's true.

839
01:09:09,020 --> 01:09:11,146
- You― How do you know?
- Never mind about that.

840
01:09:11,231 --> 01:09:13,649
But you've got to promise me
you won't say a word to anybody.

841
01:09:13,733 --> 01:09:15,567
Are you crazy?
After what happened today?

842
01:09:15,652 --> 01:09:18,195
But you don't understand.
You don't realize how important this is.

843
01:09:18,279 --> 01:09:21,114
lmportant? Ofcourse it's important.
The point is we can do something about it.

844
01:09:21,199 --> 01:09:23,742
No, that's what l'm trying to tell you.
We mustn't do anything about it.

845
01:09:23,827 --> 01:09:25,828
Believe me, Tom.
l know what l'm talking about.

846
01:09:25,912 --> 01:09:28,664
He's a menace to the whole world.
lt's our duty to turn him in.

847
01:09:28,748 --> 01:09:31,667
But he isn't a menace.
He told me why he came here.

848
01:09:31,751 --> 01:09:34,336
He tol― He told you?

849
01:09:34,420 --> 01:09:38,006
Oh, don't be silly, honey,
just because you like the guy.

850
01:09:38,091 --> 01:09:40,259
You realize, ofcourse,
what this would mean to us.

851
01:09:40,343 --> 01:09:43,178
l could write my own ticket.
l'd be the biggest man in the country.

852
01:09:43,263 --> 01:09:45,180
ls that what you're thinking about?

853
01:09:45,265 --> 01:09:47,683
Why not? Somebody's gotta get rid of him.

854
01:09:47,767 --> 01:09:49,810
- l'm not going to let you do it.
- Yes?

855
01:09:49,894 --> 01:09:52,771
- Tom, this is the most
important thing in the world.
- What's his name, Margaret?

856
01:09:52,856 --> 01:09:54,940
General Cutler. Yes.

857
01:09:55,024 --> 01:09:57,901
- All right. l'll hold on.
- Tom, you mustn't.
You don't know what you're doing.

858
01:09:57,986 --> 01:10:00,821
lt isn'tjust you and Mr. Carpenter.
The rest ofthe world is involved.

859
01:10:00,905 --> 01:10:02,906
l don't care about the rest ofthe world.

860
01:10:05,827 --> 01:10:08,871
You'll feel different
when you see my picture in the papers.

861
01:10:08,955 --> 01:10:12,708
- l feel different right now.
- You wait and see.
You're gonna marry a big hero.

862
01:10:12,792 --> 01:10:15,085
- l'm not going to marry anybody.
- Helen, l―

863
01:10:15,169 --> 01:10:17,546
Hello, General Cutler? No, l don't―

864
01:10:17,630 --> 01:10:20,883
No, l don't want to speak to his aide.
l want to speak to the general.

865
01:10:20,967 --> 01:10:22,885
Tell him it's about the spaceman.

866
01:10:31,978 --> 01:10:34,104
That's right, General.
That's where he's staying.

867
01:10:34,188 --> 01:10:36,106
Yes. Ofcourse l'm sure.

868
01:10:36,190 --> 01:10:38,191
Thank you very much, Mr. Stevens.

869
01:10:38,276 --> 01:10:41,069
l want to talk to you further,
but l haven't time now.

870
01:10:41,154 --> 01:10:44,489
Deploy all Zone 5 units
according to Plan "B"― immediately.

872
01:11:32,705 --> 01:11:34,915
- Hello, Mrs. Benson.
- Hello, Sammy.

873
01:11:44,175 --> 01:11:47,594
Attention, all units. Attention, all units.

874
01:11:47,679 --> 01:11:50,597
When deployed according to Plan Baker...

875
01:11:50,682 --> 01:11:55,102
maintain station and remain
on radio alert until further orders.

877
01:12:45,987 --> 01:12:48,572
l'm sure Barnhardt can arrange
to hide me until the meeting.

878
01:12:48,656 --> 01:12:52,034
- Where's the meeting going to be?
- At the ship.

879
01:12:53,995 --> 01:12:57,789
Yeah. They got in a taxicab
and went offdown that street.

880
01:12:57,874 --> 01:12:59,875
Thank you, son.

881
01:13:01,335 --> 01:13:04,963
Attention, Zone 5.
Attention, Zone 5.

882
01:13:05,048 --> 01:13:08,425
Yellow Cab moving north on 1 4th Street
from Harvard Street.

883
01:13:08,509 --> 01:13:11,970
A man and woman in backseat.
Get license number and report.

885
01:13:20,730 --> 01:13:22,606
That's the one.

886
01:13:26,152 --> 01:13:28,737
Right. Attention, Zone 5.

887
01:13:28,821 --> 01:13:32,866
License number oftarget vehicle is H001 2.

888
01:13:32,950 --> 01:13:35,702
Hey.
Looks like something big's going on.

889
01:13:45,922 --> 01:13:49,466
Attention, Zone 5. Attention, Zone 5.

890
01:13:49,550 --> 01:13:51,843
Report when target vehicle
passes your position.

892
01:14:08,111 --> 01:14:11,947
- lt's only a few blocks to Barnhardt's.
- l'm worried about Gort.

893
01:14:12,031 --> 01:14:15,784
l'm afraid ofwhat he might do
ifanything should happen to me.

894
01:14:15,868 --> 01:14:19,746
Gort? But he's a robot.
Without you, what could he do?

895
01:14:19,831 --> 01:14:24,167
There's no limit to what he could do.
He could destroy the earth.

896
01:14:26,838 --> 01:14:30,799
lfanything should happen to me,
you must go to Gort.

897
01:14:30,883 --> 01:14:36,054
You must say these words:
Klaatu barada nikto.

898
01:14:36,139 --> 01:14:38,974
Please repeat that.

899
01:14:39,058 --> 01:14:41,101
Klaatu...

900
01:14:41,185 --> 01:14:43,311
barada nikto.

901
01:14:43,396 --> 01:14:45,647
You must remember those words.

902
01:14:45,731 --> 01:14:48,733
Klaatu...

903
01:14:48,818 --> 01:14:50,735
barada...

904
01:14:50,820 --> 01:14:52,737
nikto.

905
01:14:56,617 --> 01:14:59,619
Yellow Cab, license number H001 2...

906
01:14:59,704 --> 01:15:02,455
heading west
on 1 5th Street at Treasury Place.

907
01:15:07,795 --> 01:15:10,881
The target vehicle is turning west
into Massachusetts Avenue.

908
01:15:14,302 --> 01:15:17,637
Yellow Cab heading northwest
at Columbia Road and Connecticut.

909
01:15:17,722 --> 01:15:21,183
Repeat. Yellow Cab heading northwest
at Columbia Road and Connecticut.

910
01:15:21,267 --> 01:15:25,103
Attention, all units,
northwest area, Zone 5.

911
01:15:25,188 --> 01:15:28,398
Block offall streets intersecting
Connecticut Avenue...

912
01:15:28,482 --> 01:15:31,067
on a line from Wisconsin to the park.

913
01:15:31,152 --> 01:15:34,070
All vehicles close in. Let's go.

914
01:16:11,943 --> 01:16:13,693
Say, what's going on here?

915
01:16:14,779 --> 01:16:16,780
Dri―

917
01:16:33,256 --> 01:16:35,590
Get that message to Gort...

918
01:16:35,675 --> 01:16:38,093
- right away.
- All right.

922
01:16:58,864 --> 01:17:02,242
- Captain, move these people back.
- Yes, sir.

923
01:17:02,326 --> 01:17:05,537
See ifthey have a stretcher
at the police station. Take him there.

926
01:19:51,078 --> 01:19:53,663
Gort. Klaatu...

927
01:19:53,747 --> 01:19:57,041
barada nikto.

928
01:19:57,126 --> 01:20:01,254
Klaatu barada nikto.

931
01:22:13,470 --> 01:22:18,224
Yes, sir. Yes, we have the body here now,
locked in a cell.

932
01:22:18,309 --> 01:22:21,686
There's no question about it, General.
He's dead, all right.

933
01:22:21,770 --> 01:22:25,440
l understand. l'll be right there, sir.

934
01:22:25,524 --> 01:22:28,109
Bring in a squad of men, Lieutenant.
Place a guard around that cell.

935
01:22:28,193 --> 01:22:31,070
- Yes, sir.
- Captain, don't let anyone
in or out ofthe building.

936
01:22:31,155 --> 01:22:33,156
- Yes, sir.
- Come along.

938
01:24:35,696 --> 01:24:37,739
- Professor Barnhardt?
- Yes.

939
01:24:37,823 --> 01:24:40,908
l'm very sorry, but l have to askyou
to call offthis meeting.

940
01:24:40,993 --> 01:24:43,828
Call it off?
But l had permission from the army.

941
01:24:43,912 --> 01:24:47,582
l knowyou did, sir. But the robot's on
the loose now, and it's not safe around here.

942
01:24:47,666 --> 01:24:49,667
You'll have to get your people
out ofthis area.

949
01:26:24,012 --> 01:26:26,472
Hello.

950
01:26:26,557 --> 01:26:29,600
l― l thought you were―

951
01:26:30,894 --> 01:26:32,895
l was.

952
01:26:34,439 --> 01:26:36,440
You mean...

953
01:26:37,776 --> 01:26:39,902
he has the power of life and death?

954
01:26:39,987 --> 01:26:43,865
No. That power is reserved
to the Almighty Spirit.

955
01:26:43,949 --> 01:26:46,033
This technique, in some cases...

956
01:26:46,118 --> 01:26:48,411
can restore life for a limited period.

957
01:26:48,495 --> 01:26:50,413
But how long?

958
01:26:50,497 --> 01:26:53,040
You mean how long will l live?

959
01:26:53,125 --> 01:26:55,126
That no one can tell.

960
01:27:08,390 --> 01:27:11,392
Under the circumstances...

961
01:27:11,476 --> 01:27:15,646
the army people have asked us to leave...

962
01:27:15,731 --> 01:27:19,984
and since their concern
is for our safety...

963
01:27:20,068 --> 01:27:23,821
l can do nothing
but suggest that we comply.

965
01:27:57,689 --> 01:27:59,690
l am leaving soon.

966
01:27:59,775 --> 01:28:01,859
And you will forgive me
if l speak bluntly.

967
01:28:03,695 --> 01:28:07,073
The universe grows smaller every day...

968
01:28:07,157 --> 01:28:12,203
and the threat ofaggression by any group
anywhere can no longer be tolerated.

969
01:28:13,246 --> 01:28:15,373
There must be security for all...

970
01:28:15,457 --> 01:28:18,501

or no one is secure.

971
01:28:18,585 --> 01:28:21,087
Now, this does not mean
giving up any freedom...

972
01:28:21,171 --> 01:28:24,548
except the freedom to act irresponsibly.

973
01:28:26,134 --> 01:28:28,177
Your ancestors knew this...

974
01:28:28,261 --> 01:28:30,513
when they made laws
to govern themselves...

975
01:28:30,597 --> 01:28:33,474
and hired policemen to enforce them.

976
01:28:33,558 --> 01:28:36,769
We ofthe other planets
have long accepted this principle.

977
01:28:36,853 --> 01:28:39,814
We have an organization...

978
01:28:39,898 --> 01:28:42,650
for the mutual protection
ofall planets...

979
01:28:42,734 --> 01:28:44,944
and for the complete elimination
ofaggression.

980
01:28:46,697 --> 01:28:49,281
The test ofany such higher authority...

981
01:28:49,366 --> 01:28:51,409
is, ofcourse,
the police force that supports it.

982
01:28:52,995 --> 01:28:57,832
For our policemen,
we created a race of robots.

983
01:28:57,916 --> 01:29:02,378
Their function is to patrol the planets
in spaceships like this one...

984
01:29:02,462 --> 01:29:04,463
and preserve the peace.

985
01:29:04,548 --> 01:29:06,799
ln matters ofaggression...

986
01:29:06,883 --> 01:29:10,219
we have given them
absolute power over us.

987
01:29:10,303 --> 01:29:13,097
This power cannot be revoked.

988
01:29:13,181 --> 01:29:17,727
At the first sign ofviolence,
they act automatically against the aggressor.

989
01:29:17,811 --> 01:29:21,439
The penalty for provoking
their action...

990
01:29:21,523 --> 01:29:23,649
is too terrible to risk.

991
01:29:24,776 --> 01:29:26,694
The result is we live in peace...

992
01:29:26,778 --> 01:29:29,572
without arms or armies...

993
01:29:29,656 --> 01:29:32,700
secure in the knowledge that we
are free from aggression and war.

994
01:29:32,784 --> 01:29:36,620
Free to pursue
more profitable enterprises.

995
01:29:38,040 --> 01:29:41,709
We do not pretend
to have achieved perfection...

996
01:29:41,793 --> 01:29:43,878
but we do have a system...

997
01:29:43,962 --> 01:29:45,921
and it works.

998
01:29:46,923 --> 01:29:50,301
l came here to give you these facts.

999
01:29:50,385 --> 01:29:54,430
lt is no concern ofours
how you run your own planet.

1000
01:29:54,514 --> 01:29:58,392
But ifyou threaten
to extend your violence...

1001
01:29:58,477 --> 01:30:01,562
this earth ofyours will be reduced
to a burned-out cinder.

1003
01:30:04,524 --> 01:30:07,443
Your choice is simple.

1004
01:30:07,527 --> 01:30:10,404
Join us and live in peace...

1005
01:30:10,489 --> 01:30:14,492
or pursue your present course
and face obliteration.

1006
01:30:16,078 --> 01:30:18,913
We shall be waiting foryour answer.

1007
01:30:18,997 --> 01:30:21,957
The decision rests with you.

1008
01:30:42,521 --> 01:30:44,522
Gort, berenga.