Doc Holliday just got off
the stagecoach.
Do you want me and some of
the boys to come along with ya?
Why do you ask that?
Well, I certainly wouldn't want
to fool around with him alone.
I don't blame ya,
But I’m not gonna make
any trouble for Doc Holliday.
He's my best friend.
As long as I’m sheriff
around here, the place is his.
[♪ Camptown Races on piano]
Mike, where's Doc Holliday?
In here, Pat.
Hi, Pat.
Hi.
Gosh, I’m glad to see you.
Doc, how are you?
You're lookin' plenty sassy.
Well, you wintered
kinda fat, didn't you?
What are you doing
over this way?
Well, for one thing, I want
to have a little talk with you,
And the other is this--
Have you seen anything of
a little strawberry roan?
Somebody steal your horse?
Yeah. Cutest little fella
you ever saw.
Mean as mean, but I dote on him
like he was pure rock candy.
[Chuckles]
What are you laughing at?
Joke's on whoever done it.
First time I ever felt sorry
for a horse thief.
Did you hear
he was headed this way?
Yeah. Oh, uh, put that
on the table in there.
What are you gonna have, Pat?
Well, I started with rye.
I don't see no cause to change.
Where you been
keeping yourself?
Well, mostly across the border.
That's what
I want to see you about.
I, uh, I need a little money,
And I thought maybe you might
want to come in with me.
[Laughs]
Well, what's the matter?
I'll let you have the money,
But if the deal is anything like
that last one of yours,
You'd better not
tell me about it.
Why not?
Where'd you get that thing?
Oh, they stuck it on me
a couple of weeks ago.
You're the last man
I ever thought
Would be so easily satisfied.
Well, a man's gotta
settle down sometime.
Say, mike, did you see anything
of a strange strawberry roan?
Strawberry roan?
Yeah, about 13 hands high
and cute as a bug's ear.
Seems to me I did see
one about that size.
Yeah, when I came on duty.
Where?
Up in front of
the dentist's place.
Yeah? Where's that?
I'll show you.
Man: I’m only gonna
tell you once more.
You put that glass
on top of your head.
But what are you
gonna do then?
Just put it up on your head.
I'll show you.
Best thing in the world
for that dandruff of yours.
Wait a minute, Doc.
Hello, Fred.
Hello, Pat.
You're--You're still
using that one, huh?
My old standby.
Never has failed yet.
How many fingers
do you see, Fred?
Well, I guess I better
take Fred over to the jail,
Let him sober up there.
You go ahead, Doc.
The dentist's place is just
up the street near the corner.
I'll be along in a minute.
[Whinnying]
Well, Red, Red.
How--How are you feeling, huh?
Hello.
Nice little horse
you got here, sonny.
I think so.
Where'd you get him?
Bought him
in Santa Fe Springs. Why?
Somebody stole him
from me in Socorro.
If it wasn't for those two guns,
I'd say you were
starting in pretty young.
You think it was me?
You haven't
told me any different.
I ain't going to.
My name's Holliday.
Doc Holliday?
Yeah.
I've heard of you.
Thanks.
I don't wanna
take advantage of you.
Thanks. For a while I thought
it'd be the other way around.
What's your name, son?
Bonnie. William Bonnie.
Billy the kid, huh?
Still think I stole your horse?
Doc: How much'd
you pay for him?
Wouldn't do any good
if I told you.
Why not?
I like this little horse,
and I’ve got kinda used to him.
So have I.
I don't blame you.
Just like sitting
in a rocking chair.
Now, look, son--
I hear you're pretty good, Doc.
That's what I hear about you.
All right.
You mind standing away
From in front of that horse?
Pretty sure of yourself,
aren't you?
No sense in going to
all this trouble for nothing.
That's right.
Garrett: Hello, Doc.
Any luck?
Yes and no.
What do you mean?
It's your horse, ain't it?
It was.
Garrett: Say, you're a cool one.
Better get you over
to the hoosegow
Before this gets around.
Come along.
Ah, thanks, Doc,
for being so forbearing and all.
All right, Pat.
Garrett: See why I left off?
He's just a kid.
I told you to come along.
Didn't you hear what I said?
Yeah, I heard you.
You're not doing
any better than I did.
Wait a minute, Pat.
I'd like to make you acquainted
with this young man.
Uh, Billy, this is an old friend
of mine, Pat Garrett.
Pat, this is Mr. William Bonnie.
William B--
Well, well.
I've been wanting
to meet you for a long time.
How are you, Billy?
Hey, Pat, how many
fingers do you see?
[Laughs]
You ought to use that
only on your friends.
While you two are talking,
I better put my horse away.
Back up, boy.
Why, you--
Hold it, Pat.
Don't fly off the handle.
Nice little horse,
ain't he, Doc?
[Chuckles]
Remember me?
Where's Mr. Garrett?
I sent him home.
How about you and me
having a little talk?
I don't believe in talk.
Unless the other fella
holds all the cards.
Sonny, that head of yours
sure is screwed on tight.
If it wasn't, somebody would
have knocked it off long ago.
I guess that's right.
Say, how did you know
Pat was gonna hit you out there?
Well, it's the first time
A sheriff ever wanted
to shake hands with me.
He heard you say, "shake hands."
Huh?
Oh!
How do you do, Mr. Horse?
I'm pleased to meet ya.
Well, I’ll swear, I didn't know
he could do tricks.
What else can he do, Doc?
You back up there,
and I’ll make him walk over
And take those gloves
right out of your belt.
Over that way a little.
Now, back a little farther.
That's far enough, kid.
Put your hands up.
All right, Doc.
This is something
new for you, ain't it?
What?
Bein' arrested
for horse stealin'.
Doc, you know
I didn't steal that horse
Any more than you did.
Billy, many a true word
is spoken in jest. Hm?
This is something new for you
too, isn't it, Doc?
Yeah? What's that?
The great Doc Holliday getting
someone else to help him.
And a policeman at that.
I can hardly believe it.
And after the way I’ve heard
people talk about you,
Ever since I was in short pants.
That's enough of that.
Turn around.
Now, walk out that door.
Oh, wait a minute, Pat.
Why?
Well, this thing don't seem to
sit right on my stomach no how.
What?
Doc, you're not gonna
back out on me?
I'm afraid I am, Pat.
I'd never hear the end of this.
Hold on.
I'm not through with you yet.
Step aside, Doc.
He may shoot me in the back.
They tell me that's the way
You've given it
to some of the boys.
Now, Pat, that's
a pretty strong thing to say.
I never heard
anything like that.
Well, Mr. Garrett,
if you believe that,
Here's your chance
to do the same to me.
Comin', Doc?
Yeah, think I will.
I want the two of you
out of this town by sundown.
Well, what did I do?
That's all right, Doc.
You've got the right
to choose your friends.
Shucks. I don't take
kindly to that at all.
He knows there's no stage
until tomorrow,
And he knows that I’m afoot.
Or am I?
Not by a darn sight.
You mean that, son?
Sure. We'll dig you up
another horse somewhere.
Well, I guess
that's enough for me.
Cleaned out?
Not quite.
Uh, where you stopping, son?
I got a room at the hotel.
Doc, could I see you a minute?
Why, sure.
You might as well cash me in.
All right.
What's on your mind, son?
No offense, Doc,
but that last ace you just drew.
Yeah? What about it?
I got a feeling I saw it
on the bottom of the deck.
Are you sure?
I wouldn't have asked
you if I was.
That's where
you showed good sense.
Here you are, Doc.
Oh, thanks.
$640.
Thanks.
Huh.
You know, you could have
paid three or four times
For the horse
and still saved money.
That's right.
Hope you're satisfied now.
You gonna turn in?
Yeah, I think I will.
Oh, I’ll walk down
to the hotel with you.
Good night, gents, and thanks.
Man: Good night.
2nd man: Good night.
Doc, if you're not
already fixed up,
You can bunk with me tonight.
No, thanks, Billy.
I've got a girl.
She and her aunt
just moved in town.
Yeah?
You got a girl, Billy?
No, I ain't got nothin'.
Except that horse.
You can't fool me.
Good-looking boy like you,
you must have a girl somewhere.
No, I don't trust 'em.
Hey, you're pretty young
to talk like that.
Well, I’ve known quite a few.
And they all did you dirt, eh?
Every one of them.
Yeah. Every one of 'em.
That's too bad, Billy.
I guess things haven't been
so easy for you, have they?
Tell you what I’m going to do.
Since that little horse
means so much to you,
I'm going to make you
a present of him.
That's awful nice of you, Doc.
Thanks a lot.
All right, Billy. Good night.
See you in the morning.
Good night, Doc.
Hi, Billy.
Just thought I’d say
good night to little horse.
Well, if you're
all through,
You might as well
put him back in his stall.
All right.
Good night, Red.
See you tomorrow.
What, no kiss?
No, he don't like mush.
All right,
back in your stall, Red.
Hey, that's my tobacco,
isn't it?
I think it is.
You don't mind if I take that,
do you?
Red, I think I’ll bunk
right here tonight,
If you don't object.
[Gunshot]
Say, what is this, anyway?
What are you
shooting at me for?
Hey, are you crazy?
Stop it. Cut it out,
do you hear?
Can you understand English?
Can you?
Yes.
What's your name?
Rio.
What's the rest of it?
McDonald.
Where'd you come from?
What do you care?
Where'd you live
before you came here?
Socorro.
McDonald.
Oh, yeah.
Who was he?
My brother.
Oh.
Well, he shouldn't have
taken so much tequila.
What became of the girl?
She married another fella
two weeks afterwards.
Well, that's the way it is.
How'd I know
he was your brother?
It was him or me.
And I didn't lay for him
in no barn, neither.
I'm sorry
I was so rough with you.
You didn't hurt me.
Sure?
It's too bad I didn't know.
What?
He was your brother.
What's that got to do with it?
Well, maybe
I wouldn't have tried so hard
To get the other girl.
[Scoffs] Oh, you wouldn't?
What's the matter?
There's a rock under here.
Here, let me fix it.
Rio: Let me go!
Billy: Hold still, lady, or you
won't have much dress left.
[Tearing]
Rio: Let me go!
He did not.
I say he did.
He didn't.
You really hear him holler?
Sure, I did.
So did I.
Then that ain't Billy the kid.
Well, shucks, a dentist
can make anybody holler.
Look out, here he comes.
Sorry to keep you waitin', Doc.
I'm in no hurry.
Say, mister,
you're Billy the kid, ain't ya?
That's what they tell me.
See? What'd I tell ya?
[All talk at once]
Hey, wait a minute.
One at a time.
Have you really got
20 notches in your gun?
Is it true you got 15 Indian
scalps in your war bag?
I had to throw them away.
Boy: Why?
The moths got to them.
Oh, you should have tanned 'em.
That's the best way to keep 'em.
Is that a fact?
That's what my pa told me.
What are you doing with
that piece of willow, son?
Trying to make a whistle,
but I can't get the bark off.
Have you soaked it?
I sucked it till I’m near dry.
Can't you shoot the insides out?
Yeah, can't you?
Come on!
Yeah!
Put it up on that post.
Can I hold it?
Can you hold it steady?
Sure!
Billy, you don't have
to prove anything to me.
It's all right, Doc.
Turn the end up a little.
Little more. Little more.
He hit it!
[All shouting]
Don't you ever have
to bother to take aim?
Sure, I took aim.
When?
Before I drew.
Look, Billy, it's all right.
You fixed it fine.
Thanks.
Glad to help.
If there's anything I can do for
you, Billy, just let me know.
All right, I sure will.
Bye, Billy.
Well, that's a new one on me.
What's that?
Aiming before you draw.
I've got to.
Why?
My hands seem to be
a little quicker than my eye.
Well, ain't that too bad?
Where'd you get the horse?
I bought this one.
[Chuckles] Looks all right.
He'll do for the time being.
Ham and eggs.
Fry the eggs on both sides.
I'll take the same,
mine straight up.
How about a cold hand
while we're waiting?
How much?
How's that?
Suits me.
Before you get started, I’d like
to speak to you for a minute.
Who is he?
I don't know.
What do you want?
Let's go in the back room.
Why?
You don't know me,
but we have a mutual friend.
Yeah, who?
And I don't like him
any better than you do.
Oh, Garrett, eh?
The name sounds familiar.
Figure on staying
in town tonight?
Why?
Well, everybody knows
that Garrett told you
To get out of town.
Sooner or later, you're gonna
have a little trouble with him.
I thought
I might give you a hand.
That's very kind of you, mister.
[Chuckles] Listen,
I ain't doin' you no favor.
It'll be a pleasure.
Well, what I figure is,
when he's arguing with you,
He won't be watching
anyone else.
So it'll be a cinch for me.
Be careful you don't knock me
over with the same bullet.
Don't worry,
I’ll stand at an angle.
I'll do it like this.
Now, um...
Suppose this chair
is Garrett there.
And if you're standing
about where you are,
Why, I’ll be over here.
Do you mind if I draw my gun
so you can see the line of fire?
No, go right ahead.
[Knocking at door]
Doc: It's me, Billy.
Come on in, Doc.
Well, what happened?
He's a pretty smart hombre.
Do you know him?
Yes, he's been hangin' around,
Trying to talk Garrett into
giving him a job as a deputy.
Yeah, well, I guess
he figured if he got Billy,
He'd be such a hero
he could have the deputy job.
Or run for governor
if he wanted it.
You better
get out of here, son.
Why? He pulled on me first.
Gonna be hard
to make Garrett believe that.
Well, we'll see.
Where's my dough?
Well, I guess
I must have picked it up.
You're foolish
to stick around, son.
I think I’d be a whole lot
more foolish to pull out.
Then Garrett'd be sure
that was my fault.
Come on, cut the deal.
What you mean is
you wanna play poker, huh?
That's right.
Doc, you're not
worried about me
If I tangle with Garrett,
are ya?
Pat's pretty good.
I know him better than you do.
All right, if he's so good...
Then you'll get
your horse back, won't ya?
Say, I never thought of that.
[Sighs] Hmm.
What's the matter? Huh?
Nothin'.
Lend me a hundred, Doc.
Sorry, son, I never
lend money in a poker game.
Spoils my luck.
But I’d be glad to have you
Put up the little horse
for a hundred.
I guess you would.
Hello, Pat.
Care for a bite to eat, boys?
Or a little hand of poker?
No, thanks, Doc.
Were you in there
when it happened?
No. But listen, Pat,
he pulled on Billy first.
How do you know?
His gun was on the floor.
That don't prove nothin'.
Pat, you've got an ugly temper,
And you're letting it
get the best of you.
You have no right
to hold Billy for this killing
And you know it.
You're just sore at him,
that's all.
Doc, I’m gonna give you
a chance to stay out of this.
Thanks.
Your horse is outside.
Go on, get on him.
Good luck to you, Doc.
Same to you, Pat.
Well, what are you waitin' for?
He's waiting for those chickens
of yours to hatch.
Are you gonna put up a fight?
I'll tell you one thing,
Garrett,
I ain't goin' to jail for
no killin' I was pushed into.
What are you tryin' to do?
I still think that fella
pulled first on Billy.
Are you throwin' off
on me again?
Doc: No.
Then what do you call it?
Well, uh, since I figure
That this is purely a personal
matter between you and Billy,
Uh, I don't think
you ought to bring in
All this, uh, hired help.
Well, I only did that to keep
Billy from putting up a fight.
So I wouldn't have to kill him.
Do you, uh,
stuff birds too?
You're makin'
a big mistake, Doc,
Turning on an old friend.
And all because of a little snip
Who's never given
anybody nothin'
Except the back of his hand.
Speaking of hands--
Come on, let's get out of here
Before this hothead
makes us plug him.
He ain't gonna
run me out of town.
Well, all right,
if you want to hold the fort
While I ride off
on your little horse,
It's all right with me.
Well, since you put it that way.
Go ahead, son.
Take it easy, Pat.
Doc, this finishes you and me
for good and all.
I'm sorry.
Can you get up, son?
I don't know.
Doc: Can you make it
to the horse?
Billy: I think so.
You see what
that little horse did?
Pulling me out like that?
He's a regular bird dog.
Say, I gotta get you
under cover someplace.
I'm all right.
Charley, you better stay here
and have a look around town.
That kid's got a bullet in him,
he ain't goin' very far.
Let's go.
[Neighing]
Who's that?
Quit that yelling.
Doc.
Get these horses out of sight.
This is Billy the kid.
He got a bad one
on the left side,
But the bullet didn't hit
anything vital
And came out in the back.
Don't move him at all,
no matter what you have to do,
Or the bleeding
will start again.
And I guess you better
cut his clothes off.
Put a bandage on the wound
and see that it's always moist.
Keep him warm and dry,
no matter how much he sweats.
If he gets a chill,
he's a goner.
If he goes out of his head,
tie him down.
If the neighbors
hear him yelling,
Well, tell 'em
your aunt's got the smallpox,
That'll keep 'em away.
Guess that's all.
Now, do your best for this boy.
If I can't come back,
I’ll send word where I am,
And Billy can bring you along.
Shoo, shoo.
[Squawks]
A face like a baby.
He's so hot.
He's no hotter than
your brother Julio was.
He's soaking wet again.
Get me some sheets,
aunt Guadalupe.
Get them yourself.
What's the matter with you?
I wouldn't
lift a finger for him.
What's the matter?
They're looking for him
around here.
Well, ain't that too bad?
Chico, what's
the matter with you?
He smells the blood.
He was just getting ready
to peck his eyes out.
You stay out of here.
Shoo.
Is your name McDonald?
What do you wanna know for?
What's the matter?
Why don't you wanna tell me?
Yes, that's my name. Why?
Was your father's name Angus?
Yes.
Well, my name's Woodruff.
Charley Woodruff.
I used to work for him when
he was town marshal at Socorro.
Oh, yes, I--I guess
I was a little girl then.
Charley!
Aunt Guadalupe, how you been?
Very well, thank you.
Say, you're getting
fat as a pig. [Laughs]
What are you doing up here?
I've been working
with the sheriff.
By the way, we're looking
for Billy the kid, if you should
Happen to hear anything--
You get out of here!
[Clucking]
Why don't you come in
and sit down for a minute?
Woodruff: Some other time. I'll
drop in the first chance I get.
[Squawking]
What's wrong with that bird?
Oh, nothing. I have
a hen setting under the bed,
And he likes to peck at her.
Want me to get him
out of there for you?
Rio: Oh, no,
everything's all upset in there.
We just got up.
Goodbye,
I’m glad to have seen you.
Same here.
So long, aunt Guadalupe.
I'll walk down a ways with you.
Oh, no, you won't.
Lunch is all ready.
Goodbye.
[Clucking]
I'll fix you.
How's Billy?
Looks like he's having a chill.
A chill?
Where are ya?
Here. Right here.
Don't go away.
I won't.
So cold.
I'll get you warm.
Don't go away.
I'll only be a minute.
How can you stop
a thing like this?
You're mad at me.
No.
Yes, you are.
No, I’m not.
Why do you hide from me?
I'll be right back.
Where's that bottle of whiskey?
I finished it. The time
I had that bad cough.
I tried those hot stones with
Julio, but it was just the same.
He shook like a leaf
till he died.
You get out of here.
And shut the door.
Why?
Just get out of here.
Have you gone crazy?
You can bring the minister
here in the morning
If it'll make you
feel better about it.
Now get out.
You're not gonna die.
I'll get you warm.
Well, Red, you can't stand
this pace much longer.
I guess I’ll just have to slow
those boys down a little.
It's none of my affair, Pat,
But we crossed the county line
ten minutes ago.
That's right, Swanson,
it's none of your affair.
Break up.
Scatter for those rocks.
You look different today.
You look better.
Say, is that you?
Yes.
What are you doing here?
I live here.
Well, I’ve been tryin'
to figure this out.
How'd I get here?
Doc brought you.
Doc?
Oh, are you Doc's girl?
Well, what do you know
about that?
Be careful, your wound.
You'll hurt yourself.
That's right, I remember now.
I caught one yesterday,
didn't I?
Yesterday!
It was a month ago.
You've been terribly sick.
A month?
That's a long time.
How's Red?
Red?
You been takin'
good care of him for me?
Who's Red?
Didn't Doc leave my horse here?
No.
Well, I’ll swear.
I didn't think
he'd do a thing like that.
Behind my back too.
Is he all right again?
Say, who's this ol' lollipop?
That's my aunt Guadalupe.
tía Lupe, cómo está?
You haven't got a ham sandwich
on you by any chance, have you?
You hungry?
I don't think we have anything
cooked except some beans.
That'll do for a starter,
eh, lollipop?
Say, you don't talk
like a sick man.
Who said I was?
What does that lollipop mean?
Oh, something sweet.
Sweet?
Mm-hm, sweet. Like
candy, you know, dolce.
Oh. Is that a fact?
Where are you going?
Oh, to see if I can find
a fresh egg or two.
How do you feel?
Fine. When do we eat?
You just had lunch
about an hour ago.
Honest?
[Sighs]
Will you bring me my clothes?
I wanna get up
and have a look around.
What for?
Well, I can't spend
the rest of my life in bed.
Anyway, I want to see
if I can find my ring.
Your ring?
Yeah, I had a ring
on this finger and it's gone.
I've been sort of
worried about it.
Oh, well, you mustn't be upset
about a thing like that.
You can always
get another one, can't you?
Well, this one's been
kinda lucky for me.
Belonged to a fellow
who's supposed
To have had a charmed life,
As long as he kept it
on his finger.
Well, then, how did you get it?
Did you kill him?
No. Somebody else did that.
Oh. Well, then the ring wasn't
So lucky for him
after all, was it?
Well, nothing happened to him
Until he took it off
to wash his hands.
No, no, you'd better not
get up till tomorrow.
You said that yesterday.
But you're not
strong enough yet.
Who says I’m not?
Billy, you mustn't.
You'll hurt yourself.
Then why don't you quit
wrestling with me?
But you've been so sick.
You're not well enough.
You're...not...
Rio.
Come on. I want you
to go down to the store with me.
I have some washing to do.
Guadalupe: You've got all
afternoon to do it. Come on.
I have to fix my hair first.
All right, hurry up, then.
Why do you have to go with her?
I'd better.
What if somebody
should come by?
Like that deputy sheriff friend
of yours the other day.
Oh, yes, that's right.
I'll go tell aunt Guadalupe.
[Loud knocking at door]
[Knocking persists]
Who is it?
Doc: It's me, Doc.
Come on, hurry up.
Open this door here.
[Banging] Coming.
Coming.
Hello, Doc.
Glad to see you, Doc!
Yeah, well, you'd never know it.
I thought I’d have
to break the door down.
It's the rain, Doc! I--I
couldn't hear a thing, Doc!
You don't need to yell so loud.
I'm not deaf.
Did you ever see such a storm?
And it's been going on like this
for three or four days, Doc!
Well, it's lucky for me.
The only way I could shake
those bloodhounds.
Washed out all your tracks, huh?
Hungry?
First sit-down
I’ve had since I left here.
[Chuckles]
How's Billy?
Oh, he--He's fine. Sure.
He--He has been up
almost a week, now.
Good.
Where's Rio?
R--Rio? Oh, yes.
Oh, so that's what
all the yelling was about, eh?
I'll go and call her for you.
Now, wait a minute.
You made enough noise
now to raise the dead.
Oh. So that's it.
All right, where is he?
He's getting dressed.
Well, maybe I better
give him a hand.
No, no, Doc. Please,
let me talk to you first.
What got into ya? Were ya drunk?
What happened to ya?
I don't know.
He's a devil.
He did the same to me.
He can charm a bird
right out of a bush.
Yes, or a--
I never saw it to fail.
Don't talk that way, Doc.
What do you want me to say?
"Bless you, my children"?
You might as well.
Huh?
I'm married to him.
You're what?
That's the truth, Doc.
Only, please don't tell him.
Tell who?
Billy.
You mean to say
he doesn't know it?
No.
Then how could you
be married to him?
He was out of his mind.
I never would have done it,
only I thought he was gonna die.
And so he would have
If it hadn't been for you.
I don't want his gratitude.
Yeah, I guess I should have
Stayed out in the rain
with the sheriff.
Make me a cup of coffee.
Sure, Doc. Sure.
It's a good thing
you don't want his gratitude.
Why do you say that?
You know, when I come to think
of it, after what you done to me
I couldn't wish
for anything better
Than you hooking up with Billy.
What do you mean?
Oh, I--I wouldn't wanna
spoil it for you.
[Door opens]
Hello, Doc.
Is that all
you've got to say to me?
Now, look here, Doc. I'm sorry,
but it's your own fault.
Oh, my fault, huh?
Who brought me here?
Yeah, now you wanna
switch the blame on me.
First you take my horse,
and then my girl,
And both times
it's all my fault.
That reminds me
of something else.
You ran away with Red,
didn't you?
Think that's any excuse?
It was good enough for me.
Doc: There's only
one trouble with it.
What's that?
The horse was mine too.
I wasn't in much shape
to argue that with you, was I?
No, I guess you weren't.
But you didn't have
much use for that horse
Lying flat on your back...
or did ya?
All right, Doc, if that's
your way of looking at it.
You just took
the loan of him, so to speak.
Say, what are you getting at?
Yes, that's what
I’d like to know.
You borrow from me,
I borrow from you.
What does that mean?
Let's have a cup of java.
We'd better be
getting out of here, huh, Doc?
Not at those prices.
All right, Doc,
I’ll tell you what I’ll do.
What's that?
Well, just to show ya
my heart's in the right place...
...I’ll let you take your pick.
Huh?
You mean
you'd trade me for a horse?
It's up to Doc.
After all, I’ve got to think
of the other fella, you know?
Well, I appreciate that, Billy.
I sure do.
Billy, you don't mean that.
And after all she did for you.
Say, you should have seen what
that little horse did for me,
Huh, Doc?
That's right.
I, uh, hope you won't
think too hard of me,
But, uh, under
the circumstances,
I'm going to take the horse.
You are?
You're not satisfied?
Listen, Doc, I like
that little horse.
What'd I tell ya? Huh?
I still can't believe it.
What are you talkin' about?
Nothing.
Say, what's eating you?
Here, uh, fill these
with fresh water.
The creeks are muddy
as all get out.
How about grub?
Can you spare us
enough flour and bacon
To get us to Fort Sumner?
Sure. Sure, Doc.
Hey, it's clearing up.
We'd better be getting out of--
Lend me some dough, will ya?
How much do you want?
About 50 bucks.
There's 40.
Here.
Buy yourself a horse and buggy.
Don't ya think it's too much?
You can give aunt Guadalupe 20
if you want.
If we get located in
Fort Sumner, I’ll send for ya.
What for?
I can't stand ranch cookin'.
Here you are, Doc.
Thanks. Goodbye.
Bye, Doc.
Bye, lollipop.
Bye, Billy.
Take care of yourself.
You do the same.
Fill these up for Doc.
Hello, you old hay bag.
Have you missed me?
Say, he's thin as a rail.
He's been getting
a little exercise.
Where'd you get that plug?
I wore out
that black horse I had,
So I traded him
to a sheepherder for this one.
He's all right.
Little wild, yet.
Come on.
Ain't Red a sweetheart?
Doc: I’m going
to let ya have
The loan of him
for a little while.
Huh?
Until ya get
your strength back.
Say, you're not gonna
do me any favors.
What's the matter with you?
I don't wanna be
obligated to you about Red.
Why not?
'Cause I haven't given up
getting Red back yet.
Any more than I’ve given up
getting on this ornery goat.
Bye, Rio.
What's the matter?
Boy, am I tuckered.
What are you lookin' for?
Sack of tobacco.
Say, is there anything of mine
you don't cotton to?
I guess I forgot.
Yeah.
It's a bad habit you've got.
What?
Forgettin' what
belongs to other people.
You think I did it on purpose?
Yes.
Listen, mister, I don't
feel any too good as it is.
Neither do I.
You wanna make
something out of it?
That's a big advantage
you're taking.
I can't help it.
I'm so plumb beat out, I’ll be
lucky if I can draw 'em clear.
Oh, I don't wanna
crowd a sick man.
I'm all right.
Just give me 40 winks
And I’ll take ya on
with both hands free.
Well, I guess this is as good
a place as any to make camp.
No water.
No, and you won't find any
between here and Fort Sumner.
That's a long ways off.
When we get there, our friend
the sheriff won't be far behind.
Huh?
Garrett?
How do you know
it's him?
I can tell him
farther off than that.
He wouldn't be coming
after the two of us alone.
Maybe he's lost
too many of his friends.
How come you didn't
knock him over?
Or did you try?
Did I?
That's what I said. Did you?
Didn't do nothin' else.
Who do you suppose
put him on our trail?
Well, maybe somebody
saw us pulling out, or, uh--
Or what?
Nothing.
Sure, she was the one.
Yeah, Rio.
Why do you suppose she had to
up and do a thing like that?
Well, women are funny.
Hey, go easy on that water.
We've only got two canteens
to get us to Fort Sumner.
[Spits]
What's the matter?
Look.
Sweet spirits of niter.
The little darling
put sand in instead of water.
Now, that sure is
one for the book.
Well, no use hangin' around here
holding postmortems.
Let's get goin'.
You know, Doc, I think
I’ll have another drink.
What are you talking about?
You didn't have one
in the first place.
No, but I had the same notion
about an hour ago.
Yeah, I know
what you're thinking,
But it won't do you any good.
Take my advice.
What?
Killing a woman.
Why not?
Ah, they're all alike.
There isn't anything
they wouldn't do for ya...
Or to ya.
[Sighs]
Hey, why didn't you wake me up?
We should have
got started long ago.
Garrett: Keep 'em up.
Oh, hello, Pat.
Where's Billy?
Looks like he left ya.
And on my horse, eh?
Try those on.
Oh, you know me, Pat.
Do I have to put
these things on?
I know ya.
Put 'em on.
That was pretty smart,
putting sand in those canteens.
I had to give you something
for your money, didn't I?
Oh, I see.
So you sent the sheriff after us
for good measure, huh?
No wonder he came alone.
All he had to do
was take his time
And wait for the sun
to finish us off.
Then how did ya get back?
It was pretty tough.
But the more I thought
about seeing you, darling,
The easier it got.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Go ahead.
Say, that sounds real nice.
I like to hear you ask for it.
Keep it up. Beg some more.
What would you like me to say?
Well, you might say
"please" very sweetly.
Please.
Will you keep your eyes open?
Yes.
Will you look
right at me while I do it?
Huh.
What is it?
Everybody drinks but me.
I'm supposed to be a camel, huh?
You want a drink,
you can climb down and get it.
[Muffled moaning]
Say, did you hear something?
What kind of a track is that?
I don't know.
Too small for a man.
There's another one.
Couple over there.
Oh, take a look at that.
[Moaning]
Yeah, it's an old Indian trick,
Soaking rawhide in water
to make it shrink.
Another hour, she'd have been
hanging by her wrists.
Well, I’ll say
one thing for Billy.
He sure does pay off poetic.
He put her right where
she could see the water.
He just left here,
less than half an hour ago.
He went that way.
Toward those mountains.
Are you all right?
Sit down here.
Don't worry about me.
Go on after him.
Well, we can't catch him now.
Why not?
He's got too much of
a head start on us. Sit down.
You know, I think
he's in love with you.
What are you talkin' about?
The crazier a man is
about a woman,
The crazier he thinks,
and the crazier he does.
He's only crazy
about one thing. Himself.
Hey, that gives me
a thought.
Maybe we'll get
Mr. Billy after all.
How?
Well, just like he says.
If he's crazy enough
to do you like this,
Maybe he's just crazy enough
to come back to turn you loose.
You're the one
that's crazy.
He doesn't care anything
about me. He'd never come back.
Maybe so,
but it's worth tryin'.
Ain't it, Doc?
Well, if he's fool enough
to come back,
He oughta get himself caught.
I told you
not to breathe so loud.
All right,
all right, all right.
Well, how do you like it?
Hmm, I thought I tied it
tighter than that.
You came back.
You don't think I did it
on your account, do ya?
You didn't?
Have you seen anything
of Doc and the sheriff?
Garrett: Here we are, Billy,
right behind ya.
And put those hands
where they belong.
Say, why didn't you tip me off?
Hurry up with that grub. I wanna
get back to town before dark.
Well, I’ve only got two hands.
Well, why don't
you use both of 'em?
I'll use one on you
in a minute.
I wouldn't put it past you.
Now's your chance with me
all trussed up like a chicken.
Here we are together again.
Same old happy family.
Yeah, and I’d have been halfway
to Fort Sumner by now
If it hadn't been for you.
Me?
Yeah, you.
Give me a cigarette.
Nah, you mean her.
Rio?
Say, are you out of your mind?
Why don't you come out
and admit it, like a man?
Admit what?
You didn't know
that Pat had caught me
Until you got back
to our camp, did you?
No.
Then what's the use
of coming after us?
Why not?
Well, we'd have been
clear to Lincoln
Before you even got back here.
Say, mister,
what are you tryin' to make out?
Well, I heard you say once
you didn't like ranch cooking,
So I guess you figured you'd
better come back and get Rio.
Ah, you're daffy. I wouldn't
come back two inches to get her.
You did.
I tell you I didn't.
Actions speak louder
than words.
Do they?
All right, I’ll show you
how much I care about her.
If you want her back
you can have her. And welcome.
Now what do you think
about that?
I don't want her.
Cattle don't graze
after sheep.
Sheep?
Sheep, did you say?
I didn't say goats
or monkeys.
Why, you--
Ah, sit down.
What's the matter with you?
None of your business.
Careful, young fella.
You want it now? I've just been
waitin' for an excuse like this.
Hey!
I'll fix you up.
Never mind fixin'
any more food.
We're leavin' now.
Come on.
Let me get a drink first.
All right, hurry up.
Hey, Rio, come here and hold
my hands so I won't fall in.
Come out of there.
You're all right now.
Come on.
You're figuring on takin' us
back to Lincoln, ain't ya?
Where'd ya think
I was takin' ya?
It's over that way, ain't it?
Sure, it's over that way.
What are you gettin' at?
Take a look.
Hey, Doc.
Well, the Mescaleros
are out early this year.
They're talkin' about us,
ain't they?
Yeah, they're--They're tipping
off another hunting party
That must be out somewhere.
Right over there.
Hmm. On both sides of us.
Well, I guess our best chance is
to high-tail it to Fort Sumner.
Don't figure on me
doing much high-tailing.
Why not?
I ain't no acrobat.
Oh.
Well, I hope you fellas
Will have sense enough
to behave yourselves.
Why, sure, Pat. Certainly.
Sure, Pat.
Thank you.
No, you don't.
That's your horse over there.
Who says so?
I say so.
Get on him and hurry up.
Rio, you ride the paint.
Thanks.
Hey, Red's my horse.
I know he is,
but I’m gonna ride him.
I don't like this.
Looks like some of those
Mescaleros are ahead of us too.
No, no, you--You better not
come over here, Rio.
Why not?
They put the fire on them.
Those Mescaleros
sure do play for keeps.
Say, what's that?
It's a good-size party. We'll be
knee-deep in them in a minute.
Look over there too.
Hey, what are ya doin'?
What do you think I’m doing?
I want my guns.
Ah, now, wait a minute.
You're not gonna argue
at a time like this, Pat.
Aren't you gonna
give us a chance?
He'd like to see them
put the fire on me.
I sure would.
What about her?
Well, we can't
talk about it now.
I wanna know one thing--
Do I have your solemn promise
That you'll give them back
when I ask for them?
Sure, what do you think
we are?
Will you see to it
that he does?
Now, who's gonna
see to it that I do?
I'll take your word for it.
Where are my cartridges?
Here you are.
Now, what do we do?
Make a stand or run for it?
Can't make a stand here.
I know something
that might work.
What is it?
Come on, do exactly what I do.
Cut 'em loose!
Garrett: I know this place.
We're about 40 miles
from Fort Sumner.
Señor Garrett. What
are you doing up this way?
Hello, Pablo. Can you
put us up for the night?
Sure, glad to have you.
Go right in. My house is yours.
I'll take care of the horses.
Well, boys, I guess we're
out of the woods now. Huh?
Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
Oh. No, I--I wouldn't be
too sure of that, Pat.
Oh, yes, he's right, Pat.
Those Mescaleros
don't give up so easy.
Pablo.
This is very important.
I want you
to ride to Fort Sumner
And give this note
to the town marshal.
Did he say town marshal?
That's what
it sounded like to me.
Thanks, Rio.
It certainly is
a beautiful night out.
I think I’ll take
a little stroll.
And, uh, gentlemen,
Just in case I shouldn't
return before you retire,
I'll say good night now.
I think I’ll go with ya.
Well, Billy, you've been
pretty good to my little horse,
And I guess the least I can do
Is to let you
say goodbye to him.
That's awfully nice of ya, Doc.
Oh, I always like
to think of the other fellow.
So if you'll just stand
right here in this doorway
And don't make no warlike moves,
Then you can wave farewell
to him as we ride off.
In other words,
you think you're gonna leave.
I'm sorry, Pat,
I--I hate to eat and run,
But, uh, well,
you know how it is.
Listen, Doc.
You're only
wasting your time, Pat.
Haven't you
forgotten something?
No, I don't think so.
Good night, all.
Say, Doc.
Yes, what is it?
I'm afraid you'll have
to listen to me for a minute.
Why?
What if I don't feel like
wavin' goodbye to Red?
Oh, you still think you got
Something to say
about that horse, eh?
Yes, I do.
All right, go ahead and say it.
That's a pretty big advantage
to give a man like you.
Didn't you tell me that once?
How's this?
You don't have to go that far.
Thanks.
What about him?
Will he leave us alone?
Or do you think we ought to
pull his teeth before we start?
Don't worry about me.
I wouldn't lift a finger, Doc,
to keep you from killing him.
You and me never had any trouble
till he came along.
He'll keep out of it.
All right, son. I'm waiting.
[Clatter] Put those plates down.
You're making me nervous.
Billy, he'll kill ya.
What do you care?
But you can get another horse.
I want this one.
Why?
I wanna see if I can
teach him to make smoke
Come out of his ears.
Say, I haven't got all night.
Get back against that wall.
But, Billy--
Go on.
And count up to three.
I won't. You're out
of your mind. Both of ya.
How 'bout you, Pat?
Sure, I’ll be glad to.
You're too willing.
I don't trust ya.
I think I’d rather have
that cuckoo clock
Do the counting for me.
Yeah, that's good enough.
It's gonna strike in a minute.
Shall we pull
on the last cuckoo?
All right.
Well, Billy,
I guess this is it.
Men are pretty much like
children, after all.
Have you ever seen two kids
wrestling in the yard?
They push and tussle and maybe
They look like they're fighting,
but they're not.
They're really friends.
And everything's in fun.
Then, pretty soon,
they play a little too rough.
One of 'em gets mad,
And in the end,
somebody always gets hurt.
So for you and me, this is
where somebody gets hurt.
But when it's over,
and however it turns out, son,
No hard feelings.
Doc--
[Cuckoo clock strikes]
[Cuckoo]
Why didn't ya draw?
I changed my mind.
Sure you did.
You lost your nerve.
I always knew you were
nothin' but a show-off.
Shut up. Why did you change your
mind? This some trick of yours?
No, I just don't feel like it.
Maybe I ate too much.
But some other night,
you will feel like it, eh?
Who knows?
That's no good, Billy.
If you and I are bound
to fight sooner or later,
I'd rather do it now
and have it over with.
You've been ready to pull on me
every day since I met you.
I never wanted it, but I waited
And let you pick
your own time and place.
You've done that tonight.
Are ya gonna draw
or do I have to make ya?
Are you gonna fight or do you
want me to nick your ears?
Doc, have you gone loco?
What's the matter
with you, Billy?
I didn't think
you'd take this off anybody.
Maybe I wouldn't
off anybody else.
What do you mean by that?
Doc, don't listen
to that kinda talk.
Haven't you ever seen
a case of cold feet before?
He never had cold feet
in his life.
What is it, Billy?
I guess that idea about the
cuckoo clock wasn't so good.
Why?
Well, it gave me time to think
and remember a few things.
You're the only partner
I ever had.
Gosh, do ya really
feel that way, son?
I treated you
worse than anyone.
Nah, it was all my fault, I--
I had no business getting sore
and cutting you up this way.
Come on, let's get out of here.
No, we'd better split.
Split? What for?
Well, I wouldn't want to make
Red carry the both of us.
Oh, don't worry.
We'll find a better way
than that to divide him up.
Say, you can
ride him out of here.
No, I had him last.
Yeah, that's right,
come to think of it.
Doc: I ain't worried about
You and me
ever fighting now, Billy.
Because one thing is certain--
If we didn't do it tonight,
we never will.
Come on, let's go.
Uh, so long, Pat.
Don't take any wooden nickels.
You're not goin' with him.
Now, look here.
You ain't gonna
Start something
with the two of us, are ya?
I might have known
you'd do this to me.
Ever since you met him,
you've treated me like a dog.
The very first day,
you sided with him against me,
And made me
the laughing stock of the town!
Take it easy.
I gave you your guns so you'd
have a chance for your life,
And now you tell me I’ve gotta
Fight the two of you
to get them back.
You stand there,
Side by side with
that little snip of a kid,
Against me?
Me! I was the oldest
and best friend you ever had!
And I still would be
If it wasn't for him!
Say, mister, that's about enough
out of you for one night.
Wait a minute, Billy.
You let me handle this.
Pat is a friend of mine.
I don't wanna kill him and
I don't want you to kill him.
Is that clear?
Pat, you're just getting
yourself all steamed up.
I'll be seeing you
one of these days
And we'll have
a good laugh about all this.
Well, so long.
Be careful. You know you haven't
got a chance against me.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Pat.
Say--
Don't, son.
Please don't do that.
Oh, Doc. Lie down.
No.
Why not?
No, that--That's one thing
I’ve always been afraid of.
What?
Dying in bed.
Doc!
Why didn't you shoot?
You had me beat a mile.
You had me cold!
Maybe I don't like cold meat,
Pat.
Well, go ahead.
Go ahead what?
Aren't you going to say
something over Doc?
I don't know what to say.
I never said anything
over anybody I killed before.
I think we ought
to say something over Doc.
You'd better do it.
So long, Doc.
Pat?
I want you to know I’m sorry.
I honestly am.
Last night
I was ready to kill you.
But in the daylight,
I can see things much better.
You and Doc
had been friends for years.
If I hadn't come between you,
None of this
would have happened.
It sure is funny
How two or three trails
Can cross
and get all tangled up.
Well, go ahead.
After you.
Say, you don't think I’d shoot
you in the back, do you?
I don't know,
but I ain't gonna tempt you.
I don't think you're
gonna be fool enough
To try to do it from the front.
You never trust anybody,
do you?
I apologize, Pat.
Go ahead.
Who's that?
Where's Pat?
He's still in the house.
What's he doing?
He's not gonna try to stop you.
How do you know?
He told me so.
Huh.
Say, Billy--
Can I see you for a minute?
What do you want?
If that's the way
you feel about it, never mind.
At least I’m not afraid
to turn my back on you.
Here, hold these a minute.
I thought you might like to have
Doc's guns as a keepsake.
Say, I sure would.
Thanks, Pat. Thanks a whole lot.
I never had an extra pair.
Black holsters too.
They'd go nice with Sunday
clothes, if I ever get any.
Do you think they'll suit you?
If the barrels ain't too long.
No, they're just the same.
Be careful. They're loaded.
That's right.
Say, I think they're even better
balanced than mine.
Then how about
letting me have yours?
My guns? What for?
If I had your guns,
I could say it was you out there
in that grave, instead of Doc.
Huh? You'd pass Doc off as me?
Sure.
Everybody would believe me
Once they saw Billy the kid's
six-shooters.
You could leave an end
to your trail right here.
Nobody'd follow you up north.
All your troubles would
be buried. Past and present.
You and Rio could go off
with nothing to worry about.
How come you'd do
a favor like that for me?
There you go again, Billy.
Distrustin' a person who's
tryin' to be decent to you.
Don't you realize
that's your whole trouble?
Don't you see that's what's
gotten you into all your fights?
You've got more enemies
Than anybody
in this part of the country.
How do you expect
to get along with people
When you think every man
who holds his hand out to you
Has a knife behind his back?
Son, I--I just don't know
what's going to become of you.
Honest, I don't.
Oh, I didn't mean anything.
I'm sorry.
That's the spirit.
That's my boy.
Now, give me those guns
and clear out of here
Before it's too late.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
But I’ve had these guns
a long time.
I sure hate to let go of 'em.
Billy, I’ve been
pretty patient with you--
Oh!
Billy, my son.
It's your duty to give them up.
You owe it to yourself.
You ought to start
a new life today.
Those guns are
the badge of your shame.
They represent everything
you must leave behind you.
Don't you realize that?
Don't you understand
That if you're going
to start all over again,
Your hands must be clean?
I guess you're right, Pat.
I never thought of it like that.
Thanks, Pat.
Billy, you don't know
what this means to me.
You'll never forget this day.
Goodbye, Pat.
Why do you say that?
Why shouldn't I?
Why should you?
You ain't goin' anywhere.
Hmm?
I took the firing pins
out of those guns.
Hmm?
Why, you--
Nothing would make me happier
than for you to keep coming.
[Click]
[Sighs]
Is that one of your own guns?
It sure looks like it.
How did you get it?
You dirty little cheat.
You switched those guns on me!
Of all the dirty,
rotten tricks! I--
I didn't mean to, Pat.
Honest I didn't.
They must have gotten mixed up
while I was playing with 'em.
Thanks.
I left my guns right there.
What for?
Didn't you say you'd have
to show them to everybody
To make people believe
that story of yours?
You see, I have an idea that
you'd rather give Doc the credit
For doing you up like this.
Because I think
you'd rather be dead
Than have people know
Billy the kid did this to ya.
Goodbye, Pat.
You don't wanna go off
without your canteens, do you?
Did you fill 'em up for me?
Yes.
[Sloshing]