[Music]
foreign
these men are members of the KGB working
in North America
this man is an illegal a spy trained in
Moscow and sent to the United States
this man is a Defector from Cuban
intelligence living in hiding under
constant threat of death
this man ran operations against the west
from Czechoslovakia
[Music]
this man was trained by the most
Sinister Department of the KGB and sent
to North America
all of them received their orders from
here number two zerjinski square in
Moscow this is the headquarters of the
KGB from here the KGB continues to carry
out the Mandate given to the secret
police by Lenin who said it was to be
the sword and shield of the Revolution
the offense and defense of Soviet aims
throughout the world
foreign
is the center of the vast KGB
bureaucracy directly responsible to the
pilot Bureau for its operations against
the West
ever since Lenin took over the secret
police of his defeated enemy the Tsar
the Soviet Espionage apparatus has
mirrored the leadership under which it
serves under Lenin in the early days of
revolutionary turmoil it was known as
the Checker and it imposed the Bolshevik
rule upon the nation setting up an
international network of informers and
tracking down and liquidating enemies of
the new regime
foreign
the name of the secret police was
changed to GPU and it became the most
effective instrument of mass murder
until the second World War
Stalin used the GPU to eradicate
millions of peasants in the Ukraine who
protested the creation of collective
Farms from their lands and during the
mid-30s Russia was wrapped by what
became known as the terror the mass
purges created by Stalin
show trials became a function of the
secret police activities and more than
75 percent of the Soviet general staff
of the army and Senior Ministries were
arrested by the GPU tried and executed
in 1953 Stalin died
[Music]
it was appropriate that the small band
of survivors at the top of the Communist
hierarchy quickly arrested one of their
own labrenti Beria the ambitious and
coldly ruthless head of the secret
police which by then had become known as
the nkd
it was barrier who had presided over the
purges ordered by Stalin
he himself was executed
in 1955 Nikita Khrushchev took full
power the secret police became known as
the KGB
under Khrushchev and his successors the
KGB looked increasingly outward to
Espionage and intelligence activities in
the rest of the world in the past decade
it has become a Vanguard element of
Soviet expansion and activities
throughout the third world Western
Europe and North America
the KGB has become a massive bureaucracy
reporting directly to the pilot Bureau
the select body that runs the Soviet
Union its functions are tied to the
international Department which runs and
finances both communist and
non-communist organizations in other
countries and to the ministry of Defense
with whom it shares Espionage activities
in other nations
the KGB is organized into Chief
directorates from a separate
headquarters in Moscow the first Chief
directorate controls foreign Espionage
activities the second Chief directorate
is the largest and most important with a
network of informers it is responsible
for ensuring internal security
the current head of the KGB is Yuri
andropov a key member of the politburo a
close colleague of Leonid Brezhnev and
one of the most powerful men in Russia
as head of the KGB and drop-off controls
the most influential and Sinister Bureau
of the Soviet bureaucracy whose main
purpose is the total control of the
Soviet people
[Music]
first Chief directorate are divided into
departments which carry out a wide range
of activities from Soviet establishments
located across the continent
[Music]
foreign
this building has served as a Soviet
Embassy in Washington it is a major
Center of Espionage activity in the
United States
this is Alexander cloyev listed as an
attache at the embassy he is a KGB
officer
this is Buddy hibanov a correspondent
with the Soviet news service Tas he is
also a KGB officer during a recent
hearing of the Senate Foreign Relations
Committee the principal witness was
Harold Brown who at that time was
Secretary of Defense subject U.S
military posture and the defense budget
for 1980. present were Soviet TV
reporter Yuri Sultan and his cameraman
Anatoly Ivanov as well as Milo stulva a
correspondent for izvestia
here is Dr Mikhail milstein who is now
with the Soviet Academy of Science
specializing in military affairs next to
milstein Yuri capralov first Secretary
of the Soviet Embassy then there was a
man who identified himself as Andre
krutzky the Soviet Embassy lists him as
an attache and this man Victor tutin
official title third secretary at the
embassy
American intelligence sources identify
both krutzky and kutin as being officers
of the KGB in North America there are
dozens of Soviet establishments
everything from diplomatic missions to
trade offices and businesses that sell
tractors or operate Merchant shipping
since 1970 the number of Soviet
officials in North America has increased
dramatically
until 1980 Richard Kinsey was Deputy
Chief of the Soviet desk in the FBI his
duties were to closely monitor the
activities of the Soviets in the U.S the
numbers have
doubled in the last 10 years from 1970
when I left in the
early 1980 the Soviet presence had
almost doubled there was a time when I
first was in in the work where we could
almost go
One agent on one identified or suspected
Soviet intelligence officer when I left
quite the contrary was true and we were
vastly outnumbered where we our agents
were trying to cover three or four known
or suspected Intelligence Officers
foreign
s for Soviet diplomats is to file travel
plans whenever they travel in the U.S or
Canada
it is a restriction that in the Soviet
Union is strictly applied to Western
diplomats but for the Soviets in North
America the theory and the practice
seldom meet
we find through our coverage of them
that they often deviate from those
travel plans and surprisingly enough
will end up
traveling via the sac base in Omaha
Nebraska when their travel plans call
for them to go through Kansas or some
other some other route and that's a
violation of travel regulations if we
bring it to the attention the state
department then a strong note of protest
is made to the Soviet ambassador
is there anything ever done about these
strong notes of protests
they're filed
um
[Music]
the Soviet Embassy in Washington is also
distinctive for another type of spying
operation
on the roof is a large antenna that
appears harmless but is used to
electronically eavesdrop on telephone
conversations in the Washington area
one-third of all local calls and most
long distance calls are transmitted by
microwave which can be plucked from the
air by these Soviet antennae
literally millions of calls are recorded
and put through computers which are
programmed to listen for certain key
words or are activated by the phone
numbers of people who are of interest to
the Soviets
in 1972 while negotiating a purchase of
surplus grain from the United States the
Soviet Embassy used its telephone
intercept capability to eavesdrop on
conversations between the U.S department
of Agriculture and grain dealers in the
midwest because the Soviets were able to
acquire inside information about the U.S
bargaining position they were able to
outmaneuver the U.S negotiators and sign
a long-term contract for a record amount
of grain at very low prices
crop failures the next year in the U.S
drove consumer prices upwards but the
Soviets were able to continue buying
grain at the low prices they had
negotiated the previous year
in San Francisco the Soviet consulate
houses sophisticated electronic
equipment and occupies a commanding
position overlooking San Francisco Bay
our investigations determined that many
of those antenna were in such a position
that they had the capability of doing
microwave Intercept in Silicon Valley
about an hour's Drive South of San
Francisco is the area that has come to
be known as Silicon Valley
it is perhaps the most highly
concentrated area of modern technology
and research in the United States
its products include microcomputers
silicon chips and fiber optics all vital
component parts of military hardware
the San Francisco consulate has also
provided the Soviets with an easy access
to U.S military establishments on the
west coast for example by observing the
Polaris submarines being refitted in
clear view of a nearby seafood
restaurant frequented by the Soviets the
numbers of American submarines then at
Sea can be determined
in the Canadian Capital the Soviet
Embassy is also equipped with antenna
[Music]
however the most visible microwave
intercept equipment is not on the Soviet
roof but nearby on the roof of the
polish Embassy it is the Eastern Bloc
Nations the polls the Czechs and the
East Germans that play an important part
in the game of espionage
William Kelly is the former head of the
RCMP security service
intelligence Services of blocked
countries
allegedly work independently of each
other
but that isn't true
they work very closely with each other
and under the dominance of the Russian
KGB there was a time when
the uh it was felt that the KGB were too
well known around external affairs
and they didn't think that their their
their the reception they'd received
would be the best so they wanted to
naturally recruit or penetrate and they
decided that the hungarians could do the
job
under the circumstances better than they
could developing countries May that
Islam ditman was a deputy director of
check intelligence at the time he fled
to the West
because there are many people who are
afraid to
get in touch to be associated with a
Soviet diploma for example who uses who
is an intelligence officer and uses the
Diplomatic power in most cases but they
they don't hesitate to develop a very
friendly contact with a Czech diploma or
a Polish diploma or an East German
diploma because they're saying what the
representatives of these small countries
can do and they don't realize that they
do basically the same job only under a
different color but
were you with the Soviet intelligence
say they know every everything that the
czechoslovak or any other satellite
service does
on the east coast of America on Long
Island is another Soviet diplomatic
residence it is an estate near the town
of Glen cold which serves as a weekend
and summer Retreat for Soviet officials
of the nearby United Nations
Soviet citizen Arcadia shivchenko often
stayed there while he was the under
Secretary General of the UN
and all the top floors of the building
are full of the sophisticated
equipment
for the the to intercept all the
conversation telephone conversation of
anything which is going on around the
every at least 15 or 17
technicians who are working with there
to do all this job
the Estates at Glen Cove and the
electronic monitoring equipment jammed
into it also represent an interesting
Geographic Choice by the Soviets
I might point out that the estate while
it's located somewhat north of the
establishment is very close to Grumman
aircraft Factory which is one of the
United States main Builders of a
sophisticated warplanes and it's sort of
midway between the main plan and a
testing facility that Bremen has further
out in the island and those antennae are
appointed toward both facilities
thank you
[Music]
the newest Soviet residence in New York
is a building in the Riverdale section
of the Bronx they got permission to
build on one of the highest sites in New
York City
situated at an elevation that permits
interception of phone messages over the
widest possible area
[Music]
yet back in Washington the Soviets were
not pleased with the location of their
Embassy
so they asked for and again were granted
permission to build on another site
at the corner of Belmont and Wisconsin
Avenue
[Music]
it is one of the highest locations in
Washington
[Music]
because it's so high here we'd like to
get a good shot of Washington can we get
in
if you want to take it you must go to
our Embassy and decide this mission is
our ship in Washingtonville they will
have everything they can I mean listen
all the conversation which are going on
from White House to any uh the the any
departments or or Pentagon you have a
good deal from here anyway
[Music]
yeah I bet
much of the construction on the Soviet
Embassy complex is already completed the
new residences have been built complete
with antennae on the roof
in Moscow the Americans had requested
permission to build a new Embassy to
replace their old and overcrowded
facilities there
in this instance comparisons are useful
the United States was eventually offered
and accepted a site on one of the lowest
points of land in the city and after
years of bureaucratic wrangling
permission was only recently granted to
begin Construction
thank you
[Music]
in the United States there is one place
that is more important for the KGB than
even the embassy or its consulates
how important is the United Nations to
the Soviets in terms of Espionage it's a
nest spies
the KGB operations in the UN are
controlled by the first Department of
the first Chief directorate at the KGB
this department directs all operations
against the United States and Canada
the officers of the department operate
from the embassies and consulates
operations are also run from the U.N
itself where over 500 Soviets work
the U.N was formed to provide a forum
for dialogue between the nations of the
world each country sends its ambassadors
and their staffs to the debates which
occur in the general assembly and
Security Council
awarded diplomatic status their
representatives live in the equivalent
of embassies in New York City and are
expected to represent their country's
interests
but in the Secretariat building are the
international civil servants without
diplomatic status they are expected to
be rigorously non-partisan in their
administration of the un's various
departments and worldwide programs
in 1978 one of the most important Soviet
defections to the West occurred Arcadia
shivchenko who was the under Secretary
General of the United Nations stunned
his Soviet colleagues as the highest
ranking Soviet in the U.N Secretariat
shevchenko had knowledge of extensive
Soviet Espionage activities in the
United States so serious was the
defection that two of the Soviet Union's
highest ranking ambassadors debrinian
and thrianofsky demanded a meeting with
shepchenko and his U.S lawyer this is
the first broadcast of a tape recorded
at that meeting Ambassador debrinian
reveals that shevchenko was privy to
Soviet state Secrets even though he was
supposedly an impartial U.N civil
servant documents
up till the last day when he left it
showed that there was no surveillance
he gave me copies of this letter
he refers to the what he went a betrayal
of the ideals of the October Revolution
which is taking place now in the USSR
the Monstrous abuse is carried on by the
KGB compelled me to take the decision to
renounce my membership and they see PSU
Etc necessary leads one to think that
his inner some abnormal State because a
normal person or a one acting at this
free will uh I don't think these
explanations there was no need for him
to stay in the Foreign Service for 30
years or 20 years and then finally find
out that it is agrees with the fruits of
a October Revolution
United Nations secretary to give so
gives so many advantages for the KGB to
penetrate actually almost all aspects of
the American life because they unlike
diplomats
go and Tarot across the country freely
they even should not
under no obligation to notify the state
department of American Mission about the
their travel trips for participation
anywhere probably the
most active intelligence gathering
functions are carried out by Soviets
assigned the United Nations I say that
for a number of reasons primarily that
U.N employees also have total freedom of
movement throughout the United States
it's a it's a goal in the mind for the
Soviet Union that it's so easy to have
such a huge number of the people
involved in intelligence activity my
estimate would be that the people who
are working for the Soviet intelligence
in general in New York about 300 or 350
persons in the world engage in all these
activities in theory the employees are
there to carry out the ideals and
humanitarian causes of the United
Nations and run the bureaucratic
Machinery but shevchenko quickly
discovered that even though he was one
of the United Nations highest ranking
bureaucrats and the head of his
Department the orders came from the KGB
I had in my department 13 Soviets
and the the at least seven of them were
professional
because they didn't do anything
they didn't work in in my department
they didn't receive orders from me as a
head of the department they received the
orders from from their bosses in the
mission from the kanjibouti area
residents
this man was one of those Soviets
working for shivchenko his name is
valdek enger he was placed in
chefchenko's Department not by the
normal U.N hiring practices but by the
KGB resident or senior officer in New
York City who requested shevchenko's
help in placing the spy in the United
Nations I agreed with that but I think
it was a mistake because it was a very
difficult to get rid of him later
because if he transformed my office into
a kind of a center or gathering of all
these KGB guys and collecting all these
materials and all this things and he
didn't do anything at all
whenever I asked him to to do something
uh
for for the department or for the
Secretariat or to write something for me
he was always reluctant of or absent or
have this bunch of his KGB guys in my
office I was and I was absolutely I was
mad about this situation
yeah
anger is asking a U.S naval Commander to
pass on secret documents
[Music]
yeah
and just after the airport yeah
[Music]
in front of you you know after the board
just enter the search you'll see this
little box okay okay
[Music]
and you'll find everything there all
right okay okay right I'll talk to you
later all right
the head of the KGB operating out of the
Soviet mission to the United Nations has
been identified by shevchenko as B
kazakov
within the U.N the Soviets are also able
to exert influence
Victor lysiovsky is a KGB officer who
occupies the post of Special Assistant
to the Secretary General in the United
Nations he chooses the speakers for the
debates in the general assembly
is another KGB officer who served as a
senior Secretariat official a man who
served with solidonikov at the
international relations Institute in
Moscow was Igor glagalev who was an
advisor to the politburo before he
defected to the West they were high
ranking or members of the KGB
they were not you know people who were
reused by the KGB because you know many
people without their knowledge but they
were just
regular agents of the KGB
and
sublease that they can throw the staff
of the United Nations
permanently always
solidonikov was an advisor to Joshua and
Como and other rebel leaders during the
war in Zimbabwe Rhodesia is now a key
formulator of Soviet policy in Africa
and is their ambassador to Zambia
later on she was assistance
to the Secretary General and later on
she was
um
director of The Institute of Africa
and now she is
the Soviet Ambassador in Zambia where he
Mastermind it the Takeover of Zimbabwe
and now he's organizing the Takeover of
South Africa
[Music]
thank you
Noel field joined the state department
as a Foreign Service Officer in 1926.
during the 1930s he became a Soviet
Agent Lawrence Duggan was head of the
Latin American desk of the state
department and was a political adviser
to the Secretary of State he too was a
Soviet agent both Duggan and field were
brought into a Soviet Espionage ring by
the same recruiter a woman of amazing
persuasiveness I got the null field
and I got them Larry Duggan
and I got them all you know sort of
the socks small fry like Brine and you
know technical Personnel several women
that were mail drops and so on so forth
and it was always um for example with
women was mostly done with sex
I would always send somebody who was
handsome and and
they generally went to bed with whatever
it was and uh and at work during the
1930s Hayden massing was Soviet
espionage's most effective recruiting
agent in America this is her only
television interview filmed shortly
before her death in 1981.
during the 1920s she married into the
Communist Party in Europe falling in
love with its Intrigue and fellowship
her first husband was Gerhart Eisler a
top official of the Communist
International Espionage arm the common
turn
when you were 17 and you joined the
Communist party or became a member of
that Circle
but is it an emotional rather than a
political conversion only emotional not
political at all didn't understand a
thing about
that as I said I would have understood
this one sentence it is
a theory an ideology
which has as its aim a better life for
all that was good enough for me but the
life of all I'm amongst all
but that was as political as as it was
otherwise it was emotional I married
into the party
but for somebody who didn't understand
it you became one of their most
effective operators beta much much much
later
much later when I understood much more
and when I uh when really my
Effectiveness is so closely married
connected to Fascism I was effective
because there was Fascism and fascism
had to be thought it took me a long time
and I didn't want to realize it that
actually I was not fighting fascism it
was all baloney the Russians used me but
to admit that to yourself is of course
Very degrading
self-degrading you hesitate very much to
do that so for a long time I pretended
that I believe that this is the way to
fight Fascism and I acted it out okay
well let's go into some of the areas
where you were very successful you came
over to America in the early 1930s what
did you do and how did you get into that
Circle where you could operate
effectively well first of all when
that people in Moscow that many
Americans in Moscow I was functionary
for example I was called on by the
coming turn to entertain important
Americans
when they came to Moscow so I had had
connections personal connections the
connections were with those in the
American government so Hayden massing
closely controlled by the Russians
working in New York City and armed with
a sharp wit and a fierce determination
went on to recruit Lawrence Duggan one
of the senior members of the U.S state
Department
you know the
wonderful interesting isn't wasn't
difficult
I called him
because I unders you know he was a
friend of Noel field
um
and said that I wanted to see him and I
went into the state department into his
room and we made an appointment and I
approached him directly Howard Mary I
said you know I didn't tell you about
fascism you know it all you know it
better than I because you see all the
material I don't see
we want your help
will you help us
and he said yes
I have certain conditions
but yes I will help you now I will give
you all the material that I think might
be of interest to you and the Russians
into immediately who I was he was
Nobody's Fool
and only I will not give you the
material per se I will dictate it to
somebody and that somebody has to be
English speaking
and a very good shorthand
there it was I couldn't believe it
while recruiting noo field Ada messing
uncovered another Soviet spy ring in
Washington of which she had been unaware
I had worked on no field for a long time
I had listened to Wagner which I hate I
had read fraud which I dislike and
discussed fine points of Freud with him
you know really lying in my teeth and
um because I wanted I wanted him I
wanted to wanted to do a good job and I
had I also liked the family I liked her
better than him he was a little bit
although he was rather good looking you
know very tall and very sort of
gentleman like to me was a little bit
unappetizing I really could it must have
been a body smell uh I don't know what
it was but anyhow I liked her better she
was also more honest she was she was a
little dumb and one day
I said you don't know it's about time
that you you have more or less agreed
that you will work with me now I think
we
ought to start and he said
you know Heda
I wanted to tell you this and I
hesitated because I know it will upset
you but
I have decided that I will not work with
you but I would rather work with
somebody who does exactly the same thing
you do
who is however with me in the same
department and it would be so much
easier technically to convey whatever I
have to give to this person and I said
who is this person of course terrified
he was my investment of a one-year
studying Wagner and fruit for that
anyhow I said
um who is this man and he said I don't
think you know him his name is Al jahez
he was an advisor to President Roosevelt
at The crucial Yalta Conference and was
the man who flew to Washington with the
historic Charter documents of the United
Nations organizing conference in San
Francisco where he had served as
temporary Secretary General
Alger Hiss was a rising star in the
state department and director of The
Office of special political Affairs he
was never far from Center Stage
after allegations were made of his
communist activities he appeared before
the house on American Activities
Committee I am not
never have
a member of the
throughout two famous trials and a
conviction for perjury he has
steadfastly proclaimed his innocence and
today there is a strong Lobby in the
United States to overturn his
convictions Mr Chambers charged except
that I knew him briefly were you ever
come no
this man's memory is rather different
Nathaniel Weil was a member of the same
Communist Party cell as Alger his I want
to ask you if you ever met Elder hiss oh
yes about 30 times or so 30 40. under
what circumstances well I'm speaking
about uh see the cell met every week
and uh attendance was a very
duty to be taken very seriously
you had to have an extremely good excuse
for not being there
so that if one assumes that um
that I was in this unit for nine months
and that there was a meeting every week
it works out to about 30 or 40 times but
Hayden massing trying to recruit Noel
field had no idea that algerhis was also
working for the Soviets each of the
Communist cells were small and carefully
separated in this case both Alger Hiss
and Hayden messing were trying to
recruit the same man
I met algeris because Noah called me a
week after I'd been there in New York
and said can you come to Washington I
have dinner a dinner date for you and
after his at my house and I said of
course I'll come and I came
and I met him
and the beginning was that he said so
you are the girl that is trying to take
Noel away from me and I said uh well you
are the man who was trying to take Noel
away from me and
then I said I suppose I don't know the
exact words uh don't forget after all
I'm female and I'm a fighter and I won't
let that happen so easily
uh and he grinned and then we had all
sorts of conversations we stood alone he
and I at the window and spoke and the
farewell was that I said or he said and
I don't remember
who said what but he I think he said
whoever gets Noah after all we are
working for the same boss
[Music]
more than 90 percent
communist agents
are blackmail these people are not
ideological supporters
but they are brutally blackmail was this
what you look for when you were in the
check intelligence yeah the ability to
Blackmail people that's right that's
right yeah the fact that you were
forcibly trapped
and we know the way that you were
trapped it was a homosexual entrapment
that you were entrapped in which the
checks got you this is correct right
this man was blackmailed while on
Embassy Duty in Prague Czechoslovakia as
an Air Force Cipher clerk he was in a
position to seriously compromise NATO
Readiness secrets
it was a stupid thing to do and I did it
I got caught doing it by somebody that
shouldn't have or shouldn't have
I've gone through this rigging world for
over a year after we left the front
I haven't heard from anybody since that
time most Americans have a very naive
politically very nice
and so I think it's in many cases very
easy for
for communist intelligence offices
to get in touch with important Americans
to
seduce them in one way or another and
likely to complete mail them
I was not contacted in Texas were back
here until about a month or two before
he ever left the country
when you say contact if you're contacted
by the text by the Czech intelligence
service well I don't know who they were
I was saying that was contacted yeah but
I assumed that they had what do you mean
when you say contacted how what form did
that contact take we just did a meeting
on the street
of a man just walked up to
and what did this man say well he
indicated that they had had photographs
of me and you know that he was
contacting it it's on future today
well can you tell me what did the check
intelligence service
ask you for or want you to do there's no
discussion at all
it was just the fact that he confronted
me with the fact that they had pictures
and photographs of me doing this
homosexual act with the other
individuals that was the whole
experiment there was nothing asked for
or given
when you said a fellow that was involved
in the situation
in the photographs yeah he he was he was
the other man with whom you were having
this affair with right
and he defected and as a result that was
how they found out about you
and you were never asked for secret
documents
there was just a man that came up to you
in the street in Prague and said that we
have photographs of you and we're gonna
ask you for something at a later date
[Music]
or whatever what kind of information
could you have theoretically given them
[Music]
in Moscow the KGB targets not only low
ranking officials sometimes their
blackmail extends right to the top John
Watkins was the Canadian ambassador to
the Soviet Union in the late 50s when he
was targeted for recruitment
two KGB defectors nasenko and goliczin
have revealed that Watkins was under KGB
control but the story has never before
received official confirmation William
Kelly is the former head of the RCMP
Security Service they knew he was a
homosexual he knew that they knew he was
a homosexual
were you saying that he was being
blackmailed by him
uh in in a kind of a way yes that he
knew that they could embarrass him if he
didn't cooperate
while in the Soviet Union Lester B
Pearson later to become Canadian Prime
Minister and John Watkins met with
Khrushchev at his Dhaka on the Crimean
sea the meetings were arranged by the
Soviets to increase Watkins prestige in
Pearson's eyes and to speed his
promotion to positions with access to
sensitive information
when you find that a man like Watkins an
ambassador was a homosexual
and you knew the pressure that was being
placed on homosexuals in uh Russia at
that time
uh he was an obvious Target for 4K GB
and he was surrounded by the KGB
Watkins handler was Anatoly gorsky Alias
Professor nikitin who had controlled the
Soviet agents philby McLean Burgess and
blunt in Britain
soon after Pearson's visit Watkins was
transferred back to Ottawa as assistant
under Secretary of external Affairs
external Affairs chairs the committee
that controls all of Canadian
intelligence matters he died of a heart
attack on October 10 1964 in Montreal
after being interrogated by the RCMP for
over 10 years Tom Fox was head of U.S
military counterintelligence in charge
of breaking major Soviet operations in
America and Europe well the Soviets are
like any good headhunting business
organization that's looking for good
talent
the Soviets will establish a
relationship with the individuals
determine the individual's needs desires
strengths and weaknesses and try to
exploit that
David Barnett was a former employee with
the CIA whose business was facing
bankruptcy his solution was to approach
the KGB in exchange for money he
compromised several CIA operations and
the lives of the agents involved he was
instructed by the Soviets to obtain
positions with several Congressional
intelligence committees in order to pass
on inside information for his Services
he received 92 thousand dollars
but the Soviets used settler methods for
recruiting at the time when he was a
congressional assistant with access to
U.S naval Readiness Secrets Jim cappus
was approached by a Soviet official
offering him the opportunity to write
articles for a leading Soviet press
agency and I as a staff member had
access to most of the classified
materials that might have been presented
to the committee from time to time
how were the approaches first made
initially it was strictly social uh
later of course the meetings were
arranged they were arranged for just the
two of us they were arranged at
primarily at bars what exactly did he
suggest you should do in the beginning
he suggested that I write articles for
him theoretically to be translated and
published in the novosti Press which is
a Soviet to press service
course later it became more obvious the
type of stories that he was seeking were
those that were based on classified
information or information that was not
generally known to the public in
attempting to recruit agents the KGB
also uses the services of the
International Information Department
which controls tasks Pravda is Bestia
and the novice depress agency
[Music]
a man who is familiar with the
procedures of recruitment is Yuri
bisminov who served with novelty in
India before defecting to the West
because during my 12 years with novasti
I
I it was quite clear to me that about 70
to 80 it's hard to count percent of the
novelty employees are at the same time
either full-time officers of the KGB or
part-time Cult agents like myself when I
was working for the novice team for
Soviets like Yuri bisminov or Carlo
tuomi an illegal sent to America to
recruit agents the methods of
recruitment are deceptively easy
recruit somebody
you recruit them by
establishing a friendship but you don't
you don't recruit them as a as a Soviet
spy you're supposedly working for some
Corporation
which is interested in a trade secrets
of a competing Corporation or maybe
you're asking information on behalf of a
friend who's writing a technical book
so is this what you were told in Moscow
that you should not say that you're
working for the Soviets that you should
work for a company or right right you
come out you come out as a Soviet
intelligence agent only when you recruit
the person on ideological basis
in the 1930s no one was more successful
in recruiting Young Americans than hater
messing she recruited at the highest
levels of government and discovered that
the ideological approach worked best
with the privileged in America it would
have been almost impossible to recruit A
working class
almost impossible of America yeah
but it would be easy to recruit the
intellectual and middle class
but what does a Communist Party have to
offer the elite
great ideas
the freedom of all time
Marxism
a different economical system
thoughts
new medical experiments knew the world
the world
you see the Soviet Union has never
changed its goal never
you know it's it's called as a phrase it
still wants to dominate the world
you know that it has never changed that
[Music]
in the late 1950s when Fidel Castro was
taking his Revolution out of the
mountains toward the ultimate victory Of
Havana the world watched what was
believed to be a popular uprising of the
people that is not communism
or Marxism in our idea
our political philosophic is
representative democracy and social
justice in a well-planned economy
but the revolution provided a new base
for the KGB and the Communist
intelligence Networks
larislav bittmann was a deputy director
with Czech intelligence a few years
after the revolution the checks helped
to build up the into the Cuban
intelligence service and then I think in
the early 1960s the Soviets took over
completely when Cuba was really in the
hands of the Soviet Soviet Union
yeah
at the Cuban mission to the United
Nations in New York City where 98 Cuban
Nationals work at least half are members
of the DGI the Cuban intelligence
service
this man is Nestor Garcia until the
summer of 1980 he was officially listed
as the first Secretary to the Cuban
mission
but in reality he was chief of station
for Cuban intelligence in New York City
in Moscow the direct responsibility for
running Cuban intelligence is assigned
to Department 11 of the KGB the same
Department that controls the checks
polls and other European communist
intelligence agencies
since the late 1960s Soviet KGB officers
living in Havana have directly run the
operation of Cuban intelligence
as a result of two years research the
connections team has been able to
ascertain these startling facts
Cuban intelligence was taken over by the
Soviets in 1969.
at that time it became and has remained
totally financed and controlled by the
KGB
now living in hiding this man is the
highest ranking Cuban officer to defect
to the United States
this is the first known television
interview that a DGI officer has given
Moscow I was trained in
recruiting of Agents
in infiltrating uh the CIA
encounter intelligence was all your
training directed at the United States
or your training in Moscow directed at
the United States even if the work dealt
with corporations in Italy France
England Canada it was ultimately
directed against the United States in
the case of plan or sabotage against an
American Embassy the physical laid out
of the plant had to be known was there
any other installations than embassies
that were looked at for sabotage
big American companies
[Music]
since the late 1960s general seminov of
the KGB has controlled the DGI from
Havana for the Soviets
General Simone
Soviet chief would be the one who would
give the order so the Russians
controlled Cuban intelligence actually
controlled totally and absolutely
the second most important base of Cuban
intelligence in North America is the
Cuban Consulate in Montreal from here
and other Cuban diplomatic missions the
DGI conducts intelligence and Espionage
operations through a spy Network
designed to increase the kgb's
penetration of North American Life
[Music]
you saw the files of these people in
Havana correct
yes I know many were they working for
instance trying to get defense secrets
from America that's been yelling yes
definitely so what else
economic information leftist movements
in the United States on the blacks
industrial plants of the United States
like uh power plants and so on and so
forth why would they be interested in
power plants
this information is necessary to the
Soviets
this former DGI officer was shown the
official list of the 12 Cubans stationed
in Washington at the Cuban interest
section how many on that list do you
know as being intelligence
[Music]
certainly have you ever heard of a Mr
Ricardo es cartan
he's an intelligence officer
Juan carbonel is another intelligence
officer who was in Jamaica
[Music]
six months after this interview Ricardo
escartine was expelled from the U.S for
Espionage activities but the other DGI
officers carbonel arbolea and Martinez
are still operating in Washington
in the mid-1960s the black ghettos of
America erupted in flames and violence
in an apparently spontaneous protest
the riots did not need instigation by
outside elements yet once the conditions
were ripe revolutionaries of the left
moved in funded and supported by the
Cuban DGI
[Music]
one such revolutionary was Philip loose
what was the nature of your meeting with
Fidel Castro uh our nature first of all
was we met a number of times but our
first meeting dealt with what the group
would do in Cuba secondly was what we
could do in the United States once we
returned and third of all uh we received
uh over twenty thousand dollars to bring
back to the United States uh the next
year we were engaged in uh tremendous uh
uh riots in New York City which then
spread to Cleveland to Los Angeles to
other areas
agitation that juncture was vital not
only to our cause but to the cause of
the Cuban we train people in the use of
weapons we also train people on how to
stand on top of their tenement buildings
and throw down garbage cans the bricks
we also taught them how to make molotov
cocktails
as a matter of fact the Cubans at that
time said to us your Revolution is your
own Revolution
but while we were in Cuba
they gave us money to bring back the
United States to be utilized uh in
Terrorist activities they also invited
us to the Embassy wherein they gave us
money send Young Americans to Cuba who
were later trained in Terrorist
activities
we went to the Cuban Embassy uh on a
number of occasions uh to get funding
[Music]
do we understand
in the 1960s Bernadine Dorne was one of
the leaders of the violent radical group
known as the weathermen on December 3rd
1980 in Chicago Bernadine Dorne
surrendered after 10 years in hiding
with her was another weatherman Bill
Ayers with whom she had been living they
held a press conference and stated their
continued commitment to radical change
resistance by every means necessary is
happening and will continue to happen
within the United States as well as
around the world
and I remain committed to the struggle
ahead
the man with Bernadine Dorne Bill Ayers
was one of the key members of the
weathermen during the 1960s
a man who knew airs well during those
years was Larry grathwald a former
member of The Weather Underground which
had developed close ties with the Cubans
well when when the Cubans viewed the the
Revolutionary struggle in the United
States they recognized the fact that the
that the left as it existed in 69 and 70
was not capable of of overthrowing the
government by itself
consequently
they they had hoped that the that the
group itself would be able to to attack
the system from within and provide
assistance
to the international movement the
international Communist Revolution as a
weatherman if I became cut off from the
main body of the of the organization The
Weather Underground organization I could
make contact or re-establish contact by
going to the Cuban Embassy in Mexico or
Canada
and asking to as an example I want to to
get in touch with Bernadine Delgado
that was the code word delgado and I
would tell them that I'm Larry Delgado
and I can be reached at such a such a
phone number or such and such an address
and the Cubans would make the connection
and put me back in contact with the how
do you know this
how do you know how do you know this
information the old Bill airs gave me
those instructions and it was either
February or March of 1970 in Detroit
the Cuban DGI is organized into seven
departments and subdivided into
Geographic sections the largest one
being the United States section
controls North American operations
including the UN diplomatic posts and
radical groups
during the 1970s hundreds of Young
Americans circumvented U.S travel
regulations to go to Cuba to harvest
sugar cane and experience the Cuban
Revolution first hand as a cover for the
recruitment of the weathermen the DGI
organized the Benson Ramos brigades the
organizers tour guides and hosts were
officers of the DGI who used the
occasion to train Young American
radicals
Cuban intelligence was well prepared for
the vencer Ramos brigades when they
arrived
Brigade contingent arrived in Cuba all
the operational of the vgi had to drop
what they were doing and go to work on
adventure Brigade we had to investigate
collect background to see who could be
recruited what information could be
obtained do you know of Young Americans
who were recruited
in the Brigade to work for the Cuban
intelligence who came back to America
and were secretly working for the Cubans
yes and they are still working still
working for the Cubans in America
yes definitely the Brigade was
established with the sole purpose of
providing a cover for the weatherman to
get their people to Cuba for training
and that that's why it existed as a
matter of fact when our people came back
off the first then ceramus Brigade and I
think it was February of 1970. the
criticism that the Cubans had made about
the Valencia Ramos Brigade indicated
that the majority of people being sent
there they felt were useless they really
weren't helping them Harvest sugar cane
but that it was justified in the sense
that here was a means to train and
politicize weatherman context and
whether Cuba somehow had the ability to
uh bring out young people at that time
uh the feeling of of Communism with a
mambo beat or uh somehow that uh what
was happening in Cuba was totally
different than what was happening
anyplace else in the world
this was the main reason of the
interview showed by the Russians in
trying to control the DGI because the
Cubans could work far more easily than
the Soviets weren't the weather people
aware that they were being used by the
Soviets and something no they
they view the Cubans as being the
Vanguard of the international Communist
Revolution
now the Vanguard essentially means that
the Cubans are at the very tip of the
spear they're the leadership
um
the Russians are being used by the
Cubans now this is the weatherman's
rationalization of this this interaction
between the Soviets and the Cubans the
Cubans said you've got to become active
you've got to start doing things and
planning a national action to protest
the beginning of the Chicago 8 trial and
to commemorate the the riots during the
Democratic National Convention of 68
uh and to protest the war in Vietnam is
not action action requires that you
confront the system violently
so when the weatherman got back from
Cuba they changed the National Action to
the days of Rage
[Music]
[Applause]
1869 was an attack on the city of
Chicago and its Police Department
[Applause]
for four days anti-war protesters
urged on by agitators of the weatherman
rioted in the streets engaging in
violent confrontations and pitched
backwards with the police
[Music]
we're back during the 1960s was rocked
by terrorist bombings and confrontations
between the police and French Canadian
separatist demonstrators supporting the
flq
[Music]
DGI contacts within revolutionary
organizations like the flq had built an
international terrorist ring
it was the late March or early April of
1970. I was in Buffalo New York
uh the foco there consisted of uh five
people Bill Ayers and Naomi Jaffe were
two of those people
uh Bill and Naomi left and went to
Canada where at in Canada I don't know
to meet with members of the Quebec
Liberation Front with the objective of
establishing closer ties with them
and and cooperating and actions if
possible uh on both sides of the border
and they also received it was either two
or three thousand dollars from the
Quebec Liberation Front that had been
sent
from Cuba for the weatherman it was an
attempt in 1965.
buy a group of blacks who had gone to
Cuba under my office to blow up the
Statue of Liberty
the Black Liberation Front which had
been formed in Cuba in 1964 was the
prime mover behind this plot the bombing
was prevented however when the police
recovered the explosives from their
hiding place in the Bronx
amongst those arrested was Michel duclow
a member of the French Canadian
separatist organization which provided
the explosives to the Cuban trained
extremists she pleaded guilty to
illegally transporting Dynamite
we know that uh the weatherman
underground organization uh went to Cuba
and utilized the same kinds of
techniques that we utilized these people
uh did engage in in direct bombing and
killing uh in the United States so I
fear and yet most of them haven't been
heard from for a long long time that's
right but they're still out there
they're underground and the question is
uh over a long period of time what does
it take to activate them
[Music]
thank you
the biggest Cuban intelligence efforts
against the United States do not take
place in North America it is in the
Caribbean and Central America where the
Cuban DGI backed by the Soviet KGB are
actively assisting revolutionary
movements hostile to the United States
[Music]
in 1978 the government of the Caribbean
island of Grenada was replaced by a
Marxist regime led by Morris Bishop
the government of the criminal dictator
Eric M Gary has been overthrown
a hereby ordered
one by one the governments that have
been called right-wing dictatorships are
being attacked and replaced by left-wing
dictatorships financed by the Cubans
brother Marty Bishop the long nights of
Terror
the long night of repression and
hardship
has ended
in Grenada one of the first acts of the
new government was to bring in Cubans to
build a new airport the airport like the
island itself has military importance to
the Cubans and ultimately to the Soviets
grenada's proximity to the Venezuelan
and Middle Eastern oil tanker routes to
the U.S make it an important strategic
location and in Nicaragua where the
sandinistas overthrew the regime of
Anastasia Samosa over 3 000 Cubans moved
in immediately after the revolution
[Music]
on the first anniversary of their
takeover the new government staged a
celebration for visiting guests like
Fidel Castro whose ambassadors to
Nicaragua Lopez Diaz and to Grenada
Torres Rizzo our talk DGI officers
one of the speakers was Morris Bishop of
Grenada
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
Guatemala
Puerto Rico one after the other the
Revolutionary movements of the islands
and the Central American nations are
being assisted by the Cubans and behind
them the Soviets
Puerto Rico is an important area for
Cuban activities electronically linked
with navy installations on the U.S
Mainland Puerto Rico is crucial as a
submarine tracking base
using top secret undersea monitoring
equipment Americans are able to keep
track of Soviet submarine actions on the
entire Atlantic coastline
[Music]
in April 1980 10 faln Puerto Rican
revolutionaries were arrested outside
Chicago Illinois with them was a van
filled with explosives and arms they
were convicted on February 11 1981 of
seditious conspiracy for a wave of bomb
blasts that have killed five people and
wounded at least 100 others as Castro
run the Puerto Rican movement in the
United States team yes
I know many operations
that were done through the uh
the center of New York
where they received money weapons
for them to work in the United States
[Music]
Soviet Naval activities in the Caribbean
and the Atlantic are of increasing
strategic significance as is Havana's
Harbor to the Soviet Fleet
in addition to surface ships submarines
are a vital part of a growing Armada
for submarines are hard to detect as
they lie off America's Shores armed with
nuclear missiles
foreign fishing chips are another part
of the Soviet Armada off the shores of
North America
often used for electronic intelligence
gathering the fishing ships also serve
as Shields protecting the submarines
below from the radar and sonar of the
anti-submarine forces of the Americans
and Canadians
it was on one of these ships that Boris
Stern served
the submarine kept contact with my ship
when we came near Newfoundland
the captain
had a radiogram
on the submarine location
the fishing ship
covered the submarine
from the airplanes
above
these ships have also been used to
provide Irish terrorists with arms
my ship this is a fishing ship and not a
military ship
at two o'clock at night as my ship came
near Ireland
two boats with Irish people came to the
ship
and the KGB officer on our boat Misha
boulanger
gave them a very big box we think
of arms
Soviet Espionage efforts in North
America are designed to assist the
capabilities of their submarines in the
Atlantic and Caribbean
some of these efforts have seemed
trivial yet the results are still
affecting Canadian and American Security
this Canadian civil servant was targeted
by the KGB
he was at first offered small payments
for unclassified information but the
promise of larger sums soon led to his
acquiring more sensitive strategic
documents such as classified Naval maps
of old wrecks that lay on the bottom of
the Atlantic along the Canadian
coastline
William Kelly was head of the security
service of the Royal Canadian Mounted
Police at the time
well now these Maps were of extreme
importance
to the Russians
and particularly for their submarine
Commanders
because when there was the
Patrol boats of the Canadian Navy on the
surface
the submarine would know it and to avoid
detection that's all the submarine had
to do was settle down alongside of a
wreck so that when the patrol boat above
would make contact with some sounding
device
with the bottom of the ocean with some
metal down there he'd look on a map and
he'd say oh yes this is just a wreck and
he'd move on leaving the submarine to
continuous Patrol safely
[Music]
oh
in the 1950s an obscure unassuming
photographer lived alone in Brooklyn
operating his business from a storefront
Rudolph Abel attracted little attention
until it was revealed he headed a Soviet
spy ring operating in America
[Music]
he was caught and sentenced to 30 years
in prison
I would refer that question to my
attorney Mr Donovan
our
American System of trial by jury is the
fairest system in the world
in the world of Espionage Abel was known
as an illegal a spy who lives under an
assumed name and is controlled by
Department s of the KGB
it is Department s that selects the
agents who quietly blend into the
societies of other nations and Lead
seemingly normal lives while secretly
carrying out orders passed to them from
Moscow
[Music]
this is part of a television program
about the black riots in America in
1968.
it was produced by the Canadian
Broadcasting Corporation the end credits
are interesting in that the sound man on
the film crew Rudy Hermann was a KGB
illegal
he was Colonel Rudolph Hermann whose
cover story Bears many similarities to
that of Colonel Abel
both men entered the U.S through Canada
and both pursued careers in the film
industry Rudolph Herrmann went first to
Toronto where he lived quietly with his
family in a small house on Sutherland
Avenue
He was ordered to take a job with the
Canadian Broadcasting Corporation
in 1969 Colonel Hermann was ordered by
Moscow to move from Toronto to New York
and set up as a photographer while he
organized his network of Espionage in
the United States
his appearance has been disguised and
his voice electronically altered
oh yes for the past
25 years I was getting every weekend on
two days
a radio Transmissions
[Music]
when Herman was finally caught by the
FBI Richard Kinsey was Deputy Chief of
the Soviet desk at FBI headquarters in
Washington he had been sent on meetings
that he or had been sent to meet people
in Canada for one thing yes he had
do you know anything about why he was
sent up to Canada
I'd prefer not to go into uh to that
Colonel Hermann traveled to Quebec City
where he went to Laval University and
met with the Canadian economics
professor named Hugh Hamilton
Hugh Hamilton is a specialist in
petroleum economics he has been named by
Colonel Herman as a long time trusted
Source Professor Hamilton met Herman
many times and supplied him with
information
[Music]
this interview was filmed with hidden
cameras
[Music]
on your faces
Herman met Hamilton at least a dozen
times in Canada and in 1975 they met in
Haiti where Hamilton passed Hermann
information about the Chinese Embassy
come there to see you there was a top
secret FBI RCMP operation targeting
Professor Hamilton and Colonel Hermann
codenamed red pepper
what was the reason for the meetings
between Herman and Hamilton
again you're getting into what is still
a sensitive area I can say this that
Colonel Herman was ordered to contact
Hamilton by his own admission by his
superiors of Moscow but beyond that I
would not like to go
Professor Hamilton is not as naive as he
might appear
during World War II he worked for free
French intelligence
to the war he worked for Canadian
intelligence in Germany
but then in the late 1940s he met in
Ottawa with Vladimir Borodin a senior
recruiter for Soviet intelligence
did you not
[Music]
I guess
from 1956 to 1961 Hamilton had top
secret security clearance when he worked
for nato in Paris
Professor Hamilton has also made two
trips to Cuba
he met with a leading Cuban intelligence
officer Ricardo escartine who has
recently been expelled from the United
States for Espionage activities
in 1975 he made a trip to Moscow
how come you went to the Soviet Union
at all
[Music]
later he confessed to making a 10 to 12
day trip to the Soviet Union in 1975
where in his own words he was under
considerable pressure from the KGB
subsequently the RCMP raided hambleton's
Ottawa residence and seized the
shortwave radio and code books
Professor Hambleton was just one of
Colonel hermann's contacts Herman has
provided the FBI with significant leads
on Soviet agents operating in North
America his Espionage activities were of
the utmost importance
my job would be without any importance
I would definitely really not spend such
a long time in United States
and besides uh you know during my years
of service I was several times promoted
now Colonel Hermann is somewhere in
hiding in the United States an illegal
who came to the surface
Carlo tuomi is another example of an
illegal sent to America by Moscow
you were known as an illegal what
exactly is an illegal illegal is a
foreign agent who
enters the country with
voice documents
and
establishes himself as a citizen of that
Country and
bill by Lil acquires all the
documentation and driver's license
birth certificates credit cards and so
and so on finds a job
gets all the credentials and on the
background
future references
as a
Bonafide citizen of that country
question in this case that's what
happened to you right that's right and
you got all this from Moscow when you
were trained as a spy at a spy school in
Moscow that's right that's right that
was a major part of my schooling
in case of North America Canada and the
United States what is much more
dangerous are these so-called illicus
who are smuggled into these countries
that is people who are
who come here under a new identity
and they they live as citizens of these
countries and they would start
operating really in in case of war
between
the Soviet Union and the United States
for example or in in the time of major
of a very serious crisis when for
example the diplomatic relations would
be broken in case of War
I would I would be
among other illegals the only
means by which the Soviet Union could
get any Military
Intelligence from the from the United
States because all their diplomatic
means all the open means
would wake her up
and at the time you were with Czech
intelligence and there were actually
agents sent over here yes who were to
just sit and wait that's right yeah
and very many
the Soviets used many roots to secretly
Place their illegals the Soviet fishing
fleets which regularly stop at North
American ports have often provided the
KGB with a secure means of Landing their
spies Boris stern was a photojournalist
with the Soviet fishing fleet and
recalls an incident he once witnessed
one time we left a man in St John's
Newfoundland
he had been kept in hiding on my boat
I thought and the other people on our
boat thought he was an illegal being
dropped into Canada you believe that
this was a case of dropping a spy off in
Canada
yes
within the KGB there is another
department which controls illegals
Department V conducts what are known
within the KGB by the Macabre
description wet Affairs assassinations
sabotage and other violent acts it is
the department that takes care of the
Dirty Work of the KGB
people until he defected to the
westfchenko was the senior Soviet at the
U.N
that has been the department was uh
which operates in the in the secrecy
which is even unbelievable for the
Soviet Secret Society have you ever
known nations are have you ever known of
any Department B people in North America
yes it was in New York in the Soviet
mission in New York in the in the middle
of the 60s and uh the one of my friends
who happened also to be working with the
kajibi uh he they told me look you know
this man looks so quiet calm and even
respectable if someone if you look at
him he would never believe that he
really what he is really doing and to
what branch or to what department he
himself belonged the most Sinister thing
in the world which he is doing
this man was a member of Department V it
was trained in Moscow and sent to Canada
where explosives had already been hidden
for his use Adventure
well then fine let's do an interview I
know okay well he refused to be
interviewed after months of work the
Norfolk investigative unit traced him to
a small town where he now lives in
hiding in the KGB you were sent over to
North America to engage in Espionage
acts and you decided for one reason or
another not to go through with this
uh was sent to Edmonton in western
Canada where he spent four years working
and acquiring all the credentials of a
normal Canadian citizen in 1965 the call
came from Moscow He was ordered to go to
a Toronto suburb and observe a house and
its occupants the house was at the time
inhabited by one of the most famous
defectors of all Igor guzenko who fled
the Soviet Embassy in 1945. his
defection led to the uncovering of
Soviet spy rings in North America and
was a severe setback for Soviet
Espionage twenty years after it occurred
Department V of the KGB was still
sending its agents looking for him
[Music]
in my life of course was very very and
if I open door you see that I never
opened doors
never opened or in my house it possibly
went to the wrong house
[Music]
I don't know I really don't know so he
could they might come in a long house or
something but I never myself open the
door
where we think the Vodka had been
activated by KGB agent Oleg komenko who
at the time was working as a counselor
at the Soviet Embassy in Ottawa and was
traveling with the Russian mosaev ballet
on a North American tour
strategically placed in western Canada
sabotka was ordered to plan in the event
of war the destruction of the key
refining and pumping stations that
Supply much of North America with its
energy Edmonton is also a center of top
secret cold weather testing for Canadian
and American forces and sabotka was
ordered to find all he could about these
facilities
he had other important missions one of
which was to act as a link between
Moscow and a KGB sabotage Network in
North America was no accident that you
were sent out to Edmonton with oil
refineries and all that surfing
it it was not an accident in your Center
[Music]
and I would presume that they they had
their plans on that I must really go
[Music]
thank you
this house off Massachusetts Avenue in
Washington DC is an office of the Soviet
military attaches some of these men have
legitimate business there however most
military attaches in reality are spies
of the gru operating closely with the
KGB
working under the ministry of Defense
the gru specifically confines its
activities to espionage in military
matters
the first Chief directorate of the KGB
however has ultimate authority over the
gru Espionage networks
during World War II Carlo tuomi was
recruited into the Soviet military
intelligence he was born in Michigan a
Finnish parents who left America and
went to the Soviet Union while he was
still a boy his Boyhood knowledge of
America made him a natural candidate to
become a Soviet spy sent back to the U.S
as an illegal
I was trained to collect
military information
about the United States armed forces
with special emphasis
um
Naval Affairs and shipments of arms
locations of
docks and warehouses specifically in the
Harvard New York where these arms were
being stored and handled and from where
they've been shipped to foreign
countries in other words you were a spy
that's true
I studied
the
United States in general the geography
economy government armed forces the
woman who was
my English instructor
I've been born
in Brooklyn it was a graduate of
Columbia University I had a excellent
command of a modern American English
what about uh the American culture I
mean how were you trained so that you
would feel at home in America once you
got there from Moscow
well
that basic way of
getting me into touch with American
reality and culturally by showing
American movies or movies you can learn
quite a bit of people behave how they
dress how they talk and so that's a very
important way to train an agent who is
to operate in that particular country
one of my one of the agents he was not
an instructor but he was a more
administrative
Personnel he took me to uh Storehouse
which looked like a
really like the American
clothing store
where they picked the clothing the right
size well the suits and Overcoat had to
be had to be adjusted
were these American clothes that were
shipping over the Soviet Union they were
American clothes uh a lot of them were
foundations
I entered the United States by train I
took a train from
Montreal
to Chicago
so Canada was used as a as a stepping
ground
to enter the United States because
Canada
a usual way that the Soviets put spies
in the United States it is uh
it is considered the easiest way
Soviet agents in the U.S went to Great
Lengths to create what is called his
legend or his cover story this Legend
uh for the later years where I was
employed especially in New York and New
York and then in Milwaukee
the Soviet
diplomatic
intelligence agents had done a lot of
groundwork they had studied these
different places
they they took
picture from the outside they had even
some pictures taken inside of these
these places
in Moscow to only were shown these
photographs of a lumber company in the
Bronx where he was supposed to have
worked and of a General Electric Plant
where he was also supposed to have been
employed
they have been taken by
uh
Soviet
diplomatic personnel in most cases
working for the U.N
instructions for me originally and were
sent in corporate form to Target
intelligence agents who were posing as a
U.N diplomats
and they were
processed
by these
[Music]
diplomats by and then sent to me
um
by letter with a New York postmark did
you ever get money from Soviet officials
working with or for the U.N definitely
they they left the drops
[Music]
magnetic containers like this I usually
I usually received the three thousand
dollars at a time it was always in
advance
once I received 5400 which was in which
was in advance this container
how is it container used
well the top of the container is
magnetized
and then it is left at a predetermined
place
which is called a drop under a railroad
bridge under an elevated
um
inside a
support of a bridge or something and it
was never lost this was a very reliable
Gadget and this was used all over New
York City
or in places in New York City yes I had
four different drops as this FBI photo
shows to Omi met with his Soviet Handler
Alex a galkin he then took a cover job
at Tiffany's Jewelers in New York
beneath this Subway bridge in the Bronx
was one of the drop points he had for
messages
another was the Hudson River train line
another was under this railroad bridge
in Queens at 69th Street
another on this telephone pole in
Yonkers
once he was well established tuomi was
ordered to take a job where he could
carry out surveillance of the docks at
the Port of New York eventually he was
caught by the FBI and became a double
agent
when you were caught by the FBI did you
try to Signal your Soviet handlers at
the U.N or in Moscow that you had been
caught
not immediately because I I couldn't it
was in my mind
but I I couldn't do it immediately I did
some
the
a signal
to the center which I Soviet
intelligence Military Intelligence
headquarters in Moscow I sent
a signal
three months after having copper FBI how
did you send the signal what means I I
sent the signal by inserting
it and uh
uh message
which
I
wrote on the
under the control of the FBI
but I got away from the FBI agents for a
few minutes
uh
to write that message using the using
the washroom
and was this a hidden writing technique
that you used yes I I had an extra sheet
of
chemically treated paper which was used
for secret writing and I used that in in
the washroom
there was a internal struggle in Sodom I
was torn about apart I was
pro-soviet
I believed in a Soviet system and here I
was working for the FBI the enemy
of my country
I I just couldn't live with the idea
of of
between the Soviet Union are you still
pro-soviet oh definitely not so what
changed you I don't understand how
you've changed or why you've changed
that's uh that's a very long process
something that doesn't happen overnight
this is the KGB Blue Book where tuomi is
listed under his Soviet name in it he is
named as an enemy of the Fatherland
but even a spy caught and turned finds
it difficult to be parted from his
country
because of the family
your family that you had over in the
summer yes I I had a wife and I had
three children otherwise uh coming to
back to the United States that's that's
the greatest thing that ever happened to
me
have you ever heard from your former
wife or your children
no I haven't heard from them since 1963
[Music]
on November 15 1979 Sir Anthony blunt a
distinguished British art historian and
the art advisor to the queen was
stripped of his Knighthood what happens
now
a sharp House of Commons have been told
by the Prime Minister Mrs Thatcher that
blunt had been a Soviet agent while at
Cambridge University in the 30s he acted
as a talent spotter for the Soviets and
later while a member of British
intelligence he continued to pass
information to the Russians by remaining
silent about his friends involved in
spying he was directly responsible for
exposing British agents and operations
in the mid-1930s it seemed to me and to
many of my contemporaries but the
Communist Party in Russia constituted
the only firm bull work against fascism
since the Western democracies were
taking an uncertain and compromising
attitude towards Germany
I was persuaded by Guy Burgess that I
could best serve the cause of
anti-fascism by joining him in his work
for the Russians
this was a case of political conference
against royalty the country
I chose conscience
when later I realized the true facts
about Russia I was prevented from taking
any action by personal loyalty I could
not denounce my friends
Cambridge University in the 1930s where
young men were recruited to rise up
quietly to the highest ranks of the
British establishment while secretly
working for the Soviets these were the
moles
the most notorious was Kim philby Who
Rose to be a senior officer in MI6 the
British intelligence agency as liaison
officer with the CIA philby was well
placed to relay vital Western secrets to
the Soviets since 1963 philby has lived
in Moscow and is a colonel in the KGB
his tip-offs were to cost many Western
agents their lives
Donald McLean and Guy Burgess were
working for the foreign office and both
were friends of filby they also worked
for the Soviets until they fled to
Moscow in 1952
as head of the American Department
McLean had access to these top secret
briefs of President Truman's assurances
to then British prime minister Atlee
that American threats to use the atomic
bomb in the Korean War would never be
carried out this valuable information
went straight to McLean's Soviet
handlers
but there were many Americans also
involved in similar activities in the
1930s Nathaniel Weil was one of
thousands of Young Americans who decided
that the fascism of Hitler's Germany was
the true enemy and that communism was
the answer he became a secret party
member who took his orders from the
Soviets while working for the U.S
government we were to rise
until positions of as much power as we
could in the government
to influence the government in a
socialist or communist Direction
and uh
so that in the event of our Victory
there would be trained men
to take over a major governmental
tests
seen here at a government conference in
the 30s Nathaniel Weil was just one of
many Americans secretly working for the
Soviets within the U.S government
we were to sever all connections
with known Communists abruptly and
instantly
we were not to express left-wing views
under any circumstances
and if we saw people who seem to have
likely recruits
we would bring the name before the group
where this would be discussed
but we would have no further contact
with that person
in other words a decision would be made
and then some entirely different person
would make this the approach thus
preserving the uh clandestine nature of
the cell
Harry Dexter white assistant Secretary
of the U.S treasury during the War years
was entrusted with the responsibility
for all treasury policy bearing on
Foreign Relations he was also a Soviet
mole in his sensitive position he was
not only well placed to pass on
intelligence material but to influence
policy decisions as well under Soviet
instructions White drafted a plan for
treasury secretary Henry morgenthau one
of Franklin Delano Roosevelt's closest
advisors which was presented to the
Allies gathered at the Quebec conference
in September in 1944.
dismissed as ill-conceived by Winston
Churchill and the Chiefs of Staff The
morgenthalp Plan called for the total
de-industrialization of Germany after
the war under the pretext of permanently
disabling German militarism
it received wide publicity particularly
in Germany where Adolf Hitler faced
opposition from his own officer Corps
and had recently survived an
unsuccessful bomb plot on his life from
amongst their numbers
in the face of advancing Allied armies
German propagandists called for
determined opposition as the only
alternative to the Grim future offered
by the morgenthal plan Germany was to be
shattered no matter what
[Music]
an early end to the war would have
interfered with the Soviets plans in
late 1944 their forces were still far to
the east but by May 1945 when Germany
finally surrendered all of Eastern
Europe Poland Czechoslovakia Hungary
Yugoslavia Bulgaria East Germany and
Romania were in their sphere of
influence
Harry Dexter White's influence on behalf
of the Soviets was not restricted to the
European theater of battle
in China the Soviets were supporting Mao
tiktong in his battle against both the
Japanese and the Nationalist Chinese
forces of Chiang Kai-shek
in 1943 President Roosevelt agreed to
lend Chang's armies 500 million dollars
for their fight against the Japanese and
agreed to immediately deliver 200
billion dollars in gold
but White's personal control over the
Chinese currency stabilization program
enabled him to ignore the declared
policy of Roosevelt and Congress and
delay the goal shipments the Chinese
economy continued to collapse Paving the
way for the eventual takeover by the
Communists
there were others Lachlan Curry was
President Roosevelt's personal Emissary
to the Nationalist Chinese
yet he too was secretly working with the
Soviets to destabilize nationalist China
but it was not until a few years later
that a shocked Nation learned the extent
of Soviet penetration when Elizabeth
Bentley a Soviet spy and Courier
testified before a U.S Senate committee
we were getting information from the RMA
for particularly the air car
from the treasury from the state
department from the OSS
from the CIAA the Rockefeller committee
from the OWI
um
did I name the treasure yes
yes from the war production board from
the war of Manpower Commission
I think that about covers itself
[Music]
she revealed that she had passed to the
Soviets inside White House information
that Lachlan Curry had given to her he
did pass on the information that the
American government was just about to
break the Soviet code
what happened then I relayed that to the
Russians they wanted know which code
which I couldn't obviously but Elizabeth
Bentley named Harry Dexter white as the
man who did the most damage in his
appearance before a U.S congressional
committee he denied he had ever been a
communist two days later he died of a
heart attack all these people were
accused by um former Soviets by masters
of being Espionage agents of the Soviet
government
assume that today the situation is worse
since all of our security has broken
down
[Music]
the greatest act of Soviet Espionage was
the operation to acquire the information
needed to build the atomic bomb
in 1953 efo and Julius Rosenberg were
executed for relaying Atomic information
to the Soviets but by far the most
important secrets were obtained from
highly placed agents working directly on
the top secret Manhattan Project
British Diplomat Donald McLean
photographed classified documents at
atomic energy headquarters for the
Russians
Claus Fuchs A German scientist
infiltrated the Manhattan Project in Los
Alamos New Mexico
these two were the key operatives
passing the latest developments to the
Soviets
pukes served less than 10 years in a
British jail and left for a hero's
welcome and the top scientific Post in
East Germany
scientific Espionage is a critical area
of operations for the KGB
Department T uses business fronts trade
delegations and exchange programs as
covers to acquire America's scientific
and Industrial knowledge
[Music]
American campuses are host to large
numbers of Soviet scientists the
universities are often the site of
secret scientific research in areas of
industrial and Military significance
for 10 years Professor Robert Burns of
Indiana University ran the academic
Exchange program between the Soviet
Union and the United States who for what
purposes have Soviets been in this
country well very clearly to get access
to American Science and Technology
very often to get access to particular
fields in which they are especially weak
one of my colleagues in the 60s made a
study of cosigan a casigan speech
identifying their shortcomings and the
list of Soviet Scholars who came to the
next the United States in the next few
years the list dovetailed perfectly this
year the Soviets tried to send 19 people
in very highly classified fields in
order to get around the restrictions
that we placed on exporting equipment
after the invasion of Afghanistan
an examination of the list of U.S
scholars in the Soviet Union is
revealing
it shows without exception that the
topic studied are all in the humanities
History Literature and the Arts
the Soviets do not allow us to study the
20th century in all of the 20 years of
the 22 years of the exchange program we
have not sent anyone to the Soviet Union
to study the things in which many
Americans are most interested
but the Soviets studying in the U.S are
enrolled in virtually every
strategically important area of research
being carried out lasers microcircuitry
and Ceramics all subjects that have
applications to spacecraft missiles and
weapons aimed at the United States
but while the Soviet Scholars are
welcomed with academic courtesy in North
America the same is not true of Western
scholars in the Soviet Union
I made a study of the exchanges from
1958 through
1975 and something like 20 percent of
the American participants in the major
program
were affected by the KGB in one way or
another obviously followed in some cases
harassed and intimidated in a few cases
seduced and put under pressures to
provide information about fellow
students or about American Embassy
officials one victim of the kgb's
manipulation of exchange programs was
Canadian Professor Johann kernigstein
targeted because of his expertise with
laser technology department T of the KGB
often Works closely with the gru Soviet
Military Intelligence whose objective is
to acquire military technology while
visiting the Soviet Union Professor
kunigstein was involved with the female
operative of the KGB Galina nusinova
returning to Ottawa he met with Yuri
usati of the gru Who convinced him to
take a laser Along on his next visit
without filing the proper export
authorization forms
[Music]
you because if you took it no it wasn't
because why did you take it over well to
do these experiments they had to be
doing I didn't want to do all that
routine kind of research
not all technology is gained by academic
exchanges many North American companies
are approached on a commercial basis by
the KGB haiko a Vancouver firm built the
Pisces the most advanced deep sea
submersible in the world as the Soviets
lagged far behind the West in deep sea
technology they were anxious to obtain
the submersible so haiko was approached
by a KGB agent named segalovich working
for Department T but haiko was forbidden
to export its product to the Soviet
Union because the Pisces utilized secret
welding techniques used on U.S Atomic
submarines
in order to avoid the export ban the
submersible was sent part by part to
Switzerland where it was assembled and
tested off the coast of Italy it was
then sent to the Soviet Union giving
them instant parity with the West
Department T of the KGB often devises
intricate schemes using third-party
Nationals to act as middlemen to
illegally avoid export bans placed on
strategic technology Peter virag a
Montreal lawyer recently entered into an
export deal involving sophisticated
computer equipment aware the equipment
would require special export licenses if
destined for other countries birag
arranged for the equipment to be
initially exported to Canada he then
illegally re-exported the computer
equipment to European centers where his
partner sent it on to final destinations
behind the Iron Curtain
this man Mark Andre de Geiger is a
Belgian with business ties in the Soviet
Union through bribery he tried to obtain
a computer source code valuable to the
Soviet military because it simplifies
computer operations thus reducing the
size of the computer required
but the transfer of American Technology
to the Soviets is not only accomplished
by the subterfuges of the KGB much of it
is done openly or as Lenin had predicted
when the time comes to hang the
capitalists they will be eager to sell
us the Rope
foreign
has sold the Soviets devices known as
array processors which are now being
used on Soviet killer submarines the
array processors interpret underwater
signals and Target the locations of
other submarines
in Corona California the principles of
Spar Optical research incorporated were
convicted of exporting copper water
cooled mirrors to Europe for reshipment
to the Soviet Union
these mirrors are essential to particle
beam and Laser research and the Soviet
military is now closer to achieving the
ability to destroy vital communication
satellites
a New England firm in 1972 sold the
Soviets their product one of the most
advanced ball bearing manufacturing
machines in the world the miniature ball
bearings are essential to the successful
launch of multiple Warheads from a
single missile Americans have also
provided the Soviets with the technology
critical to the guidance systems that
greatly increase the accuracy of Soviet
missiles
Dr Miles Costick is a washington-based
defense analyst the acquisition of
American inertial guidance technology
which consists of three different
Technologies has enabled Soviets to
abridge a tremendous Gap in the circular
error probable namely Precision of
on-target develop delivery of their
missiles when they started there were
about three miles of the Target and this
was not so long ago about eight years
ago
but now the Soviet missiles are accurate
to within 600 feet of American missile
silos
in order to overcome this increased
Soviet accuracy the MX missile system
has been proposed it is the largest
construction program in the history of
mankind with missiles on movable
carriers
and bad news which is the MX missile
system will cost us 60 to 100 billion
dollars
strictly to offset the advantages which
Soviet acquire to their scientific and
Industrial Espionage in the United
States
foreign
[Music]
is a former KGB agent
follows the
statement of a very ancient Chinese
philosopher Sanjay who was born 500
years
BC before Jesus Christ who said
something to the effect that fighting
war on the battlefield is the most
stupid and primitive way of fighting a
war the highest art of warfare is not to
fight at all
but to subvert anything of value in your
enemies country be it moral Traditions
religion respect to your Authority and
leaders cultural Traditions anything
put White against black
old against Young
uh I don't know wealth against poor and
so on doesn't matter
as long as it disturbs society as long
as it cuts the moral fiber of a Nation
it's good
and then you just take this country when
everything is subverted but the country
is disoriented and confused when it is
demoralized and then destabilized
then the crisis will come
within the KGB is a department that
specializes in planting false stories
and forged documents to distort others
perception of reality it is the
department that deals in disinformation
Department a of the KGB set up and
controls the disinformation department
of Czech intelligence
ladislav bittmann was deputy director of
that department when he was with Czech
intelligence
this information can have
a variety of forms it's basically
uh an information deliberately
misleading that is leaked through
variety of channels to the opponent to
deceive him to receive the decision
makers in the United States or Germany
or Britain or it can be a risinformation
to deceive the public opinion around the
world or in a specific country
you tend to be fairly good at this when
you're with Czech intelligence didn't
you
unfortunately I have to admit yes
one of bittmann's audacious schemes was
to recover phony Nazi storage chests
from a Czechoslovakian Lake the chests
were filled with genuine gestapo and SS
documents supplied by the KGB and
specifically chosen to rekindle
animosity towards the Germans decades
after World War II
and I was a member of the diving team
and when I talked with few people in the
service about this we came to the
conclusion that this is a very good
opportunity to play and play a dirty
game against West Germany that we would
actually put something on the bottom of
the lakes and make it a big Discovery so
we prepared several
German chests supposedly they were
thrown into the legs by Germans who were
just fleeing czechoslovak territory
the cases were brought from the bottom
in front of Television cameras
the documents were then displayed in an
elaborate press conference aimed at
weakening the solidarity of the NATO
allies
it was quite successful in Italy in
France
in Austria the Press of these countries
published them and basically the tone
was anti-german look what these German
bastards did to US during the war and
made and there are so many who are still
living in Germany who are the major
targets of the disinformation campaign
that you were waging I understand there
was two or three major
yeah well the target number one is of
course the United States it is called
the Enemy Number One one of the main
enemy it's always used that is the
official term for the United States then
the second major Target was the NATO
alliance and the goal was the objective
was to work toward the dissolution of
NATO with the hope that after some few
years the the the the tension within the
organization were
reach such a stage such a level that
NATO would stop existing
[Music]
NATO was formed in post-war Europe as a
political and Military alliance against
the Soviets but its most effective
opposition now comes not from Soviet
armies but from Soviet disinformation
which continually attempts to turn one
NATO Ally against another
each one of these papers appears to be a
leaked U.S government document but
they're all forgeries designed to sow
dissension within NATO
this document made damaging remarks
supposedly from former President Carter
about both Greece and Turkey
this is a phony intelligence report on
European left Wingers this is a forged
NATO document claiming to devise ways of
getting support for the neutron bomb
a forged confidential State Department
memo advocating economic Espionage by
America on her own allies
many forgeries have been directed
against Anwar Sadat a confidential U.S
memo claiming his time is up
or false reports on former vice
president mondale's remarks that neither
Sadat nor begin are viable leaders
there have been forgeries released to
show American suppression of Islam the
religion of its oil suppliers
yet Perhaps the most successful Soviet
disinformation attack was on the kgb's
main competition the CIA it began with
an agreement in the mid 60s between the
East German and Czech intelligence
services
[Music]
the two disinformation departments again
under the supervision of these Soviets
decided to start a long-term operation
against the CIA making
life as hard as possible for CIA that is
to
label many American diplomas politicians
cultural Representatives abroad as CI
agents and paralyzed their positions
uh specifically in 1966
the first major operation was to prepare
a book which is the worst is called who
is who in CIA
the book who's who in CIA was the
beginning of the expose that seriously
undermined American intelligence
capabilities for almost a decade so
powerful was the impact of this book
that its imitators like Philip AGS
covered action information bulletin
frequently refer to it as Source
material as do other major news sources
it was used as a source in this ABC
Nightly News television broadcast in
November 1980 claiming that the Reverend
Jim Jones had a secret CIA associate
before the Guyana Massacre
this man Richard Dwyer is the focal
point of many of the questions
surrounding the possible CIA involvement
at Jonestown he's a career Diplomat who
served insensitive posts throughout the
Mideast two years ago he was the deputy
Mission Chief in Guyana he is listed as
a CIA agent in a publication that for
years has specialized in such
allegations the CIA denies the
accusation but it was lettuce love
bitman who was one of the real authors
of who's who in CIA and although it was
not published under his name the book
received exactly the attention he hoped
it would
shortly after coming to the United
States I found this book in many
bookstores I have it at home
and it it for example it was quoted by
the
covert action billeting or is this Aegis
group the group yes that's right
Philippines is one of one of the major
sources of information about CIA man
that's of course that's ironic because
that is a communist disinformation
constant in hand is a new york-based
journalist for Polish language
newspapers in North America when he
decided to expose communist agents in
the U.S The Long Reach of the KGB
influenced his life 76 we started away
for exposure of Soviet and polish
companies
intelligence Network especially here in
New York we exposed agents mostly
working around the United Nations
what agents were these who were they
working for what are KGB
a Polish communist intelligence service
which is actually nothing but an arm of
kgb2
shortly after his exposes of the KGB in
New York half stories were published in
a heavily ethnic area in Winnipeg
several thousand miles to the west by
the weekly newspaper Chas the Polish
times
in July 1978 on a day the paper had not
planned to publish a bizarre edition of
the weekly was put into circulation with
articles and semi-nude photos designed
to offend its conservative and older
readership
it was done in a very clever way you
know because
the look of it was exactly the same SUV
would have printed you know but some
things struck us right away for example
right on the front pages that uh
beautifully breasted women you know
which we wouldn't have never put into a
paper simply for the same for different
reasons you know but our readers are
mostly middle-aged people you would
never dream of doing kind of things like
that you know who inside the paper we
have a picture of one of our
correspondents in the uniform of a
German Verma you know and the letter
supposedly written by Jewish writer
referring to uh uh our journalists
contributed to the paper Mr Hunt as a
war criminal not to war criminal the
funny part of it is that when the war
ended he was about 18 years old you know
and yet they said that he was
high-ranking officer you know that he
has killed so many Jews and this and
that you know and there's another
article portraying Mr hanoff as an agent
of
you take it KGB CIA FBI everything comes
to the sun it has become a classic case
of Soviet block disinformation on a very
personal level the charges against hand
were also made in a letter supposedly
written by the Jewish Defense League of
New York and the letter was sent out to
advertisers of the newspaper informing
them that chase was harboring a Nazi war
criminal I am polish from my belief and
from my birth from my uh persuasion I
would say but my father was a German
so my
engagement in the America in the German
Army was not incidental action because
how long were you in the German Army and
just what did you do I was uh regular
Soldier
was drafted in a match of 44 March 1944
yes when I was 17 and a half of age
and in February of 7 of 45 I was
captured by this audience
the accusing letter was revealed to be a
forgery when the real Jewish Defense
League examined this and declared it had
not been written on their stationery and
also that they had never accused Mr hanf
of any war crimes
what effect
would this have had on your readership
what effect did this have on your
advertisers I mean what was it well
obviously I think the main aim was to
stop Childs being published and have the
same editorial policy as it was you know
since Mr mirajkowski took over and they
want that I'm sure to create Panic on
the board of directors so that you would
fire him and get some woolly headed
fellow you know which would be a little
bit softer on communism yeah there is a
long-term plan and strategy how to
uh how to frighten prominent exercise
who are politically active
or
organizations that are very
an
anti-soviet or anti-communist
uh
so and I have to admit that this is a
relatively uneasy
thing to do why because most Exiles most
refugees or immigrants
have some kind of
relations
with the mother country with the people
with the relatives there and they uh
they can be even black names because
imagine that you have a mother there and
somebody comes and says so if you don't
cooperate or if you if you continue
speaking against us
your mother will have a very tough life
my dear friends