Hello.
Who's here?
That's yours, Colonel.
Thank you.
I can fix you another whiskey?
You can get me one, Kathleen.
Then come and sit me by
me to change my luck.
Oh, stop talking,
I'm trying to play this hand.
The sort of hands you
hold play themselves.
Eh, Colonel Henslowe?
Ronnie holds the
most amazing cards.
The rest are mine.
I suppose because I'm
your brother, Kathleen,
I can't have a drink.
That's right, four spades.
Dr. Watson is here, Miss.
He says he won't
disturb the bridge.
Thank you, Marston.
Tell him I'll be
with him in a moment.
Thank you, Miss.
Now what about all of...
Four in one hand and
one in the dummy.
That's 8I.
Excuse me, sir.
This was on the floor.
Thanks.
Ah, thank you.
My deal, I believe.
Will you cut, Colonel?
Come and sit by me, Kathleen.
I can't leave
Dr. Watson alone.
I must go.
Is that the Dr. Watson,
the friend of Sherlock Holmes?
Yes.
Then you know Holmes?
No, Dr. Watson has known him
since Ronnie and I were Kids,
but we've never met Mr. Holmes.
He's always too busy.
I say, I've
got two aces of spades.
But we've
used this pack before.
Oh, I know, Marston
found one on the floor.
Yes, but how could...
Yes, and it must've
dropped off here.
Your cut,
please, Colonel.
Cut for me, Ronnie.
Well...
Don't go, Kathleen.
I'll come and say goodnight
to you all before I go to bed.
I expect you'll all
be at it till three.
No, don't get up.
I hope you all win.
My dear, how kind
of you to come.
A summons from
you comes before
even a summons from
Sherlock Holmes.
It's sweet of you
to say so anyhow.
Take off your coat and
let me give you a drink.
No, thanks, I can't stay.
I came for a moment
because you sent for me.
Well, let's sit
down for a minute.
Has Ronnie got
another bilious attack?
No, it's nothing really.
I'm a bit worried.
Kathleen, dear.
Won't you confide in me?
It's about Ronnie.
This gambling.
You know, six months ago
we hadn't a shilling.
You mean when your trustee
absconded and shot himself.
Yes, we were
going to leave here.
Ronnie was going to give
up the diplomatic service,
and then he began to play
bridge for high stakes.
But I always understood
he was an exceedingly
fine player.
He is, but you
can't always win.
What do you mean?
Always.
Sometimes it's 20 pounds.
Sometimes 500.
But he never loses.
It looks as if...
Oh, I can't say it.
It's impossible.
Ronnie isn't capable
of such a thing,
but I would like to be sure.
How can one make sure?
Well, I really don't know.
I'll ask Holmes.
Oh, no, he might
arrest Ronnie.
No, of course he wouldn't,
but he might frighten
him into giving up cards.
I never thought of that.
Yes, do ask him to do something.
I'll come around and see
him in the morning, may I?
Well, I don't know.
Yes, I may.
You'll make him
see me, won't you?
He thinks an awful lot of you.
Well, I don't think I need
waste time. It's a grand slam.
I make seven of
spades, three diamonds,
two of hearts, and
the ace of clubs.
That's right.
Another big rubber.
Well, that just
about cleans me out.
I make the
difference 1600 points.
You add up very quickly.
Quite a mathematician, eh?
How much is that?
160 pounds.
Well, I've lost both rubbers,
and so I owe you 255 pounds.
But we settle up at the end.
This is the end.
My wife is not very well,
and I promised to go home early.
Well, if you must, you must.
I'm sorry to
spoil your evening,
but perhaps you can get Miss
Adair to make up a four.
Kathleen plays a game
that resembles hockey
more than bridge.
Still, if you're determined,
we'll see you Monday.
I'm afraid I shan't be able.
I have to go out of town
on important business,
and I don't know
when I shall be back.
Then it's no use trying
to fix another evening.
I'm afraid not.
Let me know when you're back.
Goodnight,
and thanks very much.
I didn't know Sir
Timothy played bridge.
Sir Timothy?
Yes, Timothy Frobisher.
He's the fourth.
You know, one can't work
long with Sherlock Holmes
without picking
some of his tricks
of observation and deduction.
What makes you
think he's here?
His initials.
T.F., Timothy Frobisher.
Elementary, My Dear Kathleen.
Elementary,
and then there are
further indications.
The owner of this hat
is immensely tall.
You see, he's bruised
the top edge here.
Probably going through a door.
Excuse me, may I have my hat?
Yours?
Certainly.
My initials are inside.
T.F., Thomas Fisher.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
You're not going?
Yes, my wife is not very well,
and I promised to
get home early.
Oh, I am sorry.
I think I'll go too.
Well, goodnight,
and thanks for playing.
Sorry you had
such rotten luck.
See you Monday.
Well, really I
think I better not.
I've lost an awful lot lately,
and I think I better
chuck it for a bit.
Guess you're right.
Oh, don't think me rude,
but I just can't afford it.
That's all right.
Goodnight, Colonel.
Goodnight.
Well, have you a sick wife
and a business appointment?
No, a whiskey and soda.
I'm sorry.
Still it is rather rotten.
I don't see why.
Fisher being a millionaire,
naturally loses his temper
when he loses sixpence,
and Tony Rutherford is broke.
And you think that's all?
What else?
Oh, nothing, of course.
You can always
get another four.
Then you'll continue to come?
With pleasure.
I'm not afraid of
losing sixpence,
and I'm lucky, I
often cut with you.
What's the matter
with you all?
Stopping so early.
Well, Fisher had to go,
and for once in my life,
I'm going to have
an early night.
Then I'll see you out.
Goodnight, Ronnie.
Goodnight, Colonel.
Ronnie, you've got
to tell me the truth.
The truth, what do you mean?
I've got to find
out the truth!
A terribly difficult
thing, darling.
Ronnie, stop it.
Kindly explain
the ace of spades.
Explain
the ace of spades?
You know exactly what I mean.
When Marston picked it up,
you said it belonged
to that pack.
It doesn't, and you know it.
Well, it must belong
to some other pack.
A hidden duplicate pack.
What the devil do you mean?
How dare you suggest that I...
God knows I don't
want to suggest it.
But we were ruined.
Then you started playing
bridge for high stakes.
Look here, Kathleen.
We've always been
the best of pals,
but if you're going to
say things like that...
Don't you see
everything points to it?
Oh, I don't believe it.
I won't believe it.
If I did, I'd rather put
a bullet through your head
than own a brother who...
Yes, Marston?
Excuse me, sir, a note
from the Foreign Office.
Thanks.
Who brought it?
The commissioner, sir.
Is he there?
No, sir, he said
there'd be no answer.
Thanks.
Shall you want
anything else, sir?
Not tonight, Marston.
I shall want breakfast
a bit earlier.
The Foreign Office is sending
a car for me at half past nine.
Very good, sir.
Goodnight, Miss.
Goodnight, Marston.
Goodnight, sir.
Goodnight.
Anything serious?
Well, if you must know,
they want me to go and see
some German fellow in Hampstead
who will tell me
some official secret
which was probably published
in last night's paper.
Don't go, Ronnie.
I've got to have
this out of you.
I can't believe...
Ronnie.
What shall I do with
Mr. Holmes's breakfast?
Isn't he up yet?
Ain't no sign of him.
Hasn't even took in
his shaving water.
I do wish he'd be a bit
more regular in his habits.
Meals at all times of the day
does turn a house upside down.
But you know, Mrs. Hudson,
you always insist on
keeping his meals for him.
He never asks.
Yes, but the poor
man must eat sometime.
If I didn't see that he
had a bite now and again,
he'd have been in
his grave years ago.
I should go and
bang on his door.
Yes, sir,
but sometimes when he's
thinking out his problems,
he gets cross when
he's disturbed.
He won't be this morning.
He's rather good tempered,
and he doesn't
want any breakfast.
Lord, Mr. Holmes,
you did give me a turn.
Well, one good turn
deserves another, eh?
- What can I do for you.
- Have some breakfast, sir.
I've already breakfasted
with the manager of the
London Commercial Bank.
So they've sent
for you for this.
Are you sure I can't tempt
you to a nice bit of haddock?
My dear Mrs. Hudson,
you've always been
a temptation to me,
but haddock after a
good breakfast is not.
Oh, how you do don't carry on.
It's a good job I
don't take you serious.
I'm perfectly serious.
Jokes are not my strong point.
Ask the doctor.
I never see any of his.
No.
You know, I've been
wondering, My Dear Watson,
why you don't get the batteries
of your car recharged.
What do you mean?
You had great difficulty
in getting your car
to start last night.
The batteries are run down.
They are, but
how did you know?
You've a blister at
the base of your fingers
on the right hand.
As you've not been standing on
the serpentine this morning,
I deduced that you've
been cranking your car.
That's rather wonderful.
But that's elementary,
My Dear Watson.
Elementary. Let me
give you a hand.
- Thank you, sir.
- Can you lift that?
And the cloth on
the top like so.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
You sure there's nothing
else I can do for you?
No, nothing, thank you.
Oh, wait a minute.
Let me give you a hand.
Thank you.
Why have they
sent for you about this?
It's perfectly simple.
A man tries to burgle
a bank, is disturbed,
kills the watchman,
and runs away.
I find it very interesting.
Have you ever heard of
Professor Robert Moriarty?
No, what's
he got to do with it?
He's to do with half
the crimes the world over.
He started as a
mathematical professor,
but ugly rumors gathered
around him and he resigned.
Well after that he vanished
for 10 years or so.
I fancy he went abroad.
Then he returned to England,
and things began to happen.
What things?
For a long time I've been
conscious of some power,
a deep organization which
stands in the way of the law.
Once he made a slip,
and I was able to deduce
that behind that
power was Moriarty.
But he recovered himself,
and I could prove nothing.
He has hundreds of agents,
none of whom have ever seen him.
Sometimes an agent is caught,
but the man who plans
most of the crimes
that are committed
is never caught.
Never even suspected.
He knows that I know
of his activities.
He also knows that up to now,
I've been unable to reach him.
And you think he's connected
with this bank murder?
I think it highly probable.
Yes?
Yes, come in.
Inspector Lestrade
to see you, sir.
Oh, Lestrade.
Anything fresh?
No, Mr. Holmes.
Sit down, Lestrade.
Thank you.
I just came in to get
that piece of brown paper.
Yes, this little
piece you mean.
I should like to keep it
a little longer, if I may.
I hadn't yet decided what
the rest of the label is.
Well, I don't see
how you ever can.
It's just an ordinary
shopkeeper's label.
There's not enough of
it to tell us anything.
Well, I disagree,
My Dear Lestrade,
but then you and I
so often disagree.
Oh, come, Mr. Holmes.
I have a great respect
for your theories.
It's only when you begin
about this Professor Moriarty.
Yeah, you don't
believe in him.
And I ask you,
is it possible for a man to plan
half the crime in this country
without the Yard
knowing who he is,
where he lives, or
anything about him?
It does seem rather strange.
I mean, the man
can't live nowhere.
Never be seen by anyone.
Of course. I mean
lots of people know him,
but they don't know
that he's Moriarty.
You yourself may know him.
Jokes are not your
strong point, Holmes.
No, I'm perfectly serious.
He has a hundred disguises
and a hundred aliases,
and I'm pretty certain he had
a hand in this bank robbery.
But it wasn't a robbery.
The thief got nothing.
He broke into the bank.
Have you ever tried to
break into a bank, Lestrade?
Me?
No, I thought not.
But do you seriously
think it's possible
for one man to break into a bank
without using anything
short of dynamite?
There we no signs
of a forced entry.
Which might point
to the fact of
his having an
accomplice, or even two.
He got inside.
Which doesn't necessarily
mean your professor.
The man was interrupted
by the watchman,
killed him, got
frightened, and bolted.
And, yet, inside the safe,
we found this piece
of brown paper.
Three people swear
it was not there
when the safe was
shut last night.
Then he was inside
when he was disturbed.
Or before he went inside.
He had this paper
wrapped around something.
You will observe that this
end here is slightly torn,
and there is a
blood stain on it.
I, therefore, deduce
that the struggle
with the watchman
took place first,
and he then took his
parcel into the safe.
It won't work, Mr. Holmes.
It won't work.
There were 70,000 pounds
of notes in the vault.
Not one of them is missing.
How true.
But if you remember
a fortnight ago,
an almost similar thing
occurred in Berlin.
In Berlin?
Yes.
You should read your Berliner
Tageblatt, My Dear Lestrade.
There strong room of the
Reichsbank was entered.
The watchman was laid out,
happily not killed,
and nothing was removed.
Very strange, Mr. Holmes.
Very strange indeed.
Looks almost as if
there was a connection.
I should like time to
think it out a bit.
When can I have that
piece of brown paper?
I'll let you have
it this evening.
In the meantime, would
you be good enough to warn
all foreign customs officials
to be on the lookout
for a very large quantity
of English bank notes,
which will be smuggled
through in ordinary luggage.
What do you think?
I think it would
be a wise precaution.
Very good, Mr. Holmes.
I'll get back to the Yard now,
and put the matter in hand.
Good morning, gentlemen.
The chief has arrived, sir.
Oh, what are his orders?
He will interview
Mr. Adair himself.
Right, send Mr. Adair in.
What the devil's
the meaning of this?
Adair.
My god, am I drunk?
I hope not at 10
o'clock in the morning.
What's all this about?
I was seized in a
car, blindfolded,
and driven half around London.
I apologize for that,
but it was just a
slight precaution.
And you must forgive me
concealing my identity
behind the Sleeping Cardinal.
Please sit down.
Are you Mr. Clink?
Mr. Otto Clink?
No.
Poor Otto Clink must've
been dead a good many years.
What the devil's
the meaning of this?
Only that I
have a slight favor
to ask of you, Mr. Adair.
A favor.
Who are you anyway?
I understand
that you are leaving
on the Golden Arrow at 11
o'clock tomorrow for Paris.
And if I am?
You are going on
Foreign Office business,
and you will have
a laissez-passer,
which means that your luggage
will not be examined
by the custom.
I want you to take a
suitcase to Paris for me.
I'll do nothing of the kind!
Why should I?
Because you
can't help yourself.
Don't be ridiculous!
Sit down, Adair.
You go to hell!
Sit down.
You have been cheating at cards.
- What?
- I repeat.
You have been cheating at cards.
I should've warned you
that this picture
is painted on steel.
Sit down.
All your life you have been
interested in slight of hand.
Your trick of palming
a whole pack of cards
has been very useful to you
since your trustee absconded
and left you and your
sister penniless.
It's a lie!
You have taken
to playing bridge
for very high stakes.
When you deal,
you simply change the pack
after it has been cut to you.
You have a carefully prepared
pack in the palm of your hand.
You do the same when you cut
a pack for your opponent.
Now this procedure,
if publicly known,
is not likely to lead
to an advancement,
either social or diplomatic.
In fact, it means
the end of you.
Who's been telling you
this ridiculous story?
Last night
you made a slip.
You dropped the ace of spades.
Now, I think I can count on
your doing me this
very slight service.
Goon.
A suitcase
bearing your initials
will be delivered at your
flat at 9:30 this evening.
You will pass it through
customs with your other luggage.
I understand you
have engaged a room
at the Bristol in Paris.
You will take your
luggage there,
and by 10 o'clock
tomorrow night,
the suitcase will have
vanished from your room.
You will make no comment.
What's in this
precious suitcase?
That does
not concern you.
Yes, but it might be anything!
Stolen jewels, bombs.
Heaven knows what.
No, I'll be damned if I'll
be made use of in this way!
I feel sure that
you will change your mind.
In the event of
your not doing so,
you will find the
only alternative
in the box on the table.
What do you mean?
Here.
Come back, whoever you are.
What do you mean?
The only alternative.
Oh, my god.
What are you trying to do?
I'm trying to see how
many Bank of England notes
will go into a
parcel of this size.
You see, My Dear Watson,
this note should fit
into these creases.
There you are, as
I thought exactly.
Yes, are you busy
this morning, Watson?
No, I kept the morning free.
I rather hoped you'd
see Kathleen Adair.
She's due here now.
I sent her a note on the
way home from the bank.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Then you'll have
a talk to Ronnie?
No, I want to talk about him.
He's in the diplomatic
service, isn't he?
Yes, but what's that
got to do with it?
What's what go to
do with what, Watson?
Come in.
Miss Adair to see you, sir.
How wonderful of you
to have managed this.
It's terribly kind
of you to see me.
Not at all.
Won't you sit down?
Now Watson has
told me how worried
you are about your brother,
but I don't quite
see what I can do.
I've been wondering
if you could find out
if it's really true.
If it is, and I can't
believe that it is,
perhaps you could frighten
him into giving up cards.
With whom does
he play as a rule?
Well, last night there
was Tony Rutherford.
Old Mr. Fisher.
Thomas Fisher,
the millionaire?
Yes,
and Colonel Henslowe,
an old friend of ours.
Fisher?
I wonder...
Forgive me, Miss Adair,
but does your brother travel
at all on official business?
Quite a lot.
In fact, he's off
to Paris tomorrow.
Ah, I thought so.
How long has he known that
he would be going tomorrow?
Three or four days, I think.
Where is your
brother at the moment?
I don't know.
At the Foreign Office
by now I should think.
He went out early this morning.
They sent a car for him.
Do you happen to know
where he had to go?
I think he said Hampstead.
I know it wasn't far.
He should be back at
the office by now.
Yes.
Yes, they think a great
deal of your brother
at the Foreign Office.
They used to,
but lately he's been
playing so much bridge,
I'm afraid he's been
neglecting his work.
That's a pity.
I wonder if you'd be good
enough to ask your brother
to come and see
me this afternoon?
Of course, I'll go around
to the Foreign Office now.
I might just catch him.
Why not telephone?
He hates being rung up there,
and I couldn't explain
on the telephone.
What shall I do if I miss him?
Well, when will
you be seeing him?
Tonight.
He's dining out, and he's
bound to come in to dress.
Very well, in that case,
would you be good
enough to ask him
to come and see me in the
morning before he starts?
That's awfully kind of you.
Don't mention bridge to him.
As a matter of fact,
I shall not say a word
on that subject myself,
but you may rest assured
that after he has seen me,
he will never gamble again.
I can't tell you
how grateful I am.
Not at all.
It's I who am grateful to you.
Goodbye.
Watson?
Yes?
What's all this mean, Holmes?
It means, My Dear Watson,
that the Foreign Office
doesn't send a car
to take a very unimportant
young man to Hampstead.
Hello?
Yes, speaking.
Who's that?
Mrs. Smith?
I seem to know that name.
Mrs. Annie Smith?
A Mrs. Torboy has
put you on to me.
I don't think I
know a Mrs. Torboy.
No, you're quite right
it doesn't matter.
You think it's appendicitis?
What's the address?
Would you mind taking
this down, Holmes?
1006 Fentonville Road.
Yes.
Yes, I'll come at once.
I'll take a taxi.
Goodbye.
Here's the address.
I've added a note which
I want you to read
when you've found a taxi.
What's it about?
You read it when
you've found a taxi.
I hope your friend
Mrs. Torboy's friend
is not as bad as she thinks.
Now what is it?
Please, mother said can
I have Paul's pajamas.
They've blown off our
line into your backyard.
You have no right to hang out
your washing and your whatnots
in a respectable
neighborhood like this.
Mom said if you started
carrying on about the washing,
I wasn't to stand
any of your lip.
Your mother said that?
Yes, she did.
Well, I've never heard such
impotence in all my born days.
You go, and I'll
give your mother lip.
You wait.
Mother said I was to take the
pajamas and not talk to you.
She doesn't think
you're respectable.
What's that?
She says it's disgraceful,
a widow living in a house
full of nothing but men.
Now, you wait a minute.
I'll give her respectable.
Go on, off it!
Go on, up you go!
Oh, my word, respectable.
- Yes, come in.
- Mr. Holmes, sir.
- Yes.
- Sir.
I'm just going to step
around to that Mrs. Freeman.
I've got a few things
I want to say to her.
Yes, Mrs. Hudson,
but what has upset you?
Well, she just told me.
She sent her daughter
around to say that I...
Well, I won't demean myself
by saying what she did say.
But I want you to know I
shall be out 20 minutes.
Well I wouldn't be too violent
if I were you, Mrs. Hudson.
Violent!
Indeed, I'll set her
back so good and proper!
Indeed I would if it wasn't
for my chronic enteritis!
Come in, Professor.
You think you
know me, Mr. Holmes.
Why not?
You called upon me once before.
On that occasion your face
was completely covered
with surgical bandages,
but your arrival
coincided with the same
removal of Watson
and Mrs. Hudson.
You were a little more original
in your methods last time.
Today, I recognized
the symptoms.
I was expecting you, Moriarty.
How clever of you, Holmes.
Won't you take off
your scarf, Professor.
Perhaps you're right.
This room is rather drafty.
Shall we sit down?
I'm afraid my
method of getting rid
of Watson and Mrs. Hudson
was a trifle crude.
But I had a sudden impulse,
and anyhow it
served its purpose.
Except that our interview
will be a brief one.
Watson will have read
my note in the taxi
telling him to ignore the call
and come back here
in five minutes.
In that case, I will be brief.
On the fourth of May 1928,
you crossed my path.
A dangerous thing to do, Holmes.
Eight months later, to be exact,
the 20th of January 1929,
you incommoded me seriously.
Yes, you made a bad
slip in 1929, didn't you?
Nearly had you, Professor.
And now I find
you so constantly in my way
that it would be better
for me if you were removed.
Perhaps what I have to say
has already crossed your mind.
Possibly my answer
may have crossed yours.
You stand fast?
Absolutely.
A great pity, Holmes.
I have a great respect
for your mentality.
A great pity.
You're getting in the way
of a great organization,
the full extent
of which even you,
with all your cleverness,
cannot realize.
You wish to put me in the dock.
You never will.
If you destroy me,
rest assured I shall
do as much for you.
That's very
interesting, Professor,
but your five minutes are up.
I fancy I hear the
arrival of Watson.
May I offer you a
piece of advice?
Never give way to
sudden impulses.
They're even more
dangerous to you than I am.
I read your note, Holmes.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Did you come to see me?
Your friend is
in great danger.
Great danger.
What's the matter with him?
It is the draft, Watson.
He's feeling the draft
very badly at this moment.
But who was he?
- Well, that was Mrs.
- Smith of 1006 Fentonville.
Missus?
Or shall we say Professor?
Oh, the mythical Moriarty.
What does he look like?
Well, I know no
more than you do,
except that the first
molar in the left side
of the upper jaw is very
badly filled with gold.
Have you a mathematical
mind, Watson?
I think so, fairly.
Well, never give way
to sudden impulses.
They're not good
for mathematicians.
Moriarty has made the worst slip
he's made since January 1929.
You mean you think you
found out how to get him?
No, I found out where
he gets his boots.
I wish you'd be serious.
The professor's boots
are made by Mr. J.J.
Godfrey, bootmaker.
Yes, here we are.
502 Pond Street,
Southwest One.
Godfrey of Pond Street?
Yes.
Well, that's where
I had mine made.
You do surprise me.
But Godfrey's a perfectly
respectable tradesman
with a high-class clientele.
Well, obviously.
Obviously, you and Moriarty,
you share a bootmaker
with the professor,
and for all I know he may
be a great friend of yours.
Oh, really, Holmes.
Does Mr. Godfrey make
his boots on the premises?
Yes, in the basement.
He showed me over
his workshop once.
Yes.
I think I'd like to
see over that workshop.
We'll arrange with
Lestrade to call there
about eight o'clock tonight.
But can how it possibly matter
where Moriarty buys his boots?
Only that this
piece of brown paper,
which was found in the
strong room of the bank,
bears a piece of the label of
Mr. J.J. Godfrey, bootmaker.
Holmes, you're marvelous.
Elementary, My Dear Watson.
Well, that's that.
Now what am I to do with it?
You will be at Down
Street tube station
at nine o'clock precisely.
You'll take the
suitcase with you.
Oh, it's all right
it keeps the time.
It isn't eight o'clock yet.
In the main entrance,
you'll see a man with a
scar on his left temple.
He will take the
suitcase from you.
Yes, sir.
The keys?
- There we are, sir.
- Good.
Looks a good bit of work.
Yes, sir.
I'm a good workman.
Moran.
Oh, the chief's here.
I have
just been informed
that Inspector Lestrade
has left Scotland Yard
in a powerful car
with police constables
number 47, 54, and 83.
All of the C Division.
They will doubtless
call for Sherlock Holmes
and that great
detective Dr. Watson.
Don't attempt to
hide the suitcase.
It would look suspicious,
and see that everything is tidy.
If the police detain you,
I have arranged for someone
else to take the suitcase.
Come in here, Moran.
You heard?
Yes, sir.
Put this right,
Godfrey, will you?
All right, sir.
Which of you is Mr. Godfrey?
I am.
Here's my search warrant.
Search warrant?
Well, what are
you searching for?
You'll know when
I've found it.
Why, if it isn't Dr. Watson.
Hope the last pair of shoes
I made were satisfactory.
I see you're wearing them now.
Yes, quite, thanks.
I say, Holmes, this
does seem rather absurd.
You know, Godfrey's
made my shoes for years.
Yes, your shoe last is in
that cupboard over there now.
Over there?
- Yes.
- I'll go and find it.
I suppose, Godfrey, you
know what we've come for.
I haven't the slightest idea.
Hello, starting
out a new branch, eh?
Oh, that.
Yes that's an experiment.
Special order for
a new customer.
Thought I might as
well try my hand at it.
I'm glad to see you look
after your work people, Godfrey.
Well, I've only
got three of them.
There's Roberts and Williams
and his brother here.
Well, you look after them.
The place is
properly ventilated.
Ventilated?
Oh, that.
Yes, sir.
Yeah.
Oh, yes, a ventilator.
Where's that door lead?
To the area,
but as you can see,
it hasn't been opened for years.
Well, I should
like you to open it.
Heaven only knows
where the key is.
That door hasn't been opened
since I don't know when.
Godfrey,
this is curious-looking thing.
What do you use it for?
It's used for special work.
So you wanted to know what
I was looking for, Godfrey?
Well, you know now.
I was looking for a press
that made perfect
Bank of England notes.
Take them all away.
What are you doing?
Quick follow this
wire, Lestrade.
What for?
Come one quick, Lestrade,
help me get this door down.
On one!
Watson.
Damn.
Have another drink,
My Dear Watson.
You'll feel better.
Thanks, I'm all right.
I haven't a scratch.
It was a bit of a
shock being seized
and trussed up like that.
You saw nobody?
Nothing.
I was standing in the cupboard.
The shelves swung around.
I was seized from
behind and blindfolded.
Well, anyway, we've
done a good night's work.
My theory of the bank
robbery is proving correct.
What does your finding
a forger's outfit
in a bootmaker's basement got
to do with a bank robbery,
which wasn't a robbery at all?
Well, I'll try to explain.
Within a fortnight the
strong rooms of two banks
are entered by
unauthorized persons,
and nothing is removed.
But in each case,
something is taken
into the strong room.
In the case of the
Reichsbank, a cardboard box.
In the case of the Commercial,
a piece of brown paper.
Well, he wanted to take
the notes away in them.
The brown paper
had been creased
and folded around something.
Well?
Mr. Godfrey's printing
press makes perfect.
Bank of England notes.
Now supposing they
have an accomplice
who gives them the numbers
of the notes in stock,
they make duplicates.
Probably perfect duplicates
if my friend Moriarty has
anything to do with it.
They change these
for the real ones.
Now the forgeries have
to arrive at the bank
uncreased and spotless.
Hence, the brown paper.
But the real ones can
be taken away anyhow.
Shoved into pockets, anything,
and the paper discarded.
The robbery will not be
discovered until two notes
of the same number arrive
at the Bank of England,
and the longer that event
is postponed the better.
So what does my
learned friend do?
Well, holds them up.
No, no, My Dear Watson.
No, there's no use having
70,000 pounds worth of notes
if you don't use them.
Then he must start
circulating them.
Yeah, or send them abroad.
Oh, no, that sounds difficult.
You see, customs officials
might ask questions
if they opened a trunk full
of Bank of England notes.
Yeah, how true,
Watson, how true.
Well, in any case,
I don't feel I've been
trussed up for nothing.
It was worth it to find
that printing press.
The printing press,
My Dear Watson,
was valuable to get
your friend Mr. Godfrey
a term of penal servitude,
but the really important
discovery was the suitcase.
Suitcase?
You probably didn't observe
that on the lid were
the initials R.A.
I didn't, but what
does that signify?
Ronald Adair is leaving
tomorrow morning for Paris
on Foreign Office business.
He will have a diplomatic
passport and a laissez-passer,
which means that his luggage
will not be examined.
Well, you can't
connect him with...
Good heavens, you don't
think he's one of the gang.
Supposing Moriarty
were to threaten
to expose his bridge exploits.
But how should Moriarty know?
Well, how do I know it then?
What time is it, Watson?
It's quarter till 11:00.
Well, I wonder if we
could get hold of Adair now.
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
Miss Adair
sent a message to say that she
missed her brother at
the Foreign Office,
and that she'd send him
around in the morning.
Well, ring her up
now, Watson, will you,
and see if we can get
hold of him right away?
- Yes, certainly.
- If I'm right,
that young man is the one
weak spot in Moriarty's armor.
If I can get hold of
him, Moriarty's wrong.
He will stand in
the dock tomorrow
and not long after
on the gallows.
Mr. Adair!
Mr. Adair?
Hello?
Yes, yes.
You can't, sir.
You can't he's killed.
Yes, I've just found him
shot through the head.
Is it usual
for you to go to bed
as early as 10 o'clock?
Yes, sir, when
there's no company.
And you
heard nothing at all?
No, sir.
- No.
- You see,
our bedrooms are all at
the back of the building,
completely cut off from
the rest of the flat.
I see.
Thank you.
Would you send the butler to me?
- Yes, sir.
- You can go too.
But surely, Lestrade,
considering what I've told
you about the bridge party,
it was obviously
a case of suicide.
Then where is the revolver?
Well, he must've thrown
it out of the window.
Well, the bullet didn't
penetrate the brain.
He may have been conscious for
a few seconds after the shot,
and his fireplace shows
that he'd be burning
his correspondence.
A good deal of correspondence.
Then what about the
letter he was writing?
I can't make that out.
"The Sleeping Cardinal
forced me to..."
I can't think what it means.
Oh, Mr. Holmes.
Would you care to
examine the servants?
The cook and the housemaid
neither saw nor heard anything.
No, no, no, Lestrade.
No, no, no, you carry on.
No, I'll just amuse myself.
We found this on
the table in front of him.
"The Sleeping Cardinal...
"The Sleeping Cardinal,"
now where have I heard
that name before?
You're the butler here.
Yes, sir.
Have you been with
the family long?
Three years, sir.
Then you know their ways.
Did anything unusual
occur here this evening?
No, sir.
Miss Adair dined alone at home,
and Mr. Adair came in
at a quarter past nine
with Colonel Henslowe.
Who is Colonel Henslowe?
He's an old friend
of the family.
He knew Ronnie Adair's
father in India.
Sir Henry Adair was Governor
General of Bengal, you know.
They used to hunt
tigers together.
Did you gather at all
what they were talking about
when they came in?
- Well, sir, Mr.
- Adair was saying,
"And you think Fisher
means trouble?"
That was all I heard, sir.
How long was the Colonel here?
Barely half an hour, sir.
Was Miss Adair with them?
No, sir, she was in her room.
Was anyone else in the flat?
No, sir.
You're positive that there
was no one else at all?
No, sir.
Oh, a man came about half
past nine with a new suitcase
that Mr. Adair had ordered.
What kind of a man?
I didn't notice him
particularly, sir.
He wasn't actually
inside the flat.
He just handed me the case,
and I signed for it.
Where did the case come from?
I really didn't notice, sir.
I Just told Mr.
Adair it was here,
and he told me to put it with
the other luggage
in his bedroom.
Which one?
That's the odd thing, sir.
It isn't here,
and I can't find it anywhere,
though I searched the flat.
It was quite an
ordinary sort of case.
Can't think where
it could get hidden.
But it must be somewhere.
Unless Mr. Adair took it out.
He didn't go out, sir.
He went straight to his room
after the Colonel had left.
Why didn't Miss Adair
come and see the Colonel?
Wasn't she friendly with him?
Oh, yes, sir.
She was quite friendly with him.
Wasn't she friendly
with her brother?
They were devoted
to each other.
They were, sir.
But there was a bit of a
shindy last night, sir.
Well, she never mentioned
anything about it to me.
No, sir.
It was after you and the
other gentlemen had left.
I can't think it
was a serious quarrel.
I beg pardon, sir, it was.
I brought in a
note for Mr. Adair,
and I don't think
they heard me come in.
What were they saying?
Well, sir, Miss
Adair was very excited,
and she said, "I'd rather put
a bullet through your head
"than own a brother who..."
And then she saw me and stopped.
Directly afterwards,
Mr. Adair left the room.
And tonight how did you
know he'd been killed?
The phone bell was
ringing in this room,
which was locked,
and I got no answer
to my knocking.
What did you do?
I broke down the door,
and then I found Mr.
Adair in that chair,
lying across the table dead,
and the window open.
How long had he
been in his room?
Abut half an hour, sir.
And you heard nothing?
Not a sound, sir.
And I was in my pantry,
which is on this
side of the flat.
Thank you, Marston.
Would you ask Miss
Adair to come here?
- Yes.
- I think if I were you
I should see Colonel
Henslowe first.
I understand he's
with Miss Adair.
And after all, he was the last
person to see Adair alive.
Yes, will you ask the
Colonel to come here?
Very good, sir.
Well, that disposes
of your suicide theory.
What do you mean?
You're not suggesting
that Miss Adair...
At any rate, she
threatened him.
But the door was
locked on the inside.
Ah, Colonel.
I don't think you know
Inspector Lestrade,
and my friend, Sherlock Holmes.
Delighted to meet
two such famous people.
I also am delighted to meet
such a distinguished
big game hunter.
My hunting days are over.
Yes.
That must be a great trial
to you of all people.
Was it the war?
No, a tiger mauled my arm.
It turned septic and had to
be taken off at the shoulder.
I'm lucky to be alive at all.
Yes, I'm immensely
ignorant about tiger hunting.
Tell me, you go out on elephants
with beaters, don't you?
Pardon me, Mr. Holmes,
but I must ask the
Colonel a few questions.
Yes, all right there,
Lestrade, just a minute.
I'm very interested
in tiger hunting.
Well, elephants
and beaters are used
when royalty and
rajas hunt tigers,
but they're expensive.
Oh, very.
You can always tether a goat
and wait till the
tiger comes for it.
Really, Mr. Holmes!
I'm pressed for time,
and I'm must ask the
Colonel a few questions!
Well, fine, Lestrade, fine.
You were the last to see the
deceased alive, weren't you?
Yes, he's been very
nervous since last night.
He came around this evening
and asked me to come
back with him for a chat.
I suppose you all know what
happened at the bridge party.
Yes.
One of the players
looked like me, unpleasant,
and Adair wanted my advice.
And what was your advice?
To do nothing at all.
Even if it were true,
nobody could prove it.
And he was less
worried when you left?
I think he was, a little.
I understand a new suitcase
was brought to the
house last night.
Were you there when it arrived?
I believe so.
I never saw it,
but I heard Ronnie tell Marston
to take it into his bedroom.
What time did you leave?
About a quarter to 10:00.
And within three quarters
of an hour he was found dead.
Surely, it's obvious
he shot himself.
I disagree, My Dear Watson.
He was murdered.
Of course.
You don't really think so?
Yes, My Dear Colonel,
I'm certain of it,
and what is more I'm sure
you'll all be glad to hear
that within 24 hours,
I shall not only be in
a position to prove it,
but I shall have the
murderer under lock and key.
I'm delighted to hear it.
Not that it can bring
the poor lad back.
You know, Ronnie,
with all his faults,
was extraordinarily lovable.
I feel rather as if
I had lost a son.
Thank you, Colonel Henslowe.
I shan't need you anymore.
Would you mind asking Miss
Adair to come to me a moment?
Certainly.
Goodbye, Mr. Holmes.
Goodbye, Colonel.
I'm sorry I interrupted
you, Mr. Holmes,
but you seemed so
interested in tigers,
that I thought you were
never going to stop.
Mm, they interest me.
The stark ferocity.
The cold cruelty,
There are human beings sort
of like tigers, you know.
Now I suppose you're back
to your Moriarty theory.
You're not gonna try and tell
me that this is his handiwork?
Well, who knows?
That man has become
an obsession with you.
He is.
Miss Adair,
I want to offer you my
very sincere sympathy.
It was a ghastly shock to me.
I can imagine what it
must have been to you.
I won't keep you a
minute, Miss Adair.
Won't you sit down?
When did you last
see your brother?
At half past six.
He came in to dress,
and I came in here to
give him a message.
What was the message?
- I told him that Mr.
- Holmes wanted to see him
before he went to Paris.
You see, I'd asked Mr.
Holmes to interview him.
What did he say?
He was upset.
In fact, we had rather
a quarrel about it.
Another quarrel?
You had one the night before.
Yes, but this
was not so serious.
He was merely annoyed that
I'd spoken to Mr. Holmes.
He was very annoyed?
Well, rather.
He seemed more
frightened than annoyed.
I couldn't understand.
So you quarreled again.
Well, yes.
He said I had no business
to interfere in his affairs.
And did you again
threaten to shoot him?
Shoot him?
What do you mean?
The night before your butler
heard you threatening him.
Oh, no, I never did
anything of the kind.
I shoot Ronnie?
You said you would rather
put a bullet through his head
than own a brother who...
Oh, that was only
a figure of speech!
I was accusing him of something.
A most unfortunate
figure of speech,
considering that within
24 hours he was found
with a bullet through his head.
But you don't think that I...
No, Miss, but I must ask
you to come along with me
after I've finished
my investigation.
I say, Lestrade,
this is grotesque.
Holmes, listen.
Here's Lestrade suggesting
that Miss Adair...
No, Dr. Watson, I didn't.
All I want is her to come
along and make a statement.
I'm sure Miss Adair
will be delighted
to go with you, Lestrade.
It is quite a warm night.
Anything you say, of course.
Thanks, Miss.
I shall be ready in a minute.
Then I'll go and
put on my things,
if you have no more questions.
No, nothing else, thanks.
This is outrageous!
Well, Mr. Holmes,
what do you think?
It's really remarkable
how many varieties of trees
there are in these London parks.
Have you ever noticed what
remarkably fine specimens...
Really, Mr. Holmes, you're
a most extraordinary man.
In the middle of an
investigation like this,
you begin talking about trees.
Holmes, you heard
Lestrade's ghastly accusation.
Surely, it was suicide.
He burned his correspondence.
I don't think he did.
These are the ashes
of, I should say,
at least a dozen packs
of playing cards.
Because he was afraid Fisher
was going to expose him.
My Dear Watson,
as I've already told
you, this was murder,
and it was committed
from outside this room.
What, shot
through the keyhole?
Ronald Adair burned
those playing cards,
and they caused a
great deal of smoke.
He opened the window and sat
down to write that confession,
and the moment he sat down
he was shot from outside.
But how?
From this height you can
hardly see the street.
He would had to have been
hanging out of the window.
And he wasn't.
He was sitting in that chair.
And you're suggesting
that somebody stood in
the middle of Park Lane,
between 10 and a half
past, and fired a rifle?
It would've had to
have been a rifle
to carry as far as this.
And that nobody saw
or heard anything.
Though there must have been
hundreds of passers by?
Yes, passers by
there undoubtedly were.
But as you doubtless
already ascertained,
there were no police about.
I beg your pardon, Mr. Holmes.
There are always police about.
There were a couple on
point duty at stand up gate.
I find on inquiry that
three separate disturbances
occurred at precisely 10:15
in this neighborhood tonight.
A lot of roughs who are
not accustomed to frequent
the public house around
the corner refused to leave
and were ejected by the police.
A young woman drove
a car into a lorry
not a hundred yards up the road,
and there was a false alarm
of fire in Hartford Street.
It's curious that
all these things
should've been
absolutely simultaneous.
But even supposing the
police were occupied,
you can't stand and fire a
rifle into a Park Lane window
without somebody having
seen and heard something.
How true.
Do you know a hornbeam
when you see one?
- A hornbeam?
- Mm-hmm.
There are some remarkably
fine specimens in the park.
What is a hornbeam?
The Latin name is Carpinus.
They're common in the
temperate zones of Asia
and some parts of
Southern England.
It looks like a beech,
but it isn't.
You know, Dr. Watson,
in spite of the fact that I've
known Holmes for some years,
I sometimes wonder
if he's all there.
Put this in your
mouth for a few minute.
Hmm, whatever for?
I don't think
you're at all well.
Oh, nonsense, My
Dear Watson, nonsense.
I'm in the very best of health,
in spite of a couple
of nasty shocks.
When did you have a shock.
I said two.
During the stroll I
took this afternoon,
I was just going to cross
the Marylebone Road.
The policemen on point duty
was holding up the traffic.
When a two-horse van
apparently out of control
whizzed around the corner
and was on me in a flash.
I sprang to the pavement
and saved myself by a
fraction of a second.
Good heavens.
Ten minutes later a brick fell
from the roof of a house that
was shattered at my feet.
They were repairing
the roof at the time,
but the police proved
it was an accident.
But, I know better.
Very nasty indeed.
But these things
happened this afternoon.
I was worrying about you
in the early hours
of the morning.
What did I do?
Do?
In the middle of a terribly
serious conversation,
you started talking
about trees in the park
and the difference between
a hornbeam and a beech.
Altogether disconnected,
and, I thought, a
little delirious.
Yes, I did ramble
a bit, didn't I?
And I'm sorry you made
what Lestrade called
a bombastic statement.
That within 24 hours,
12 of which by the
way have already gone,
you will have the murderer.
You know, it wasn't at
all like you, Holmes.
No, it did look as if I
were very ill, didn't it?
It gives Lestrade
such a chance to crow.
He thinks he's done a
frightful lot and you nothing.
He's disposed of my
suicide theory and...
And made an arrest.
Who?
I wonder he hasn't arrested
you or Mrs. Hudson.
And he never stops talking
about this mythical Moriarty.
Now, listen, My Dear Watson.
I have established to
my own satisfaction
that in both the Reichsbank
and the Commercial Bank cases,
forged notes were
substituted for real ones.
Yeah.
I have also established
to my own satisfaction
and through the missing
suitcase that Ronald Adair
was to have taken those
English notes to Paris.
And the same brain that
planned that scheme
planned the removal
of Ronald Adair.
But why should they
remove their means
of getting the notes
safely out of the country?
Because Ronald Adair
refused at the last minute.
Why should he?
He was still open to
exposure as a cheat.
That's what frightened him.
But I frightened
him still more.
When his sister told him
that I wanted to see him,
he was panic-stricken
because he realized
that his cheating could
only result in scandal.
The other meant certain jail.
I see,
and what did you
make of that letter
he was writing about
the Sleeping Cardinal?
Now that, My Dear Watson,
is the most significant
aspect of the case.
Do you remember eight months
ago when Trimble the forger
was found on the embankment
dying from terrible injuries?
He...
Yes?
Here.
Yes, we mustn't forget
your appointment.
Appointment?
Yes, it's necessary for me
to remain alone a little while.
So you, My Dear Watson,
are going to Euston.
Euston, whatever for?
What's the idea?
You'll see.
You're going to
have a busy night.
Now, I want you to put
on your coat and hat.
Take a suitcase.
You needn't pack anything.
Get a taxi, and make a
great fuss about getting it.
Call Euston to the driver,
and tell him if
he doesn't hurry,
you'll miss the Scotch Express.
The Scotch Express?
Yes.
You'll be followed.
The moment you get to
Euston, pay off the taxi,
and rush around to
the booking office.
Really, Mr. Holmes,
this is a bit too thick!
My apologies, Mrs. Hudson.
Once again you've proved
yourself far above ordinary women.
Well, Mr. Holmes, I
did what you told me to.
I moved the statue
every few minutes,
when suddenly the whole blooming
thing falls on top of me.
But you've done very
well, Mrs. Hudson.
Very well.
Lestrade, bring in the prisoner.
Oh, may I see that, Lestrade?
Thank you for that that's an
admirable an unique weapon.
Absolutely noiseless and
with tremendous power.
Crikey.
I knew Von Herda,
the German mechanic
who constructed it
to the order of
Professor Moriarty.
I've known of its
existence for some time,
but I never handled it before.
Ah, Watson.
Appears I've just been murdered.
Perhaps you'd like to
see who my assailant is.
As I thought.
But, Holmes, that's
Colonel Henslowe.
And what are you
charging me with?
Why, for the attempted murder
of Sherlock Holmes, of course.
No, no, no, Lestrade, I
shall not appear in this.
To you and you alone
belongs the credit
for this remarkable arrest.
With your usual happy mixture
of cunning and audacity,
you've got him.
Got him?
Got who?
Why, the man who climbed the
tree in the park last night,
Hornbeam, to be correct,
and shot Ronald Adair
through the open window
of his flat in Park Lane.
Has it occurred
to you, Mr. Holmes,
that it must be rather
difficult to climb
a tree and shoot anyone
when one only has one arm?
Ah yes, yes, I'd forgotten.
Your left arm must be causing
you great inconvenience.
Lestrade, I wonder if
you'd be good enough
to free it for the Colonel?
Hello, what's the game?
Let me introduce you to
Professor Robert Moriarty.
The mythical Moriarty,
my obsession.
I warned you when you
called upon me yesterday
that sudden impulses
were dangerous.
I observed that the first
molar in your left upper jaw
was very badly filled with gold,
and when Colonel Henslowe was
feeling as if he'd lost a son,
I observed the same bad
workmanship in the same tooth.
You clever, cunning swine!
You think you've got
me and you're safe.
But you're up against
an organization, Holmes.
They'll get you.
They'll destroy you.
I might even do it myself.
Take him to the
station, Lestrade.
I think you'll find most
of your organization
waiting for you there.
Also a brand new sealing,
70,000 pounds of good
English bank notes.
Take him away.
- We shall meet again, Mr.
- Holmes, and next time...
Come on.
Are you all right?
I am, except my
feelings and my tie,
which is entirely disorganized.
Well, we proved our Moriarty
theory all right, Mr. Holmes.
It's not easy to throw dust
in your eyes, My Dear Lestrade.
Doesn't do to trifle
with Scotland Yard.
- Quite true, Mr.
- Holmes, quite true.
Well now, Watson,
what about a drink?
You'd like one, wouldn't you?
- Thanks.
- Lestrade.
I can't think how you manage
to discover these
things, Holmes.
I saw nothing that could've
put you on the track
of the murderer.
On the contrary,
My Dear Watson,
you've seen everything,
except the tree,
which I told you about.
But you were unable to make
the necessary deductions.
I knew about the
existence of that air gun
when I found evidence
that the tree
opposite the flat
had been climbed.
By issuing a threat in
front of Colonel Henslowe,
I made certain that in
during the 24 hours,
he'd try to silence me
as he'd silenced Adair.
Hence, your little
trip to Euston, Watson,
and my placing a bust
of myself in the window,
which Mrs. Hudson
moved occasionally
to make it appear lifelike.
I knew that Moriarty couldn't
resist such an opportunity.
But what gave you
the idea, Mr. Holmes?
Old Colonel Henslowe himself.
Yes, in the conversation
I had with him,
the irrelevant one
about tigers, Watson.
"You can always tether
a goat as a bait
"and wait till the tiger comes."
Of course,
but what about the
Sleeping Cardinal?
Godfrey's led us straight
to the Sleeping Cardinal.
That's the painting in the room
in which you were
tied up, Watson,
and through which
Moriarty used to speak,
unseen by his dupes.
I have only one regret,
that the bust of myself
by Angelo Pelosini
has been irretrievably ruined.
Really, Mr. Holmes?