Pyne.
What is it, sir?
Oh.
Why, it's Mr Robin, sir.
Pyne.
Young Sperling was here with him
this morning. See if he's still around.
While I will call the district attorney.
Yes, sir.
Good morning, professor.
How are you this beautiful morning?
A terrible thing has happened.
A young man, a friend of my niece's.
Has been murdered at my house.
Try to calm yourself, professor.
I'll get Philo Vance on this at once.
In the meantime, give me all the
details you can over the phone.
In the first place.
Mr Markham, sir.
It seems urgent.
Will you speak to him?
Certainly.
I say, old fellow. Don't you ever sleep?
There's been a murder committed, Philo.
At the home of Professor Dillard.
Professor Dillard?
That interests me, Markham. Read on.
A man named Robin.
Was killed with a bow and arrow.
Robin?
Killed with an arrow?
My dear fellow, confess. You've been
on a wild chase with mother goose.
No. That's the story.
A fairytale in terms of blood, eh?
Alright, Markham.
I'll meet you there in half an hour.
Dark suit. Dark hat.
Dark tie.
And bring me some more hot coffee.
Very good, sir.
- Yarma.
Look on my reference
shelf and bring me ..
Dr. Elmer's book on archery.
The home book of verse.
And the German dictionary.
Very good, sir.
What do you know of this, officer?
The body is in the yard, sir.
Sergeant Heath is in charge.
Says he has the case
practically solved, sir.
Come on, Vance.
He converted this garden
into an archery range.
Miss Dillard is quite distressed.
Morning, Heath.
- Morning, sir.
Hello Mr Vance. Good to see you, sir.
Sorry they troubled you, Mr Markham.
It's an open and shut case.
I have it practically solved right now.
First degree murder.
How nice for you, Sergeant.
As long as I'm here you don't mind
if I take a little look around?
No. Go as far as you like.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
See here, Mr Markham.
Sergeant.
- Yes, Mr Vance?
How about the bow that fired this arrow?
Well, that was our one best bet.
But one of the servants
picked it up in the alley here.
Carried it into the archery room
and gummed up the fingerprints.
What have you done about Sperling?
We've got his address.
He lives up Westchester way.
Two of my men are bringing him here now.
- Very good.
Officer.
Mind demonstrating a point for us?
- Not at all, sir.
When I touch you with my stick.
I want you to fall over backwards.
As if you'd been hit in
the heart with an arrow.
Yes, sir.
- Stand where you are.
Thank you. Ready?
Sergeant.
You will notice that the
first instinct of a man.
Shot in a vital organ.
Is to draw in his arms
towards the wound.
His legs.
Are doubled up.
You will also notice.
That his hat has fallen at his head.
Now, Sergeant.
In Robin's case.
The arms and legs are straightened out.
And his hat.
Not only lies at his feet.
But is a good foot and
a half away from him.
Alright, officer. That will be all.
Thank you.
We're wasting our time, Mr Markham.
What is the good of all these theories?
Sperling is the boy we want.
And when my men bring him
in the case will be closed.
Sperling was probably in
love with the Dillard girl.
Had a chat with Robin.
Grabbed a bow and arrow.
Followed Robin outside.
Shoots him through
the heart and beats it.
Sergeant.
You are much too trusting
for this deceitful world.
If everything happened
as neatly as that.
Life would be very simple.
And .. very dull.
Yes. But Philo.
- Wait a minute, Markham.
Don't ignore the fact ..
That Robin was facing
the arrow and therefore ..
Would have had time to cover himself.
By Jove.
I've overlooked something.
If a man is stabbed in the heart there's
sure to be an immediate flow of blood.
Especially.
When the tip of the weapon
is larger than the shaft.
Yes. That is so.
- It is ..
Quite possible, Sergeant, you
will find some blood spots.
On the floor of the ..
The archery room.
Look and see, will you?
See here, Vance.
What is in your mind?
Numberless things.
They boil down to the notion that Robin
wasn't killed by a bow and arrow at all.
Hang it all, Mr Vance.
You had the dope alright.
There is a dark stain
on the cement floor.
The coroner here says it is human blood.
Morning, doctor.
- Morning.
You fellows must have an
arrangement with these people.
Every time I have a day off they
go and get themselves murdered.
And a nice fancy murder you've
picked out for me this time.
If I were you, doctor, I should ..
I should examine the base
of the skull for a bad fracture.
Your suspicions were right, Vance.
The skull is fractured, and badly too.
It looks like he had a crushing blow.
The professor and his niece are ready
for you in the archery room, sir.
Alright, Sergeant. You're in charge.
- Yes, sir.
Sergeant.
- Sir?
Just because this case looks so simple.
I trust you have not neglected to take
your usual excellent photographs?
Certainly not, sir.
They are being developed right now.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
Come on. What's the matter with you?
Get busy and take these pictures.
What's the idea? You just spending
the day here or something?
Good morning, professor.
- Good morning.
I regret that a tragedy should
be the reason for this meeting.
You remember my niece, don't you?
- Yes indeed.
I want you both to meet Mr Philo Vance.
How do you do, sir?
If you tell him just what
you know of the tragedy.
He'll be of great help to us.
Won't you sit down, gentlemen?
- Thank you.
You sit down there, my dear.
I told Markham practically everything
that I knew over the telephone.
Robin and Sperling called to see Belle.
But she was out playing tennis.
I heard them talking up in the
drawing room for a few minutes.
Then they came on down here.
I worked in my study for about an hour.
And I thought I heard a noise.
It sounded like a scream.
But I couldn't be sure because ..
The maid was using the
vacuum in the hall.
Then.
I stepped out onto the balcony.
And saw the body of ..
Poor Robin.
The rest you know.
About that ..
Scream, professor.
Could you be at all sure from
what direction it came?
No.
I could not be sure that it
was a scream that I heard.
It might have been an automobile siren.
We hear so many traffic
noises from the drive.
Where were the other members of your
household at the time of the murder?
The cook had gone to market.
Belle was out playing tennis.
Mr Arnesson.
My adopted son, had left
for the university.
We phoned to him but he wasn't there.
So we left him a message. I do hope
they've been able to find him by now.
I see.
I say.
There is an arrow missing here.
That is strange.
It has been taken in great haste too.
This holder.
Has been badly ..
Bent.
Poor cock robin.
Cock robin?
We all called him that.
We did it to tease him.
Miss Dillard.
Did you happen to know by any chance
that Sperling in German means ..
Sparrow?
Yes.
Yes I know.
You speak German?
No.
Then how did you know that
Sperling means sparrow?
Well.
The other day.
Robin stepped out
onto the archery range.
Just as Mr Sperling aimed at the target.
Mr Arnesson was watching
and called to Robin.
'Be careful'.
You are a cock robin in
that archer is a sparrow.
Mr Arnesson seems very well
acquainted with his nursery rhymes.
Just a minute.
Where do you think you're going?
I am Eric Arnesson. I live here.
I was telephoned for.
Of course, if you don't want me
to come in that's alright with me.
Sorry. I didn't know who you were.
- Why is the house littered with police?
Who at best are hardly ornamental.
There has been a murder, sir.
A young man.
They are expecting you so
you'll get the details inside.
A murder?
- Come on, Johnny.
Mama, I want to go home
because I'm hungry.
Hush dear. Mother is busy.
There is Mr Arnesson now.
- Eric.
Eric.
I am so glad you're here.
Robin has been killed.
- Robin?
Cock robin.
His name was against him, wasn't it?
- Please don't.
Don't be cynical now.
For my sake.
- I am sorry, darling.
And Johnny's.
I know how hard this is for you, Johnny.
What great pals you and Robin were.
I can't believe it.
Hello Markham.
- Morning.
Morning, doctor.
Mr Vance - Mr Arnesson.
How do you do?
This is John Sprigg, one of my students.
- Yes.
Robin was the best friend
I had in the world.
And I'm going to find
the man who murdered him.
Taking death tragically is
one of the weaknesses of youth.
So we have a real murder
mystery, have we?
Might I be entrusted with the details?
Where were Robin and
Sperling when you left?
Downstairs in the archery room.
Is that so?
Did you overhear anything they said?
I don't listen at keyholes.
Well, little bright-eyes.
They ought to erect a statue to you
for being the first woman who don't.
Was there anybody else
in the archery room?
When you left this morning.
I thought I heard Mr Drukker.
But he sneaks in and out at
all hours of the day and night.
Now we are getting somewhere.
You can tell me all about this case and
let me work it out on scientific lines.
Is that a bargain?
Of course, we can't very well
promise to tell everything we know.
It might be indiscreet.
- Wait a minute.
Wait a minute, Markham.
I really don't see any reason ..
Why Mr Arnesson should not apply his ..
Scientific knowledge to this crime.
I'm quite sure he can be depended upon.
Oh, I am very dependable.
Well, that is true.
- Mr Arnesson.
The first thing you can do to help
us is to tell us about the Drukkers.
We'll interview them next.
Well, Miss Drukker is a little ..
Peculiar. Though perfectly harmless.
She thinks the sun rises
and sets in her brother.
If I were you I'd take Miss Dillard
along when you go along to question her.
Miss Drukker likes her.
Yes. That's a very good
suggestion, Arnesson.
Belle darling. These gentlemen are
going to interview the Drukkers now.
I said you would go along with them.
It makes it easier for Miss Drukker.
- Yes, dear.
Now, if you can spare me for a while.
I have some lecture
notes I ought to edit.
Certainly, Mr Arnesson.
Miss Dillard.
Yes?
How good an archer is Mr Drukker?
Why, he knows nothing about archery.
Oh?
Mr Drukker is hardly the type
to be interested in archery.
When you see him, Vance,
you'll understand.
Tell me, Miss Dillard.
Is Miss Drukker an invalid?
No. Not exactly.
You see, one day when
they were children.
She let her brother fall.
He injured his spine
and became a cripple.
From that day on her
entire life was ruined.
She.
Well.
It affected her so deeply that ..
She's been unable to
leave her room since.
Where is Miss Drukker's room located?
Her room is the one with the bay window.
She sits there a great deal and
watches us at archery practice.
You know, uncle says her
condition is a sort-of ..
Insanity of tenderness.
Does Mr Drukker reciprocate
his sister's tenderness?
Well.
Please don't judge
Mr Drukker too harshly.
He's had so much to bear.
We know him well and are fond of him.
Yes.
Good morning, doctor.
- Good morning, Miss Dillard.
Mr Vance?
- Yes.
I'm Dr. Van Pelt.
- Good morning, doctor.
This is district attorney Markham.
How do you do?
- Morning, doctor.
I have attached a remote stethoscope
to my patient to safeguard her.
And at the same time not
interfere with your questioning.
Any undue strain on her
heart will prove fatal.
So, if she excites herself
I will have to stop you.
We'll be as brief as possible, doctor.
- Thank you.
Sorry to intrude, Miss Drukker.
But I'd like to get a view of the
archery range from your window.
I wanted to come right over here.
I knew how upset you've been.
Child.
Miss Drukker.
As your window has such a
clear view of the archery range ..
We hoped you may be able to help us.
- No. No.
I saw no-one.
I haven't looked out
of my window all day.
Most unfortunate.
Had you looked out of the window earlier
you may have seen who killed Mr Robin.
With a bow and arrow.
An arrow through the robin's breast.
That seems perfectly natural.
Doesn't it?
Is your brother at home, Miss Drukker?
My brother?
What do you want with him?
- Don't distress yourself. Please.
We only thought ..
Perhaps your brother might have seen
a man on the archery range this morning.
He saw no-one.
He couldn't have seen anyone
because he wasn't here.
He went out early this morning.
And he hasn't returned.
But, dear.
Adolph was at our house this morning.
He came to see Eric.
No.
Adolph went away somewhere.
Downtown.
He wasn't anywhere near your house.
I know he wasn't.
I should have known if ..
Mr Drukker.
We were just speaking about you.
Merely as a matter of form,
would you mind telling us ..
Where you were between
10 and 11 this morning?
The hour of this morning's tragedy.
Between 10 and 11?
Yes, Mr Drukker.
What did you see?
What do you mean?
I mean.
It was about that time.
When I heard a scream in this room.
You didn't.
No.
No. I didn't scream.
I didn't scream.
I am sorry, gentlemen.
But I'll have to ask you to
conclude this interview now.
Alright, doctor.
If you don't mind,
I will stay with Miss Drukker.
Miss Dillard.
Goodbye, Miss Drukker. Thank you.
I wonder.
I wonder if you would mind
coming with us, Mr Drukker?
Don't go with them, Adolph.
Don't go.
They are the enemy.
They mean to hurt you.
Mr Drukker.
Just what did you do when you
visited the Dillard home this morning?
I went down in the archery room.
And glanced over the magazines.
There was a chess
problem in one of them.
I sat down and worked it out.
Are you ..
Are you interested in chess, Mr Drukker?
Tremendously.
But this.
This particular problem
was easy to solve.
It took me less than half an hour.
Oh?
Then you must have been
in the archery room when ..
Mr Robin and Mr Sperling
came there this morning.
Were you under the
impression, Mr Drukker ..
That they had been quarrelling?
Now that you mention it.
There did seem to be a
coolness between them.
But I left the room.
Almost immediately after they entered.
Anyhow, you're quite sure
that you heard your ..
Your sister scream?
At the hour of the murder this morning.
What are you driving at?
I tell you I heard her scream.
I don't care whether
she admits it or not.
I was in my room.
At the time of the murder.
You can't prove anything different.
What has her scream ..
Got to do with the murder anyway?
Didn't she tell you she ..
She saw nothing?
Alright, Mr Drukker.
That will be all for
the present, thank you.
Back already?
This Mr John Pardee,
the famous chess player.
How do you do?
These gentlemen are
Mr Markham the district attorney.
And Mr Philo Vance.
I trust I'm not intruding.
But I perceived that something
unusual had happened here.
It occurred to me that I
might be of some service.
Occurred?
My dear Pardee, I've no doubt you were
hanging out of the window all morning.
Panting with curiosity.
May I be permitted to
see Professor Dillard?
Professor Dillard has a very hard ..
- Certainly, Mr Pardee.
I think you will find him upstairs.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Mr Pardee.
- Yes?
How good a chess player ..
Is Mr Drukker?
Why, he isn't really a player at all.
Though he thinks he is.
Of course, he has some understanding ..
Of the theory of the game.
Oh yes?
If I can be of any assistance.
I shall be very glad
to see the murderer ..
Brought to justice.
Yes.
Excuse me.
Here's a funny one, sir.
The officer outside thought
he'd take a peep in the mailbox.
And found this.
Read that.
Is there by any chance a
typewriter in this house?
No. There never has been
one to my knowledge.
Thank you.
'The Bishop'.
Dear me. I hope the church
isn't involved in this mystery.
That would be embarrassing.
Some crank wrote that note, Mr Vance.
Don't forget, Sergeant.
That crank of yours would have
to know a good many details.
He would have to know that Robin's
middle name was 'Cochrane'.
That he was presumably
killed by a bow and arrow.
And that Sperling was with him
around the time of the murder.
Well, that is what I said.
We got him, Sergeant.
He beat it straight home from here.
And was packing up when
we walked in on him.
He said he was going on a weekend trip.
Well, young fellow.
Thought you'd get away, did you?
Oh. You're one of those
silent lads, are you?
Say, we'll have you talking so much ..
That lockjaw will look like
a case of St. Vitus dance.
Shall I send him to headquarters, sir?
Perhaps Mr Sperling won't object
to answering a few questions.
Mr Sperling.
What time did you leave
here this morning?
A quarter of ten.
- And Mr Robin?
I don't know what time Robin went.
Say, look here.
What's this all about anyway?
Mr Robin.
Was murdered here this
morning around ten o'clock.
Robin murdered?
Who killed him?
We don't know.
Yet.
He was shot through the
heart with an arrow.
Mr Sperling.
Will you let me see your right hand?
Easy now. Easy.
Alright. I took that hunting arrow down.
Robin and I had an argument about it.
And I cut my finger doing it too.
But that doesn't say that I killed him.
No. No, of course not.
Say, Mr Sperling.
If you left here at quarter to ten.
What did you do between then and when
you took the train to Westchester?
I .. I was sitting in the park.
Twittering to the little
birdies, I suppose?
What were you doing there?
Feeding nuts to the squirrels.
Nuts?
Mr Markham, you going to let this
bird make monkeys of us?
Let me send him to headquarters.
- Send him in.
And Adams. Check his alibi.
- Yes, sir.
You know, Mr Vance.
I got nothing against theories.
Except that you can't hang them.
Mr Arnesson.
Do either Mr Pardee or
Mr Drukker own a typewriter?
Yes. They both do.
- Would it be a trouble to you ..
To secure me samples of type
from both those typewriters?
No trouble at all.
- See here, Mr Vance.
What's the good of all this hooey when
I got the murderer right outside?
Nevertheless, Mr Arnesson,
I should like those samples of type.
If you don't mind, Sergeant.
Eric.
- Yes, dear?
How can you sit there calmly and discuss
books and theories and formulas ..
When right outside this house
that poor boy was murdered?
Doesn't it mean anything to you?
My dear, don't you see that
what I'm doing it for your sake?
You must put Robin out of your head.
As cruel and as unnecessary
as his death has been.
Life is cruel.
But what can we crawling
microbes do about it?
Not that you aren't a
very charming microbe.
I know.
I'm just horribly nervous. That's all.
If only I could do something
to distract my mind.
I wish I could take you out tonight.
Unfortunately, I promised to see Markham
and Vance at the Stuyvesant Club.
Why must they drag you into this?
Why can't you keep out of it, Eric?
Please.
It frightens me.
My dear child.
Eric is quite right.
After all.
What have we to fear?
What is it?
Drukker, what the deuce
are you doing out there?
I'm looking for the blunt instrument.
That was used to bash in Robin's head.
If I can only find that.
I've got a theory.
That will surprise all the experts.
The scientific mind, Arnesson.
That is what counts.
Aha. Competition.
Another scientific mind on the trail.
I'm too nervous to sit here any longer.
May I be excused please?
Certainly, my dear.
Goodnight, darling.
You've startled me.
You always slip into a room so
quietly no-one ever hears you.
My dear, you mustn't be
rude to Mr Pardee.
I am sorry.
Pardon me.
I am a little earlier than usual.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, dear.
Oh, Arnesson.
I had that quotation
typed you asked me for.
I hope it's the right one.
Thank you. That is quite right.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, my boy.
Won't you sit down, Pardee?
- Thank you.
Have some coffee.
Help yourself.
I wonder why Arnesson
asked me for that quotation.
He hardly looked at it.
I really don't know.
No, Markham. I can't quite agree.
- Well.
Evening, Eric.
- Hello Arnesson.
Your great brains are hard at work, eh?
I felt the vibrations
as I entered the room.
Won't you sit down?
- Thanks. I will.
Have a cigarette.
- Thank you.
The juvenile Sherlock Holmes,
not to be outdone.
Has been collecting
typewriter specimens.
Good. Thank you.
Now let's see.
The style of the uppercase
'G' used in The Bishop note.
Was changed before ..
Either of these typewriters
was put on the market.
And the 'E'.
The most frequently used
letter of the alphabet.
Is out of vertical alignment.
Evening, gentlemen.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
- Will you have some coffee?
No thank you.
Or some .. nuts?
No.
This was received by
The World in the last mail.
The Herald and The Times
have a copy too.
See the station number?
This was mailed from the
neighborhood of the murder.
It was also mailed.
After you put Sperling under arrest.
The Bishop was afraid the
public wouldn't get his joke.
So he explained it to the press.
Now the thing to do.
Analyse the person
with the type of mind ..
Who would find himself a bishop.
I saw several chess bulletins.
In the Dillard archery
room this morning.
A bishop.
Is a very important
piece in a chess game.
I wonder if that's what it means.
No. You're wrong, Vance.
The Bishop's signature.
Is undoubtedly the working of a
mind deranged by religious mania.
Isn't that your reaction, Arnesson?
- Yes.
And no.
I can imagine the sane mind would
use a chessman or a churchman.
Gentlemen, I think we're
all wasting our time.
There are enough suspicious elements in
this case to warrant our making arrests.
And I propose to act and not
sit here all night on theories.
My dear Markham, the people have
invested you with the power of action.
But if you insist on plunging in wildly
and making reckless decisions, well ..
You will have to make them alone.
For I shall withdraw from the case.
You know, gentlemen.
This is no ordinary crime.
And we cannot proceed
in an ordinary manner.
Mark my words.
This is not a single murder
that we're trying to solve.
It is the beginning.
Of a series of murders.
Ghastly and inhuman.
A bishop.
Hello darlings.
- Hello Miss Belle.
Would you read a story to
me out my big book today?
Sweetheart.
Miss Belle hasn't much time, darling.
Just one?
Well, maybe just one little one, huh?
- Yes.
Who said I was going to read to you?
Who said so?
Everybody is here today.
Tell me now.
What would you like to hear?
- I would like to hear ..
Jack and Jill.
I like to hear little Cock-Robin.
I'd like to hear Cinderella.
Here's one. Here we go.
Alright. Now listen.
Listen, everyone must keep quiet.
'Jack and Jill went up the
hill to fetch a pail of water'.
'Jack fell down and broke his crown
and Jill came tumbling after'.
'Old King Cole was a merry old soul'.
'And a merry old soul was he'.
Are you looking for somebody?
Uhuh.
He'll be here in a minute.
'He called for his pipe and
he called for his bowl'.
'Little Miss Muffet say on a
tuffet eating her curds and whey'.
Then along came a spider
that sat down beside her.
And frightened Miss Muffet away.
Eric. You frightened me.
Sorry, darling. I'm just a clumsy brute.
Morning Arnesson.
- Why, Holmes.
And Dr. Watson.
What's this I hear about
Johnny Sprigg being shot?
There's nothing much to tell except that
Johnny Sprigg was shot this morning.
With a little gun.
Through the top of his head.
More storybook nonsense.
What a pity his parents called
him 'Johnny'. It sealed his doom.
A brilliant student. Almost a genius.
An extraordinary thing
happened last night, Arnesson.
The murderer visited the Drukker
household around midnight and left a ..
A black bishop from a chess
game at Miss Drukker's door.
A chess bishop?
That clears the church anyway.
Just as a customary routine.
- Yes?
Would you mind telling us
where you went last night?
After you left us at
the Stuyvesant Club?
That is easy.
I dropped in at the theater to see an
Ibsen play. An old favorite of mine.
When I got back, the
professor was still up writing.
Pardee and Drukker had visited him.
Pardee had shown him one of his
chess problems and he and Drukker ..
Had quarrelled about every
position on the board.
Pardee had gone on to his chess club.
At what time did you arrive
home from your theater?
A little after midnight.
Too late to have distributed
chessmen to the neighbors.
I am sorry to disappoint you.
You're not necessarily under
suspicion, Arnesson. But ..
You can help us by
answering some questions.
Glad to.
Are there any revolvers in this house?
No. No revolvers.
No sliding panels and
no secret stairways.
You say that Mr Pardee went
straight from here to his chess club?
Yes.
I assure you Mr Pardee is the last man
in the world to suspect as a murderer.
Oh yes.
Yes, I am sure of it.
But we mustn't hurt his
feelings by neglecting him.
So I think we'll pay
Mr Pardee a little visit.
Yes.
I should think a chess expert would be a
great help to you in solving the crime.
Mr Vance.
I am so glad you are here.
Some.
Some dreadful things seem be happening
to everyone who comes to this house.
I am afraid. I'm afraid for all of us.
Something keeps saying to me.
'Which of you will be next'?
- My dear Miss Dillard.
Our problem is to match
normal thinking ..
Against the abnormal
scheming of a criminal mind.
Please believe me when I say we're doing
everything in our power to help you.
Come along, Markham.
Eric.
If only you could take
me away someplace.
I only feel safe when I am with you.
Did you ..?
Hey.
Did you know this young Sprigg
that was shot this morning?
Yes. And if you ask me
they shot the wrong man.
What kind of ..?
Turn it off.
What kind of a guy was this Drukker?
With the crooked back.
If the only thing crooked about you
was your back you would be lucky.
Did you see ..?
Did you see anybody go out
the front door this morning?
It ain't what goes out of
this house that counts.
It's the tripe that comes in.
Look here.
Turn that thing off.
It's about time you had some
respect for the hand of the law.
The hand of the law?
The only thing I ever see around
here is a lot of flat feet.
Is that so?
Oh yeah?
I wish you would come down to earth.
And admit we have a good
circumstantial case against Drukker.
I'm not so sure that we have.
- Who else could have done it?
Sperling is out.
His alibi sounded crazy but it was okay.
Feeding nuts to squirrels.
And so he was.
He left enough peanut shells
to have fed an elephant.
That's a pretty little thing
you're playing, Mr Vance.
One of my favorites.
It's the Nutcracker Suite.
By Tchaikovsky.
Oh?
Tchaikovsky.
Yes.
I don't know.
You may be right, Markham.
My chief objection to your conclusion
is that the case against Drukker ..
Is too easy.
I wish I had more cases
that were too easy.
Remember.
Our criminal is super sane.
His acts were not senseless.
They are hideously perfect and precise.
Consequently, that same mind would
never permit the case against him ..
To seem as easy as our case
seems against Drukker.
How are you going to reconcile
Mother Goose rhymes ..
With a super-sane mind?
The grim humor of an intellect.
That says cynically.
Behold.
This is the world you take so seriously.
Like a child's game is hardly important
enough to make a joke about it.
You will find that is a
sound theory, Markham.
Well, theory sure makes
swell talking, Mr Vance.
But when it comes to
action give me facts.
It ain't what you imagine
that counts then.
It's what you see.
Right.
Right as usual, Sergeant.
But it all depends on what you see.
For instance.
I can see that tonight you took
a young lady out to dinner.
That you didn't have enough
money to pay the bill.
But when you told her you were coming
here the young lady became tearful.
And you promised to join her later.
Come now, Vance.
- It's all quite simple, Markham.
Really.
I know that he took a
young lady out to dinner.
Because he has shaved
since this afternoon.
You did not have enough
money to pay the bill.
And wrote a check to cover it.
For there's an ink stain on your finger.
And you're otherwise immaculate.
I know the young lady became tearful
and that you wiped away her tears.
For there is a smudge of
mascara on your handkerchief.
You promised to join her later as you've
looked at your watch since you arrived.
Clearly, my dear Sergeant.
Well, at least you wouldn't mind ..
If Sergeant Heath brought
Drukker here tomorrow morning.
Then we can find out what he knows.
And act accordingly.
- No. Not at all.
Not at all.
Well, I guess I'll be going.
Before you tell me
what I did last night.
Have something before you go, Sergeant.
It's right there.
No thanks.
It's too easy.
Ha, ha, ha.
Nevertheless, Markham. He's the finest
Sergeant you have in your force.
Indeed he is.
What a terrible fog over the river.
I can never remember the
fog being so thick before.
Confidentially, professor.
Don't you think that Pardee ..
Has been acting rather peculiar of late?
You know as well as I do.
Pardee was always strange.
He is worse than ever.
I think he is responsible.
For those detectives snooping around.
I don't think so.
The fog is getting worse.
Good evening, professor.
A fine way for a grown-up guy
to earn a living, ain't it?
Playing around here in the fog.
Aren't you neglecting your
chess this evening?
You should not forget that ..
Practice makes perfect.
It would hardly be of much use
to practice, my dear Drukker.
Without you to hang over my chair.
And criticise my moves as
you do so brilliantly.
Well, a little criticism won't harm you.
Now, gentlemen. Gentlemen.
Please.
I wish there was somewhere to
be comfortable around here.
Those old dodos will stand
there and gab all night.
I ain't stuck on this kind
of a case you know.
If I was making them.
I'd like a nice, snappy love nest.
Gentlemen, it's getting late.
Goodnight.
Well, the boys are leaving us.
I'll pick up my man and get
to the street ahead of him.
And see him safely off to bye-bye land.
I'll pick up Pardee the same way.
- Right.
Some kids in the park found the body
about seven o'clock this morning.
The doctor said he must have fallen off
the wall about ten o'clock last night.
Killed instantly.
Has Miss Drukker been notified?
No. I told them we would attend to that.
Drukker was our principle
clue and he falls off a wall.
Fallen off a wall.
A hunchback falls off a wall.
Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall.
Another mad Mother Goose rhyme.
Well, I've sure got to
hand it to you, Mr Vance.
You are right.
Here's another one of these goofy notes.
I'll wake up some morning and think I'm
little Bo Peep and start chasing sheep.
'To the world'.
'Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall.
Humpty Dumpty had a great fall'.
'All the King's horses
and all the King's men'.
'Cannot put Humpty
Dumpty together again'.
'The Bishop'.
Sergeant.
Did your men trail Pardee
and the professor last night?
They tried to but they
lost them in the fog.
So they went back to the house to wait.
Sure enough, the professor
shows up in about ten minutes.
But Pardee.
He don't show up for
nearly half an hour.
Miss Drukker is dead.
Her poor heart gave out.
Some sudden shock.
She must have known.
If we knew the exact
time it might help us.
I should say it was within a few
minutes of her brother's death.
Mrs Menzel.
What time did Miss Drukker
usually go to bed?
Ten o'clock, sir.
It was the doctor's orders.
May heaven forgive me.
I slept all last night myself.
I see it all now, Markham.
Miss Drukker went to take
her medicine before retiring.
Found her water carafe empty.
Came in here to get some.
Was surprised by her brother's murderer.
Who then forced open this desk.
To obtain something of Drukker's
that he knew to be of value.
That is all, Mrs Menzel.
We'll attend to the arrangements here.
I've asked Sergeant Heath.
To bring Mr Pardee over here.
If you don't mind, Professor,
I'd like to question him before you.
I hope nothing I have said will
cast any reflections on Mr Pardee.
I should be terribly distressed.
- Not at all.
Merely a formality.
Professor Dillard.
- Good morning, Mr Pardee.
You have of course heard
of Mr Drukker's death?
I should like to ..
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
I should like to ask
you a few questions.
What conversation did you have with
Mr Drukker in the park last night?
I went for a stroll in the park.
And meeting Professor Dillard
and Mr Drukker.
I stopped for a moment.
Not wishing to appear rude.
Drukker was in a beastly mood.
And made so many insulting
sneering remarks.
That I left.
Mr Pardee.
Can you explain to me why ..
Why you arrived home so much
later than Professor Dillard?
When you both left Mr Drukker
at the same time.
I sat down by the
79th Street entrance and ..
Smoked a cigarette.
Rather a foggy night
to sit on a park bench.
Wasn't it, Mr Pardee?
Anyone see you sitting there?
Rather a foggy night to
depend on eyewitnesses.
Wasn't it, Mr Vance?
Certainly, Mr Pardee.
My mistake.
That will be all.
For the present.
Dear me. Dear me.
This has been a wretched
business for you.
But I think it will soon be over.
- I just heard the sad news.
A frightful business, isn't it?
The Drukkers wiped out.
And more storybook nonsense to boot.
Eric. Eric, please.
May I be excused?
Certainly, sir. Certainly.
Sergeant Heath tells me
that one of his men ..
Saw you walking toward the
park last night at ten o'clock.
That you didn't return for an hour.
Just as a matter of form.
To please the Sergeant here.
What were you doing in that time?
I mailed a letter at the
other end of the park.
Yeah?
Well, where was the letter addressed?
So that we can sure that
it gets there safely.
China.
China?
Ha.
A classmate of mine is an
instructor at the University of Peking.
Arnesson.
- Yes?
What was the scientific formula
that Drukker was working on?
A tremendously important thing.
It would have made him famous and rich.
And he kept a notebook?
- A very complete one.
Never let it out of his sight.
The whole theory was
in that little book.
That must have been what was taken
from the top drawer of the desk.
In Drukker's bedroom at
ten o'clock last night.
Drukker was always standing behind me.
Criticising me.
And I hated it.
Tonight.
It seems odd not to have him there.
I looked round .. half a dozen times.
Expecting to see him there.
To .. to feel him.
Leaning over my shoulder.
Perhaps the fact that you
disliked him so in life.
Makes you regret his death the more.
No-one knows the intricacies
of the human heart.
Why don't you go to bed early?
And try to relax.
Yes.
Yes .. I believe I will.
Goodnight.
Oh, it's you.
It's raining outside, sir.
Would you permit me to
escort you across the street?
Thank you. It is very good of you.
Goodnight, dear.
- Goodnight.
Eric.
Are you sure the house
is safely locked up?
Of course, dear. It's all locked up.
Nobody can get in.
You can rest easy.
Eric.
Who has the key to the attic door?
I don't know, darling.
No-one has used it for years.
Tyne I suppose. Why?
Well.
I heard a strange ..
Tapping noise there last night.
Nonsense, dear.
It couldn't be anything but pigeons.
You go to bed like a good little
girl and stop imagining things.
You're not nervous with me so near.
I will .. try not to be silly.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight, darling.
Robin.
Sprigg.
Drukker.
When the gong sounds once.
It will be exactly midnight.
"You're now back in the main studio."
"And the orchestra will
resume its program."
Very well, Mr Markham.
- That's all.
I'll be hanged if I know
what to make of this note.
'This is the house that Jack built'.
'The Bishop'.
Well.
We'll go ahead with serving our
warrant for Pardee's arrest.
And worry about this note later.
Is the car waiting?
- Yes, sir.
There is your warrant.
What's wrong, Manning?
Mr Vance is inside waiting for you.
He said he would explain.
"Complete relaxation is
essential at a time like this."
"Lie flat on your back
with every muscle at rest."
I always thought that
guy Vance was cuckoo.
"Breathe deep."
"Exhale."
Morning.
This radio has been running all night.
And now Pardee.
How did you know about this, Vance?
A reporter from the times
came to see me this morning.
He brought me the latest .. Bishop note.
It occurred to me at once that John
Pardee was Jack and he'd been murdered.
So I sent the note along to you knowing
that you'd figure it out as I had and ..
Come along here.
Perfectly simple reasoning.
That's what we thought right away.
Didn't we, Mr Markham?
Hardly.
What do you make of it, Vance?
It's as plain as the nose
on your face, Mr Markham.
This guy Pardee wasn't murdered at all.
He was The Bishop.
I suspected him right along.
And yesterday I put
Flaherty to watching him.
And when Pardee found out I had him.
He knew the game was up
and committed suicide.
It's very simple.
Well, I guess we can call
The Bishop murder case closed.
Sergeant, what about the ..
The house that Jack built?
You see. It collapsed when I
barely leaned against the table.
And yet.
It didn't topple over when
Pardee fell across it.
What of it?
- Don't you understand?
The house of cards was
not built by Pardee.
But by the murderer.
After Pardee was killed.
That is just what I thought.
You say that this chess table was
set up just as he left it last night?
Precisely. He was the
last man to touch it.
Curious.
These chessmen are set up ..
Just as they were the night he
resigned the contest at the club.
The black bishop.
Is one move away from a checkmate.
Well, we mustn't detain
you any longer, Professor.
No. He's had a very trying day.
I am sorry Mr Arnesson
is not here tonight.
Some students are doing an Ibsen play
and Arnesson has a passion for Ibsen.
The Pretenders is the play
they are doing tonight.
I have.
I've just been reading
it over again myself.
Am I intruding?
- Good evening.
No, my dear. Come right in.
Mr Vance and Mr Markham
were just leaving.
They have been asking me if I have any
opinion to give on this tragic affair.
I feel as if we were ..
All living in a dreadful nightmare.
And couldn't wake up.
Mr Vance.
Do you, as a student of human nature
share Arnesson's enthusiasm for Ibsen?
Well.
I've read Ibsen a great deal and there's
no doubt he was a genius of high order.
I think he had his superiors.
Then I know Mr Arnesson would enjoy
talking the play over with you.
The Pretenders is his favorite.
Since you're unable to throw new light
on this mystifying affair I think ..
If you'll pardon us,
we ought to be going.
Goodnight, Miss Dillard. Goodnight, sir.
Goodnight, Professor.
I think I'll stay here
for a while, uncle.
I'm too restless to go to bed.
There, my darling.
You must remember.
That when one is young all wounds heal.
And in time are forgotten.
Goodnight, darling.
Goodnight.
As I see it, Markham.
The professor tried to convey a gesture
to us without putting it into words.
And we.
We were supposed to guess.
Yes.
That's why he wanted to see us while
Arnesson was away at the Ibsen play.
Ah, what a fool I've been.
Markham.
Markham, come here. Look at this.
Arnesson.
Bishop.
That's what the bishop meant.
It had nothing to do with chess.
He meant to tell us that
Arnesson was The Bishop.
Arnesson?
We haven't a moment to lose.
We must get to that house at once.
- You're right, Markham.
Now we've been told who the murderer
is it makes us partners in crime ..
If we let innocent people spend even
one hour under the same roof with him.
You had better telephone to Heath.
- Right.
Heath?
Meet us at the Dillard home at once.
Bring a couple of men with you.
- Okay, Chief.
George.
- Yes, sir?
Go via the 69th Street entrance.
It's quicker.
Yes, sir.
Alright. Somebody is coming.
Forgive me, Professor, for
breaking in on you like this.
What does this mean, gentlemen?
We've no time to explain now.
Every moment of delay spells danger.
Yes.
Come in, gentlemen. Come in.
Put your hats down there please.
We want to see Mr Arnesson at once.
Pyne.
Yes, sir?
These gentlemen wish to see Mr Arnesson.
Go to his room and call him.
Yes, sir.
Mr Vance found what was disturbing you.
After we left here tonight.
He showed me his copy of
the Ibsen play you referred to.
For days, that play has been on my mind.
Poisoning every thought.
What does it mean?
- It means you have led us to the truth.
Professor Dillard.
Mr Arnesson is not in his room, sir.
Pyne.
See if Miss Dillard is in her room.
Yes, sir.
I am sorry, sir.
But it's absolutely necessary.
Alright, Pyne.
Yes, sir.
Can't we keep this poor
child out of this terrible affair?
Her heart is heavy enough already.
I don't see why we should
disturb Miss Dillard.
After all, it's Arnesson we're after.
- Look here, Markham.
It's too late to consider
anyone leaving now.
But the information
that we have on hand.
Means we must not
leave a stone unturned.
Sir!
Miss Dillard's room
has not been slept in.
Then, Professor.
Much as I regret taking drastic steps.
It will be necessary for
us to search this house.
Come on, Heath. Upstairs.
Arnesson's room is at
the end of the corridor.
Mr Vance, you lead the way.
Me and my men are right behind you.
Which is Miss Dillard's room?
This one here.
Take one man and look around it.
- Come with me, Sweeney.
And.
Mr Arnesson?
That one there.
Come along, Markham.
Careful, Collins.
Watch your step.
It's nothing but the wind.
He obviously isn't here.
Alright, let's get through
the rest of the house.
I could have sworn that he did
not leave the house this evening.
Can I do anything?
There's nothing in those two rooms.
Where does that door lead to?
- To the attic. But it is never used.
Who has the key?
- Pyne.
Pyne, bring the key to the attic.
I lost it, sir.
- Lost it?
Very well. We'll break it open.
- Philo, are you mad?
You can't without a warrant.
I'll search that attic if I have to
spend the rest of my life in jail.
It's alright, Markham. Mr Vance must
do whatever he thinks necessary.
Alright. Collins, Sweeney.
Break it down.
A lamp.
Alright. Hold it.
The chimney of this lamp is still warm.
You were certainly
justified in breaking in here.
I agree with you.
Markham.
This.
This is incredible.
Now this lamp was put here.
In order to use the light.
Somewhere in this radius.
Now let me see.
And Arnesson told you there never
was a typewriter in this house.
The same type as that used in
The Bishop murder notes.
I would not have believed it.
If I hadn't seen it with my own eyes.
I don't understand, Markham.
We can't accomplish anything more now.
We'd better go downstairs
and wait for Arnesson.
But my niece?
You're not going to abandon
the search for her?
Nothing matters until we find her.
I warn you.
If she's come to any harm
through, Arnesson ..
I shall not be responsible
for my actions.
Please control yourself, Professor.
We all understand how deeply you feel.
But we cannot find your niece
except through Arnesson.
And you must control
yourself when you see him.
Let us handle this in our own way.
Very well, gentlemen.
Take charge of the typewriter, boys.
- Yes, sir.
Sergeant.
- Yes, sir?
No.
Yes, sir.
Certainly a harrowing experience.
I hope for all our sakes.
That Arnesson will come back soon.
Has it occurred to you that ..
He may not come back?
What do you mean?
I.
I have often heard him quote.
Nietzsche's famous words.
'One should .. die proudly'.
When it is no longer possible ..
To live proudly.
You mean suicide?
If he were convinced that the evidence
against him was strong enough.
Is Mr Arnesson in the habit of leaving
the house at this hour of the night?
Only during the last two weeks.
Since then, he's been apt
to disappear at odd hours.
And reappear at even odder hours.
Eric.
- Careful.
You see the words 'The Bishop'?
Written there.
Do you recognise the type, Mr Arnesson?
I thought so.
We found the typewriter
on which this was written.
Hidden in the attic of this house.
Well.
I don't see that you have a cast-iron
case against anyone at that.
After all, a typewriter isn't a
thing that only fits one person.
You must do better than that, Mr Vance.
- I assure you, Mr Arnesson, we know ..
Who is guilty.
Really, you almost terrify me.
By any chance.
I happened to be the murderer I should
be almost inclined to admit defeat.
But since you know who
The Bishop is, why all this palaver?
Mr Vance.
You were right.
The girl was in the cupola.
Not hurt. But unconscious from shock.
And the worst of it is, Mr Vance.
She don't know who did it.
Very good, Sergeant.
- Yes, sir.
Well, Professor.
It's been a very tiring
night for all of us.
I'm sure we'd be most grateful if you
offer us a glass of your excellent port.
Why certainly.
I'm not quite myself tonight.
- Thank you, sir.
Mr Markham.
- Thank you.
I hope this horrible business
will soon be over.
For your sake.
You're bearing up wonderfully.
You would put to shame
a man half your years.
Well.
Since when have I been a teetotaller?
Help yourself.
Alright.
While you were talking
to Mr Markham just now.
I changed the wine glasses.
The glass from which
you are about to drink.
The one you prepared for Mr Arnesson.
I trust it makes no difference to you?
What would you say if I told you ..
That we have found your niece?
And that in spite of all precautions ..
She will recognize the
man who seized her.
And I had everything so perfect.
So easy to keep myself innocent.
To throw the guilt from one
to another until it struck.
I planned it from the beginning ..
On you.
You, who robbed me of the
only things that I lived for.
My fame as a scientist.
The affections of my niece.
The only creature in the
whole world that I loved.
Now.
Now you rob me of the triumph
of seeing you sent to the chair.
It could have been perfect.
Perfect.
But for you.
Fools.
Idiots.
Children, all of you.
Baffled by Mother Goose.
Three blind .. mice.
Vance, don't let him drink it.
Do you realize what you've done, Vance?
This is murder.
Here is the glass that he
prepared for Mr Arnesson.
It was the poison that fermented in
his own diseased brain that killed him.
Fear.
Vance. I've suffered tortures.
For heaven's sake, where is Belle?
That's alright, Arnesson.
She'll be here in a minute. She ..
She surprised the professor
in the act tonight.
He locked her up safely until
he could get you out of the way.
She was in no real danger.
She was the one person in the world
that he never would have harmed.
He certainly prepared
us for your suicide.
You see, he could then explain things in
his own way and the only one left ..
For her to cling to.
Oh yes.
One other point.
She did not recognise him.
- Why?
That was a little dramatic
license on my part.
Arnesson, I owe you an apology
for the way I've treated you.
No apology necessary, old son.
I knew you didn't have your eye on me.
It gave me a terrible shock but of
course I knew I had to play up to it.
I didn't know what you were after but
I followed your cues as far as possible.
I hope I didn't bungle the job.
- Play up?
What do you mean?
'Pretend you are guilty.
Trust me and play up'
Well, no wonder you acted guilty.
Tell me, Vance.
How did you know that the professor
intended to poison Arnesson?
When I followed you down
the stairs just now.
And heard him preparing
you so carefully.
For Arnesson's suicide.
I was more than ever on my guard.
I gave him his opportunity.
By going to Heath at the door.
And watched him.
And this.
Of course, I knew he hated me.
He's been losing his intellectual grip.
For months I've been doing all his
work for him and he loathes me for it.
Then too, he felt I was
robbing him of Belle.
But what diabolic hatred
to kill four men ..
In order to send me
to the electric chair.
The four were not intentional.
He meant to hang only
the Robin murder on you.
Something went wrong.
You had an alibi that
he didn't reckon on.
Sprigg was the next.
That seemed to him the perfect crime.
He was your pupil and close friend.
And everything went off
just as he had planned it.
But then.
He made the frightening discovery ..
That Drukker had seen him kill Robin.
Miss Drukker too perhaps.
That knowledge destroyed what little
sanity was left in his diseased brain.
And he killed Pardee.
He became a killer with one obsession.
To see you convicted of these murders.
And paying the supreme penalty.
Eric.
Belle, my poor darling.
Well, Mr Vance. We did it again.
Don't drink that, Sergeant.
Why not?
- It's poisoned.
And I need it for evidence.
Well.
Thank you, Sergeant,
for your assistance.
Well, you are a good
detective too, Mr Vance.
..s-d..