-Hello, Mike.
What's new?
Got anything for the
afternoon edition?
-No, nothing new.
-Tell our king his
nemesis is out here.
-Now miss Logan, maybe you'd
better drop back a little
later.
Capt. Street's tied up
on a very important case.
That's a riot.
-An important case, huh?
So
the boys get a fast call.
Fairly wreck the car and
when they get down there,
it's just another
family quarrel.
-Hello Bill.
How many
times have I told
you not to bust into my office?
If I can you
can three hours
from noon.
-Of course, you know miss
Bobbie Logan of the Herald.
Little gal gets all the medals
for digging up the bodies.
Check for those
fingerprints, will you?
-Right.
Well, goodbye.
-Polite policeman?
-Ah.
-Ah, c'mon, Bill,
give me a story.
You know I've got
to have something
for the afternoon edition.
-Everything is
peaceful and quiet.
I have nothing for the
afternoon edition, now scram.
-Captain, the coroner phoned.
They've just taken Dan
Grady to the morgue.
They fished him out of
the bay about an hour ago.
Murdered.
-Oh, he's going to take
this pretty hard, Mike.
-Sure.
Him and Dan was
just like brothers.
-Yes, I know.
-What makes you think they
tried to hide his body, Doc?
-Well, in the first place,
you know where it was found.
Washed ashore down the bay.
Lungs were collapsed.
That means the body was under
water pressure for some time.
This was tied around the ankles.
And there were deep bruises.
-Tied a weight on him
and threw him overboard.
-That's right, Bill.
After the bullets
had done their work.
-Yeah.
Did you get them
over to ballistics?
-Mhm.
Here's the clothes he had on.
Take a look.
-Seaman's outfit.
Andy, check these
clothes and see
if you can find out
where he bought them.
Thanks a lot, Doc, I'll check
with you later about Dan.
-Bye Bill.
-It hits the whole
department with a jolt, Bill.
-Hit me a little
harder than the rest.
Dan and I were together as kids.
Took our training together
down to the same beat.
-Yes, I know.
-You say he was on
a smuggling detail.
-Yes.
-That aught to lead
us to something.
-Nothing unless he was
following a hot trail.
You know Grady.
He always preferred to
work lone wolf on a case.
-Well, it's in my
department now, Chief.
It's homicide.
-Yes, and you will have
command of every resource
of the department.
-I may need it.
Because I'm going
to find out who
killed Grady if it's
the last thing I do.
-I know you will, Bill.
And good luck.
-Thanks.
-Gee, Bill, I'm sorry.
I wish I could help.
-Thanks, Bobbie.
Funny, but somehow,
I can't realize it.
-Does his wife know?
-Molly?
No, not yet.
Poor kid.
Say, you can help me
with that if you want to.
-Of course, anything.
-Go on out to Molly's and break
it to her as easy as you can.
-She doesn't know me very well.
You're the one to tell her.
-Well, it's a woman's job.
-OK, Bill.
-I came just as soon
as I heard the news.
-Am I glad, Wong.
I sure can use you.
Unfortunately, I can't call you
in on this case, officially.
I'm more or less
doing it on my own.
-I'll do everything
I can to help.
Dan Grady was my friend too.
-Thanks.
You know what it means to me.
-Not too fast with you thanks.
You know, the only reason
I've been useful in the past
was because in each case,
the Orient was involved.
-But Dan Grady was assigned
to the smuggling detail.
And smuggling in San
Francisco means the Oriental.
Let's have a look at his office.
-Go ahead.
-Wife and kid.
-You say he was working
on a smuggling detail.
-Yes, sort of a
roving commission.
The reason they
gave it to Dan was
because he was born and
raised here in San Francisco.
He knew every nook and cranny.
-Seaman's clothes
would indicate that he
was working on something
at the waterfront.
-Yeah, but what?
-Woah, look here.
What is that?
-Why, that's a rare
piece of emerald jade,
as fine a specimen
as I've ever seen,
Carved in the fashion
of the Ming Dynasty.
Why, the art of that
carving has been
lost for hundreds of years.
This piece is worth two
or three thousand dollars.
-Really?
Dan was sure working
on something hot.
-Probably that's
why he was killed.
-Yes, I have seen many similar
in the past three months.
-From the captured provinces.
-Even so.
From the ruined
temple of Lau Jade.
Is it not so?
Torn from their
settings by alien hands.
Even young China would not use
such methods to win its wars.
Where did you obtain this?
-It was in the
drawer of the desk
of the policeman who was killed.
-A policeman?
-A good man.
Can you help me?
-A store called Belden's
is on Market Street
and there, a wise man
could become more wise.
-How do you do?
-I'm Mr. Belden.
Is there something
I can do for you?
-I'd like an appraisal
on this piece.
-Why certainly.
-Hm.
A most unusual piece.
The coloring is magnificent.
But I'm afraid I can't
appraise it's real value.
-But I understood
you specialized
in oriental jewelry
and art objects.
Only imitation.
We haven't a piece of jewelry
in the house worth over $50.
I'm afraid you've come
to the wrong place.
-So it would seem.
-Morning, Dad.
-I suggest you try
Harrington's over on Kearny.
They handle that
type of merchandise.
-Thank you for your time.
-Not at all.
I'm sorry I couldn't help you.
-Yeah, Chief, that's
the guy, all right.
I'd know that face any place.
Why that mustache-- even
the checkered tie-- yeah,
that's him.
-Checkered tie, huh?
-Yeah.
-Where'd you see him?
-On the bus going uptown.
-What time was it?
-12 o'clock, noon.
-12 o'clock, noon huh?
Ya don't say.
-Yeah.
-At that time, he'd been
lying dead for three
hours in the morgue.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
-Why, I'd have sworn on a stack
of Bibles that was the guy.
-Sure, I know Mr. Juniper.
We all make mistakes
sometimes, but thanks
for coming in anyway.
-Oh, not at all,
Inspector, not at all.
Say, maybe it was
the guy's double.
-Yeah.
-You know, they say
every guy's got a double.
-Sure.
-Even me.
-Even you.
-Yeah, sure.
Mike, get Bobbie
Logan on the phone.
-Yes, sir.
-Market 6-400.
Hello
Bobbie, I was just
trying to get you on the phone.
-Oh, are we going some place?
Yeah, you're going some place,
if you ever pull a bright
idea like that again.
-Well, what's the
matter with that?
Somebody might be able
to give you a lead.
-Somebody might be
able to give me a lead.
I've had every crank in
San Francisco in here
this afternoon.
-Yeah.
-Logan doesn't answer.
Where do you think I
aught to look for her.
Try my office.
-Huh?
-Every one of them
has see Dan Grady
in five different sections
of the city at the same time.
-Well, but--
-But nothing.
Did you see that guy that
just went out of here?
-Yes.
-He was on the bus
today at noon with Dan.
-Well, that's silly.
Of course it's silly.
But I've had to
talk to those goofs.
That's what your idea has done,
wasted my whole afternoon.
-Yeah, Mike?
-A gentleman out here says
he saw Detective Grady.
What?
Miss Logan will interview him.
Well, did you hear it?
Just faintly.
-Go on, he's your witness.
-Are you Mr. Lyons?
-Yes.
-Well, I'm Miss
Logan of the Herald.
I put that picture in the paper.
-Oh, how do you do?
Well, I saw the man last night.
-Are you sure?
-Certainly.
We talked for quite a while in
the bar at the Club Neptune.
-Good afternoon, Miss Logan.
I came in answer to
your advertisement.
Oh,
now look, Mr. Wong.
-Now give me the
details and talk fast.
-Oh hello, Wong.
Did you get any information?
-I called on an
old friend of mine
in Chinatown who advised
me to investigate
Belden's store on Market street.
-Belden's?
-You know, the jewelry shop.
-Oh, sure.
I'll put a couple of men on it.
-No, I think I'd
leave things the way
they are for the time being.
Bill, see our guy.
-Now who?
-This man did see Dan Grady--
-Now look, Bobbie, we've
been all through that.
-But this man is positive.
-All right, if he's
so positive, what
was he wearing when you saw him?
-Well, sort of like a sailor.
You know, pea jacket,
striped sweater,
he had on dungarees, pink
cap with black patent leather
visor.
-Where'd you see him?
-At the Club Neptune.
He was sitting at the
bar having a drink.
-What time was that?
About 8:30, I guess.
-That fits in, doesn't it Wong?
-Yes, it does.
Well,
of course it does.
Silly idea, huh?
If it hadn't of been for
that piece in the paper--
Quiet.
-You're quite sure
this is the man?
You're absolutley certain
of your identification?
-Oh, yes.
My drink happened to tip
over and spilt on him
and I apologized and
we got to talking.
-And then what happened?
-Well, we talked together
for a couple of minutes
about football,
things like that.
And then I left and went home.
-You left him at
this Club Neptune?
-Eh, yes.
He was still sitting
there when I left.
-Thank you very much,
you've been a great help.
Is there, uh,
any reward connected with this?
-Well, you see, uh, Miss
Logan takes care of that.
-Well, I'm sorry Mr. Lyons.
I'm afraid there's no
reward, but-- well, I'd
be very glad to mention
your name in my next story
if it helps the case.
Uh, did you say your
first name was Homer?
-Uh, yes, Homer.
Lyons.
-Thank you.
Too bad you haven't
got a picture.
-Oh, I have.
I brought one
along just in case.
-Thank you very much, Mr. Lyons.
-Thank you.
Good day.
-Well, Bill Street, do I
get an apology or don't I?
Sure, I'm going to get
the mayor to get you
a key to the city.
Mhm, terrific.
The police thank the Herald for
giving them their only clue.
How's that.
Mr. Wong?
-Not nearly strong enough.
You've earned our
undying gratitude.
-Well I hope the information
is of some use to you.
-I'll see you later.
-Not me, flatfoot.
Get one of the nurses out
of the receiving hospital.
They don't mind a
pain in the neck.
Hey you
think that's a bad idea?
-Well, now, Street,
just what do you
know about the Club Neptune?
-Oh, not much, Wong.
We'd better have
dinner together.
And I'll take you
down there later.
I want to talk to
this Harry Lockett.
-Harry Lockett?
-Yeah, he's the fellow
that owns the Club Neptune.
Hardway Harry, they call him.
-Hardway.
Oh, a gambler?
-Yeah.
Gambler, smuggler,
crook, everything.
-Anything new?
-No.
-How are things upstairs?
-Usual crowd, not much play yet.
-Has Tanya come in yet tonight?
-No.
-I want to see her
when she comes in.
-OK.
-Hello there.
-Two dry martinies, huh?
-Well, uh, don't you
recognize anything?
-What?
-I'll bet you don't even
know what day this is.
-Of course I do.
It's Friday.
That's why you insisted upon
coming here for a fish dinner.
-Oh, no it isn't.
We came here because
this is an anniversary.
-What is it?
-Tanya's here.
But she's got young
Belden with her.
-Huh.
She's starting that
over again, eh?
Bring her in here.
-OK.
-Listen, Tanya.
I've been lying awake nights
planning our future together.
I-- I realize that I
haven't much to offer you.
But I'll try awfully
hard to make you happy.
-Well, excuse me, Frank.
I think I'd better
go fix my makeup.
-Surely.
-What do you want?
-I thought I told you to
keep away from young Belden.
-And I told you that
my personal affairs
are none of your business.
-What are you trying to do?
Get the old man on our neck?
Keep away from
that boy or I'll--
-Or, what?
I guess if I'm good enough to
help handle his smuggled junk,
to run the risks
that he cashes in on,
I'm fit company for his son.
-Well, what about a
certain other gentleman?
-Frank Belden wants to marry me.
So,
he's got a debt, eh?
Wait until his old
man hears that.
-If you open you're mouth to
make trouble for that boy--
-So, blow me down, you
have really fallen for him.
-Maybe.
Or maybe it's just the
novelty of fining someone
who's decent and on the level.
-C'mon, c'mon, have some sense.
Get the boyfriend out of
here and keep him out.
We are not in any spot to
invite trouble, girlie.
-I seem to have developed
a headache, Frank.
Maybe it was the drink.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, maybe some fresh
air will do you good.
Shall we take a drive?
-Yes.
-Hello, everybody.
Well ain't this grand,
we can all be together.
Tommy, give me my usual.
You know, the good old double.
Why, I know you.
You're Logan of the Herald.
Don't you remember me?
I'm the guy you wrote about
in that automobile accident.
You know, in those days,
I was a drinking man.
-Aren't you going
to have your dinner?
-What dinner?
-The one you ordered.
-I ordered a dinner?
-Why sure you did.
-Well, I was just getting--
-And I know you can
handle your drinks
better if you have
something to eat.
-I think you've
got something here.
Don't go away.
You know, I always forget to
eat when I go out steppin.
-I'm awfully sorry.
-Well, that's all right.
He was just feeling hospitable.
Hmm, that's
easy to understand.
The Club Neptune feels
the same way, Miss Logan.
-Gee wiz, I'm famous.
-Who wouldn't recognize
that pretty face of yours
if they read the Herald?
I'm Harry Lockett.
-I'm very glad to meet you.
I've heard a lot about
you and your Club Neptune.
-So it seems, judging
from today's Herald.
-Well, you don't sound pleased.
-I'm not.
I don't like that publicity.
-You don't?
-No.
How about we chat in my office?
-Why not?
-I think I'll take a
look around the back.
-All right, I'll see you inside.
-You see, Miss Logan,
we, uh, we don't
like newspaper
people around here.
-Hmm.
I see your point.
You know, if you had
this place sound-proofed,
those poker chips up there
wouldn't make such a wracket.
Just a little
friendly advice.
-Thanks.
And here's some for you.
I wouldn't write any more
stories about the Club Neptune
if I were you.
-Are you trying to tell me
what to put in the Herald?
-I'm trying to tell you what
you shouldn't put in the Herald.
In fact, I'd just as soon
you stayed out of here.
I think you'd be safer.
Sometimes, some people get hurt.
-Yeah.
Dan Grady got hurt, didn't he?
-Hey, you sure stick out your
neck, don't you little girl?
-Who is it?
Captain Street.
-What are you doing here?
-Mr. Lockett was just
making some suggestions
as to the news
policy of the Herald.
-All right, Bobbie.
-Well, now look here, Bill--
-Come on, come on.
-Hello, Hardway.
-Hello, copper.
-Have a drink?
-No, thanks.
-What's on your mind, Street?
-I suppose you read
about Dan Grady.
-Oh, yes, yes.
That's too bad.
I don't think I knew him.
-I thought everybody on
the waterfront knew Grady.
He was on the smuggling detail.
It's funny you
didn't run into him.
-I resent that, Street.
-I resent what
happened to Dan Grady.
Quit stalling, Hardway.
He was in this place last
night at 8:30, at your bar.
-Well, maybe he was.
So were a lot of other people.
We had a big night last night.
-And nobody saw Dan Grady.
-None of my boys did.
Because as soon as I saw the
papers, I asked all of them.
You can talk to them yourself.
-Maybe I will.
-Cigarette?
Over there.
-Oh, don't pay any
attention to me
if I seem a little tough, Harry.
Dan happened to
be a pal of mine.
His body washed up on
the beach this morning.
Been in the water for 12 hours.
-You know, they tied a
weight around his legs
before they tossed
him overboard.
He didn't have a chance.
That's kind of a tough
way to go, isn't it?
-Well, Street, they say that
drowning is an easy death.
-But Grady had two slugs
in the back of his neck
before he ever hit that water.
That's not so easy, is it?
-Well, Street, if there's
anything I can do for you--
-Open that door.
Open that door.
-Well, hello, Street.
-How'd you get in there?
-The secret stairway
in the haunted house.
Secret
stairway, my eye.
Those stairs were there
when we bought the place.
-But they still serve
a very useful purpose.
-This is Hardway Harry Lockett.
Mr. Wong.
-Oh, the Chinese copper.
-Precisely, Mr. Lockett.
The Chinese copper.
But to return to
our secret stairway,
I'm afraid we scared one
of your callers away.
Evidently, he didn't care to
meet my friend, Captain Street.
-Seafood as our
specialty, Mr. Wong.
That was probably Cap
from the fishing barge.
He saw I was busy and beat it.
-That very adequately
describes his exit.
-He comes in that way
because he doesn't
like to go through the Bay.
Closer to the--
-Slightly fishy, Mr.--
-Very fishy.
Now, get this Hardway.
If I find out that
anything happened to Grady
in this place, I'm
going to tear it apart.
-If you ever do, I'll help you.
-C'mon, Wong.
-Goodbye, Mr. Lockett.
-Goodbye, Mr. Wong.
-Oh, sorry.
Didn't know you were busy.
-He's not.
Because we're just leaving.
I beg your pardon, but we've met before
haven't we, miss uh-- miss, uh--
-Serova's the name,
but we haven't met.
-I'm so sorry.
Oh, now I know what
prompted my mistake.
I saw you sitting outside in a
car with young Mister Belden.
-What was he doing here?
-We had dinner here.
Do you mind?
-Execuse the boys,
Miss Serova, but it's
their business to be curious.
This is Mister Wong,
the famous detective.
And this is Captain Street
of the San Francisco police.
-Your head waiter says
you found my compact.
-Yes, it's in my desk.
I'll get it for you.
Drop in any time, boys.
-It'll be your turn to drop
in on us the next time.
-You're a help.
Why in blazes didn't you get rid
of Belden when I told you to?
-Well, I did.
He must've seen us outside
in the parking lot.
What did they want?
-You read the papers, don't you?
What do you think?
-I think that dead
policemen are bad medicine.
I don't like it, Harry.
-Relax.
They haven't got a thing on us.
So Grady was here last night.
What does that prove?
-That the party's getting
too rough for yours truly.
-So, don't tell me Miss
Serova's getting jittery, huh?
-Serova's getting out.
Murder's something I
don't want any part of.
I'm through.
-Oh, no, you're not.
When you're through,
it will be because I
tell you you're through.
-Are you threatening me?
-Maybe.
-Don't do it, Harry.
I know too much.
-Things, uh, happen to
people who know too much.
-Yeah.
They end up in the bay
like a certain policeman.
-That seafood gag of
Hardway's was a hot one.
The young lady
who lost her compact.
More seafood, eh, Street?
-I'll say.
-What's her name?
-I thought I told you to scram.
-You're always
telling me to scram.
-Well, you're not going
to ride in a police car.
-OK, let me out and I'll
put on my roller skates.
-I'm telling you, I
don't like the set.
I don't like any part of it.
When a dead copper
spells trouble
and if this girl
starts to talk--
Yeah.
Yeah, I think so, too.
-But this idea of
mine is something
entirely new in
radio, Mr. Forbes.
-Nevertheless, I'm against
continuing the program.
-But Forbes, Belden's has had
a radio program for years.
And it's been
excellent advertising.
-Not excellent enough to keep
you out of the receivership.
I represent the creditors and I
cannot approve the expenditure.
-But, Mr. Forbes, I'm
sure this new idea of mine
will create a lot of interest.
That means customers
for Belden's.
-I can only judge by past
performance, Mr. Griswold.
Results have not
warranted the expense.
That all here?
-Yes.
-Oh, but Mr. Forbes.
This is a novelty.
A complete one-act
play in which I
enact all the roles,
male and female.
You see, Mr. Forbes,
impersonation is my forte.
-I think persistence
is your forte.
-Well, I tell you, this
is the type of program
that's bound to create comment.
Why not give it a chance?
Just glance through this
and you'll get the idea.
After the commercial,
the music fades out
and you hear
footsteps and a knock.
Now, read from there on.
-Pretty melodramatic, isn't it?
-But that's the kind of stuff
they like nowadays, Mr. Forbes.
The highly dramatic programs
are the most successful.
-Suppose we try it
for a couple of weeks.
It wouldn't cost a fortune
and it might get results.
-Well, all right, we'll try it.
-Thanks, Mr. Forbes.
I'm sure you won't be sorry.
We go on from 10
to 10:15, tonight.
I hope you're listening in.
-We will.
-Those bills are all right.
I'll see you in the morning.
-Hello, Frank.
-Hello, Mr. Forbes.
-How you feeling, dad?
-Oh, as well as could be
expected considering the fact
that I don't have anything
to say about my own business.
-When you gonna
take me in with you?
-Not for a while, yet.
-But, dad, I've
got to go to work.
I've gotta make some money.
-Isn't your allowance enough?
-No.
I'm going to get married.
-Who to?
That Serova woman?
-Miss Serova, yes.
How did you know?
-I haven't taken my
eyes off you completely.
You've been out with that
adventurous-- every night for
a month.
-I wouldn't talk like
that if I were you, dad.
We're both liable
to be sorry for it.
Besides, it won't
change my decision.
-Frank, I won't permit
you to wreck your life.
To throw away your entire
future for the sake
of that scheming, unscrupulous--
That's enough.
I'm sorry you feel
that way about it dad,
but there's nothing
you can do about it.
-You'll never marry that
woman, do you understand?
Never.
-Morning, Soapy.
Everything ship-shape?
-No sign of the police,
if that's what you mean.
-Oh, why Soapy, that's the
farthest thing from my mind.
Bring me the checks
from last night, eh?
-OK.
-Hey.
Have you been fooling
around my desk?
-Me?
-Mhm.
-I wouldn't touch
your stuff, boss.
Something missing?
-Yeah, my gun.
-Surely, that ain't so good.
When did you last see it, boss?
-I don't know.
Yesterday, I guess.
I want to talk to you.
Now what are you
thinking of, coming
down here after what's happened?
I told you I'd get the
stuff to you as soon as it
was safe for Cap to bring it in.
-That isn't why I'm here.
I want to know what
that Serova woman is
doing running
around with my son.
-Well, I did my best.
You know, after all,
it's not such a bad idea.
Sort of a closed corporation.
-Are you mad?
My boy has no part in all this.
I went into it because it
was the only hope I had
of saving my business, of
meeting my obligations.
But not to the extent
of wrecking his life.
And that's what this
marriage would mean.
-That's your problem.
Right now, I have
more important things
to do than nurse a lovesick pup.
-If you value your neck,
you'll do something about it.
I'm warning you, Lockett, before
I see this happen to my son,
I'll blast everything wide open.
-Including yourself?
-Including myself.
-Uh huh.
I see.
You like the idea of a
few months on Alcatraz?
-I'll stop at nothing.
-Hello.
Hello, Tanya, this is Harry.
I want to apologize for the
way I talked to you last night.
Oh, you know I couldn't mean it.
We were both a little, uh,
jittery and unreasonable.
Now listen, Tanya, I
uh, I want to see you.
I have to talk over
something with you.
I think you'd be interested.
-All right, I'll
be in all evening.
Goodbye.
-I hope I didn't keep
you waiting, Clancy.
-Oh, that's all right, sir.
Don't mention it.
-I'll stay out here and
keep an eye on things.
Mr. Wong, Mr. Wong.
-It's all right,
Clancy, he missed me.
-Oh, I'm glad of that.
Who was it, sir?
-I haven't the least idea,
but the shot came from there.
-Well, we'll find
out who that is.
-Well whoever it was,
beat it out the back
and left the door wide open.
-Whoever it was, he
killed Mr. Belden.
-What?
Oh, glory be.
-Get Street.
-Yes, sir.
-This case has got
a million angles.
If this jade matches the stuff
we found in Grady's office,
Belden had a
fortune hidden away.
And I can't understand why
he was in receivership.
-Perhaps he went into
this kind of business
to get out of receivership.
-What's that receiver's name?
Maybe he can help us.
-Man named Forbes.
-You know where he lives?
-At the town apartments.
-Good, go up and see him.
Clancy, call my office and
have young Belden picked up.
Tell them to hold him
until I get there.
And wait for the coroner.
-Yes, sir.
-Good evening, gentlemen.
-We want to Mr.
Forbes, John T Forbes.
-Who's calling?
-Captain Street of
the police department.
-Ring 22, please.
-Captain Street of the police
department to see Mr. Forbes.
Yes, sir.
Go on up, Captain
Stree.t That's number 22.
-Captain Street.
What on
Earth can he want?
-I wonder if I've
forgotten a speed ticket.
-Excuse me.
Percy, take my hand, will you?
-OK, but it's 10 o'clock
and I'll have to meet Elsie.
-Probably won't be very long.
-Captain Street?
-That's right.
And this is Mr. Wong.
-How do you do?
-Come in here, gentlemen.
-Thank you.
-I'm afraid we interrupted
you're game, Mr. Forbes.
-Oh, that's all right.
Sit down, gentlemen.
I've heard a great
deal about you
at one time or
another, Mr. Wong.
I'm certainly glad to meet you.
-Thank you.
-Well, now gentlemen,
what can I do for you?
-Might as well come to
the point, Mr. Forbes.
Frank Belden Senior, the front
for which you are receiver,
was found dead a half an
hour ago in his store.
What?
Poor old Frank.
I had no idea he felt
so desperately about it.
Of course, I knew his,
uh, financial affairs
were in bad shape.
-It's not suicide, Mr. Forbes.
He was murdered.
-Well, this certainly
knocks me out.
I've got to have a drink.
How about you gentlemen?
-Thank you, no.
-No thanks.
-Murdered.
Who, uh, who found him?
Give me more of the details.
-Mr. Wong found the body.
-Wong?
Were you in the store?
-I was making an investigation
of Belden's stock.
I found this piece Jade worth
at least $2,000 or $3,000.
-And there are several more
pieces too, just as valuable.
-Why, I thought they carried
only cheap costume jewelry.
Could he have been
concealing any, uh,
valuable assets from me?
-That's exactly what
we wanted to find out.
-I'd like to go
down to the store
and make a complete
examination of their stock.
Would that be all right?
-I think it's a good idea.
-Here.
Will you have a
cigar, gentlemen?
-Yes, thanks.
-No, thank you.
-One more thing I
think you should know.
That jade was smuggled.
And one of our own men
on the smuggling detail
was murdered running it down.
And the trail seems to
lead to Belden's store.
-Why, this is the worst
thing I've ever heard.
-Excuse me.
Hello?
Yes.
It's for you.
-Thanks.
Street speaking.
What?
I'll go right up.
There's been a shooting
on the floor above.
Can we get out this way?
-Yes.
-That's that Serova girl.
-How do you like this?
A murder right over my head.
There?
Oh, you're the clerk.
-Yes, sir.
I telephoned headquarters
from downstairs.
-Thanks.
What do you know about this?
Nothing except what the
switchboard operator told me.
What did she tell you?
Well, I was sitting in
the lobby when all of a sudden,
she started yelling, Miss
Serova's being killed.
-All right, all right.
Take it easy.
Sit down.
-What did you hear on the phone?
-Well, I was sitting
there as usual
when the buzzer sounded
and it was a call from 32.
-What time was that?
-About 14 after 10.
-That's an odd time
to remember, 10:14.
-Well, I'm not sure,
but it was 15 after 10
when I heard the shot.
And they were arguing
about a minute.
Who was arguing?
Miss Serova and the man.
Well,
what were they arguing about?
What'd they say?
Well, he said,
get away from that telephone.
That's the last time you're
gonna pull that stuff on me.
And Miss Serova yelled,
don't shoot, don't shoot.
But he did.
-It's quite possible, Street.
The receiver's off the stand.
-Yeah.
-Did you recognize
the man's voice?
-No.
But he was awful mad.
-Anybody come through that lobby
that might have come up here?
-No, sir.
-Did you pass anybody
on the way up?
-I didn't see anybody.
-All right, that's all for now.
Stick around downstairs.
Oh, hello doc.
Prints, photographs, the works.
And I want you to get me
that--
Oh, Little Bow Peep, huh?
What are you made up for?
That's all I need.
-Just be sure to get
everything in this corner,
would you please?
-Hello, Ballard.
What are
you doing here?
I thought I told
you to tail Hardway.
-I was trailing him.
I lost him in the traffic
at Eight and Market
around 9 o'clock and I've been
looking for him ever since.
-That's wonderful.
Get my office on the phone.
DET.
Get me
police headquarters.
-Hey, remember the last
guy we saw Serova with?
Hardway Harry.
And he ditched
Ballard an hour ago.
DET.
Just a
minute, hold it Mike.
-Hello, Mike.
Hardway ditched Ballard
about an hour ago.
Eighth and Market.
Yeah, I want you to
send out a couple of men
and have them-- What?
Hardway Harry's been sitting
in my office for the last hour.
Get
her off the phone.
-Come on, get off there.
Put that thing away.
Get out of here.
Well, 327,
Harry Lockett did it.
I was just phoning the office.
How he be doing it
when he's sitting in my office?
Well, don't
know, it was your idea.
-Woah.
-Oh, don't go away.
Do you know anything about this?
-Hey, even if he didn't do
it, he could have had it done.
-Harry's alibi is perfect.
Hello, Mike?
I want you to hold Hardway.
I don't care how
you hold him, hold him.
Bill.
- Bill, the maid.
- Will you stop?
Well,
Bill, the housekeeper--
Will you
quit picking on me?
-Mr. Wong, the
housekeeper saw a man
sneaking up the back stairs.
Sit down.
I'm sorry.
Uh, who are you?
-I'm the maid on this floor.
-Well, where were
you when this--
-She was looking in the door.
-Will you be quiet?
You say you saw a man
coming up the back stairs.
-I finished by 10 o'clock.
I was going down the back
stairs when he came in.
-Who came in?
-The young man.
-What young man?
-Mr. Belden.
-Belden Junior.
-He was in the habit of
using the back stairs?
-Sometimes.
-Then, he had his own key.
-Yes, sir.
-That settles it.
Ballard, pick up young Belden.
-Good idea.
-That's all for now, thanks.
-You know, Wong?
Belden knew Serova.
Hardway knew her.
They're all mixed up
in this thing some way.
I'm going to have them all
come in my office tomorrow
morning at 10 o'clock.
I'll-- what am I doing?
-Sit down, Hardway.
See who's out there, Jim.
-Well, how'd you do?
-Not bad.
Have a pretty good breakfast
for you fellas, you know?
Thanks for the cigarettes.
-Oh, we always take
care of our guests.
Who's out there?
-Soapy and Cap Anderson.
-All right, Jim.
Couple of friends of yours.
What were you doing
here last night?
-Well, I caught one of
your boys following me
and I figured you wanted
to make sure where I was.
So, when he lost
me about 9 o'clock,
I decided I better check in.
So you'd
have an alibi,
because you knew Tanya Serova
was gonna be killed last night.
-What?
-Yeah, murdered last night.
-Well, coming in here wasn't
such a bad idea, was it?
-What time did you get here?
9:29, on the dot.
-Oh, got it figured
down to the minute, huh?
-Yeah, you can check
with the sarge on it.
-I know, I know.
-So.
-Hello, Wong.
-Oh, Mister Wong--
-The Chinese Copper.
-Look here, Street, you
haven't got a thing on me.
I knew Serova, sure.
She used to come to
my place very often.
But so do a lot of other people.
-Including young Belden.
-Yes.
With Serova, yes.
-How well did you
know young Belden?
-Casually.
-How well did you
know his father?
-Just an acquaintance.
-When was the last
time you saw him?
-I saw him in my
office yesterday.
He came to pay his
son's bar bill.
-And you had a little quarrel.
Then you followed him
down to his jewelry store.
And shot him.
-Old man Belden's shot?
-Yeah.
That's too bad.
-Yeah, it is too bad.
He got it the same way Grady
got it, in the back of the neck.
What's your alibi for that?
-I was being trailed by one
of your coppers, by good luck.
What?
Man named
Forbes is out here.
He said you sent for him.
-All right, send him in.
Wait outside, Hardway.
-Morning, Mr. Forbes.
-You wanted to see me, Captain?
-Yes.
You know Mister Wong.
-Oh, yes.
How are you, Mr. Wong?
-Forbes.
-We were kind of
interrupted last night
and I'd kind of like to
find out what you know
what you know
about young Belden.
-Well, I'm afraid I
can't tell you very much.
Most of my dealing has
been with his father.
-Well, what sort of a kid is he?
-He's always struck me as being
a rather nice sort of a chap.
Quiet, well brought
up, and-- say,
you don't think for
a minute that he
had anything to do with
his fathers murder?
-Maybe.
I do know he's mixed
up in Serova's death.
-Oh, I can't believe
that, Captain.
Why, it isn't possible.
-I'm afraid you're wrong.
-Here's Belden, Captain.
Picked him up in a quick
lunch joint, having coffee.
-All right, sit down.
-Have you met Mister Wong?
Perhaps you met him last night.
-No, I've never met Mister Wong.
How do you do?
-We've been looking
for you all night.
Where were you?
-I don't know why
the police would
be interested in my movements.
What's this all about?
-What were you doing in Tanya
Serova's apartment last night?
Oh, we know you were there.
The maid saw you
sneaking up the back way.
-If I were you, I'd tell the
captain all he wants to know.
-Well, I don't know what
this is all about, Frank,
but you're welcome
to my legal advice
if I can be of any
assistance to you.
For his father's sake,
I feel that I aught
to do everything I
can to protect him.
-All right.
But I still want to know
what you were doing in Tanya
Serova's apartment last
night at 10 o'clock.
-Were you there, Frank?
-Yes, I was there.
But-- but, I didn't kill her.
She-- she was dead
when I found her.
-Don't give me that.
-Well, you don't know
what you're saying, Frank.
I demand that this
boy be advised
of his constitutional rights.
-I'll take care of his
constitutional rights.
This is a murder investigation.
Tanya Serova was killed
last night at 10:15.
Just 15 minutes
after this young man
was seen going
into her apartment.
-It's not true.
It's not true, I tell ya.
She was dead when I found her.
-Are you sure of
the time, Street?
-Your own switchboard
operator heard
the argument and the report.
-They told Street in
your study, you remember?
-Yes, yes, that's right.
-All right, Belden,
alibi out of that.
Come clean.
Why'd you kill her?
I didn't,
I didn't, I tell ya.
I-- I loved Tanya.
Why would I want to kill her?
-I'll tell ya why.
Because you were jealous.
You thought she was
double crossing you.
And you went up to her
apartment and you quarrelled.
And then
you killed her.
-That's a lie.
Every word of it's a lie.
-So you found your
sweetheart murdered.
And what did you do?
You ran out and hid.
Why didn't you call the police?
-I don't know.
I was half crazy.
I--
-Now, see here, Street.
This boy is in no
condition for questioning.
-I'll say he isn't.
Because he doesn't
know the answers.
-Gentleman, I suggest that
we all calm down and allow
young Mister Belden to tell us
what happened in his own way.
-All right, all
right, I'm listening.
-Now supposing we go back
just a little way, shall we?
When you did you last
see Tanya Serova alive?
-When she promised to marry
me, yesterday afternoon, late.
-And where was that?
-At her apartment.
I, uh, I was going to
take her to dinner,
see, but she said
she didn't feel well.
So-- so I went
out and got a bite
and then I drove
around a little while.
-Yes, and then?
-Well, on the way home, I
saw a light in the apartment
and I-- well, I went up
to tell her goodnight.
-Are you in the habit of
using it the back way?
-Yeah, I had a key.
See, sometimes Tanya wasn't in
and I'd go in and wait for her.
-Yeah, well she
was in last night.
Did you use the key, then?
-No.
No, that's funny.
I remember that
the door was open.
-What else do you remember?
-Yes, Belden, go on.
-Well, I-- I went and called
her, but there was no answer.
So I went in the living
room and-- on the floor
I saw her by the window.
-Near the telephone?
-I don't know.
I-- I didn't see
anything but Tanya.
-Was there anything
else in the room
that was unusual that
attracted your attention?
Anything at all?
-Yes, yeah, I remember
that the radio was on.
-Aw, don't kid me.
The radio wasn't playing
when I got there.
If you didn't leave that
apartment till before 10:15,
where'd you go?
-I don't know, I just--
I-- I-- drove around.
I don't know where I went.
I drove all night.
-What?
-Captain?
Fellow out here named Griswold
says he's got to see you.
-Who's Griswold?
What does he want?
What does he do?
-What do you want
to see him about?
-I've got to talk to him.
I'm from radio station LMAB.
-He's from a radio
station, LMAB.
-I don't know anybody
from a radio station.
Tell him to wait.
-He says you've got to wait.
-Frank, come clean.
You didn't leave that
apartment until after 10:15.
After you killed her.
Stop it,
I say, stop it.
-Street, you're getting nowhere
browbeating the boy this way.
Maybe if you let me talk
to him quietly somewhere.
-All right, all right.
I'll talk to him quietly.
Would you like to
see your father?
-No.
Why should I want to see him?
He's probably glad she's dead?
-Why should he be glad?
Doesn't he like her?
-No.
-Did you quarrel over
her with your father?
-Yeah.
Yeah, we had a quarrel
and I walked out on him.
-And then you walked back last
night to his jewelry store.
And shot him.
Killed him.
-You-- you mean
my father's dead?
Stop it,
will you, stop it.
What are you trying to do to me?
Would somebody get
me a glass of water?
-Oh, nevermind the water.
-Oh, I protest.
Get him a glass of water.
Where is it?
-Outside.
-Something wrong, Captain?
-Yes, get me that brandy.
-Now go and sit down.
What else do you want?
C'mon, what is this?
-What am I supposed to do?
Spend the weekend here?
-He'll get to you.
-Mr. Hardway.
-The press.
-Yes, the press.
What do you know, today?
Pardon me.
-What's the matter?
Who is this?
-It's the fellow from the
radio station, Griswold.
-Where'd this paper
file come from?
-Say, that looks like mine.
It's missing from the desk.
-All right, who did it?
This is a pay off
right in my own office.
Stay away from that phone.
-Start talking, Hardway.
-What, again?
-Sorry for the
interruption, Mr. Wong,
but that was a new program
and I wanted to check on it.
-Not at all, it's
all most interesting.
-Yes, but full of headaches.
Replacing Griswold is
going to be one of them.
-I can quite imagine.
His programs were
popular, weren't they?
-Very.
He was a talented young man.
Wrote most of the sketches
and played all of the parts
in them.
-He played female
roles, as well?
-Oh, yes.
In the sketch you want to see,
the one they did last night,
he played a very
emotional feminine role.
-Here's the manuscript for it.
-Thank you.
Now, this program went on the
air sharply at 10 o'clock?
-Oh, yes.
radio works on split seconds.
Every program is timed, exactly.
-And it ran for how long?
-15 minutes, in all.
The sketch went on at ten, one
and a half, and finished 10:14.
The balance of the
program time was taken up
with, uh, commercials
as advertising.
Uh, would it disturb you if
I turned on this program?
-Not at all.
I've just finished, but I'd
like to take this with me.
-Oh, perfectly all right.
-Thank you very much.
Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
-How do you do, sir?
Can I help you?
-Yes.
Is this the new
remote control radio?
-Why yes.
And a very fine instrument, too.
-I wonder if you'd
be kind enough
to give me a demonstration.
-I'd be glad to.
Won't you sit down?
-Thank you.
-Now, this is the
remote control box.
-Like the dial on an
automatic telephone.
-And works very much
on the same principal.
You see, it's not
attached in any way
to the demonstration radio.
However, being in
any part of the house
and desiring to
change the program,
we simply change the
dial and the radio
automatically switches.
I'll show you.
-At just what distance would
that still be effective?
-Guaranteed up to 200 feet.
-And you can shut the
radio off in the same way?
-Oh, yes.
just press down on
this, right here.
-What, again?
-Yeah.
-Didn't take long for that
lawyer to get you and the boys
out, did it Hardway?
-Why should it?
Say, listen, you can't hang
that murder wrap on any of us.
-Somebody killed Griswold.
And three of you were
there when it happened.
-Yeah, and he plenty of others.
That office of yours was a close
second to a railroad station.
But, uh, what's this visit for?
-According to
ballistics, the same gun
killed Serova, Belden and Grady.
Mind if I check yours?
-You know I don't carry a gun.
I haven't had one
around here in years.
C'mon, search the place.
You think if I had one, I would
keep it here just to show--
-Looks like you're getting
a little careless, Hardway.
That gun matches those bullets,
it'll be too bad for you.
Get that to ballistics.
-So you still think
I killed Serova
while I was in your office, eh?
-You could have
farmed that rat out.
Take him away.
-You're making a
mistake, Street.
Murder is not my racket.
-Maybe.
We'll wait and see what
that ballistic report says.
-All right, keep you
hands right there.
Turn around.
Oh, Cap Anderson, huh?
From Harry Lockett's
fishing barge.
So this is the
thief who supplies
this place with jade, huh?
Same stuff that Wong
found at Belden's.
Now I know how it comes in
and how you get rid of it.
You better figure on spending
quite some time ashore
this trip, Cap.
You can't beat this rap so easy.
Out that door.
-This is Mr. Wong, Bessie.
I'll be experimenting with
the phone for a little while
so pay no attention if it rings.
-Oh, come in Forbes.
Oh, it's you Mr. Wong.
Well, that is a relief.
I was wondering who was up here.
Oh, you put that string
down past my window.
-Yes.
When I found the receiver
off the stand last night,
I had an idea that the
switchboard operator
was intended to
overhear what she heard.
-I don't follow you.
-I believe that the murderer
had a way of forcing
her to listen at the right time.
-You think that a murderer
would deliberately
invite a witness to his crime?
-He might arrange to have
her think she was a witness.
With a piece of
cord, a telephone,
and a radio.
-I don't understand.
-Now, this radio is a
new remote control model.
Now, let us assume that
a certain radio program
exactly fitted a
given situation.
How easy it would be tune
in the desired station
at the right time and be
nowhere near the instrument.
-Oh, I see.
You mean that the
crime could have
been committed sometime before.
-Of course.
And by any of our suspects
who had such cast-iron alibis.
Hardway Harry Lockett, for
instance, who planted himself
in Street's office at the
supposed time of the murder.
Any of his friends.
-Even young Belden?
-Even young Belden.
He was here at 10 o'clock.
Who knows?
Perhaps it was his second visit.
-You don't believe that, do you?
-No.
-Nor that any of the
others did it, either.
-No
-Is that what you were
looking for, Mr. Wong?
-Yes.
And you pulled the cord--
-When I went to get the drink.
-And when you reached
for the cigars--
-I turned off the radio
by remote control.
-Thank you, Mr. Forbes.
-Keep away from that telephone.
Get over there.
Operator.
-Oh, hello, Captain.
-Hello, is Mr. Forbes in?
-I'll see for you.
Operator.
-Mr. Forbes doesn't answer.
-All right, thanks.
-Why don't you answer that call?
-Oh, that's Mr. Wong.
He told me not to pay
no attention to it.
- Mr. Wong?
- Yeah.
He's at Miss Serova's apartment
playing with the telephone.
-Well, I hope he's
having a good time.
I'll drop up and see him.
Playing with a telephone.
-I killed Grady because
he was in the way.
And Belden because he was
getting ready to talk.
-Griswold when he recognized
his own program and Tanya Serova
because she knew too much.
-No.
Because she was leaving
me for a younger man.
-It's you who knows too much.
Wong, this is Street.
-Just a moment, Street.
-What are you doing
up here, Wong?
-Get 'em up.
Over there with him.
-Well, the two of you.
That makes it perfect.
-I suppose you'd like
to have us turn around.
So you could give
it to us in the back
like you gave it to Grady.
-Drop that gun.
Drop it, I say.
-Nice work, kid.
-Take him, Wong.
Oh, Bobbie.
Bobbie.
Honey.
-Yes?
Oh, it's all right, Bessie.
The experiment's over.
You might get me the
Herald, will you?
Herald?
You have a star
reporter on your staff.
A Miss Roberta Logan?
She has just been instrumental
in the capture of John Forbes,
confessed murder in the
Dan Grady, Serova case.
Oh, yes.
This is a scoop.