- [Narrator] Those
who hunt by night
will tell you that the wildest
and most vicious of all
animals is the tiny shrew.
The shrew feeds only by
the dark of the moon.
He must eat his own body weight
every few hours, or starve.
And the shrew
devours everything.
Bones.
Flesh.
Marrow.
Everything.
In March, first in Alaska,
and then invading
steadily southward,
there were reports
of a new species.
The giant killer shrew.
Use the free code JOINNOW at
www.playships.eu
- Sure is a lot of
quiet out there.
Almost smell it, can't you?
- No, I but I can feel it.
That pressure's dropped so fast,
it's almost made my ears pop.
- Hurricanes got definite ways
of telling you it's there.
Where is it?
- Dead ahead.
- What's that mean to us?
- Now boy, that puts our port
right in the middle of it.
There's a cove on the
east side, though.
We'll snuggle up close to
the bluff and ride it out.
- What about the bottom?
- Well, the chart shows
it's good holding ground.
It's clay.
You know something?
If this thing had
an automatic pilot,
I wouldn't have to
put up with you.
- Then you wouldn't
have nobody to chew out.
- We should he there
in a couple of hours,
these mills of
yours keep running.
- Look, automatic pilots
can't play dixieland jazz
on the mend, just like I can.
- Hey, Rook!
Rook, come here.
Take a look.
There she is, dead ahead.
- Man, that shore do look good.
- Man named Craigis owns
this island, doesn't he?
- That's the name on the
crate. Dr. Marlowe Craigis.
- We'll unload tomorrow.
I don't want this crap
sitting high in that water,
when that blow hits.
- You gonna ride stern too,
with a lot of water under?
- That's right. That sea
won't make up in that cove.
That wind will have her
whippin' around like a kite.
Step forward and break out
the heavy weather hook.
Check it and make
sure it's free to run.
- I don't mind, Mr. Sherman.
- Good.
Aw, she'll ride like a duck.
If she swings loo
far to starboard,
we might have to take
a check line to shore.
Hey, Rook.
Take a slant up that trail.
Now, that's a rather strange
setup. Wouldn't you say?
- Look like somebody's
getting rid of somebody.
Huh, Captain?
- Maybe.
Hard to tell.
- I'm Dr. Craigis.
- Thorns Sherman. I have
your supplies aboard.
- That's good.
Nothing wrong with
Captain Ferguson, I hope?
- Well, I wouldn't know.
I just bought his run.
- Oh, I see.
Were you able to fill our order?
- [Thorne] Everything on the
list. Here's the manifest.
- Missing last week's supply
has run us a little
short, you know.
Captain, after you have unloaded
I have a passenger for you.
Ann.
This is my daughter,
Ann Craigis.
- Well, it's gonna be
nice having you aboard.
I'm getting a little tired
of looking at Griswold.
But we're, uh, we're
not leaving today.
In fact, we're not
even unloading.
That load will cut
the roll in half.
You expecting an invasion?
- Yes. Animals.
- Game, or otherwise?
- Under certain conditions,
it could be dangerous.
- [Thorne] Hey, Rook! You
wanna shake the kinks out?
Limber up a little?
- Not me, Captain.
You go right ahead
and stretch your legs.
That ship's gonna be bucking
like a bucking
bronc, before long.
Besides, I got some
work left to do.
- If you do come
ashore, wear a gun.
- Got you, Captain.
- When I told you
about the hurricane,
you acted like you didn't
know anything about it.
What's the matter?
Your set broken down?
- We've been out
of communication
for more than a week, Captain.
- Can't it be fixed?
- It's totally
out of commission.
- My assistant.
Mr. Farrell. Jerry Farrell.
- Father, perhaps the
captain would enjoy a drink.
- Well, of course. (chuckles)
Will you join us in a cocktail?
- Well, I've never been known
to turn down a drink yet.
I'd be glad to accept.
- Yeah. Fine.
In that case, we'll
have martinis.
Mario?
- Si, senor?
- Mix them, please.
Right this way,
Captain. Come in.
- You have everything
here you need?
- Oh, we are self
sufficient here.
We have cows for fresh milk
and chickens for fresh eggs.
- We even have Sermon horses.
- Sort of a world
all to your own.
- That's exactly what
I've tried to create.
- Well, to each his own.
If you have to be
isolated for your work,
you've picked a
lonely little island.
- Excuse me, please.
I think I'll change.
- She's a little worried because
you aren't leaving
until tomorrow.
- Well, I can understand that.
Bu! there's something
else bothering her.
- Radford?
Radford.
Redford, would you
please step over here?
I'd like you to meet someone.
- Just a second, Doctor.
- That could go on for hours.
Dr. Baines!
- There's no need to shout,
Doctor. I'm right here.
- I'd like you to meet
Captain Thorne Sherman.
This is my other
assistant, Radford Baines.
- How do you do?
- Two new litters
since lunch, Doctor.
Both support GT116.
- [Marlowe] That's
good, but, uh-
- We can breed them to the 205
group in about three weeks.
But I'd prefer to wait and
expose about half of them
to the Hoskins factor, first.
If you agree.
- Good idea.
Do you know there's
a hurricane coming?
- Hurricane?
Well, I don't suppose there's
much we can do about that.
Glad to meet you.
Sherman, was it?
- You have to excuse Radford.
Anything that does not
concern his project
does not get through to him.
Brilliant mind.
He would starve to death,
if someone didn't
remind him to eat.
- Must be very interesting
work. What's his field?
- Biology. He specialized
in genetics, heredity.
- I'm afraid my interest doesn't
run in that line, you know.
- Think what would happen if
you could isolate and identify
the inherited
factor in each gene.
- Now, wait a minute.
I'm afraid I'm not very
good with pure research.
- This is practical research.
Generally among mammals,
the smaller the size,
the higher the metabolism
and shorter the life span.
- Is that right?
- Well, I'm attempting
to decrease the size
by maintaining a low metabolism,
and resultant, a
longer lifespan.
- What reason?
- Overpopulation.
Not a problem now, but
it will be, in time.
If we were half as
big as we are now,
we could live twice as long
on our natural resources.
- Father, may I speak
with you a moment?
Will you please
excuse us, Captain?
- Well, providing you
drop the "Captain".
I prefer "Thorne".
- No.
Well...
Yeah.
- Tell me something, Doctor.
Has a hurricane ever
hit this island before
that you know of?
- I wouldn't know. (chuckles)
We've only been here nine months
and this place has been
unoccupied for years.
- Well, have you ever
been through one?
- Only the fringes.
- Well, this one's
building up very fast.
Pressure drops very
quickly in the center.
I'd advise you to get some doors
and windows open in this place.
- (chuckles)
Ventilators on the roof.
And if you'll freshen Ann's
drink, I'll go and check them.
- I'd be happy to.
- Thank heavens
you arrived today.
- Why? Are rations
getting short?
- No, it's more than
that. Much more.
We'll surely be able to
sail tomorrow, won't we?
- Possibly.
But not probable.
Not till late, anyway.
Takes a long time for a sea
like that to quiet down.
- Well, if you're worrying
about me, you needn't.
I'm a good sailor.
- Oh, I'm not worried about you.
We'll sail when
the time's right.
- Got them opened, all right.
Well, Captain, let me
freshen you a drink.
One for the road.
Not trying to rush you, but
it will be dark soon.
- I've invited Thorne
for dinner, Father.
- Oh? (chuckles) I see.
If you're not worried about
your ship, you are welcome.
- I'll take a rain
check on that dinner.
- If you wish.
- Father, I've asked
Thorne to stay.
- Progress, Doctor!
This is the sole
survivor of group 30.
28 months old, today.
- Well, that's equivalent
to 140 years to us.
- That's right, yet it still
maintains low metabolism,
without any sluggishness.
- It's not the
breakthrough, but,
it certainly sets our course.
Radford.
Suspend series 52
through, uh, 96, and we'll
concentrate on the rest.
- What is that?
- It's a sorex soricidae.
- Looks like a small rat.
Smells like a skunk.
- (chuckles) They have
musk glands in their knees.
These little fellas
are our subjects.
They have a birth
cycle of 10 to 14 days,
and using them, we
can establish traits.
We can trace the progressions,
through a number of generations,
over a short period of time.
- Well how big do they get?
(ominous orchestral music)
- That's an adult.
See, the muzzle is long
and thicker than a rat's.
It extends over the
lower mandible, see?
- Does he bite?
- Only when he's hungry.
- [Thorne] Well, maybe
you'd better take him.
He doesn't know me.
- All he knows is his
next meal. (chuckles)
Ah.
He's just been fed.
He'll be all right for
another eight hours.
A shutter blew open!
Radford!
- I got it, senor.
- Don't let that scare
you. It's gonna get worse.
- Storms always frighten her,
ever since she was a child.
They are not climbers.
They are digging
animals, like the mole.
They feed only at night,
unless they are starving.
And when they are
hungry enough, they,
they'll tackle anything,
regardless of size.
- No kidding.
- Mm-hm.
If you leave two of them
in a cage for 12 hours,
without food, the
stronger will eat the weaker.
- Like cannibals.
- Precisely.
You see, their intense
activity requires
a tremendous amount of energy.
To supply, they must eat
three times their
own weight in food
every 24 hours, or starve.
Radford?
Would you please take this?
Take him.
Some call them bone eaters.
When the flesh is gone, they'll
eat the bones for marrow.
All they'll leave
are teeth, horns-
- I could use another
martini. Do you mind?
- Of course, my dear.
I'll get you one.
There you are.
Mario?
Mario!
Mario will show you to the
bath, you will freshen up a bit.
- Excuse me.
- Mm-hm.
- Have you got a problem, too?
Que paso?
But you will leave
on the ship tomorrow.
- Well, I think that all
depends on the wind and the sea.
Don't you?
- Si. Si, senor.
I no know.
Ah!
I feel the point.
I see.
- Well, I'm glad to hear that.
Now, if anybody else is concerned
about my sailing tomorrow,
why, you see they feel
the point too, huh?
I don't like to repeat myself.
- [Mario] Okay, senor.
- I know, but I'm not saying
that you created them, Jerry!
I am saying that because
of your drunken stupidity
in leaving the cage door open,
you created the horrible
situation that now exists.
- Look, Ann, this is a mistake
any one of us might have made.
And I'm getting a little sick
of being called "An
irresponsible drunk."
Now, believe me I am.
Excuse me.
- Care for a cigarette?
- Thanks.
And thank heavens
you arrived today.
- You said that before.
What's the strain?
- [Ann] If I don't make
sense, please excuse me.
But it seems like everything
is coming to a head at once.
- [Thorne] Oh?
- I want to leave, but I
want my father to go with me.
- Well, then why doesn't he?
- We've discussed it many
times, but he's adamant.
I'm sure Jerry has a lot
to do with his decision.
He tried to convince
me that the crisis
will only last for a few...
- Well.
This is certainly a
cozy little scene.
Might even be called
intimate. Boy meets girl-
- Stop it, Jerry. That
remark is uncalled for.
What I do or have to say
does not concern you.
- I can't disagree
with you more, my dear.
I'm concerned with
everything you do,
and I intend to
keep it that way.
Now, in my book, an engagement
isn't a casual thing.
- In my book, it isn't, either.
And last night ended ours.
- Help! Help!
Captain Thorne!
Somebody help!
Help!
Captain Thorne!
- Be reasonable!
Everybody in the world is
scared to death of something.
- That's evident.
When they came at us last
night, you knocked me down,
getting inside the fence.
- Oh, it's just that
I can't stand them.
- And I've discovered
something I can't stand.
- All right.
But I advise you not lo
mention it to anyone.
I'm gonna complete these
experiments with your father,
regardless of anything,
do you understand that?
Nobody is gonna take
this chance away from me.
- Where's Captain Sherman?
- Checking the
weather. I'll get him.
Captain?
Time for dinner.
- Somebody help!
Somebody!
Help, Captain!
Help!
Captain Thorne!
Somebody!
Help!
Help! Captain!
Captain!
- Well, a miss as good
as a mile, I always say.
- You know, if one of those
trees crashes through,
it might just knock the whole-
- Look, honey, any tree
on this side of the house
will fall away from
us, so just relax.
But I think I'd
better go back aboard.
Oh, don't think I'm not
grateful for your hospitality.
I am, but I'll see you tomorrow.
- Thorne. Your ship is safe.
Please, stay here with me.
- Why?
You scared or lonesome?
- Both.
- I'll take a rain check on it.
- Thorne!
You can't leave.
No one opens that
gate after dark.
- Well, who's
gonna stop me? You?
- With this.
No one opens that gate at night.
- Now, look, I
don't ask questions,
because it's against
my principles.
But wouldn't you
like to explain that?
- All right. Sit
down and I will.
- Give me the gun.
Not very becoming, anyway.
- Do you believe in fairy tales?
- Well, I'm a little old
for that sort of thing,
but uh, what'd you have in mind?
- Well, I'll tell you about one.
A true fairy tale, and you've
right in the middle of it.
- Oh?
- Have you ever
heard of a shrew?
- As in "Taming of the"-
- No, the animal.
Radford called them sorex
soricidae, when he showed you one.
- Oh, well, then shrew
must be the common name
for those cute little animals.
- "Cute"?
That's the last word
you can use to describe
those little monsters.
They're the most horrible
animals on the face of the earth.
As father told you,
they breed within three
weeks after birth.
Their lifespan is
around one year.
- Yeah, I know what
your father told me,
but what's that got to do
with me opening that gate?
- There are 200 or 300
giant shrews out there.
Monsters, weighing
between 50 and 100 pounds.
- 50 to 100...
Wait a minute. You
must be kidding.
- I'm definitely not kidding.
- That's as big as
a full-grown wolf.
- And what's more, they
are beginning to starve.
- No wonder you didn't
want me to go out there.
Thanks for saving my skin.
- And I'm sorry I had to
threaten you with a gun,
but I didn't know
how else to stop you.
- Oh, it was very effective.
Bu! all you had to do
was tell me about them.
- Well, I hoped I
wouldn't have to.
But you changed everything,
when you started to leave.
And I had to stop you, some way.
- You say there's
200 or 300 out there?
- Ann.
That's right, Captain Thorne.
And if you'd stuck with your
row boat and played captain,
instead of trying to play
detective, you wouldn't have
to worry about how many
are out there, would you?
- [Marlowe] That's
enough, Jerry!
What's wrong, Ann?
- Thorne decided to leave.
To dissuade him, I started
to tell him about the shrews.
- He might as well know the
whole story as half of it.
I guess we're all a
little jumpy, Captain.
- Yeah, well, I'm sorry.
Six months ago, we
managed to isolate
the path to controlling size.
Two litters were born.
Six individuals,
we kept for study.
They were about the size
of buckshot, at birth.
But the rate of
growth was abnormal.
They continued to grow and grow.
They were mutants.
But they inherited all the
negative characteristics
of their breed.
Somehow, they managed to escape.
About a month later, we
saw one of the offsprings.
They were multiplying.
We did everything in the
world to exterminate them,
but no apparent luck.
Then we haven't seen any,
since daylight blinds them
and they forage only at
night, unless starving.
But the fact that two of
them charged Ann and Jerry
at the gate last evening
indicates that their
available food on the island
is nearing depletion.
- Then what, Doctor?
- They will
exterminate each other.
It'll take a couple days.
- And what do we do
during that time?
- Stay indoors and
wait until it's over.
- [Thorne] I guess some wires
blew down on the transformer.
- [Ann] I'm sorry.
I'll gel some lamps.
' [Jerry] Mario! Mario!
- [Mario] Si, senor?
- There's a lantern
in the pantry.
Light it and bring it in here.
Radford, light all the
candles you can find.
- All right, I will.
- Where's the generator?
- Outside. Can't
get at it at night.
- [Jerry] Here. Let me help.
- A lantern will give you
all the light you need.
I will join you shortly, Jerry.
- Well, Jerry, I
felt she was sincere
and made sense,
from her standpoint.
- Wanting her father to
leave the island with her
makes sense?
It'd be much
better for the project
if I went with her
for a few days.
As a matter of fact, I think
I'll talk to Doctor about that.
That might be the answer.
And another thing, I don't take
much to this Thorne Sherman.
He looks to me like the
type that'd try anything.
- That left-handed
dinner invitation.
That was just to keep me here
till after dark, wasn't it?
- I wanted you here tonight.
I thought something terrible
was going to happen.
- Well, do you still feel
the same way about it?
- Not as much. Not since you're
here and know everything.
I love an open fire. Don't you?
- Mm-hm.
- The wind has a lonesome sound.
Doesn't it?
- [Thorne] Sure does.
- Back in Sweden, we don't
have a wind this strong.
You're a strange man, Thorne.
I never met anyone like you.
- Oh?
- You seem so disinterested
in everything.
Aren't you the
least bit curious?
Don't you wonder about the
unusual things around here?
The guns, the fence,
the shattered windows,
my accent, anything?
- I'll tell you something.
I'm only interested in
anything that concerns me,
and then I do
something about it.
You're gonna sail
with me tomorrow,
whether your father
intends to or not.
- [Ann] Thorne, no!
Father! Rad!
Out there!
- I don't think he
was going out, Jerry.
- I couldn't take a chance!
He's fool enough to!
- Don't be stupid.
I had no intentions
of going out there,
opening that gate, unless
somebody needed it.
Did you hear it, Doctor?
Sounded like a human voice.
I was thinking of Rook.
- It was the livestock. The
shrews got into the barn!
- What was it, Father?
- I! was the livestock.
- [Jerry] Did Mario
forget to bar those doors?
- No.
I put them in the barn myself.
They couldn't get
through the wood doors.
They dug through the dirt floor.
- Let me ask you
something, Doctor.
How could you expose all our
lives, yourself included,
with those things out there?
All you had to do was get
the coast guard or the navy
to come in here
and burn 'em out.
If those things got loose-
- Any unusual experiment
can produce unusual results.
That's why I chose this island.
It's isolated.
Miles of open water,
in any direction.
Our project is
privately financed.
It's not a product for the
government, or military.
And the world is in no danger.
This species does
not swim,
And as far as the
shrews are concerned,
this island is their world.
- Very soon, right here on this
island, there's going to be
a miniature reproduction
of an overpopulated world,
and you'll see the importance
of what we're working to avoid!
- I'm not concerned
about all this theory.
What I'm concerned
about is our lives!
- There'll be ample time to
panic when they run out of food
and go on a 24-hour forage.
- How do you know
they haven't already?
- That's possible.
Their main diet has been the
small animals on the island.
That source could have been
depleted, 18 or 20 hours ago.
And that's why they went
after the livestock.
- There's still some
food on this island,
before they reach the crisis.
- Where?
No worry about them
digging in here.
The floors are tile.
- But the walls aren't,
Doctor. They're adobe.
Our safest bet would
be on that boat.
- You may be right.
You can reach your
boat in daylight.
The shrews will gorge
themselves on livestock.
That should keep them
lethargic for several hours.
- There's no sense
looking at the dark side.
- And there's no sense
minimizing a serious situation.
It leaves you completely
unprepared to cope with it.
Now, we certainly
can't make it tonight.
That's out of the
question. Maybe tomorrow.
I have it.
We'll get some sleep tonight,
but we'll have a watch.
An hour and a half, apiece.
Doctor, you go first,
and then Radford,
Mario, Jerry, and then me.
Shutter all the windows.
Make sure they're
locked good and tight.
Check all these walls.
- Come, darling.
- No, I think I'll stay here
by the fire. I feel safer.
I couldn't stand it
in that room alone.
- All right. As you wish.
But try to get some sleep.
- I will.
- [Mario] Senor
Farrell, it is Mario.
You are next to
make the patrol, no?
- Uh, sure, Mario. Come on in!
I've been, been waiting
for you to finish.
I must have dozed off.
You kinda startled me.
Sit down!
Here.
Have a drink. It'll
help you to relax.
- Gracias, senor.
- Sit down!
Rest a while.
You just checked every room
in the house, didn't ya?
- Si.
- Fine.
You're a good man, Mario.
A man that can be trusted.
You know what I've been
thinking about, Mario?
Ann,
and that captain.
You and me.
Imagine an intelligent
girl like her, going for a
COMMON
sea tramp, like him.
I know
why! You do, too.
In case anything goes wrong,
she's looking out
for her own hide.
That's why I keep
thinking about you and me.
Anything goes wrong,
we're gonna outlast them all.
I'm going to trust you
to take my turn at
patrolling the house.
Bu! when you finish,
don't wake the captain.
Come back here and get me.
See, I'll probably feel
good enough by then
to take his turn.
Okay, Mario?
- Si.
- Okay.
- Senor, it is Mario.
- [Thorne] Oh,
Mario. Come on in.
What is it?
- A shrew in the cellar?
- Si!
I hear him singing down there.
- Well, how did he get in?
- The storm breakout the
kitchen window but I close it off.
He went down there.
- Why should he go down there?
- The food for the
(speaks Spanish).
(speaks Spanish) They love it.
- Well, did you tell Jerry?
- No, senor.
He get your turn next.
Here is on the loose.
We kill him, no?
- Yeah.
Ann.
Ann, wake up.
A shrew got in.
It's all right!
He's down in the cellar.
Now, we're going down after
him, bull don't want you
to let anybody open that
door, till I tell you to.
You understand?
Good girl.
Okay.
Open it just a crack.
Open it.
Hold on to it!
Okay.
You take that side.
Mario?
- [Thorne] You see anything?
- I see where he was.
I do not see where he is.
(Thorne speaks Spanish)
- Si, senor.
I will be careful.
- Here, let me fix that.
- You all right down there?
- Doctor! Get down here, quick!
Mario, Mario.
- Mario?
He...
He's dead.
- Dead?
I got this on him right away!
He couldn't have bled to death.
- Might as well let go of it.
Won't do him any good now.
- What could've killed him?
- I'm not certain.
Till the autopsy.
- Hemotoxic syndrome.
- I'm afraid so.
We'll know, after pathology.
- Doctor, that's not the
same animal you showed me.
That's a monster.
- As I said...
They are mutants.
In controlling the size factor,
we seem to have crossed some
of the other characteristics.
- Well, you certainly
did a good job of it!
- I've known that for
some time, Captain!
Would you please give
me a hand with Mario?
Radford, bring up the animal.
- Extremely high poison
content in the shrew's saliva.
- Mm-hm.
Now, compare it with this.
Careful count isn't necessary.
Any indication it's the
same poison in Mario's blood
will give you the answer.
- Yes, you're right.
- Look, Ann.
Brooding about it's
not gonna do any good.
Now, why don't you try to
think of something else?
Tell me, what do
you do around here?
Are you a scientist?
- I'm a zoologist.
- Oh? That's the study
of animal life, isn't it?
Well, do you specialize?
What do you specialize in?
- Their diet.
Oh, I had a hand in this, too.
And I'm partly to blame.
If we ever get off this island,
I'll never have anything
to do with it again.
- What will you do?
- Live normally,
like normal women do.
May seem a little dull, after
the life I've been living,
but rather dull and
alive, than excited and-
- I'll take a dull,
alive woman, every time.
- Say, Thorne.
The autopsy has proved
what we suspected.
Several weeks ago,
I concocted the most
virulent poison I could
with the materials
I had at hand.
And we put it out as bait.
Mario was killed by poison.
- Doctor, I wonder if you
thought the system of the sorex
enabled them to
assimilate that poison.
It remained in the salivary
glands of their jaws.
Isn't that wonderful?
Well, I am sorry.
Of course, I always speak from
the clinical point of view.
- Well, don't you have something
to counteract that poison?
- Once Mario was bitten,
I'm afraid there's nothing
anyone could have done.
This indicates that we
cannot afford to get
even so much as a scratch
from these animals.
They're more
poisonous than snakes.
- What, do you think
they're all affected?
- Best way to find out
is let 'em all bite ya,
and see which bite
you die after.
- We might just all get that
chance, Jerry. You included.
Doctor, I've closed all
the doors in the house.
I suggest we do the same thing
with this hall and this lab.
It'll cut down the chances
of getting in the
front of the house.
I think if we keep a
close watch on those walls
and windows in there, we
might make it till daybreak.
- [Marlowe] Hm. The
walls are two-feet thick.
Do you think they have
a chance to dig in?
- Of course there's a chance!
Anywhere that Master's off,
that adobe's as soft as
mush where that rain hit it.
It's not a bad idea, Doctor.
But here's another
possibility, Doctor.
It's very light out. It's
going to be daylight soon.
We'll take the shrew
that killed Mario
and throw it over the
fence and use it for bait.
If they show up for it,
of course, the run
for the boat's out.
But if they don't,
then I'll go down
and have Rook lay
to with a lighter.
Then I'll return to
the bend in the trail
and give you the
all-clear signal.
- Sounds fine, Captain.
- Good, then you
explain it to the rest.
- Yes, I will.
- Well, the bait's been
out for 20 minutes.
Nothing's touched it.
- Even the wind has gone
down. Isn't that wonderful?
- I'm afraid it's not over,
my dear. It's just a lull.
There'll be a lot more.
- He's right. I'll be
back a! the bend, shortly.
Now, you watch
for my signal, hm?
- You can't go alone!
- I'll go with him.
- Not you, Father. You
haven't even fired a gun!
Take Rad or Jerry.
- Sure, I'll go.
Then you'll be sure
of getting a signal.
- Don't shoot that gun,
unless you have to.
We've only got 20
rounds all together.
- I know that as well as you do.
Sherman.
You stay away from her.
- Do you have that
gun pointed at me?
- Right at the
middle of your back.
- Look, we got enough problems
without worrying about Ann.
- I'm telling you,
stay away from her
or when the shrews
get through with you,
they won't even
find the buckshot.
- Hey, Rook!
Hey, Rook!
Rook!
- Where's the skiff?
- I'll follow that check
line. I've gotta find him.
- Since last night, you
won't find much of him.
- Would you shut up?
- I'm not going back!
- You what?
- I'm staying here.
- All right. You suit yourself.
But if I were you, I'd
swim out to that boat.
- Can't swim!
- Then stay here.
- Wait a minute! You
gotta give me a gun!
- Give you a gun?
- Sherman, wait!
- This is the gun
we had on the boat.
They don't leave much, do they?
- Sherman, we've gotta
make a deal for...
What is it?
- Shh!
They've been trailing
us on both sides.
- Where? I didn't see anything.
Look, Sherman, you
gotta give me a gun.
- All right.
Whatever you do, don't you run.
And you stay in front of me,
'cause I don't trust you.
- They're coming!
Open the gate!
Open it!
-[Thorne] open up!
- [Marlowe] You've got to
let him in! Let him in!
- Jerry, open the door!
- [Marlowe] Jerry, you
have to let him in!
Sherman!
- The shrews were out there!
I couldn't take a chance!
- For heaven's sakes,
Doctor! Stop him!
- All right. Didn't he have
it coming or didn't he?
- What happened out there?
- Oh, nothing much.
Jerry just tried to kill me
twice, in the last five minutes.
Rook came ashore last night.
He's dead.
This is all that was left.
Won't do us any good.
It's got no ammo.
- I'm deeply sorry, Captain.
I wish he had
followed your orders.
- Look, Doctor. You
casually mentioned animals.
You didn't explain to us what
we were facing out there!
- You have every right
to feel the way you do.
My mistake was only mine.
It was one of judgment.
I didn't know about
the hurricane.
I didn't anticipate the effect
it would have on the shrews.
I thought the house would
be safe through the crisis.
- How could you expose
your own daughter?
How could you
expose Ann to that?
- She was going to leave last
week but the boat didn't come.
- I need a drink.
Anybody else care for one?
- I could use some coffee.
- I'll make some.
- Thank you, my dear.
- Cream and sugar?
- [Radford] Oh, my leg!
- [Jerry] Slam the door!
- You all right, Doctor?
- He just ripped my
trousers, that's all.
- Are you sure that's all?
- I'm completely
aware of it, Doctor.
- I'll kill them!
(gun fires)
- That was a stupid
waste of ammunition.
Every one of 'em, a clean miss.
There's still four
of 'em in there.
- [Marlowe] How did they get in?
- Through that kitchen window.
That rope must be rotten.
- (gasps) It got him!
Radford!
He...
He's dead.
-[Ann] Oh, no!
- He recorded every
symptom and reaction,
right up to the
moment of his death.
- Jerry, tear down one of
those drapes and cover him up.
- Sure!
Sure!
Craigis'll cover Ann
and I'll cover him.
You'll cover me, but
who'll cover you?
- Shut up!
- We can get on mantle,
sway from the chan-
- I told you to shut up!
Now, you stop
sniveling and think!
- [Jerry] It'd take a
tank to get us outta here!
- Thorne!
There!
- [Thorne] Give me
a hand with this.
- It won't take them
long to dig around this.
- You're right. No telling
where else they're digging, too.
- [Jerry] There!
- Come on!
- Oh, no!
There's not enough stuff here
to barricade those walls.
I'll tell you we'll pile some
of those crates up over there.
That roof's our last chance.
Here, help me, Doctor.
Ann, see if you can
find something light!
- (groans) All right.
- Here, help her
with that, Doctor.
Jerry, see if you
can find some rope.
Yes. Use these chemical
drums as tanks!
Individual tanks!
Here, I'll show you.
- All right.
- Se! it down here.
- Yeah.
- Let it down now.
- All right.
- Slow.
All right?
- Yeah.
I've got you. It'll work!
It'll work!
- But these drums are
too tall for the base!
If the shrews don't push
us over, the wind will!
- Not if we lash 'em together!
- Huh? All right.
- Hey, are there any
more around here?
- Only that one over there!
- Have any coal chisels
or hammers or anything
I could knock a hole in
here and make air pieces?
- [Marlowe] There are some
tools over there in the corner!
- Hey, here's another one!
Hey, get that out there
and we'll work on it.
Hey, this is even better!
Give me a little more slack.
Get some rope and
put it on that latch,
so we can reach it
from the ground.
Jerry!
- [Jerry] Somebody
hold the other end!
- Now, hold this end.
- All right.
- All right. We're all set!
Look, it's gonna be rough,
bu! we should be able to
duck walk to the beach.
Where's Jerry?
- [Jerry] There's a lot of
'em out there! I can see 'em!
I'm not going!
- [Thorne] Look, come down here!
That wind will blow you
right off that roof!
- I told you, I'm not going!
I'm staying here!
- We've got to get him
down here, somehow.
Ann, see if you can
coax him down here.
- Jerry! Jerry, please
come down with us!
- No, Ann! They'll get
you if you go out there!
- Come down here, you fool!
Poor devil. I hope he makes it.
- We can't leave him! He's
not responsible for himself.
- We've got to go now.
All right, Doctor.
- All right.
All right!
- Now, hold it up!
Put it down slow.
- All right!
- Everybody ready?
I'm gonna open that gate!
- [Marlowe] We're ready!
- Ready.
- Okay, here they come!
Hold on! Hold on!
- Ann, what's the matter?
Your side's dragging.
You wanna rest? You tired?
- What'd you say?
- She says she's all right.
She's keeping her eyes closed.
- All right. Keep
your eyes closed.
They can'! get at
you through the slit.
- This empty drum is
too heavy for her.
I can barely hold up my side.
- I'll be all right in a minute.
- All right.
You walk.
I'll drag for a while.
Listen. Don't let
their head get under.
They'll flip us over!
- He got my foot!
- Check your foot!
- No, my foot is free,
but he got my boot.
- Is there a scratch?
- No. Not a mark.
- Keep moving!
Let's go! Let's go!
- Thorne, I don't think I...
- What?
- Sand! (gasps)
We have sand!
Thorne, we're close!
- We'll hi! the water soon.
It doesn't sound like
they're following us anymore.
- We'd better walk deeper.
- I'm about drowned out.
- Okay, let's swim for it.
- Okay.
We are safe, aren't
we? I mean, the storm.
- Oh, sure.
She rode out the
first half all right,
and that's always the roughest.
Anyway, riding an anchor
out will give me a chance
to learn a little bit more
about that Swedish accent.
- In 24 hours, there'll be
one shrew left on the island,
and he'll be dead of starvation.
An excellent example
of overpopulation.
- Well, you know
something, Doctor?
- What's that?
- I'm not gonna worry about
overpopulation, just yet.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/fgtyd
Help other users to choose the best subtitles