Larry, give me one of those empty jars.
Fill them up, will you?
Extra!
Read all about it!
Give us a swig.
- Hello, Tommy.
- Hello.
Can grease?
Come on, Matt. We got business.
Give us a little kiss.
That's what you get
for fooling with women.
Hey, little boy, stop.
Stop, I say! Stop that!
Officer, get those boys.
Don't let them escape!
if I get a hold of you...
Matt, look.
That ain't fair, Tom.
- What do you care? It's only a girl.
- She's my sister, ain't she?
What difference does that make?
Help me up, Matt.
Leave her alone. She's doing fine.
That's the way to learn.
That's just like you, Tom Powers.
You're the meanest boy in town.
He is not.
He give you his skates, didn't he?
I believe he did it
just so he could play that trick on me.
- I'm gonna tell your brother Mike.
- Go ahead and tell him.
Here he comes now.
You'll help me, won't you, Mike?
- Where'd you get the skates, Molly?
- Tom gave them to me.
Tom did? Where'd you get them, Tom?
He got them from a kid
who owed him some money.
I'll bet you stole them, Tom.
Give them back, Molly.
Why don't you mind your own business?
Nobody asked you
to put your two cents in.
Here, Tom.
I don't want them if you stole them.
- So you're getting like sissy Mike, too.
- Take them, Tom.
You ain't so darn good.
Your old man swipes pigeons.
Tom Powers, he does not!
You're a big liar.
He's in jail.
They don't put people there for nothing.
Everybody who belongs there, ain't there.
That's where you'll be someday,
Tom Powers.
I ain't there yet.
if I do go, it won't be for swiping pigeons.
Tell him you were only kidding, Tom.
How do you want them this time:
up or down?
Three for me, too. Three skins.
- Hello there.
- How's it going?
How are you?
Hit you. There you are.
- Hit me again.
- Hit you. There's one.
Hit you again. There you go.
Hey, Putty Nose.
All right. I'll be back in a minute, boys.
Hello, boys. What's up?
- We've got something.
- Really?
Fine. I'll bet you a nickel.
- Where'd you get them?
- Wentworth Avenue.
How much are they worth?
Not much. Just cheap watches.
- Cheap watches? $1 apiece.
- Yeah, and there's six of them, too.
I don't know what I can do with them.
They're hot.
Come on. Quit stalling, Putty Nose.
You know how to sell them.
You're too smart.
- I'll see what I can do with them.
- How much do we get?
What do you say to 50 cents
for each of them?
- 50 cents?
- I ain't cheating you. That's a good price.
I have to take all the risk,
and maybe I can't sell them at all.
Give us the 50 cents.
You know old Putty Nose always
plays on the square with you, don't you?
- This is only two bits.
- Yeah, and this is only a nickel.
- My mistake.
- Yeah.
All right.
You both owe me a month's dues
to the club, don't you?
- That's right, Tom.
- So we're calling that square, see?
- That's all right, isn't it?
- Sure.
You've done a good stroke of business.
And if you find anything more...
you'll just remember old Putty Nose,
won't you?
Okay. Let's scram.
What do we want with
a couple of young squirts like them for?
They ain't gonna be so bad.
They won't expect much of a cut.
- Hey there, Tom.
- Hello, Putty Nose.
Hello, boys.
Are you alone?
I'm always alone when I'm with Matt.
You looking for a sock on the button?
I was afraid you might have
brought Mike with you.
That sucker.
He's too busy going to school.
He's learning how to be poor.
Ain't he working
on the streetcars anymore?
Sure. He's a ding-ding in the daytime,
goes to school at night.
What do you want us for, Putty?
Something sweet.
Remember how I always said...
when I got something good, I'd cut you in?
Now, Dutch here knows the whole layout.
We've been casing the joint
for a whole week.
- How about the cops?
- You ain't afraid of cops.
There ain't gonna be no trouble...
and if there is,
I promise you that I'll protect you.
Now, Limpy here will be lookout.
The place is dead at night, anyhow.
Well, are you on?
- We ain't never done nothing so big.
- "Big" is right.
I'm giving you a break, like I promised.
Furs is worth plenty nowadays.
How about you, Tom?
- It's kind of new stuff for me.
- You gotta grow up sometime.
Wait a minute.
Christmas present from Santa Claus.
With best wishes
for a prosperous new year.
- I'm scared stiff.
- Come on, ain't nothing to be scared of.
Is that so?
Look at you, you're shaking yourself.
Take it off me, will you?
Stop!
You tried to get away, did you?
They got Limpy Larry.
Stop there!
- Where's that big loony?
- Where's Putty? We knocked off a—
Yeah, I know all about it.
Putty Nose beat it.
You better lay low for a while.
The heat's on.
But Putty Nose got us into this.
He promised to see us through.
Why, that dirty, no-good,
yellow-bellied stool.
I'm gonna give it to him right in the head
the first time I see him.
Yeah? You and who else?
My Larry.
He was a good boy.
Larry got what he asked for. I warned him.
He was a no-good boy.
My Larry was a good boy.
He got into bad company, that's all.
Come here, Tommy boy.
I'm so glad you came, Tommy.
Mrs. Dalton will be pleased to see
some of Larry's nicer friends.
"U.S. declares war." Read all about it!
Wait a minute, Tom. Here comes Mike.
Extra! Read all about it.
You should come on home with me, Molly.
I don't know just how to tell Mom.
All right, Mike.
That sister of yours
ain't getting any bargain in Mike.
How come he ain't working?
I guess he got fired
for snatching too many nickels.
- They look like something's happened.
- Come on, we gotta see Paddy.
You don't need to stall
with Paddy Ryan, Tom.
I've been watching you ever since
you bought your first drink from me.
I know what you been doing.
You see, Paddy, it's like this.
We delivered some cigars today.
Must be worth about $2,500.
Took them to a place on 63rd
and was told to put them in the back.
- We could lift them easy tonight.
- But we don't know what to do with them.
You sell cigars, don't you?
Not that kind. Can't afford it.
I've got my own system, boys,
but being a fence ain't part of it.
- We thought maybe you know somebody.
- Maybe I do.
You might take them there.
- I'll call up and say you're coming.
- Thanks, Paddy.
Wait a minute.
if you get in a jam, give me a ring.
You'll find out Paddy Ryan's your friend.
Thanks, Paddy.
Why do you want to front for us?
We ain't never done nothing for you.
Maybe not.
But I may need a friend myself sometime.
I'm older than you...
and I've learned that nobody can do much
without somebody else.
Remember this, boys:
You gotta have friends.
I've been watching and hearing about you,
and I've been worried.
I was worried when you got mixed up
with that two-timer Putty Nose.
Such guys are dangerous.
I'm glad you come to me.
As far as I'm concerned,
there's only two kinds of people:
right and wrong.
Now, I think you're right.
You'll find that I am, unless you cross me.
That's swell.
Don't cry. Everything will be all right.
Hello, Ma.
Tommy boy.
You won't leave me, will you, Tommy?
You're all I've got left now, Tommy boy.
What's the matter, Ma? What's up?
Mike's enlisted.
Enlisted? In the Army?
- In the Marines.
- But you won't go, Tommy.
Promise me you won't go.
You're just a baby.
Now, listen, Ma—
if your pa was alive,
I wouldn't care so much.
Promise me, Tommy.
I won't go, Ma. When's he going?
As soon as he gets his call.
He's up packing now.
Go up and see him, Tommy.
We ought to be very proud of him.
- Hello, Mike.
- Hello, Tom.
I'm glad you came. I suppose you've heard.
Yeah. Kind of rushing it, ain't you?
Well, Tom, when your country needs you,
she needs you.
I suppose you think I ought to go, too.
No. Maybe it was selfish of me, Tom...
but somebody's got to stay here
and take care of Ma.
You earn more money than I do,
and they'd have called me first anyway.
- You always did get all the breaks.
- Don't take it like that, Tom.
You've got to be
the man of the family now.
And while we're on the subject, I wish
you'd try to stay home a little more.
- I gotta work, ain't l?
- Sure.
Listen, I was in a place today,
and I heard somebody say something.
- What of it?
- Well, they were saying...
It seemed as though they were
pointing a finger at you and Matt.
Who was?
What rat would say anything about me—
Now take it easy.
You're always hearing things.
You'll get too much in your nose someday
and wonder how you got it.
For crying out loud,
I heard some guys talking about you...
saying you were in on some crooked work.
What am I supposed to do? Run?
You ain't asking me, you're telling me.
And I don't know a thing, see?
All I've got to say is that
you've got a good job now.
You don't need these rats
you're running with.
You want me to go to night school
and read poems.
I've been hearing a few things myself.
- There's nothing to hear about me.
- That's all you know.
You ain't so smart.
Books don't hide everything.
- You're a liar. You're covering up.
- Covering up for what? For you?
- You're nothing but a sneak thief.
- What did you say?
You heard me, a petty larceny sneak thief.
Robbing the streetcar company.
Don't you think that
booze ain't gonna be valuable.
I heard today that
alcohol's gone to $30 a gallon.
The real McCoy's hard to get.
All you gotta do
when you deliver a good shipment...
is size up the layout and let me know.
I can use some of it.
I know two or three others
that'll buy all that I can't handle.
It means real dough, a three-way split.
I said we'd get together sometime,
didn't l?
Well, the time has come now.
Grab the rope.
One jerk to start, and two to stop.
Thanks, Hymie.
There.
- Are you satisfied?
- I'll say.
Pretty soft, wasn't it?
How do you like playing with Paddy?
- I wonder what to do with so much dough.
- You ain't started.
I'll make big shots out of you yet.
- Anything you say goes for me, Paddy.
- Me, too.
And here's to us.
31.5 inches.
Don't forget, plenty of room in there.
Sir. Here's where you need the room.
Such a muscle.
Make it snappy
or you'll find out what it's for.
- Yeah, come on. Let's get out of here.
- Yes, sir.
22.5 inches.
Did you read about that big robbery
at the booze warehouse?
42.5 inches.
- Right under their very noses.
- Yeah, a guy was just telling me about it.
33.5 inches.
if those men get away with that,
they'll be rich for life.
37.5 inches.
Did you read what it said
in the papers? 150,000.
150,000.
Dollars.
Why don't you two mugs
get an adding machine?
All through now, gentlemen. Thank you.
Don't forget what I told you.
Plenty of room there.
Yeah, and remember: six buttons.
Be careful, Matt, or you're going to
cut the nose right off of you.
- if it ain't Mr. Tom and Mr. Matt.
- Hello, George. How's business?
- Big night.
- Good.
Hey, stoop, that's got gears!
It ain't no Ford!
Okay, boss.
Mr. Powers, Mr. Doyle. Alone as usual?
I am, but Matt's all fixed up.
He's got me with him.
The night's young yet.
- You'll wind up with something.
- Yeah, with the morning paper.
- Couple of lightweights.
- Yeah, flat tires.
Why don't you send them
home to their mothers?
- They're no good to the joint anymore.
- And the ladies, too?
Don't be silly.
How about something with ice in it?
Well, we're with friends.
Yeah, I know it. I'm one of them.
Hello, baby.
- What are you going to have?
- Anything you say, big boy.
You're a swell dish.
I think I'm going to go for you.
- Look at what I got measured for.
- I don't even know you're here.
Come on.
Then it's a deal?
if you can assure me
my name will be protected.
You'll be protected all over the place.
Hello, boys.
You can take off those clothes.
You got new jobs.
First, meet Mr. Leehman.
These are the two lads
I was telling you about.
Sit down, boys.
How do you like the brewery business?
- We don't know nothing about it.
- You will.
You're in it now.
Mr. Leehman and I got it all fixed.
Mr. Leehman owns that big brewery
over on Union Avenue.
- But that's been closed since—
- Yeah. It's going to open up.
You spoke of a rather remarkable man
from the West Side.
Nails Nathan.
- Paddy, is Nails throwing in with us?
- He'll be here any minute.
I don't believe I'm acquainted
with the gentleman.
Then you're the only man in town
that ain't.
At least everybody's heard of him, boys.
Believe me, Mr. Leehman,
when Nails and his mob start on a job...
it's already done.
That Schemer Burns' crowd
tries to muscle in on us...
I pity them.
You understand that my desire is merely
to furnish a better grade of beer...
than the working man can now obtain...
- under the present, unfortunate—
- In your hat.
And again in your hat, mister.
I've heard that north wind blow before.
if you're in this, you're in for the coins,
same as the rest of us.
- Gentlemen, meet Nails Nathan.
- Born Samuel.
Tom Powers, glad to know you.
And you're Matt Doyle.
- How are you? Sit down, fellas.
- How'd you know?
Know all about you.
Paddy has been talking.
Meet Mr. Leehman, Nails.
Tickled pink. Don't take offense
at anything I say, Mr. Leehman.
if we're in this racket together,
we got to keep the cheaters off, right?
My name is not to appear—
Don't worry.
We won't use it in our advertising.
Paddy, the mob's all ready
by the time you can open.
Got some swell routes laid out for you,
and the stock's all marked.
You mean,
you have the customers all signed up?
- Signed up?
- Yes, sir.
Signed up or sealed up.
Tom and Matt here
is the official signers and sealers.
- The trouble squad.
- And if they need any help...
Nails has got some pretty handy boys
with their gloves all oiled.
Dear me, I'm afraid this means—
It means they buy our beer
or they don't buy any beer.
All right, Dutch, get going.
And don't take any back talk
from those speakies.
Tell them, "Here's the beer you ordered."
if they doubt you, call Matt and Tom.
All right, Matt, Tom, get going.
- Hello, Steve. How's business?
- Business?
Business is on the bum.
That's with telling us
you only took two kegs of beer last trip...
- but now you don't want any at all.
- Business is on the bum.
Give us a couple of beers.
That'll help a little.
- That ain't our beer.
- Where'd you get this slop?
It's good, ain't it?
And it's cheaper than yours.
How much you paying for this stuff?
- Two bits a glass.
- All right. Screw.
I thought so.
You can sell ours for the same price.
Get your hands off that!
Somebody's got to protect
your customers.
What can I do? I can't help it
if I have to buy from Schemer Burns.
- They tell me the same thing that you do.
- You're yellow.
Please, you ain't gonna slug me, are you?
Maybe not today.
But I'm telling you this for the last time.
When Dutch comes,
he will leave some beer.
You're going to take it
and kick in with the dough.
if you don't, somebody will come and kick
your teeth out one at a time. Get me?
You'll be needing some right away.
How many should we leave?
- Two kegs.
- You hear that, Dutch? Bring in five kegs.
"Mr. And Mrs. Patrick J. Ryan."
"Mr. And Mrs. Bernard Grogan."
"Welcome home, Michael Powers."
"Samuel Nathan"?
I never heard of him.
Nails Nathan. One of Tom's new friends.
What's Tom doing now, Pat?
Mother said something
about a political job.
Yeah? And that ain't all.
He and Matt have been running around...
with a couple of girls
at the Washington Arms Hotel.
Now, the worst part of it all
is that he's been lying to his mother.
He's leaving her think
that he's made an honest success.
Why, sure it's only a question of time
when he's going to be caught.
And then he'll be
after breaking her poor heart.
But what's he doing?
Beer. Bootleg.
He's one of Paddy Ryan's gang.
But that's not all.
Sure, they stop at nothing.
You either take their beer,
or they put you on the spot.
I tell you, Michael, it is a wicked business.
Why, only last week...
- Got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
That's nice of you, Tommy...
but I don't think
Mike will be able to drink any.
It's the best beer in town.
It'll do him good.
Dinner's all ready, Michael.
- Shall I help you in?
- No, Mother. I can make it.
I'll be getting along. I'll see you all later.
Bye-bye.
How's the meat, Mikey?
Fine, Ma.
I wish you'd eat more.
Try some of this cabbage.
I've had plenty, Ma.
Say, we haven't drunk to your health yet.
This is a swell celebration.
There you are, Mike.
- That's enough for you, Ma.
- Put a head on that, will you?
Miss Powers.
Well, here's to you, Mike.
Why don't you drink, Mike?
Come on, it's only beer.
I don't want any, Matt.
What's eating you?
I'm not interfering with your drinking.
if you want to drink it, go on.
if I don't want to, I don't have to.
So beer ain't good enough for you?
You think I'd care
if it was just beer in that keg?
I know what's in it.
I know what you've been doing...
how you got those clothes
and those new cars.
You've been telling Ma you're in politics,
that you're on the city payroll.
Pat Burke told me everything.
You murderers!
There's not only beer in that keg,
there's beer and blood.
The blood of men!
You ain't changed a bit.
Besides, your hands ain't so clean.
You killed and liked it.
You didn't get them medals
for holding hands with Germans.
Please, he ain't himself.
He don't know what he's talking about.
This trip's been too much
for the poor soul.
Lord have pity on him.
Please, Tommy.
Come on, Matt. Let's get out of here
before I go screwy, too.
Don't go away, Tommy. Don't be angry.
You can send my clothes
to the Washington Arms Hotel.
Get up, lazybones.
What are you gonna do, sleep all day?
Button up. I can sleep as long as I like.
That's a fine way to talk to me
after I cooked this lovely breakfast for you.
With my own lily-white hands.
Lake View 8515. Right.
- Hello?
- Hello, is Tom there?
I just called his apartment. They said
he stepped across the hall for breakfast.
Nails Nathan.
Just a minute. Tom, it's for you.
- Who is it?
- Nails Nathan.
- Hello, kid.
- Hello, Tom.
- What's the matter, kid?
- Nothing.
Only the dame's beginning
to get on my nerves, that's all.
Listen, I'm getting fed up
on these rubber checks bouncing in.
We're laying down good beer and
getting nothing but a lot of bum paper.
I got one this morning for $1,200
from that Pete over on Kedzie Avenue.
Get over there. I want that dough.
Cash or his heart.
if you can't bring in one, bring in the other.
I'll bring you both. Leave it to me, kid.
All right.
Come on in, Matt. Shake a leg.
Nails wants us to do him a favor.
In a minute.
It's all ready, Tom.
- Ain't you got a drink in the house?
- Not before breakfast, dear.
I didn't ask you for any lip.
- I asked you if you got a drink.
- I know, Tom...
- but I wish—
- There you go with that "wishing" stuff.
I wish you was a wishing well...
so that I could tie a bucket to you
and sink you.
Maybe you found someone you like better.
How goes it, babe?
- Going south?
- Yes.
But I'm not accustomed
to riding with strangers.
We're not going to be strangers.
- How far are you going?
- Pretty far. Near Jackson Park.
- Is that out of your way?
- No.
My chauffeur's just crazy
about long drives.
Step on it, James.
Well, do I look good to you?
- You sure do.
- I feel flattered.
You know,
you're not the worst I've seen, either.
- From Chicago?
- Not exactly. I came from Texas.
- Where you living?
- The Congress Hotel.
if you're a stranger here,
Tom and me will show you the town.
Stick to your driving, mug.
Say, you can let me off here.
I'm going to meet my friends
on the corner.
Could I see you again later?
I'd be happy to have you
call me sometime.
I mean, later today.
I'll think it over. Give me
your phone number and I'll call you.
All right, babe. Yards 3771.
I'll remember it.
And in the meantime, thanks.
- My name is Gwen. Gwen Allen.
- And mine's Tom Powers.
- Yeah, and mine is Matt.
- He ain't got a name, just a number.
She's a honey. I could go for her myself.
What do you mean,
you could go for her yourself?
You could go for
an 80-year-old chick with rheumatism.
When are you going to see her?
- She's going to call me.
- Find out if she's got a friend.
What do you want with her friend?
You got Mamie, ain't you?
Ain't you going to kiss your little baby?
- You got Kitty, ain't you?
- I ain't going to have her much longer.
I'm fed up. You can tell her so for me.
Step on the gas, will you?
Max, George, quick.
Delighted to see you, Mr. Nathan.
- How are you, Joe?
- Fine, thank you.
Where would you like to sit?
Where do I always sit?
Right at the ringside.
- May be full up there.
- We can fix that, sir.
Max, George, fix a table immediately
at the railing for Mr. Nathan.
Great. The best is none too good tonight.
This is a wedding celebration.
- Really?
- Yep.
Matt's decided
to take something lawful: a wife.
- That's something to celebrate about.
- I should say so.
- Meet Mr. and Mrs. Doyle.
- We're honored, I assure you.
- Let's dance while they're fixing the tables.
- This way, please.
- Hiya, Nails.
- Hello, Tom.
- How are you, Mr. Nathan?
- Harry, making money?
- Right this way, please.
- Hello, Jim. How are you?
- Are you as happy as I am, Matt?
- Sure, honey.
You fellows don't know what it means
to a girl, getting married.
You knew all the time
I was going to marry you, didn't you?
Of course I did.
I was just thinking of Tom and Kitty.
Well, they're different.
I guess Tom ain't the marrying kind.
No, I guess not.
Are you sure that was old Putty Nose?
- I ought to know him when I see him.
- Sure you know him.
I suppose you'd like
to put in with him again.
That's the Fagin that
put something over on you, ain't it?
I had to laugh when I heard about that.
That guy's going to get you again.
He thinks you're soft.
- He ain't going to get me.
- We don't want any part of him.
I haven't got a thing to say, boys.
But they got the lndian sign on you, Tom.
- He thinks you're a cinch.
- In a pig's eye.
That McGonagall ain't got a chance.
Take care of the women, Nails.
You're not going out
in the cold, dark night, are you?
Nails will see that you get home.
We got a little job to do.
Come on, Matt.
You're not gonna leave me tonight, Matt?
There's something we forgot to do, honey.
I'll be home later.
Come on.
Where's he going?
They're just walking around the block
to cool themselves off.
What are you worrying about? Sit down.
Have it ready at 8:00. Fill it with gas.
I'm going on a long trip.
Well, if it ain't Tom Powers and Matt, too.
How are you, boys?
- Been out of town?
- Yeah, I was down home, visiting.
- Got a little drink for us, Putty?
- Sure, Tom.
But I can't let you in just now.
You see, I've got a Jane inside.
I'll bring it right out to you.
Wait a minute, Putty Nose.
- We got words for you.
- What's up, Tom?
We got a little business to settle,
Jane or no Jane.
You ain't sore, are you, Tom?
I've always been your friend.
Sure. You taught us how to cheat,
steal, and kill. Then you lammed out on us.
if it hadn't been for you,
we might have been on the level.
Sure. We might have been
ding-dings on a streetcar.
Come on.
A Jane, huh?
There ain't no one here but him.
I thought so.
Why, you dirty, double-crossing...
What are you squawking about?
You got plenty more coming.
What are you gonna do?
I don't want to die.
So you don't want to die?
Tommy, don't you remember
you and Matt...
how you used to be just kids
and how we were friends?
You won't let him, Matt.
I'll do anything for you from now on.
Ain't you got a heart, Matty boy?
Don't you remember
how I used to play to you?
And didn't I always stick up for you?
I ain't got this coming.
Please, Matt, don't let him.
I ain't a bad fellow, really.
Tommy, don't. Ain't you got a heart?
Tell me you won't let him, Matt, will you?
You remember that song I used to sing?
That song I taught you?
You remember, Tommy.
Back in the club,
how you kids used to laugh at that song.
Guess I'll call up Gwen.
She ought to be home by now.
Let me make you a cup of tea.
I got to be getting back on the job
in a minute.
My, but it's good to see you again.
I was beginning to think I'd lost you.
You can't lose me that easy.
Poor Michael.
I'm afraid he's working himself
into an early grave.
Days on the cars, school at night,
and studying in between.
Listen, Ma,
I came over to give you something.
Here, take this.
When you need more, just say so.
I'm making plenty.
You're a good boy, Tommy, but I can't.
- Take it.
- Mike wouldn't like it.
- Mike ain't got nothing to say about it.
- No?
Listen to me.
I've got something important to say.
Keep it to yourself.
Nobody wants your two cents.
I don't want you two boys fighting.
It ain't right for two brothers.
There won't be fighting.
Only, I don't need his preaching.
- What is this, Ma?
- Tommy gave it to me to buy some things.
- Ain't that nice of him?
- It's more than you can do.
We don't want your money.
I'll look after Ma.
- On two bits a week?
- Ma don't drink champagne.
How do you know?
I used to dance when I was a girl.
I won't argue with you, and
I can't tell you all I'd like to in front of Ma.
But get an earful of this:
You ain't welcome in this house.
That's blood money. We want no part of it.
- Hiding behind Ma's skirts, like always.
- Better than hiding behind a machine gun.
You're too smart.
- I'm going, Ma.
- And don't forget your change.
- Money don't mean nothing to me.
- No, I guess not.
But with no heart or brains,
it's all you've got. You'll need it.
Why you sneaking, stooling...
Michael, why did you hit him?
I may leave town next week.
You don't care, do you?
When I first met you,
I sort of figured you was on the make.
Not much. You know what I mean.
And besides that...
I figured you was sort of different, too.
That is, different from the kind of girls
I was used to.
I don't go in for these long-winded things,
but with me, it was always yes or no.
And I could never figure you out.
- Now can you?
- No.
But I guess I ain't your kind.
- I think I better call it quits.
- Don't be like that, Tommy...
because I "go for you," as you say.
Maybe too much.
You know, all my friends...
think that things are different between us
than they are.
They figure they know me pretty well...
and don't think I'd go
for a merry-go-round.
Do you think
I'm giving you a merry-go-round?
- No, l—
- Then do you want things to be different...
to please your boyfriends?
No, but how long can a guy hold out?
I'm gonna go screwy.
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna blow.
You're a spoiled boy, Tommy.
You want things,
and you're not content until you get them.
Or maybe I'm spoiled, too.
Maybe I feel that way, too.
But you're not running away from me.
Come here.
Now you stay put,
if you know what that means.
My bashful boy.
You are different, Tommy.
Very different.
And I've discovered
it isn't only a difference in manner...
and outward appearances.
It's a difference in basic character.
The men I know...
and I've known dozens of them...
they're so nice...
so polished, so considerate.
Most women like that type.
I guess they're afraid of the other kind.
I thought I was, too.
But you're so strong.
You don't give, you take.
Tommy, I could love you to death.
Oh, nuts.
ls Tom here?
Nails is dead.
- Who killed him?
- Nobody. His horse.
He was thrown off in the park,
kicked in the head.
- You got that horse that killed Nails?
- You mean Rajah?
He bad animal. Terrible.
Yeah, what's he worth?
Spirited horse.
I told Mr. Nathan not to ride him.
What's he worth?
He could be bought for $1,000.
You see, it's—
- Never mind. Here.
- Where's he at?
Stall Number 3.
Stay where you are.
Right now, we ain't got a chance.
Since Nails has gone, his mob has
scattered. They're ten-to-one against us.
Look at this dump.
Four pineapples tossed at us in two days,
and the brewery set fire.
I'm telling you, they got us on the run.
- Not me. I ain't running. I ain't yellow.
- Who said you was?
I ain't talking about that.
I'm gonna need you.
And you won't be no good to me
when you're in the cemetery.
I got to have a couple of days
to get the boys lined up again.
While I'm doing that...
you'll be where nobody knows
where to find you except me.
Come on, give me your guns
and your money. All of it.
- What are you trying to pull, Paddy?
- I'm gonna keep you off the streets.
Even you wouldn't be sap enough
to go for a stroll without your gat.
Come on, shower down.
All of it.
You got a phone here, Jane?
I'm gonna call Gwen.
No, you keep away from that phone.
I'll call from outside and tell her
I sent you out of town for a few days.
- And ring up Mamie, will you?
- Leave it to me.
This won't be for long, boys.
I'll have the mob lined up again
in a couple of days.
You'll see that they're comfortable?
- You leave that to me, Paddy.
- Okay.
Gather round, boys.
We're going to be a happy, little family.
I hope you got plenty of this medicine.
Yards 6321.
Hello.
ls Schemer there?
Let me make you another drink, Tommy.
You mean to say
you got any of that stuff left?
You haven't drank so much.
I can drink it as long as you can pour it.
Only a coal truck.
Had me going for a minute.
- Come on, get in the game, will you, Tom?
- No.
I'm gonna hit the hay.
I thought you'd like a little nightcap.
You don't need to feel ashamed
in front of me.
Here, let me help you.
- I don't need any help.
- Be a good boy and sit down.
I'll take your shoes off, too.
I want to do things for you, Tommy.
You don't think I'm old, do you?
- No.
- You like me, don't you?
Sure.
What's the idea?
Just a goodnight kiss for a fine boy.
In your hat.
Get away from me.
You're Paddy Ryan's girl.
- Breakfast is all ready, Tommy.
- I ain't hungry.
Give me some coffee, will you?
And make it black.
You aren't sorry, are you?
- Sorry for what?
- For last night.
What do you mean, for getting drunk?
Aren't you the little playactor?
Wait a minute.
Do you mean that—
Why, you...
- Tom, where you going?
- Home.
- But Paddy—
- I don't care what Paddy said!
I'm getting out of this dump.
Hey, Tom, wait a minute.
- What happened?
- Nothing. I just got burned up, that's all.
What do you wanna run out on me for?
We're together, ain't we?
Sure.
Yes, sir?
I was looking at some of the pistols
in the window.
- Shall I show you some?
- Yeah.
- I kind of like that big one.
- That one? All right.
- What do you call that?
- That's a.38 caliber. It's a fine—
You got any more like it?
- I've got some smaller ones.
- No, same size.
Sure.
- How do you load that?
- First you break it.
Then you stick the cartridges in the holes.
- Could I see?
- Sure.
- That's right.
- Like that?
- It'll hold six.
- This will be enough.
Stick them up.
Okay, Schemer, it's all set.
I ain't so tough.
- Well, Doc, what do you think?
- Can't say.
We'll hope for the best.
Doctor, this is Tom's mother, brother,
and Miss Doyle.
You can go in for a few moments,
Mrs. Powers.
Thank you, sir.
Tommy boy.
Do you know me?
Sure, Ma.
Mike's here.
He's come to see you.
- Hello, Mike.
- How are you, Tom, old scuff?
I've been wanting to see you.
You're gonna be seeing a lot of me, Tom.
There's something
I wanted to say to you, Mike.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry for what?
I'm just sorry.
You know.
You and Mike
are going to be friends again?
Sure.
Friends.
Boys, I'm so happy.
So happy.
Ma, you must like Mike
a lot better than me.
No, Tommy boy. You're my baby.
Sure.
I'm your baby.
You're coming home, ain't you, Tommy?
To stay?
Sure.
Coming home.
I mean, if I can ever get out of here.
You're gonna get out of here, all right.
Why, of course you are.
You're going to get well and strong.
Both my boys back.
All of us together again.
I'm almost glad this happened.
And he really looked better today,
did he, Michael?
Sure, Ma, a lot better. He was sitting up.
I told him you'd be in
to see him tomorrow.
- And he'll be coming home soon, won't he?
- Sure, Ma.
Paddy, come in.
What's wrong? ls Tom—
They kidnapped him
from the hospital this afternoon.
What? Who did?
Must have been the Burns mob.
First they give it to him in the back,
then they take him when he's helpless.
Who knows
what they're doing to him now.
- They ain't gonna get away with this.
- I'm doing all I can.
My boys are out in the street now.
I'll bring Tom back,
if it's the last thing I do.
- I'm gonna—
- You're gonna...
stay here at that phone
and take messages.
I told my boys to call you up
if they find anything.
- I'd like to smash—
- Listen...
I sent word to Burns that
if he'd bring Tom back here tonight...
I'd quit the racket.
He could have it all.
I'd leave town and I won't come back.
- You think they'll do it?
- It's a sweet offer.
You stay here.
if you hear anything
from any one of my boys...
call me at my place.
I got to get back on the job.
Don't you like your dinner?
Why, I just ain't hungry, Ma.
I'll get it, Ma.
This is Mike.
When? You are?
Fine. Ma, they're bringing Tom home.
- They are? When?
- Right now. He's on his way.
- Is he all right?
- He must be.
- They wouldn't be bringing him home.
- It's wonderful.
I'll get his room ready.
I knew my baby would come home.
- Who called?
- One of Paddy's boys. Didn't say who.
- Molly dear?
- Yes, Mother?
Bring up some clean sheets
out of the linen closet.
- Hurry, dear.
- All right.