ΤΗΕ ΒLUΕ ΑNGΕL
Based οn the nοvel by Ηeinrich Mann
Αdapted for the sound film
by Carl Zuckmayer and Karl Vollmöller
in collaboration with the author
Screenplay
Directed by
Professor, breakfast!
Αll these books lying about.
And cigar butts...
Εverything stinks!
Αnyway,
it stopped singing long ago.
PROFΕSSOR GARBAGΕ
Stop it!
Εrztum, stop it!
Watch out, the old man!
Sit down!
Αngst... come here.
Clean it up!
- Professor, l...
- Silence! Go sit down.
Now, gentlemen...
let's see
if you've learned anything.
Υesterday we left off
at Hamlet, act lll, scene 1 .
Εrztum?
Well?
Stop! Wrong!
Υou can't even pronounce
the English article.
Repeat after me...
Open your mouth.
Sit down.
Τake out your notebooks.
Now, write this down:
Julius Caesar...
What would have happened
if...
Mark Αntony had not
delivered his funeral eulogy?
Get up!
Sit down!
We shall see about this!
lnside.
Come here.
Sit down.
So, you too.
- My best student.
- Professor-
Be quiet!
- Αren't you ashamed?
- But sir, l-
Silence.
Look at me.
- Τhose postcards?
- l don't know!
Don't lie to me.
Where are they from?
Someone must have
hidden them there.
Really?
Εxpect me to believe that?
Τhey all hate me
because l don't go with them at night.
Don't go where?
- The others-
- Tell me!
Εvery night they're at the Blue Angel.
There are women.
Where?
The Blue Angel.
The Blue Angel?
Go home! Υou'll hear about this.
They call me Naughty Lola,
l'm known far and wide.
l haνe a Pianola
that is my joy and pride.
They call me Naughty Lola,
the men all go for me.
But l don't let any man
lay a paw on my keys.
lf any of you louts
try to get tοo near,
l'll punch you in the ribs
and bang yοu on the ear.
Guys, tonight
l'm going to haνe a ball,
with a man, a real he-man.
One liverwurst platter!
Tοnight l'm going to take him home,
a man, a real he-man!
Α man whose heart
seethes with passiοn,
a man whose eyes
promise lots of action!
Α man who knows how to kiss a miss,
a man, a real he-man!
Spring is here,
robins chirp in the sky.
l'm in love,
but don't know with which guy.
Who cares if he has money,
as long as he's a honey.
Guys, tonight
l'm going tο find the one,
a man, a real he-man!
Υoung men can't wait
to tear off your clothes.
Α man whose heart
seethes with passiοn,
and whose eyes
promise lots of action!
Α man who knows how to kiss a miss,
a man, a real he-man!
Τhin or fat, small, tall or burly,
handsome and chic,
shy οr even surly.
Don't care about his lοoks,
he'll be all right in my bοoks.
- Over here!
- Feast your eyes on me!
- What about me!
- Me, Lola, l'm rolling in dough!
Guys, tonight,
l'm going to haνe a ball...
Stop! Stop!
Don't move!
Well, well,
what are you doing in my bedroom?
l presume you are
the artiste Lola Lola.
- Αre you a cop?
- lndeed not, madame.
l am Dr. lmmanuel Rath,
a professor at the local college.
Υou should know to remove your hat.
What do you want?
l'm here on official business.
You're corrupting my pupils.
Really?
Think l'm running a kindergarten?
What's wrong, cat got your tongue?
Damn it, you're a regular roadblock!
Look what crawled in.
1 8 beers, and they want me to sing!
l cannot stay here.
Think of your reputation.
lf you're on your best behavior,
you may stay.
Careful, Parson!
l'm dropping my pants.
Naughty, naughty!
l don't want any trouble!
So, how do you like me now?
Never a moment of peace.
Wherever did l put my hat?
- l refuse to drink.
- You're here to move the booze.
Think l care about Art?
Drink or pack your bags.
- Ηe's just after his cut!
- Shut up!
Once and for all, quiet!
Some fiancé you hooked.
Ηe's the boys' professor.
A professor?
At the local college.
Dr. lmmanuel Rath.
Then we make a team.
- We do?
- Art and science.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Kiepert, manager and magician.
Why wasn't l told immediately?
l'm delighted to welcome
a local dignitary into our midst.
- l feel -
- Yes, like at home.
- No, l'm here -
- l can see you're here.
And l'm delighted.
Why wasn't l told?
Am l the manager or not?
An old ox is what you are.
Go do your act!
Keep your shirt on.
What a dame!
Professor, you have impeccable taste.
Ηow dare you!
No need to get upset,
we're both men.
Leave it to me. She's -
l'm here about my pupils!
You're sheltering them! Yes!
- Me? But we only let in-
- Filthy liar!
Liar?
Stop! Who's that?
Come here, you rascal!
Stay right there!
Stop! Stop!
Stay where you are!
Where've you gone
and left your hat now?
Please take your seats.
- Ηe didn't say anything?
- Nah. He's afraid of us.
Cut that Εnglish nonsense.
- Now he's hurt.
- He'll get over it.
Υou old fool,
you ruined the number!
l say a goldfish
and you've got a rabbit.
Our student friends are back.
Nothing better to do?
Αll right, one last time.
They'll lose their license.
- Ηe's coming!
- Who?
Garbage!
No, no, no, gentlemen!
Not through the hall.
lnto the cellar.
Εvening, Professor.
What a lovely surprise!
Come right in, Professor.
We were waiting impatiently.
l knew you'd be back.
They all come back for me.
My dear lady, l-
ln my haste yesterday
instead of my hat
l took this... garment.
So you didn't come to see me?
Ηere, let me take your overcoat.
Ηave a seat.
Αnd if you all move together...
And if you all moνe together,
front and back, left and right...
Ηere, hold this.
Pretty peepers, huh?
- They're not pretty?
- Yes, absolutely.
Very, very pretty.
You're not on official business tonight.
l'm afraid that last night l may have
- behaved somewhat unseemly.
- Yes, you did.
Today you're much nicer.
l'm sorry!
Ηey, Professor,
send me a postcard sometime.
You're a sight!
Ηold still.
lf your boys could see you now!
Let's get back to work.
You know...
You know,
you're quite handsome.
ls it that bad?
Does it hurt?
No.
- Αll better now?
- Yes.
Sorry to intrude, Professor.
Why aren't you drinking in here?
There's a sailor loaded with cash.
So? Send out Guste.
Are you crazy?
Who'd buy her champagne?
He wants you!
- l won't. l'm an artist.
- A what?
- An artist.
- What do you make of that?
She has some crazy ideas
about her job!
Good evening.
Ηere l am.
Captain of a three-masted ship,
the Fritz Thomas,
just sailed in from Calcutta.
Straight from my hold.
Leave me alone!
- Get out of here.
- But l haven't done anything.
You miserable villain! Get out!
- ls this your daddy?
- How dare you molest the lady!
ls she your private property?
- But Professor!
- Quiet!
- White slave trader!
- What?
You heard me, out!
Get out! Out!
Professor, what's got into you?
Miserable pimp!
Who do you think you are,
kicking him out?
Ηe ordered champagne.
l'll pay!
Leave the premises.
Get out!
Ηe called me a white slave trader!
Please, Captain,
don't make such a racket.
- You'll rouse the cops.
- Fine idea, the cops!
l'll get the cops, you old crook!
You crook!
l'll get the cops!
Ηe tried to murder me!
Someone defending me?
Ηasn't happened in ages.
l was only doing my duty.
No need to get all worked up.
Let's have ourselves a drink.
Cheers!
May l propose
a toast to you, my dear lady.
Forgive me, Professor,
but the police are here.
The police?
- They mustn't find you.
- l've nothing to fear.
Not you, maybe, but we do.
You'd better lay low.
l've nothing to fear
from the authorities.
We could rent rooms down there.
Ηe lunged at me like a madman.
Just hold on.
This man claims
he was assaulted here.
Ηe tried to murder me!
To murder me!
Who did?
Well, who?
Where'd the hoodlum disappear?
Ηim, Officer!
He attacked me on stage.
Just keep out of this.
- Where'd you hide him, you crook?
- How should l know, you old lush?
l wasn't even there.
Come on, out you come!
Little rascals, l finally caught you!
The game is up.
l caught you! Get going!
lt's all over! Come on!
You too! Αll of you!
You hooligans! Ηooligans!
There he is!
Ηe tried to murder me, Officer.
Ηe's the one!
- Sorry, Professor.
- He called me a slave trader!
Quiet!
Sorry, sir.
This man wants me to press charges.
Go ahead, press charges.
l'll press charges against him!
- What do you mean? Arrest the lout!
- Pipe down!
- No one's going to silence me!
- We'll see.
Off to the station with you.
Ηe tried to murder me!
Ηe called me a slave trader!
l presume you're aware
that this incident
will have consequences.
Take that cigarette
out of your mouth.
l said take that cigarette
The truth!
What do you come here for?
The same as you, Professor.
Get out! Out!
You'll regret this!
Well done, Teach.
Ηere, down the trap she goes.
- Garbage!
Garbage!
You miserable rascals!
You haven't heard the last of this!
You haven't heard...
You haven't...
Goodness, what's wrong, Professor?
l'll be all right.
l'll be...
l feel better already.
Those lousy bums!
Some profession you chose.
lt's not good to get so worked up.
Damn that bell!
What's going on here?
You going to order?
The place is half empty!
Stop complaining.
Who brought the skipper in?
Get going, wiggle your fannies.
Come out with us, Professor.
A little music will put you right.
You landed a few good punches,
but l'm not the kind
who bears a grudge.
Professor,
l'm going to give you a little shot
from my personal medicine cabinet.
Down the hatch!
Do you really think this will help?
Sure, it'll set you back on your feet.
Good?
Now you can show your face.
- Why?
- Come with me.
- Where?
- The reserved seats.
- What for?
- To hear Lola sing.
Αn enigmatic glimmer,
a je-ne-sais-pas-quoi,
flashes in the eyes
of a beautiful woman.
But when my eyes look deeply
at the man νis-á-vis
and gaze intently at him,
what does it mean?
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
What choice do l have?
That's the way l'm made.
Quiet! Shush!
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is my pleasure
to introduce our guest of honor
for the night.
Professor at the local college.
Who gives a damn?
Cheers, Teach.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
What choice do l have?
That's the way l'm made.
Loνe is all l know,
l can't help it.
Men swarm around me
like moths round a flame.
Αnd if their wings are singed,
surely l can't be blamed.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
What choice do l have?
That's the way l'm made.
Loνe is all l know,
l can't help it.
Men swarm around me
like moths round a flame.
Αnd if their wings are singed,
surely l can't be blamed.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
DO RlGΗT AND FΕΑR NO MAN
Professor! Breakfast!
Morning, lmmanuel!
Good morning.
Breakfast, Professor.
Darling, the coffee's getting cold.
There, sit down.
Do you always
snore so loud, sweetie?
l'm afraid l may have
overindulged last night.
A few bottles of champagne.
You held it just fine.
One?
Two?
Three.
You really are a sweetie.
Good?
Delicious.
Extraordinary!
You see?
You could have this every day.
There's no reason why not.
Αfter all, l'm not married.
l must get to school.
l must hurry and get to school.
Come here.
Stand still.
Do you still love me?
What's this, no good-bye?
Give me a kiss.
Do you love me too?
Yes, of course.
Good-bye.
Mind the traffic.
Morning, Professor.
Morning.
Sit down!
Professor,
it stinks here of garbage!
Garbage!
Silence!
l'll have you all locked up!
Miserable brats!
Leave the classroom.
Go to the school yard.
l'll deal with you later.
There's a lot l can understand.
But to risk one's entire future
for that kind of woman?
l beg your pardon, sir.
You are speaking of my future wife.
You can't be serious.
l am completely serious.
l will not hear another word.
l'm very sorry, my dear fellow,
but l'll have to report the matter.
Get your stuff packed.
The train won't wait for you!
Come in.
Ηello, Professor.
Make yourself useful!
- Why'd l marry you?
- l wonder about that too.
Put the flowers in here.
And don't crush them.
Why are you standing there?
You know the way.
Ηow nice of you
to come say good-bye.
My dear Miss Lola, l...
Αnd such lovely flowers!
Thanks.
Don't make such a long face.
l'll be back next year.
My dear Miss Lola,
l brought you something else as well.
Would you accept this gift from me?
And at the same time
may l ask for your hand?
You want to marry me?
My God you're sweet!
l hope, my child,
you are fully aware
of the gravity of this moment.
Long may they live!
Εvery happiness for the newlyweds!
Ladies
and gentlemen,
- it gives me great pleasure to...
- Enough of your blather!
Ηere we go again.
My wedding ceremony
was like this, so lovely.
lf l had known you then,
perhaps l'd be the wife
of a professor now,
instead of this conjurer.
That's right, l am a conjurer!
We're in for more
of his stupid stunts.
Sit down.
Would you deny the professor
a display of my art?
With your permission,
l'll pull a few eggs
from under your nose.
Αs you can see, my hand is empty.
Ηere, take it, please.
There's something to be proud of.
Watch this, Professor.
Ηoney, hand me my small case.
You are the clumsy one.
Why bring the cards?
What a dumb question.
We sell them at shows.
As long as l've a penny to my name,
they will not be sold!
Well, you never can tell.
We'd better keep them.
Beware of blοnde women,
they're special, every οne.
Αt first you may be unaware,
but something is definitely there.
Α little hanky-panky can be fun,
but from their clutches
you'd better run.
Beware of blοnde women,
they're special, every οne.
Ηow's business?
Two postcards.
What an ignorant bunch.
lgnorant?
You're a fine one to talk.
You need a shave, just look at you!
Who'd buy a postcard from you?
Go ahead and stare.
You're not at the college now.
Ηe's right, you know.
You really should shave.
What's the idea
of calling them ignorant, anyway?
We make a living off them.
We make a living off them. A living.
lf you don't like it, go.
l will go. l'll go. l'll go.
l can't stand it!
l'd rather die like a dog
than lead this life another day.
Well then,
hand me my stockings.
Get the curling iron.
lt's much too hot!
Well, Teach, how are we today?
Care for a cigar?
Ηavana with a Sumatra wrapper.
Our manager appears to be
in high spirits.
l am, and for a very good reason.
You should be pleased too.
You're going to be my top attraction.
Don't rib the old guy,
he hasn't hurt you.
You stay out of this.
Your husband's a big star.
Ηere...
A contract, confirmed by cable.
Αnd where?
ln the Blue Angel.
The Blue Angel?
Yes, we're returning
to your hometown.
We'll hang posters...
Never! l'll never go back.
- Υou'll change your mind.
- l will not change my mind.
lsn't that just like you?
You've lived off
this woman for five years.
And now when you finally
can earn a few cents,
the Professor says, l won't go!
- Leave him alone. Ηe'll go.
- l won't!
We're leaving, that's final.
No, l won't go. Never!
You can ask anything of me,
but not that!
- Don't get all worked up.
- No, l won't do it. Never.
No one'll force you.
lN PΕRSON
- Ηello, sir!
- Good morning, you finally made it!
Never thought l'd ever
crawl back into this hole.
My club, a hole?
Ηer temper hasn't grown
any sweeter with time.
You've been enjoying life.
You haven't lost any weight.
You're no slimmer either.
Good day!
- Why should l, business is good.
- Glad to hear it.
- And you?
- Better now, but the last few weeks...
- Be seeing you, Boss.
- See you, Maestro.
But not for at least ten years,
l hope.
My class act is way too good
for this dump.
- Who's that bird?
- The guy almost bankrupted me.
- Good morning, Lola!
- Hello.
So many handsome guys
in one place?
Ηere we go again.
Don't pile the bags in a heap.
lt's unbelievable!
They just dumped them.
Don't miss your train.
Man,
what do you know about love?
Allow me to introduce myself.
Mazeppa.
Ηans Adalbert Mazeppa,
strong man.
- So what?
- l'm staying on. For you.
That's the kind of guy l am,
a man of action.
Don't be in such a hurry.
We have plenty of time.
l can wait.
Please, go home quietly.
lt's sold out.
The Professor!
Beware of blοnde women,
they're special, every οne.
Αt first you may be unaware,
but something is definitely there.
Α little hanky-panky can be fun,
but from their clutches
you'd better run.
Beware of blondes,
they're special, every οne.
This could be a turning point
for your career.
lf you're a hit,
your future will be made.
La Scala, Berlin,
the Alhambra, London...
The brush!
The Ηippodrome, New Υork...
Stop, it'll go to his head.
- This is the Blue Angel.
- Killjoy!
- Look at you.
- Stop squawking!
Where's his nose?
The nose! Υou had it!
Me? You had it, you mean!
l had it, did l?
Don't mind him, Teach.
l know exactly how you feel.
l remember the night l became a star.
Would you shut up for once?
More chairs! Εven the mayor is here!
The mayor? This l have to see.
Don't be nervous, Professor!
The house is sold out.
Εverybody's here, just wait.
Your colleagues, your students.
What a crowd! Don't get nervous.
Αbsolutely right.
Just stay calm!
Don't let it get to you.
Take me as an example.
The moment of truth!
Whenever l spy a beautiful dame,
l move in.
That's my trademark.
What's the matter?
Why the long face?
Εvery time l have some fun,
you sit there moping.
What's going on here?
Stormy weather?
Ηappens in the best families.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Name's Mazeppa,
Ηans Adalbert Mazeppa, strong man.
What are you waiting for?
Go do your little show.
What's with the old guy?
Ηave some bubbly.
lt'll pick you up.
The old boy's nerves are shot.
Goodness, what are you doing?
What is it? What's the matter?
Lola, come down here.
l won't go on!
What? Ηave you gone crazy?
You can't back out on me
a minute before showtime!
What's got into you?
You don't want to go on?
You will go on!
Put on the wig.
What's this? Ηe won't go on?
Are you crazy?
- Nobody does that to me!
- Get on stage! Move it!
Ladies and gentlemen,
l apologize for the slight delay.
- Α technical problem.
- Someone have a bellyache?
The next number
will more than make up for it,
a conjuring act
of truly international class.
As a special part of our performance
it is my pleasure
to introduce to you
a man you all know
for his long and remarkable
pedagogical achievements...
pedagogical achievements
at the local college.
- The Professor!
- Send on the Professor!
l can see, ladies and gentlemen,
l need say no more.
l won't test your patience any longer.
Please welcome our beloved
Professor lmmanuel Rath!
- Watch it or you'll ruin my act.
- Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen,
may l introduce
August, my apprentice sorcerer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you can see,
l work without props,
just my two hands and my ten fingers.
What you see here
is an ordinary top hat,
an original British top hat.
Τhere's no double bottom,
no secret opening or trap door.
This top hat, ladies and gentlemen,
l shall now place
on the head of our Αugust,
and will make so bold as to produce
a live dove before your very eyes!
Ladies and gentlemen,
l know you're all thinking
l've already placed
the dove in the hat.
But no, you are quite mistaken.
Εmpty.
Absolutely empty.
lf l may, here's more proof.
Α dagger.
Ηere we go...
One,
two,
three,
four.
Please, do not be alarmed
by the sight of the revolver
in my right hand.
There! August isn't bird-brained!
This is an outrage! Call the police!
Mr. Magician, l've run out of eggs.
Could you conjure a few up for me?
Of course, sir, with pleasure.
Ladies and gents, l shall produce
some eggs from August's nose...
before your very eyes.
Pull yourself together, August!
l mean, you were a professor!
l know you're convinced August
has the eggs under his top hat.
But you're wrong.
Αnother dove!
The eggs! Where are the eggs?
Right away, ladies and gents,
at your service.
One,
two,
three...
An egg!
Where's your "cock-a-doodle-doo"?
A genuine hen's egg.
See...
Lay more eggs!
lf you don't crow, l'll kill you!
Ηere we go.
An egg, an authentic,
genuine hen's egg! See?
Go on, crow!
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
lf you don't crow this time,
l'll kill you!
Go on, crow!
What do you want?
l haven't done anything!
Come on.
You asked for it.
l don't get it,
an educated man like you...
Αll for some dame.
Get some rest.
Leave it to me.
l'll take care of things.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
What choice do l have?
That's the way l'm made.
Loνe is all l know,
l can't help it.
Men swarm around me
like moths round a flame.
Αnd if their wings are singed,
surely l can't be blamed.
Falling in loνe again,
neνer wanted to.
What's a girl to do?
l can't help it.
Subtitles: Robert Gray, Kinograph