Bring out Elizabeth Selwyn.
Bring out the witch!
Bring her out! Bring her out!
Witch!
Burn the witch! Burn the witch!
Burn the witch!
Jeth row! Jeth row!
Jeth row!
Jethrow Keane, hast thou consorted
with the witch, Elizabeth Selwyn?
No.
Burn the witch!
No! No!
Please!
No!
No! No! No! No! No!
Help her, O Lucifer, help her.
Elizabeth Selwyn...
on this third day of March,
in the year of our Lord, 1692...
we, the people of Whitewood,
Massachusetts,
condemn thee as a witch.
May the flames
cleanse thy soul of its evil.
Of its lust for blood
that made thee bring about the death
of Abigail Adams.
Help her, Lucifer, help her!
I have made my pact with thee,
O Lucifer. Hear me!
Hear me!
I will do thy bidding for all eternity.
For all eternity shall I practise
the ritual of Black Mass.
- Lucifer.
- For eternity shall I sacrifice unto thee.
I can feel my soul
taking me to thy service.
O Lucifer, listen to thy servant.
Grant her this pact for all eternity,
and I with her,
and if we fail thee but once,
you may do with our souls what you will.
Make this city an example
of thy vengeance.
Curse it.
- Curse it for all eternity.
- Curse?
And let me be
the instrument of thy curse.
Hear me, O Lucifer.
Hear me!
She's making a curse.
Curse?
Burn her! Burn her!
Burn the witch! Burn the witch!
Burn the witch!
Burn! Burn her!
Burn the witch! Burn the witch!
Burn the witch!
"Burn, witch! Burn, witch!
Burn, burn, burn!"
So shouted the people of Whitewood when
they burnt Elizabeth Selwyn in 1692.
Little is known today
of the actual practices of witchcraft
in 17th century New England.
Superstition, fear and jealousy
drove the puritans
to accuse their friends and relatives
of consorting with the Devil.
Parading around huge bonfires,
repeating vindictive chants,
they consigned the poor creatures
to the flames.
Their tortured souls cried out in agony
as the flames mounted higher and higher.
"Burn, witch! Burn, witch! Burn, burn!"
- Dig that crazy beat.
- Shh!
That will be all for today.
Tomorrow will be my concluding lecture on
witchcraft in 17th century New England.
I shall bring along some illustrations,
which I'm sure will interest you all.
I'll bring the matches.
Maitland!
Since you chose
to attend these lectures,
I had hope that it was in the spirit of
scientific curiosity about the subject.
That'll be all.
- How could you?
- He takes it all so darn serious.
He's got you all hypnotised!
- Oh, Miss Barlow?
- Yes, Professor?
- Can I see you for a moment?
- Yes.
What about our date?
- Look, urn...
- I'll meet you.
I'll wait for you outside.
Yes, Professor.
Rather a difficult young man, that.
You're more than an attraction
to him than my poor efforts.
I've been reading
through your papers, Miss Barlow.
They show a very sound appreciation
of the subject.
I want to go to New England
to do my senior paper.
Mm-hm. They're really quite good,
you know.
Well, I'm not quite satisfied
with them yet.
I feel like I need
some first-hand research.
I wanna get the atmosphere.
Find out how widespread
witchcraft really was,
what the witches were really like.
- That might take a little time.
- Well, I have the time.
My brother and I were gonna spend
our vacation with our cousins.
What I'd really like to do
is to get a room in the smallest,
oldest town in New England I can find.
Check through all the town hall records.
Recheck the libraries.
Talk to the puritan descendants.
Make a really thorough investigation.
Your brother is a Professor of science.
I hardly think
he'd be interested in witchcraft.
Then I go alone.
You don't think he'd object to that?
You leave Richard to me.
He's picking me up here for lunch.
Hello, Bill.
- Professor Barlow.
- Nan here?
She's in there with him.
I don't like her getting mixed up
in this witchcraft business.
Why not?
It's only part of her history course.
- Professor Barlow?
- Yes?
Before you go in there,
could I have a word with you?
- Yes, sure.
- Well, it's about Nan and me.
Oh.
If you're really serious about this, I
happen to know the town in New England.
It's the identical place where the events
occurred that I mentioned today, Whitewood.
It's quite a small place.
It's a little bit off the beaten track.
- So maybe these directions will help you.
- Thank you.
I think you might very well find
what you're looking for there.
I happen to know the woman
who owns the inn at Whitewood.
Her name is Mrs Newless.
So you just tell her I sent you.
Raven's Inn, Whitewood.
What's Whitewood?
Now, Dick, don't be too upset,
but I'm gonna change my plans
for the vacation.
- Change of plans?
- Yes.
I'm going to a place called Whitewood
for a week or so to do some research.
Oh, are you?
And what about cousin Sue?
She's expecting you
for her birthday party on the 17th.
She'll never forgive you.
I can still easily make it by then.
This is important.
My term paper's got to be good.
It could mean a scholarship.
- I've made all the arrangements.
- Dick, you'll have a good time without me.
My mind's made up.
I'm going to Whitewood.
But surely any good encyclopaedia will
give you all the nonsense you wanna know.
Witchcraft is not nonsense, Barlow.
I'm sorry, Driscoll.
Witchcraft, black magic, sorcery, to me
it's nothing but fairy-tale mumbo-jumbo.
I'm a scientist, Driscoll.
I believe what I can see,
what I can feel and touch.
"The basis of fairy tales is reality.
The basis of reality is fairy tales."
As a scientist, you should be familiar
with that quotation.
I don't believe somebody in Chicago
can die of a heart attack,
because some woman in New Orleans
sticks a pin in a wax doll!
Maybe you don't, but practitioners
of voodoo claim otherwise.
- Dick, you're just being difficult.
- No.
When I look into a microscope, I see the
bacteria, swimming, fighting, existing.
That's real! These witches, they were
persecuted and burned in the 17th century.
Were real too, but they weren't witches.
They were pitiful human beings.
Victims of hysteria.
There are many eminent scholars
who have documentary proof
of the actual practice of witchcraft.
Yes,
but how effective was this practice?
Did any of these eminent scholars
ever meet a real practising witch?
Did you ever meet a witch, Driscoll?
Perhaps.
Oh, come on. You're a historian.
No witch ever survived a burning at the
stake for all their pacts with the Devil.
In 1692 Elizabeth Selwyn
went to the stake.
She was buried in a churchyard
in New England.
- And yet three years later...
- Yes.
And yet three years later a new wave of
blood sacrifices broke out in the village
that condemned her.
The daughters of the elders who had
condemned her were found murdered
with every last drop of blood
drained from their bodies,
and afterwards people came forward to
testify they had seen Elizabeth Selwyn.
Stop! This'd be more effective at midnight
with howling winds and crashing thunder.
And even then it
wouldn't frighten anyone.
Dick!
I'm sorry Professor Driscoll.
It's all right, Miss Barlow.
You won't be the first person
to have scoffed at the subject.
Honey, when you get to,
urn, where is it?
- Whitewood.
- Ah, yes, Whitewood.
Well, send me a picture postcard
of the witch.
If possible, autographed.
Now, uh, let's have some lunch, eh?
I'm sorry, I have a date.
Nan, darling, I still don't see why you
have to go up to this Whitewood place.
Huh? I thought we were gonna have
some time together during this vacation.
You know I wanna be with you.
It's just this is important.
Look, what the heck can you find
that hasn't been found before?
I don't know.
It's just that maybe, hidden in some
attic or buried in some old antique shop,
there's something that might give
a new outlook on the subject.
Oh, what new outlook can there be?
You're a science student.
You know how important research is.
But this isn't about anything real.
This is just superstitious people
burning silly old women.
But suppose the women weren't silly.
Suppose they really had a pact
with the Devil.
A pact that could have
supernatural power.
Oh, come on. What kind of power?
I don't know.
Oh, look, it's no use, Bill.
We've both tried our hardest
to talk her out of going.
Do you think
she will find anything worthwhile?
I think we have to respect her desire
to find something new,
even if we don't agree with the subject.
Agree with it?
I've never heard so much nonsense as
that guy Driscoll talks in all my life.
Well, here I am, all packed.
Oh. I suppose nothing I can say
will stop you from going, huh?
Yeah, well, I'll, uh,
I'll put this in the car.
I still hoped you'd
change your mind, Nan.
Don't worry, darling. I'll be back
as quick as I can, and I'll write.
Well, don't forget me altogether, huh?
I won't. Give Sue my love, and don't
forget we have a date at our party.
Bye, darling.
Uh, excuse me.
Can you help me? I seem to be lost.
Sure, if I can.
- I'm looking for the Wamport Road.
- Wamport Road?
Hardly anyone uses that any more.
Well, my friend gave me the directions.
Uh, "take road 28A,
turn onto the Wamport Road,
"bear left at the fork
through to Whitewood."
- Whitewood?
- Am I that far away?
No, ma'am. Not far.
Not many God-fearing folks visit
Whitewood nowadays. If I were you, I...
If, if you'll excuse me.
I'm in a hurry. Which way is it?
Well, follow this road
about two miles, you come to a fork.
There'll be a sign: Wamport Road.
Turn left, keep straight,
there'll be Whitewood.
Thank you very much.
Does that sign say "Wamport Road"?
Wamport Road? Yes.
Oh, good. I was afraid I missed it.
- Is it Whitewood you seek?
- Yes.
I, too. Uh, would I be imposing if...?
No, of course not. Get in.
Thank you.
You'd think the Highway Commission
would do something about these roads.
Watch out. Here comes another bump.
What is your mission in Whitewood?
Mission? Well, I'm going there
to do some research on witchcraft.
Professor Driscoll gave us very
interesting lectures on the subject.
I'm going there
to get some original source material.
- Do you know Whitewood?
- I've known it for many years.
- Do you go there often?
- Fairly often.
Oh, then you must know the Raven's Inn.
- I shall be resting there.
- Oh, so shall l.
Oh, my name's Nan Barlow.
My name's Jethrow Keane.
- Pleased to meet you.
It's just like a picture
out of a history book.
I feel as though I were
in the 17th century.
Why hasn't Whitewood been written about?
It's off the beaten path.
Few tourists come here.
For Whitewood time stands still.
Look at that church.
Must have been beautiful.
What a shame
they let it get so run down.
- Straight on?
- Yes, follow the road around.
Ah, there it is.
What a lovely old building.
17th century at least.
How picturesque can you get?
Right by the graveyard.
Yes. It has not been used
for more than 200 years.
- Any witches buried there?
- There are, indeed.
All in a section of
unconsecrated ground.
Spooky, isn't it?
Well, keep your fingers
crossed for me, Mr Keane.
I hope Mrs Newless has that room.
Oh, I didn't hear you come in.
Are you Mrs Newless?
- No.
- Oh, I'm Nan Barlow.
I was told I might find a room here.
I was recommended by a friend,
Professor Driscoll.
Perhaps you know him.
That will be all, Lottie.
I'm sorry to keep you waiting.
Unfortunately, Lottie cannot talk.
I've often told her
not to answer the bell.
Poor thing.
Then you're Mrs Newless.
I am. May I help you?
Yes, I'd like to have a room here
for two weeks.
The hotel is quite full.
Oh, the guests are never about
at this time of day.
Well,
I'm a student of Professor Drisc0ll's.
He told me if I mentioned his name,
I'd have no trouble.
Well, there is a room
I could let you have.
It's just off the lobby.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, Mrs Newless, that plaque.
Is it true that Elizabeth Selwyn
was really burnt here for being a witch?
She was.
And do you believe she was a witch?
Come along.
I'll show you to your room.
I hope you will be comfortable.
Yes, it is a nice room.
The previous occupants
have always found it most agreeable.
Well, if there's anything you should need,
just ring the bell for me at the desk.
Thank you.
Oh!
It's been so many months.
I have counted the
days till this holiday.
So have the others.
It wasn't easy
for some of my guests to get here.
Many had to travel vast distances.
I was lucky.
The last few miles were enchanting.
Miss Barlow is very good company.
You must be tired, Jethrow.
Your room is ready.
And the festivities?
I am prepared.
Oh, Mrs Newless.
I thought I'd have a short look
around town.
I won't be gone long.
I think you'll find
the church interesting.
Unfortunately,
it no longer has a congregation.
He will be pleased.
I'm told this was once
a house of worship.
It is still a house of worship.
I am the reverend of this church.
As long as the breath
of life is within me,
this house shall remain God's house.
Must have been a beautiful building.
For me, it is still beautiful.
I'm sorry. What a shame that people
have let it fall into such a state.
Strangers rarely come to Whitewood.
Who are you?
I'm Nan Barlow.
I'm staying at the Raven's Inn.
Why have you come to Whitewood?
Well,
because I'm interested in witchcraft.
Young woman, leave Whitewood.
Leave Whitewood tonight.
For 300 years the Devil
has harboured over this city,
made it his own.
The people in it are his.
Evil has triumphed over good here.
Look at my church.
I have no parish.
No one worships here.
His is the power.
- What power?
- Leave Whitewood.
Leave Whitewood tonight.
I beg of you!
- What power?
- Leave before it is too late!
- Good evening.
Please excuse the mess.
We haven't been open long.
- You have some very interesting things here.
- Yes, they belong to my grandmother.
When she died,
I came back to sort things out.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Then you don't live here?
No. My family have lived here
for generations,
but I've been back a few weeks.
- Would you like to have a look around?
- Thank you.
I didn't mean to frighten you
when I came in.
It's just that all the
people I've met here
have acted like I'm a person
from another world.
They don't see many strangers here.
And I had the most, well,
unusual experience with the reverend.
He barred my way from the church.
And he talked to me about a curse.
And he warned me to leave Whitewood.
Can you explain that?
No, I can't.
Does he often act that way?
- He's my grandfather.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, it's all right.
It's happened before with strangers.
The lack of parishioners,
the loss of his sight
has made him bitter and suspicious.
I'm afraid what with him and the town,
I was very scared.
When I saw your lights
I made a dash for them.
I'm glad you did.
Do you have any books
or pamphlets on witchcraft?
- You do, don't you? A friend of mine...
- We have a collection gathering dust.
But why on earth
would you be interested in...?
- I'm sorry. It's none of my business.
- That's all right.
I'm studying it in college, and I've
come here to write my term paper.
Just wait. I'll see what I can find.
That's Elizabeth Selwyn.
Burned as a witch, March 3rd, 1692.
Yes, I know. I saw the plaque
in the lobby of the hotel.
- You're staying at the Raven's Inn?
- Yes.
It was recommended to rne
by a friend, Professor Driscoll.
- Alan Driscoll?
- Yes. Do you know him?
No, but my grandfather speaks of him.
His family come from here.
- Oh, I didn't know that.
- Here. I think this'll do for a start.
What a lovely locket. May I see it?
- I believe it's quite old.
- Oh, it is. You're very lucky.
I'm even more lucky to have found this.
"A Treatise on Devil Worship
in New England".
This must be a very rare book.
I'm afraid I couldn't afford to buy it.
You can borrow it if you like.
Oh, could I? That would be wonderful.
I promise I'll bring it back
in a few days.
- You're very welcome, Miss...?
- Barlow. Nan Barlow.
Nan Barlow.
- Thank you very much. Good night.
- Night.
Mrs Newless!
- Mrs Newless?
- Yes, Miss Barlow?
L- |- I've heard some strange noises
in my room.
Oh, possibly the water in the pipes.
This is a very old inn.
No, it seemed to be coming
from the cellar underneath.
I hardly think so, Miss Barlow.
The cellars do not extend
beneath your room.
But then why is there
a trap door in the floor?
The ground was filled in many years ago
to strengthen the foundations.
- But I'm sure...
- If you insist, I will come and see.
I don't hear anything.
Well, just a few minutes ago...
- Never mind. I'm sorry.
- You're welcome.
But you can see,
there is no ring in the trap door
because there is no reason to lift it.
There is nothing underneath but earth.
Come in.
Oh, hello, Lottie. Come in.
Oh, I don't need any more towels.
I haven't used mine.
They're quite clean.
Lottie... I've told you before
not to bother the guests.
Miss Barlow, I thought
you might care to join the others.
I will as soon as I finish my notes.
I'll put some clothes on and join them.
"A Treatise on Devil Worship
in New England".
Well, do you find this interesting?
Well, it's fascinating.
The things I've learnt.
I bet you don't know the half of it.
And you live right here on a spot
where the witches were actually burnt.
Listen to this.
"On Candlemas Eve,
February 1st, in the year 1692,
"a coven of witches... "
a coven, that's 13,
some men, some women,
"whose power came from the Devil
"gathered beneath the Raven's Inn
"to perform a black mass
in the honour of Lucifer.
"The witch, Elizabeth Selwyn,
later to be burnt at the stake,
"marked a young girl for sacrifice
"by obtaining an object of value
belonging to her, with which to call her.
"And leaving in its place
a dead bird and a sprig of Woodbine.
"The witches sacrificed
her on the altar,
"and drank her blood at the hour of 13."
What's the hour of 13?
Well, personally I have never heard
a clock strike more than 12.
- Now, how about joining the dancing?
- In a little while, I promise.
Oh, by the way,
I seem to have misplaced my locket.
I remember having it in my room,
and now it's disappeared.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll ask Lottie.
Well, I-I'm not saying it was stolen.
It's just I remember having it
on the dresser, and now it's gone.
I would appreciate it.
Of course.
I'll look into it immediately.
Lottie, I have warned you too often
about annoying our guests.
If you disobey me again,
I shall turn you out.
And if I turn you out,
there will be no place for you anywhere.
You do understand, Lottie, don't you?
Ah, Miss Barlow.
I'm afraid Lottie is nowhere
to be found.
I will enquire about your locket
first thing in the morning.
Oh, thank you.
Where is everybody?
Most of the other guests
have gone to the services.
Services? On the 1st of February?
Candlemas Eve.
The night when the witches
mock the rituals of the church.
Are you all right, Miss Barlow?
Yes, quite, thank you.
- Good night.
- Good night, Miss Barlow.
Mrs Newless!
Mrs Newless! Mrs Newless!
Quiet.
No! No!
No! Let go of me!
Help! No!
Let me go! No!
No! Take your hand off me!
Let me go!
No! No! No!
Let go of me! No!
Six, seven...
No! No, Mrs Newless, no!
No! No! No!
I am Elizabeth Selwyn.
No! No!
- 11...
- No!
- Let go of me! Let go!
- 12...
13.
Mmm, yummy.
Delicious.
Dick, have you got any idea
what's happened to Nan?
I'm sure she'll show up.
She's probably met
a good-looking he-witch.
Bringing him,
but his broomstick blew a gasket.
It's not like Nan to be late for anything.
Aren't you a bit worried about her?
She'll be here.
I'm sure she'll make it.
That's probably her now.
You answer the door. I'll put
a record on for some dancing.
All right.
- Hi, Dick.
- Bill.
What's the matter?
Expecting somebody else?
Oh, yes, Nan.
Come in, come in.
Nan? Isn't she here yet?
We made a date to meet here
before she left for Whitewood.
Well, she probably got held up.
Look, look, give me your coat.
Nan was never late
for anything in her life.
Relax. Take it easy.
Enjoy the party. She'll be here.
Dick...
Dick, I haven't had a letter from Nan
in over two weeks now.
She's probably been too busy
working on her paper.
Oh, no. There's something wrong,
I know it.
- Will you do something for me?
- Mm-hm.
Ring up Whitewood, will ya?
Ask 'em, ask 'em if she's left.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, I am.
OK.
Hello. Long distance.
I'd like to speak with a Miss Nan Barlow
at the Raven's Inn, Whitewood.
No, I don't have a phone number.
What, didn't she give you
the phone number?
Why, no, but that's my sister.
They say there's no such place
as the Raven's Inn.
But that's crazy.
She's staying there.
Give me the police.
She left in such a hurry,
she must have forgotten
to return it to you, Miss Russell.
She seemed such a nice girl, too.
Wouldn't have thought
she was the sort who'd forget.
We cannot always judge
by our first impressions, can we?
I'm not usually wrong about
the people I lend my books to.
Well, perhaps
you'll be more careful in future.
- Thank you for letting me have it.
- Remember me to your grandfather.
Lottie! Get out of the way,
you clumsy creature.
- Can I help you?
- We're from the Sheriff's office.
We had a call this evening.
A missing person report
for some college kid named Nan Barlow.
The party calling said her last known
whereabouts was the Raven's Inn.
Nan Barlow. That's strange.
Yes, I met her.
When did you last see her?
About two weeks ago.
She came to my shop,
and borrowed this book.
It's quite valuable,
and not hearing from her,
I decided to come and get it.
Mrs Newless had it.
- May I?
- Yes.
"A Treatise on Devil Worship"?
I must put this in the report.
Peculiar things some of these
college kids do nowadays.
Well, thanks for your help.
Come on, Charlie.
Hello?
Yeah.
It's the police.
OK, thanks.
Thank you.
Well?
The police sent a car
out to the Raven's Inn.
Nan checked out two weeks ago.
- I don't get it.
- Well, neither do I.
Look, these are Nan's books and papers.
Go through them. See if you can find
anything which might give us a lead.
I'm gonna pay a visit
to a colleague of mine.
Oh, Lord of Light,
accept this sacrifice.
- Why, Barlow.
- May I come in?
Well, yes, of course. Please do.
Can I take your coat?
I tried to phone you last night,
but I guess you weren't in.
No... No, I wasn't.
Would you care to go in the study?
- Sit yourself down.
- Thanks.
You take a drink?
Brown soda.
- Ice?
- Please.
- Now what's on your mind?
- Well, Nan's missing.
And she has been since the day after
she arrived at Whitewood.
Really? You quite sure?
It's what the police said.
- What are they doing about it?
- Carrying out a routine check.
I don't suppose they can much more
until they've got something
definite to go on.
I would have thought
there was a great deal more.
What? As far as they're concerned,
she disappeared two weeks ago,
and no one in the village
seems to know anything about it.
- What have you come to see me for?
- I thought you might have some ideas.
- Why did you send her to Whitewood?
- It was the best place for her research.
- You suggested she stay at the Raven's Inn.
- It's the only inn there is.
With an unlisted phone number.
The inn has its own clientele,
it doesn't need to advertise.
- How do you know it so well?
- Because I was born in Whitewood.
I see. Then you'd have every
reason to believe
she'd be perfectly safe
in going there.
I've no reason to
suppose she wouldn't be.
Nan struck me as being perfectly capable
of taking care of herself.
I grant you that, but why hasn't she
come back, or let us know?
I can understand your anxiety,
but I'm quite sure there's
nothing for you to worry about.
She's probably got absorbed on the
subject, and gone off someplace.
I wish that all my class
had her application.
Yeah, well, I'm gonna find out
where this application led her.
I'm going to retrace
every step Nan took.
I'm either gonna find Nan,
or know what happened to her!
- I can't stop you from going.
- No.
- You're not afraid?
- Afraid? Why?
If anything did happen to your sister,
and somebody went to find out about it...
- The same thing might happen to them?
- Possible.
You seem to think something
happened to my sister?
No. You are jumping to conclusions.
Really? I shall find her.
- Professor Driscoll?
- Yes.
I don't like to disturb you,
but may I see you?
Of course. Please come in.
- Good luck in Whitewood.
- Thanks.
I'm sorry, but did you say
he was going to Whitewood?
Yes, he is.
It's silly to be surprised,
but I've just come from Whitewood.
Really? It's quite a coincidence.
My family happens to come
from Whitewood. I was born there.
- Yes, I know.
- Please sit down.
Thank you.
- Care for a drink?
- No, thank you.
I think you know my grandfather,
the Reverend Russell.
Russell? Oh, yes, of course I do.
How long have you been living
in Whitewood?
Since my grandmother died
a few weeks ago.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, now how can I help you?
I've come about a pupil of yours?
Barlow.
- Nan Barlow?
- Yes.
She came to Whitewood two weeks ago.
I met her and liked her.
She told me that she was a student
in one of your classes.
That you recommended
that she stay at the Raven's Inn.
It's quite right, I did.
That's what I've come to see you about.
On the day after she arrived,
she disappeared.
- Oh?
- Later the police came asking questions.
The family were worried.
I thought you might
have their address.
Why do you want her family's address?
Because I have something of hers
I want to return.
Leave it with me,
and I'll make sure they get it safely.
I don't want to trouble you.
If you just give me their address...
As you wish.
Her address is Dorchester Street.
225. She lives with her brother.
He's a colleague of mine.
You just met him.
He was leaving when you arrived.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I've got a lot of work to do.
I'm rather a busy man at the moment.
- Thank you for your help.
- Not at all. I hope it achieves something.
- Remember me to your grandfather.
- Yes, of course. Goodbye.
Goodbye, Miss Russell.
Yeah, it's Nan's locket, all right.
As far as I know, it's unique.
I gave it to her.
Where did you get it?
The servant at the inn gave it to me.
It was strange.
I don't think she wanted Mrs Newless
to know I had it.
- Mrs Newless?
- She runs the inn.
Oh. Why did you come here,
Miss... Miss Russell?
I found this.
It's Professor Drisc0ll's notepaper.
I found it in a book I lent your sister
on her first evening in Whitewood.
When she didn't return it,
I went to the hotel.
- What was the book?
- An old book. A book about witchcraft.
Do you believe in it, Miss Russell?
I don't know. Sometimes I think
I almost live with it.
Live with it?
It's an obsession of my grandfather's.
Up till now I didn't take him seriously.
He's an old man.
But now I'm beginning to wonder
if what he says isn't true.
What does he say?
That there's something evil
about the village.
And on a certain night the inhabitants
leave the streets, close their doors
and stay behind them.
That on these nights
the dead come to life.
Nights like Candlemas Eve?
What do you know about Candlemas Eve?
It's in one of Nan's books.
I don't believe it!
Things like this don't happen today.
In Whitewood I wonder.
I'm going to Whitewood tomorrow
after classes. I can give you a lift.
Thank you, but I must get back.
I can't leave my grandfather alone.
He's blind.
May I come and see you when I arrive?
I'd... I'd like to have a talk with him.
Please do. It's the house
next to the church. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
- I'll see you to the door.
- Would you be going to Whitewood?
- Yes.
Would you take me along with you?
It's a dark night for walking.
You're the Reverend Russell's
granddaughter, aren't you?
- Yes, how did you know?
- I know a great deal about Whitewood.
- Have you ever been there?
- Now and then.
- I've never seen you.
- To see me is a special privilege.
It's reserved for a chosen few.
What does that mean?
We'll soon be at Whitewood now.
This is as far as I go. You will...
She's pretty, too.
Yes, she is. Very pretty.
A living descendant
of those who were cursed.
It somehow seems to make it better.
Another day.
And tomorrow...
The Witches' Sabbath.
Which way to Wamport Road?
Straight ahead. Fork in the road.
You see a sign, turn left.
- You heading for Whitewood?
- I am.
- Many people head this way?
- Not many.
Is this the only way
in and out of the town?
In this direction, yep.
You wouldn't remember by any chance
a pretty girl in a convertible
about a month ago?
The Barlow girl. Read about her
in the papers. Never seen her again.
- I told the police.
- Thanks.
Could you tell me the way
to Whitewood, please?
Another one. Straight ahead.
Fork in the road. See a sign,
"Wamport Road",
turn left as you ride in.
All right, thanks.
Let me warn you, young fellow.
They don't like strangers in Whitewood.
OK. Fine. Thanks very much.
- Good evening.
I'd like a room, please.
The inn is closing.
Well, I'll only be here a few days.
But the inn is closing.
- When?
- In two days.
If you don't mind,
I'd like to stay until then.
If you insist.
And could I... could I have
the same room my, my sister had?
- It's still available, isn't it?
- Yes, it's available.
Mrs Newless, you told the police
that my sister checked out.
You are mistaken, Mr Barlow.
I told them that on the morning
of February 2nd,
I went to her room
and found it empty.
Her bed not slept in.
Her luggage and car gone.
And her bill unpaid.
Well, you can put the charges on mine.
- When was the last time you saw her?
- On the evening of February 1st.
It was shortly before midnight.
She'd been in the lobby
dancing with some of the guests.
She seemed to be enjoying herself.
Did any particular guest
pay special attention to her?
Not that I noticed.
Your sister kept very much to herself.
You know why she came to Whitewood?
It is not my habit to enquire
into people's private business.
Would the fact
that she was investigating witchcraft
antagonised anyone in the village.
Hardly. There have been
other students here, you know.
Besides, your sister was a very
agreeable and likeable young woman.
Well, have you any idea
where she might have gone?
- None.
- Thank you.
Now, may I see the room?
As you wish. It is this way.
If you should need anything,
and I am not at the desk,
you have only to ring the bell.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- I'm so glad you've come.
I saw your car outside
the Raven's Inn earlier.
I wondered what had happened to you.
I've been talking with Mrs Newless, and
then I took a walk around the village.
Find out anything?
Everyone here seems
to be afraid of something.
Then you don't think
it's just my imagination?
I don't know. Who's to say where
imagination ends and truth begins?
It's nothing tangible. It's...
Just the way they look at you.
I felt it too.
May I see the...
the book that Nan borrowed?
Yes, I put a marker between the pages
where she must have stopped reading.
Sit down, and I'll tell my
grandfather you're here.
Thank you.
I warned you, Lottie.
Grandfather, this is Mr Barlow.
How do you do, sir?
God be with you.
Shall we sit where we'll
be more comfortable?
Here's your chair, Grandfather.
You must be tired.
I am. Really tired.
I have little strength left these days
for the fight.
Won't you sit down?
I'll make some coffee.
Fight against what, Mr Russell?
Against the evil that
besets this village.
The people are creatures of the Devil.
They know no other God.
You mean they worship Satan
here? Today?
Satanism was never stronger
than at the present time.
For 200 years the people of Whitewood
have carried out rituals
that mock the Church's teaching.
I find it very hard to believe, sir.
Do not doubt, my son.
It is real enough.
For years I struggled
against the witches.
Their master took away my sight.
It seems incredible.
I have tried to convince others.
They too found it unbelievable.
But I know these people
have a pact with the Devil.
To worship him and do his works.
In return he gives them eternal life.
- Eternal life?
- Aye.
And to seal this bargain
they must sacrifice a young girl
on two nights of the year.
When are these nights, sir?
Candlemas Eve
and the Witches' Sabbath.
Candlemas Eve.
That's, that's February the 1st.
- And when is the Witches' Sabbath?
- Tonight.
Now you know why I came to see you.
I had no idea it was so late.
May I... may I have a
rain check on the coffee?
I'd like to have a few words
with Mrs Newless again.
- Of course.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
- I'll see you to the door.
God be with us.
Miss Russell,
do you think that Nan's disappearance
is connected in some way
with these... witches' ceremonies?
Yes.
Well, I'd... I'd like
to come back later, if I may.
- Please do. And my name is Pat.
- And mine's Richard.
I think I feel better now you're here.
Well, I'm... I'm gonna stay
until I find out what's happened to Nan.
Take care.
Now drink your coffee
before it gets cold.
You must not see
that young man again tonight.
- Why not?
- The Devil comes in many disguises.
I'll get you a spoon.
Grandfather, there's a bird in the
drawer. It's got an arrow through it.
Go and look on the front door.
- It's a sprig of Woodbine.
- Shut the door! Shut the door quickly!
- Grandfather, what does it mean?
- Now, listen, my darling.
This is their sign. The witches' sign.
- What can we do?
- We must leave here.
Leave here immediately.
I'll start the car.
Somethings wrong.
They've wrecked the car.
Barlow! Phone Barlow!
Hello? Hello?
Hello. I want the Raven's Inn.
Yes? Mrs Newless.
Mr Barlow?
- Is that for me?
- Yes.
Hello?
Dick, I'm in terrible danger.
We've got to leave Whitewood at once.
Danger? But from what?
'We've got to leave...'
- Pat? Patricia!
- 'Please help me!'
Pat!
Patricia! Pat!
Patricia!
Mr Russell, are you there?
Mr Russell.
What's happened, Mr Russell?
The witches...
The witches... have Patricia.
Destroy them.
- Mr Russell, how?
- The shadow of the cross.
Use the cross.
I adjure thee, O creatures of salt
by the living God.
Mr Russell.
Maitland! Maitland,
what, what's happened?
Pat! Patricia!
Hello? Hello, operator?
Damn!
Pat!
We've been waiting for you.
Dick, these are the dead
who killed Nan!
Barlow!
Please help me!
Come on, Pat! Hurry up!
Quick! This way!
Dick!
No!
- Pat!
- Dick!
Maitland! Get to a cross! A cross!
A shadow of a cross!
Dick! Dick, he's moving!
Lift the cross!
Quick!
O creatures of salt,
I adjure thee by the living God.
Back from the cross!
Come nearer, Bill.
- Get the shadow over them!
- It comes nearer.
We dare not fail.
We must finish the sacrifice.
- Dick!
- Pat!
Wait. Wait for the hour of 13.
Pat, are you all right?
I think so.
Bill!
I have a score to
settle with Mrs Newless.
You stay here.