We've given her an injection.
She's not in pain.
Is she asleep?
We can't tell.
She called out for her mother.
I've let her know. She hasn't come back.
Is she going to pull through?
We'll attempt the operation
when the professor arrives.
Success is one in every hundred.
Please excuse me.
Madame.
I'd like to be with her.
In case she...
Of course, go ahead.
She might not recognize you.
It's not possible.
Dora.
No, I don't want this.
It's not possible.
PLEASE SEE THE CHARGE NURSE.
You can't stay here.
You can leave.
You can leave. I have permission.
From the head nurse?
Yes.
The bell is there if you need it.
My dear?
My poor dear.
Are you the husband?
Yes.
What a shame.
She was young.
She was?
Dora.
Dora, you're not going to die!
It's not true. Don't leave me.
You're all I have, Dora.
I've got nothing left.
I've only got you. Don't leave me.
I want to start all over again. With you.
Not all alone.
You can't die.
I love you too much.
We're going to save you.
What would I do
if you weren't here anymore?
What would I do?
You're warm, my dear.
I can't do anything for you.
I'd like to...
Nothing.
What will I become if you die?
I love you, Dora.
I love you.
It can't end.
It can't.
It's stupid.
A stupid accident.
Why you?
The driver got out unscathed. Why you?
He's old, he could die!
It had to be you...
I shouldn't have let you go out just now.
- They always say that afterwards.
- Goodbye.
I couldn't have known.
My poor dear.
It's been too hard for you.
I understand, you've suffered too much.
It was the end for us.
It was the end.
Everything was ruined.
- We had nothing left.
- Drive on!
Nothing left.
- I'm keeping this one.
- Yes, sir.
That was the last time I saw you, Dora.
I can't watch that. I'm going to mother's.
- Goodbye.
- Despite everything, you smiled.
You've been so brave, Dora.
Always.
In Neuilly.
The street.
The first time I took you there.
Were you able to pay
for the whole thing at once?
No, of course not. I signed loan papers.
And the horses, the buildings, are yours?
- Everything?
- Yes.
And you, my dear, said nothing.
You just smiled.
- Well, then.
- You were happy.
That shows wealth.
Ah, you must be happy.
Not quite yet, actually.
You will be soon.
Stay cheerful!
You always went on at me
for not being cheerful.
I'm not so young anymore, you know.
At my age, you don't laugh
as much as at yours.
Be cheerful.
That always comes back to me.
Even at the start,
when everything was good.
Your heels, lower your heels.
In step, stay in step!
Excellent! Ribbons on the right.
Let's see! Your heels, Mr. Guy.
Smile, you need to be more likable.
Come on, your grip, let's see! Your heels.
Keep the reigns low.
Robert!
I'm heading out to my mother's.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Everything is fine.
Better than fine.
I love you.
Well...
Don't make that face, then.
You're losing your hair.
Careful, with your sad air,
you'll look ugly.
You laughed.
I would hear your laugh.
You'll laugh again, Dora,
like you used to laugh.
Again. Aren't you scared? Oh!
Oh, it's nothing. Stay there.
Mind the stirrups.
- Bertrand, 2400.
- Brissel, 6700.
Charpentier, 4000.
I'm off to the cinema with mother.
Oh, I've got no money.
Good evening!
I might keep her for a while.
I always wondered
why Louis didn't like you.
I believe he thought
that you spent too much.
Back then, it wasn't anything.
You could have taken it all.
I would have liked to give you more.
Everything was for you.
I'll make it, Dora.
If you get better, I'll make it.
As much as you want.
You won't want for anything.
Never again.
I need to hurry up. I've got a fitting.
- Shall I drive you?
- You got the Chrysler?
This morning. It's fantastic.
Darling,
you took everything too much to heart.
Your eyes, the first time I told you
I wasn't able to pay the loan.
Are things that bad?
Yes.
I didn't dare tell you
just how bad things were.
But I fought.
I did, but...
It all went so fast.
The accounts.
The bills.
The loans.
Bills, deadlines, taxes, loans.
Selling off the first horse.
Louis' grief.
His complaints.
Emile's accident.
What happened?
Nana did it.
It just happened. She doesn't like him.
Is he insured?
He's not even on the books.
All that cost.
And you tried to help me
however you could, poor darling.
A wife, three kids.
That's a bad blow for us.
Thank you.
Since you'll have to replace him,
mother knows someone
who's a very good rider.
- Really very good.
- Tell her to send him tomorrow morning.
Dora, my dear.
You have been so kind.
You've worked hard.
You didn't worry about anything.
You were interested in the riding school.
A little more supple, madam.
And watch your hands.
Good.
- I should have listened to you more.
- Are you happy with him?
Not worth losing Émile, of course,
but he's not bad.
We're not in a position
to be too difficult.
You should thank mother.
You, who never wanted to
speak to the clients,
you became so pleasant
in order to try to keep some of them.
You even started riding again,
even though you didn't like it very much.
You accompanied them to the woods
when they asked you.
Deep down, I didn't like that.
I told you once. Please forgive me.
You're mad
if you think I actually enjoy it.
You were right not to be angry with me.
You were right about the girls as well.
I had so many troubles.
- Get on the horse!
- No, I'm scared!
Let that go now! Come on, back down.
Oh! Come on, let's go. Move forward.
- Are you holding on?
- No, I'm scared!
What on earth is going on?
What's all this?
I'm letting out the center to them
for two hours a day.
They're rehearsing.
- Are you going to see your other clients?
- Yes.
The others let me go.
It's horrendous!
In any case, I couldn't cope anymore.
I already knew that it was over.
The night of your birthday,
I knew it then.
I didn't want to tell you anything.
I had already sold one horse
the day before.
That's how I was able
to buy you that little ring.
You didn't know.
It was stupid. I was scared.
Your mother was worried as well.
I don't understand. What's she doing?
You were lost in the woods.
Like a little girl.
That evening,
you made yourself act cheerfully.
Thank you for that.
I love you, Dora.
You could never know
just how much you mean to me.
I'm not handsome.
I'm not cheerful.
Five years of prison behind me.
You deserved better than that.
But you accepted me.
I love you.
I love you, my dear.
When I finally had to tell you,
I would rather have died, Dora.
But I had to tell you.
I've got to sell the center.
There's nothing more I can do.
It's over.
You've no money left at all?
Nothing. Not a penny.
Don't be angry. I've tried everything.
What will happen to me?
I'm too old.
No one will take me on.
He could have done whatever he wanted,
I didn't care.
I only cared about you.
I'd rather die, Dora.
I'd drop dead if it meant
not having to see you like this.
Get out of here! Leave her!
It's your fault, after all.
I'm telling you, get out!
I didn't believe
that you really liked the center so much.
That day, Dora. That day!
- Three saddles, bad condition.
- Seven bits and bridles.
I blame myself for
letting you go through that.
I blame myself.
I can't watch that.
I'm going to my mother's.
But your mother wasn't home.
My mother's.
They told me she was away for the day.
You must have known.
You'd seen her the day before.
You tell each other everything.
Where were you going, Dora?
What did you...
No need for a taxi. She lived nearby.
You weren't going there?
It's doesn't matter anymore,
I suppose. I don't know anymore.
I don't know anymore.
When your mother comes,
I'll ask her about it.
A taxi.
Why?
Oh, Dora.
My Dora, just a little patience now.
The operation will work, Dora.
My little girl, my poor little girl,
my pretty thing.
It's mother, Dora. Mother's here.
You can't die.
I need you to stay alive for your mother.
To help your poor mother.
We'll be happy together again. Don't die!
They can't let her die!
They've got to do something.
They might be able to operate soon.
You! Go back to your horses!
Go on and see to your accounts!
- You're responsible. It's your fault!
- Quiet, you'll wake her.
You're going to give me orders now? Me?
Your place is not here.
It's you that took her there.
If she dies, it will be your fault.
You son of a bitch!
Penniless! We're bankrupt!
We're selling everything, everything!
And we don't really care
what happens to her.
We could live anywhere, do anything.
And she would come with us.
She would come with us.
And that's why she's going to die.
Because of you.
At her age.
Dying.
- Dying!
- Quiet, for God's sake, be quiet!
Bastard.
Bastard, Bastard! Imbecile!
- Just wait, if she dies, just you wait!
- She's not going to die, I'm sure of it.
No, I know she'll die! I'm her mother,
I know it in my heart. She's dying!
Dora.
My little Dora...
She's going to die!
Mother.
It's not true. I did what I could.
I love her, too. I love her more than...
You love her!
What good is your love to her now?
Mother.
Dora.
Dora, I'm here.
Yes, my dear, mother's here.
Your mother's here.
You're not going to die, Dora.
- Tell me that you're not going to die!
- You'll get better.
It's not serious. It'll be over soon.
Go back to sleep.
We won't talk anymore.
Mother.
Yes, my dear?
Tell him.
You want...
- Everything.
- Everything?
Good.
I...
I want to hear.
Tell me what?
Now she has nothing to lose,
she wants you to know.
What do you mean?
You're going to hear it all,
exactly what you deserve.
You really thought she loved you?
You always believed it.
But no, it's not so!
Neither of us could stand you
from the beginning.
We were in rags, we had to pull through.
And so, we found you.
Oh, we had trouble hooking you in.
But we got you eventually.
We started to reel you in. And you.
You came right along blindly, like a fool.
You gave us a good laugh.
Really, you can only laugh!
I think he'll do.
I think so. But could he be any uglier?
Well, he's not a looker.
Well, he's there
until you find someone better.
Were you hoping he'd put money in there?
He's very thoughtful.
I'm not used to that.
You've got to take it.
You'll be a little "Madame".
He'll be a good boy.
It worked! You could change things for us.
You were quite amusing as a lover.
We thought you were a bit pathetic.
But when you showed us
the school, we were impressed.
It was something solid.
Well, it shows wealth.
You must be happy.
Not quite yet, actually.
You will be soon.
You can really talk.
We're not going to miss that!
Since she's so ambitious,
she took over right away.
Lots of nice people here.
We never know.
See? I was right. It's not a bad deal.
We believed it.
But people can be wrong,
and we were wrong.
She hated me as much as that?
Hated you?
At that point, she had no reason to.
You had money.
And she had lived with less.
Poor dear.
Luckily she had me.
I helped her.
She always told me everything.
Everything that happened between you.
Even the small details.
I was a friend to her.
I know all about your little household.
Everything she did,
everything, I tell you.
Everything you said to her, every word.
- You'll get this on you.
- Ah, don't worry.
Do you love me?
Isn't it obvious?
Yes, very.
I know very well that you love me,
but I'm scared.
I get scared all the time.
Scared of what?
It's too much for me, you see?
I've got everything I could want.
But I'm not there yet.
You'll get there.
You'll get everything.
I love you so much.
That scares me too.
Ask me for whatever you want,
anything at all.
I want you to be happy.
I'm a good husband, no?
I want to spoil you.
I could never refuse you anything.
Even if it's expensive?
Even if it's expensive.
Don't hesitate, I'll arrange anything.
Oh, I won't hesitate.
Well, there is something.
Tell me.
It's a little awkward. It's not for me.
It's for mother.
You know she's not...
If you could, well...
Just a little money to help tide her over
at the end of each month.
- Would you be so kind?
- Of course, my dear.
Naturally.
- You're a kind man.
- Dora...
Dora, dear.
You'll suffocate me.
My Dora.
What would I become
if you ever stopped loving me?
Does that make you laugh?
To think that
we could stop loving each other?
- What if I leave you one day?
- You?
You wouldn't leave me.
I'm scared about that,
but I know deep down.
If I found someone better, maybe richer.
What nonsense!
We're too good together.
I've got another favor to ask.
I'd like us to settle here
and make a beautiful home.
Do you want to?
A beautiful house
in which we can love each other even more.
- See you tomorrow, sir.
- See you tomorrow.
Heels!
Michel!
Sit straight.
And your heels, lower your heels.
Huh?
Aren't there more of them?
Yes. These three started this morning.
- Already riding?
- Yes, but we'll need to start again.
- They're not getting it.
- See you later.
Heels! Lower your heels.
Go with your horse.
Straight in front of you,
in front of you, young man.
Keep your distance. Bernard!
Mr. Robert, please come.
I can't hold Nana.
I need to untie her.
I know she can be hard,
but you don't know how to handle her.
- Robert!
- Yes.
Here.
I'm heading out to my mother's.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Nothing.
Everything is fine. I love you.
- Don't make that face, then.
- I promise I'll never make it again.
- Do you need anything?
- No. I took some money. Bye.
Bye. Eat with your mother if you like.
I'll sort myself out.
Give her a kiss from me.
I still smell of horse.
And then he stole her away,
married her, and now they're in Chicago.
- No!
- Shit, it's sticking.
It seems that she's got two cars.
Good for her.
Don't be like that. Your turn will come.
I took some money to the bank.
A lot of money?
What I could get hold of.
Not bad for one month.
You're so organized. You're a smart girl.
You've got to be prepared.
You never know what might happen!
It's nice to be back here.
I can't afford the rent.
There's plenty of money in my bag.
Take some.
Yes, there was money.
Plenty of money. More than enough for us.
So why would we hate you?
You were a Godsend for women.
Helper to the poor.
I'm going to knock that down
to make more room.
I have to do up the bedroom first.
I'm doing the bathroom from scratch.
A new toilet isn't possible.
Then I'll get to the living room...
When is your next loan payment?
In two weeks.
- How long until it's paid off?
- Eighteen months. Once every three months.
Maybe you should wait a little.
Don't worry. I know what I'm doing.
You've got the stables to think about.
Not to mention your employees.
Things aren't all in order.
Two of them aren't declared yet.
Let's talk about something else.
Monique!
When did you get back from Cannes?
Yesterday. It was marvelous.
- We spent the whole time out on the boat.
- Your tan is unbelievable!
- Excuse me.
- Hey!
What bad manners! Who's she?
No one. The owner's wife, I think.
Look at her ugly clothes.
Jean, where are you going?
- To the woods.
- The woods? Wait for us.
Hello.
- Hello!
- So.
I want to learn to ride.
And the little jobs. It all started
in order to improve your house.
It was all set up.
Comfort is everything for a woman.
Comfort and entertainment.
The horse rides with company
give one new ideas.
It was me who told her not to walk
in the woods when she was little.
Because of the wolves.
You see, I'd do the whole thing in pink.
- I thought about it, but I'd rather not.
- You can take a bath tomorrow.
It's about time.
I like his type.
Are you joking?
Maybe it's not worth the trouble.
It's annoying. Only old men have got cash.
That, my dear, is
the problem for all women.
What on earth is going on?
Why are these curtains here?
I asked for them to be taken down.
Don't get worked up,
it's not a difficult job.
Here.
I'm beginning to get fed up
with Robert and his riding school.
Isn't it time to end all this?
We'll see, such a good little husband
who fixes you up a lovely apartment
for you to grow old in.
A husband who pays the rent for
his mother-in-law who he loves so much!
Good little husband.
This will be nice.
Don't you think, mother?
Dora takes after me. She has taste.
When it's finished,
we'll have a house-warming.
A nice meal and champagne, yes?
If you like. I'll get the horses ready.
Are you going to the woods?
No, it's too cold.
And I don't really enjoy it now.
Now, leave us to work!
Come on, my dear, go on. Be nice.
Away and leave us to work.
You're not going to the woods anymore?
What about the old man?
He went to prison yesterday.
Good God!
Took them three years to work out
he'd been conspiring with the Germans.
Ah! We'll never forget these old stories.
It's bad luck but still, there's Robert.
We'll live.
Are you still putting money away at least?
I'm no fool.
I'll show you the dining room.
They started work yesterday.
See, I want a nice man like that
for a change.
So, she's dying?
As good as dead already.
Now that winter's here,
if you don't make the repairs,
all the rest will be too.
But we can't. We're building a bathroom.
That's how it all started.
Not making the repairs.
It was because of her
that I didn't do the work.
And then, one day, we met François.
- François?
- He was pretty good.
I didn't like him,
but had to acknowledge him.
François!
But you, you poor fool,
you didn't see anything.
François.
We had everything set up.
Civilian clothes. We were set.
We'd even managed to hide the signs.
- Three hours to go.
- Four, three, two.
And it was winter. It was cold.
My fingers couldn't hold any longer.
I thought I'd let go the whole time.
They'd have had us at the second station.
We thought they'd be waiting for us.
When they took us, they insulted us.
The first camp was hard,
but it was nothing compared to that one.
Thankfully, I had Raymond.
We supported each other.
He received some packages.
Did I tell you he died?
Oh, he died? How?
When we were trying to escape
the second time.
They had guns.
We stopped when we saw
we didn't stand a chance. Better that way.
He thought it'd be worth it.
He started running across the field.
They went after him.
It's a terrible thing, losing a friend.
He was the only friend I had there.
- Don't think about that. It's over now.
- I can't help it.
Forget about it. Cheer up.
Waiter, one more!
Now, I have Dora.
You see?
He doesn't know his luck.
Don't forget the olives!
- You need to come. It's happening again.
- What's happening?
Jupiter is sick.
A sudden cold, like the other one.
I'm worried he's dying.
Don't be angry. See you soon.
- Just the two of us, then.
- Good idea!
- Don't be worried if I come home late.
- Very well. Bye!
You nearly blundered that.
Here!
Pay the bill. Then go.
- Here, did you see the watch?
- Yes.
- Go on.
- Yes, I'm going.
Bye.
- Keep the change.
- Thank you, sir.
And your horse died
while she was
sampling the menu in a fine restaurant.
Poor dear.
She profited well from it.
He had hair.
He was her age.
I can tell that you're unhappy.
Even when you laugh,
there's something about you
which doesn't seem right.
A sort of nostalgia.
One could imagine you've suffered.
Is that maybe not ripe?
- Yes, but...
- Wait.
No. I'll try to eat it, thanks.
- Really?
- Yes.
Something in your personal life.
No sense of joy, perhaps.
I saw that earlier at the bar.
Tell me what it is.
Don't you want to?
It's because of my husband.
I got married too young.
He's older than me and...
he doesn't understand me.
Oh, it's not that he's nasty.
I couldn't say that.
Only, he doesn't see what I need.
He's a man with no ambition. You see?
Me, I want to travel,
have a change of scene.
Ah, that's very hard, of course.
The bill, please.
He's not the man I need.
In many ways.
I felt sorry for him.
He had been a prisoner before.
So you see, I felt for him.
Ah! I regret it so often.
You mustn't regret.
You did what you had to do.
My life has passed me by.
Don't say that.
I'm sure you love him.
Yes.
It's more affection, really.
That's enough.
- He gives me a lot of freedom, you know.
- I'm sure of it.
Shall we go?
Yes, if you like.
Let's go.
What shall we do?
Make use of the freedom that he gives you.
I live in Neuilly, not far from you.
Good! Some would call you forward!
I hope I haven't shocked you.
This way.
Excuse me.
Here we are.
Make yourself at home.
Goodness!
My apologies for having to bring you here.
I've come on hard times.
I hope that you're not too disappointed.
I've been a fool.
If you want to leave, I'll be sorry, but...
- You don't want anything else?
- No, thank you, my dear. This is good.
Hello.
Nothing to say? No news from you.
Nothing for three days.
How I would have looked if I had phoned?
And he thought that you were with me,
of course?
Correct.
I even slept at your house last night.
No! Be careful, though.
Him from the other night?
The handsome one?
Yes, him.
- He's flat broke.
- You're joking?
It's true.
Ah, he had money, once,
but I've come along a bit late.
Are you going mad?
- Are you...
- Oh, it's fine!
Aren't I allowed to have a little fun?
Drink your coffee, that'll keep you quiet.
What a bastard!
It's not right, that!
Are you in love?
- What would that look like?
- Being in love? Well.
When you're with a man
and you don't think about money.
Well, with him, I do think about it.
It even makes me angry that he has none.
Well, no danger, then.
- I'd like to know that feeling once.
- Don't talk about misfortune!
It's the right way to wind up done for.
Loving.
It started to work on her all at once.
It's a shame we don't love each other.
That would change things for us.
I wonder what there is
that we need to change.
There's that, and there's money.
Do you want more money too?
Yes,
and a lot of it.
That's everything.
If we had money,
there would be no reason
for us not to love each other.
I think there would be, even so.
At least, for me.
- Isn't this good?
- Yes.
Very good.
- But it's not just that.
- What else is there?
I'll tell you one day.
You should go to sleep.
I could love you.
I'm bored to tears.
If I forced myself.
Certainly don't force it.
It's much better if you don't.
Go home. It's late.
Oh, I've got time.
I'm out at the cinema with mother.
- Do you play golf?
- I have played, yes.
When you stay in nice hotels.
Precisely.
- Do you ride?
- Yes.
I also swim, I ski, I play tennis,
I drive and I dance. Is that enough?
All the fashionable sports.
Exactly.
Seriously now, you have to leave.
But we never go out together. I'm fed up.
It can't go on like this.
I'm getting out of here, you'll see,
I'm getting out.
You always say that.
So, what are you waiting for?
Where would I go?
Well. Find that out.
Thank you.
Are you going to decide to do something
some day?
So I can support you?
If I don't do something,
it'll get serious.
You've got no money?
Enough for two or three days.
Great.
Do you want to lend me some?
This isn't that type of house, you know.
It's quite like mine.
But not in that way.
No, yours must be bigger.
Much bigger.
Oh, get dressed. It's time.
We get no luck, do we?
We don't ask so much of life.
Lots of money,
and a little love.
Some people have that.
Are you sure we couldn't love each other?
Completely sure.
I'm falling asleep.
Kiss me.
I want you to kiss me. Come on.
You're not going to become
a nuisance, are you?
Come on. Since we've nothing else,
we can at least have that.
It became an obsession.
I didn't know what else to do.
Did...
Did she love him?
Did she have a mind to love someone?
François.
I saw nothing, nothing.
And the toil continued.
She's nervous today.
I won't take her tomorrow.
She's always that way.
Come on!
That will get you noticed.
Bring people in.
I don't really like this type
of publicity.
Look somewhere else. There are
four riding schools in this area.
- I'll give you their addresses.
- I've been there.
Well, I'm not the only one.
But what am I going to do?
My poor students, it's for them.
We'll do a very artistic show.
We'll be doing it in the best clubs
in Tanger in a month.
Excuse me.
What happened?
Nana did it. It's just happened.
She doesn't like him.
Is he insured?
He's not even on the books.
- We're going to pay for this.
- Is it serious?
I think so.
Call the hospital.
Is he ill?
I'd say so.
That happens to workers all the time.
There's a fine to pay, too.
If you'd like to come back to my office,
we'll discuss prices.
Pelvic fracture,
injuries,
I don't know what else.
Some Camel, please.
Undeclared, uninsured, not anything.
A wife and three kids.
That's a bad blow for us.
Thank you.
Hold on.
Since you'll have to replace him,
mother knows someone, a very good rider.
Really very good.
Tell her to send him to me
tomorrow morning.
I'd say you'll like him.
It's kind of you to take care of that.
Well, old married couples need
to do each other favors.
Money running out.
Holding on to it.
It was awful to watch it slip away.
- There.
- Thank you, sir.
- So, next time?
- Yes.
- I might need a little less.
- As you wish. Just let me know.
- Good day, gentlemen.
- Goodbye.
Why will you need less oats?
I just said it without thinking.
You never know.
What are you thinking of doing?
Well?
I'm going to sell a horse.
To the ones on Longchamp Street?
Yes.
There's nothing else I can do, my friend.
Don't worry about it.
We'll buy another one when things pick up.
We might as well do it right away.
You think it doesn't hurt me too?
Selling the horses.
Louis, selling the horses.
- Let me know if you want to sell the rest.
- Not for the moment, no.
They'll take care of them well there.
One less horse isn't worth all this drama.
It's not the first time
I've seen one sold.
Me neither.
But it's a bad sign when it comes.
How far behind are the payments?
A month.
I can't even pay it with this.
It will help with small expenses.
And a few of your other jobs.
So, clients are leaving me because
I'm redecorating my flat?
- Is that why they're doing winter sports?
- They're not doing winter sports.
They're riding at the center
on Longchamp Street.
It's cleaner.
The horses aren't freezing to death.
They're better fed.
They've transformed that school.
It's very good now.
- They've got grandstands.
- So what?
Is it my fault I don't have the money
to do as much as them?
Perhaps it has something to do
with the apartment.
And some other expenses.
Mind your own business.
Émile!
This is ridiculous.
He had an accident, madam.
I'm his replacement.
So.
We've got a good bargain.
- Are you the stable boy?
- Yes, madam.
Well!
I had requested that I ride Sugar today.
- Is someone riding him now?
- I'm sorry, we just let him out.
If I had known...
Émile could have left a note.
This place is a shambles.
If this keeps up, you'll have no one left.
Well.
Give me...
Give me Azur.
Right away, madam.
- Good day.
- Good day, madam.
I've never seen you riding.
Don't you know how?
I do, but I despise horses
and everything about them.
How amusing
for the wife of a riding instructor.
Isn't it?
- Will I take him into the barn?
- No, I'm going to the woods.
Thank you.
You're far too distinguished.
I'd never dare to give you a tip.
Strange job!
This one or another.
What's so funny?
It is funny!
You working here.
And him, sorting his accounts.
You're really something, aren't you?
So self-centered.
Oh! You're not bad yourself.
Yeah.
You'd better not hang around here.
If he ever noticed...
Him? You don't know him.
Admit that it bothers you.
It's a strange situation, isn't it?
He's nice, too.
Oh, he's the best.
You're not warming up to him, are you?
That'd be something.
- Kiss me.
- Go now, come on. That's enough.
Kiss me.
Not here. It's foolish.
But that's the fun.
You're a real bitch!
If madam will let you go for a minute,
the horses are hungry.
Brute!
And I'd finally found a respectable job.
You won't be fired, you'll see.
Do you want something?
You could have excused yourself.
Well?
Well, what?
Are you going to tell him?
If I want to!
And what good will that do you?
It'll ease my conscience.
Don't you think
he's had enough trouble already?
You want to give him more?
You can talk. It won't change anything.
I'd defend myself.
And it's you we'll get rid of.
What's more, you'd destroy him.
Not very nice for a friend. Is it?
It'd even be quite cruel.
That and all the debt,
it's a lot for one man to take.
Don't you think?
I'll give you the money tomorrow.
Whore!
What's going on?
If I'm here too much, I can go.
I won't be spoken to that way.
What did you say to her?
I don't know.
Nothing.
She took it the wrong way.
Watch yourself, good God.
You know that she's on edge.
If he's not said anything by now,
he won't.
But be careful. You'll make me ill
with all this carelessness.
You're like a baby.
It will only bring you trouble.
- Maybe, but there are some compensations.
- Like what?
You won't be the first woman
to think of it.
Oh! I didn't show you.
I bought a new cushion.
Look, isn't it sweet?
You'd be better
to put some money aside, you know.
Things still aren't going well?
The center's done. It won't last long.
Are you serious?
I'm almost glad about it.
No more horses, no more dung,
no more Louis, finished.
I didn't like it anyway,
but if it's run aground...
But what will happen to us?
We won't just start again like before.
Listen, darling, I might have someone.
At any rate, I have to introduce you both.
If things fall apart,
we'll land straight back on our feet.
Don't you think?
Even if it's not certain,
that could fix things.
- I could be a streetworker too.
- Why are you saying that?
Oh! No reason.
Go on then. Bring in the goods.
He's a serious man.
Not a doormat, like the others.
Here.
You won't have to worry about anything
with him. He's reliable.
- What does he do?
- He works in food production.
He's a wholesaler.
Ah, that'd work.
And...
If he takes to you,
maybe he'll marry you. You never know.
It's easy to get a divorce.
- How old?
- He's not very young.
But he's not too old.
At least, in any case, he's healthy.
And he likes to laugh,
not like the other one.
He wants a little wife to spoil.
And you get a cut?
Oh! To say that to your mother,
who only thinks of your happiness.
Who wants to see you happy.
- You're going?
- Yes. See you tomorrow.
Oh! Don't cry.
I'm not feeling right today.
You've changed.
I can see that you're worried.
No.
You don't want to meet him?
No strings attached.
You'll like him.
Not now, I don't want to.
Dora, it's not like you
to refuse like that.
François,
you're sure that you don't love him?
Tell me.
I already told you, no.
Well then, don't throw away
good opportunities.
Think of your future.
- Think it over.
- For goodness sake!
You won't starve. Stop worrying.
Leave me alone, you hear? Leave me alone.
Pay attention!
Now!
One, two.
One, two, three, drop.
One, two, three, arms.
One, two, three, keep going.
Keep turning.
Ingrid into the middle, careful, listen!
Lead your horse.
There, into the middle,
everyone else, keep turning.
One, two, keep going.
Attention, stop moving.
Get ready, listen to the song, sing out.
One, two.
It's love
that floats in the air all around
Right hand up.
It's love...
Stretch out.
that consoles the whole poor world
Back around.
It's love...
Very good.
that makes each day a joy.
Move and smile.
It's love...
Keep going.
that sets us all free
Descending.
One, two.
It's love
that floats in the air all around
Look happy.
It's love...
Arms stretched.
that consoles the whole poor world
Two, three.
It's love...
Let's go!
that makes each day a joy
The steps, now.
It's love
Sing, ladies.
that sets us all free
You're late.
On the stage at "sets us all free".
Pay attention now,
sing and move, and sing out, above all.
One, two.
It's love
that floats in the air all around
that consoles the whole poor world
It's love
that makes each day a joy
Arms!
It's love
that sets us all free
You're coming down too early.
Only at "sets us all free".
If it's too early or too late,
it's out of sync.
And smile, ladies.
And sing. I can't hear you.
Come, children. Let's go.
Right, from the top.
Ready, one, two.
It's love
that floats in the air all around
Attention to your arms.
It's love
that consoles the whole poor world
One, two, three.
Up already?
I can't sleep with all this going on.
How long before they're gone?
Another two weeks.
One, two, three. Arms.
One, two.
You're right. It's putting clients off.
But I can't throw them out.
Ah, I need some money.
Are you remembering mother?
It's already the seventh.
You didn't send her anything last month.
I was going to do it today.
One, two, three.
Speaking of mother,
is her protégé going to the woods now?
It was that woman who asked me for him.
I think that...
What are you running?
A riding school or a brothel?
I can't disappoint the clients.
There aren't too many of them.
What does it matter?
You're so nervous.
You should go relax.
Relax? How could I with all this noise?
I want to go for a ride.
I need to get some air.
Very good! But be careful.
No one's more careful than me.
You should ask François to go with you.
You've not ridden in a long time.
I'll see. Might not be worth the trouble.
Indeed, it wasn't worth it.
- You seem worried this evening.
- Yes, quite.
I haven't seen you for eight days.
Already? How time flies!
- What have I done to you?
- You? Nothing. Why?
Very well!
Have you got something to tell me?
I stayed at your place three times.
François, don't you want me anymore?
No. It's just too complicated.
But are you looking to settle down
like me?
There's that, yes.
That woman was right about you.
You are distinguished.
Still, we're really the same, you and I.
You think you're distinguished?
Come down for a bit. I'm tired.
Haven't you found anyone yet?
It's getting urgent.
Business is pretty bad for you, I think.
Someone in sight.
Ah, that's reassuring.
- You're not going to beat me to it.
- Is that so?
Is she wealthy?
Enough.
Nice places, trips.
Megeve, Cannes, Egypt. She's elegant!
Not bad for her age, as you could see.
You've got strange luck!
Your man's not up to scratch?
He's in wholesale foods.
How excellent!
Oh, shut up.
I've not seen him yet.
It was mother who found him.
What a good thing to have a mother.
So you're going to accept, I think?
You don't want to miss out.
I'm going to try something else first.
I want to go to Megeve too, and to Cannes.
It would be a pleasure to give you that.
I want to go there
with another type of person.
Keep trying.
You've got a few weeks
before it crashes down. Enjoy them.
And us, it's...
For now.
Let me know if you're free some evening.
Will do.
If madam will allow, I have to go back.
I have a lesson at 4 o'clock.
I won't ask you to kiss me.
Why not?
It's always nice.
It's incredible how sentimental you are.
Well, that's just how I am.
He was a little bastard. Look what he did.
Treating my daughter that way.
The stable emptied! It emptied!
- And don't you want to sell this one?
- No. I'm keeping it.
Oh, I'm exhausted.
- Will you take me for some tea?
- Dressed like that?
When did you become so formal?
And then you put on weight.
Around fifty, be careful!
You should get on.
- It's awful, you know?
- Oh, I know!
- Oh, sorry!
- Excuse me. I'm sorry.
You haven't hurt me.
Éric, are you coming?
Beautiful!
If you like common folk.
From time to time, yes. It's fun.
You're right.
I'm going to take up riding again.
He didn't waste time.
The next day, he was there.
We thought we'd struck gold with this one.
I was praying for it to work out.
A real man of the world.
Wealthy and handsome, ideal!
She could be happy with him.
And I showed her nice places to go,
the kind of places she was made for.
But she's no fool. She followed my advice.
Letting him take her hand.
It's not an engagement.
She didn't pull it back right away.
Such a distinguished gentleman.
One time I saw him,
he took my breath away.
The two of them made an excellent couple.
Charming.
Taking walks.
Playing the good horseman.
And she looked the part, my girl.
She could have done it for a living.
He was kind and gallant. It worked well.
And then the first kiss.
But suddenly others came.
They thought he was making fun of her.
- Good ride?
- Yes, very good.
Thank you again for
having accepted my company.
- Will you need them again today?
- No.
Wouldn't you enjoy that?
A family celebration.
Single men enjoy that.
You always have good ideas.
It seems you like him.
It's always him you go with.
You're mad.
If you actually think I enjoy it.
I do it for you.
To keep us at least one client.
Forgive me.
I'm always afraid.
When she came back late,
I knew where she had been.
She had played the game and won.
Let me out here.
You don't regret it?
It was wonderful.
Never leave me.
Take me with you when you go.
Promise me.
I need to go now. I'll be late.
I love you.
I think I love you.
Two weeks, just two weeks left.
It didn't split.
Give it back when you leave him.
There's no reason. I'll give it to him.
- We've no gift to give him.
- Exactly.
If you don't mind, I'll be leaving.
- Well, you've looked hard.
- Wait for me.
I'll do what I like.
Oh, enough!
Take the argument into the office.
- I'm taking mother home. She's tired.
- Yes.
- Do you want me to come with you?
- No, no. Keep talking.
François is going our way.
- Good night, Robert.
- Good night, mother.
- How about lunch on Tuesday?
- You can make me something nice.
Will do.
- Wasn't that nice?
- Yes.
A nice celebration like that.
Makes you forget your troubles.
You like it?
- It'll be difficult. It's a charming ring.
- That's never the price of a horse.
- Come back quickly.
- Yes.
Goodbye!
Dora, give me your arm.
I've drunk too much.
It's the champagne!
Two bottles to myself!
Still the same price?
- What?
- Nothing.
Bye.
Good night!
- Thank you for the invitation.
- It was our pleasure.
Oh! Tell me quickly.
I didn't dare to ask before.
Yes. I'm cheating on my husband.
- Get home safely.
- Thank you, Robert!
My dear, we're out of the woods.
I've become a woman of the world.
For sure?
It's in the bag.
I'll tell you about it tomorrow.
You're old enough
to get home alone, I think.
François, wait a moment.
Oh la la! I'm so relieved.
- We deserve it!
- Oh! Yes!
Oh, yes, you have permission
to stay at mine tonight.
Go on, good night.
Don't get up to any mischief.
I wouldn't mind.
Good night, Mr. Gigolo.
Your mother is very happy.
She's what?
Sleep well, you two!
I'm going away.
Far?
Ankara.
That's a long journey.
Soon?
In two weeks.
I won. He's taking me.
It's all over.
I've got the money.
Dora in the embassies! Do you realize?
Yes.
Do you know how to peel an orange?
Do what?
Peel an orange.
No.
You should learn, you'll get them there.
That's all I have to say.
That's my advice.
I suppose you know how to peel an orange?
But you're still here.
- You're not gone yet.
- Nearly!
In fact, in three days.
I'm not going as far as you.
Just to Megeve.
It's a start.
- That woman?
- No, another one.
Is she pretty?
Beautiful!
I see.
Do you love her?
And you're sure about
this new diplomat of yours?
Somewhat!
I'll give him a year to propose.
That would annoy you, wouldn't it?
That's how it goes.
Nice people,
ball gowns,
cars,
servants, everything.
- You don't believe me?
- We'll see.
I've already seen.
You see...
It's not just having ball gowns.
It's having to wear them.
You think I won't? I'm not pretty enough?
You think I'm ugly?
I know people like that.
You won't feel comfortable.
And, if you do, then you'll be a snob.
Don't worry about me.
I can look out for myself.
But that part of you will always be there.
The old you will always have feelings
for the stable boy.
He deserved a slap in the face.
The professor's here. We'll operate.
Operate?
She won't die?
Save her.
Save her, I beg you.
Do everything you can.
My darling, come back.
Fooled, all lies.
Fooled.
All lies. The bitch.
The conniving bitch!
Bitch!
Lend me some money.
I screwed up, I know.
We're selling tomorrow. I've nothing left.
It's not for me. I don't care.
It's for her.
Lend me all you can.
Everything is ready.
Will it take long?
Everything I did for her.
I love her.
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
The bitch. Filthy bitch!
Gently. Careful now.
I'm quitting.
You don't want to work here?
No, impossible.
You can't help with the operation.
Allow me. Please accept this.
You can give it back to me later.
No need to explain. I can do it.
Thank you.
I couldn't have known. I couldn't have.
Bitch!
Give it here.
I'll put it in the bank in my name.
Yes.
Here.
Put that in too. That's all I can spare.
Thank you.
Dora.
Ah, bravo.
I love you.
You know very well that I love you.
Mother knows someone
who is a very good rider.
- Really very good.
- Whore!
I spent the night at mother's.
Ruined me.
Destroyed everything, the bitch!
I can't watch that.
I'm going to my mother's.
I'm going to mother's.
Whore!
Do you need anything?
They're operating right now.
She was leaving. I'm sure she was leaving.
She was leaving.
- They won't let me in.
- She was leaving.
Where was she going in the taxi? Where?
It's too much. Leave me. Oh, my girl.
Where was she going? Where to?
Tell me. Was she leaving me?
Yes, she was leaving.
With all the money
she got towards the end.
You would never have seen her again.
And she was right to do it. Let me go!
Tell me everything.
You hear? Tell me everything.
Was she going to see Éric?
Speak! Tell me!
No, not him. It was the other one.
He was awful. Even uglier than you.
It fell apart with Éric
because he was a bastard, like all of you.
All of you!
Didn't he say anything? No warning at all?
He told me he'd take me with him.
Ankara.
So you would fall for him.
We've been fools.
He didn't have to.
- It's all over now.
- No!
Don't get like this. It won't help.
Dora, my dear, we'll pull through.
It's just a bad turn.
I shouldn't have told her
that we're selling.
Get out of here. Leave her!
It's your fault, after all.
Get out, I tell you!
Dora, my little girl.
Dora.
The bastard, the pig!
Pig!
The things he sent me. There!
For the horse, for me!
For me!
All for the horse! And the saddle too.
Dora, that's from Hermes.
To screw with me!
He's gone.
François too.
We've nothing left.
Nothing.
We've still got a little money set aside.
Introduce me to the vegetable salesman.
That'll work. If he's got money,
it'll be hard for the others.
I want to see him tomorrow, you hear?
Tomorrow! There's no time to lose.
That'll work out, I'm sure.
I swear it'll work out.
He loved her the moment he saw her.
He furnished an apartment
just before the sale.
We would have been happy.
With what we had
and what he would give her,
we could manage
and look for someone better.
She was heading there
when she had the accident.
- I was there getting things ready for her.
- She left me without saying a word.
You had nothing left.
She wasn't going to stay!
If she lives, won't you do anything?
No, not now.
If she had told me herself, maybe.
She wanted to do it before leaving,
to see your face.
- She got scared at the last minute.
- That was better.
I may have killed her.
She didn't even deserve that.
Not even being killed.
It's all finished. It's ruined.
You're just leaving?
No.
I'll wait for the results.
Is she alive?
Tell me, I'm her mother.
Will she live? Tell me, will she live?
Yes, she'll live.
But she's paralyzed.
You understand? Paralyzed.
For the rest of her days.
She'll never walk again.
Never.
They don't even know
if she'll be able to talk.
Her central nervous system is damaged.
- Do you know what that means?
- No.
- No!
- Yes.
The other man won't want her either.
No one will want her now.
Not even me.
She'll be all yours
for the rest of your life.
You heard me.
No, I don't want that!
Help us. Don't leave her.
She loves you. It wasn't true.
None of that was true.
Don't leave, Robert!
Robert!
Robert, come back! Robert!
What will happen to us?
You'll take care of her like a good mother
with the money you set aside.
- You can push her wheelchair.
- Robert.
What am I going to do?
The money, Robert.
Robert!
You can't abandon your wife.
She's an invalid.
Bastard! Filthy coward! Coward! Bastard!
He's gone. Robert.
It's always us who are the victims.
Our hearts that get broken.
Robert, what am I going to do?
What am I going to do?
THE END