Hello, Boys. Got any old
tires you don't want?
Only old tires I got I'm
riding on.
We got enough money to go to the circus
but not enough for the sideshow.
Save your money, plenty
of freaks around here.
Hey, you think they got all
the things they say they have?
Sure, the man told us.
Bet they ain't got no lions. They
have too, the man let us see them.
He did? Good thing it ain't
got no teeth.
Sure they have, long as anything.
Let's you and me go see them.
You can go ahead, we're going swimming.
Say, we're going past
Doc Adrian's house, ain't we?
Sure.
We're going right by
the front of the house?
Sure.
What's the matter, you're scared?
I ain't scared of no crazy doctor.
Well, if you're coming come on.
Well... Well, you see it's this way,
if I don't get home for dinner
why, mom won't let me go to circus.
All right, so you're afraid.
Well, you better stay here.
Get out of here, you little rotten.
Oh, no you don't!
Come on now.
Gee, look he's got Willy.
Hello.
I can't understand why they don't
do something about Doc Adrian.
He's destroying all the values in
this town giving Red Creek a bad name.
I think so, you're right, Mason.
He ought to been run out of
this town a long time ago.
Who ought to be run out of the town?
Doctor Adrian.
You should've been with us
this afternoon.
He scared the women so bad
they haven't got over it yet.
Yeah, this town's too healthy.
Maybe he scaring
himself a couple of patients.
Understand them big doctors make
a lot of money on nervous women.
Wasn't so funny when that
epidemic broke out, Quinn.
You know as well as I do he used a
lot of those patients as Guinea pigs.
I know nothing of the sort,
I know he did everything he could.
There's two or three in this
town who wouldn't agree to that.
However, I can understand his
reason for wanting patients now.
Well, he got himself
another this afternoon.
Little Willy over there.
He ran after me, hurt me
and I wasn't doing nothing.
Poor child.
I think you're all yellow.
She's right and none of you got the
courage to do anything about it.
His patients die on him and now he's
hanging around Miss Clifford's house
experimenting with Frances,
I guess.
You make a poor critic, Mason.
Your greed hasn't done this
town any good.
What you doing, preaching?
A little preaching wouldn't
do you no harm.
What with the people you squeeze dry
and the usury you charge on your loans.
Oh, I don't ask him to borrow.
I guess there's an answer for
that also.
But I think it'd be wasted on you.
Business is business,
Quinn and you know it.
Besides, we weren't talking
about me.
Why don't we kick the doctor
out and be done with it?
I'm ready any time
you're willing to start it.
Oh, yes, that prescription I'll fill it
in a second been quite busy this morning.
I'm sorry to delay you, Doctor.
Perfectly all right,
I can fix it myself.
It's... It's none of my business
and maybe we men of science
think different from other people
but if they ever find out in the
village what you've been doing...
You mean about the animals?
Yes, some of the dogs have
been missed.
Well, that phase of the
experiment is all over.
I found out all I need to know.
Can I help you?
Don't you think they need you
in the store?
Just as you say, Doctor,
just as you say.
Well, that's good enjoying
the last of the sun, ey?
Oh, Doctor, sit down.
Thank you.
Ah.
Well, how's my girl today?
Why, you're all dressed up.
Danny phoned, he's coming over.
So early?
He can't come tonight.
He's going to the circus.
Oh, yes the circus.
I almost forgot.
I've got a present for you, Frances.
Oh, for me, Doctor.
Well, now don't get too excited.
Just you wait until you open it.
It isn't anything at all now.
A jewelry case, oh, Doctor.
Oh, it's beautiful.
But why so much, Doctor, you gave
me a birthday present last month.
So I did.
Well, this is a make believe birthday
just as you're my make
believe daughter.
Was she very like me?
She would've been just 18 today.
She was to have worn that.
I couldn't save her and
I couldn't save her mother.
I hadn't the weapons to fight
the disease that killed them
but I have now.
Or at least,
I've got a knowledge of them.
Ten years it's taken.
Frances, you are going to
walk again.
You're so intense you
frighten me sometimes.
So Danny's going to the
circus, huh?
Yes, then he's coming back here
afterwards and telling me all about it.
Oh, he is, is he?
Well, why don't you go with him?
Oh, me?
Do you think she could?
Oh, you're fooling.
Why of course she could,
I don't know why she shouldn't.
Hello, everybody.
Oh, Danny!
Hello, Danny.
Hello, Mrs. Clifford.
Well, Danny, how would you like
to take Frances to the circus?
Gee, that'd be great only...
Why, of course she can go.
We can take care of her.
I'll be back for you later.
Oh, thanks, Doctor.
Now don't you worry, Mrs. Clifford.
Two strong men to look after
her, she'll be all right.
Be back later.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Danny, I think you better run
home and get yourself cleaned up.
You look as if you'd brought all of
the grease from the garage with you.
You know, Frances,
I think the Doc's crazy.
I suppose I'll have to like him
as long as he's nice to you.
He wants to be nice to everybody
but people won't let him.
Well, I'm not saying I
believe all the things...
Don't you believe any of the things
they say about him, Danny Foster.
Well, all right, don't get excited.
Look, Danny, the stories they
tell about the doctor
are just as dirty as the grease
on your hands and face.
Well, that about takes care
of me.
So long, Honey.
Goodbye, Danny.
Stay with it, Doc,
don't let it throw yah.
Careful.
There you are.
Okay, that was easy, wasn't it.
All right.
All right, Frances?
Oh, yes.
All right.
Right, okay.
Well, this time next year it
will take three men to lift you.
Oh, not three men, Doctor, if it did
they'd want to keep me in the circus.
Hop in, Doc.
Oh, no, you can get somebody else at
the circus to help you lift her down.
What's the matter, aren't you coming?
No, you two go on by yourselves.
Oh. Now, you don't mind if
I change my mind do you?
Oh, please, Doctor.
You'll have much more fun together,
off you go and don't forget to
tell me all about it in the morning.
So long, Doc.
We won't.
Thanks for everything.
Goodbye, Doctor.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Mother.
Bye, Darling, have a good time.
Bye.
Goodbye Doctor, goodbye, Mother.
Goodbye.
Oh, come, come, come now
this is no time for tears.
I know it, I can't help it.
Oh, nonsense, change
will do her a world of good.
Good night.
Well, we made it.
Hey, did you see him, Mickey?
Who? The gorilla,
did you really see him?
Yeah, in the sideshow,
he's a big fella.
Is he bigger than three men?
That ape, that ape is bigger
than six men, six big men!
It's the biggest ape
gorilla in the whole world.
Look, here come the clowns!
Oh!
Having a good time?
Oh, yes.
You don't act like it.
Gee, everybody's looking at us.
I'm nervous.
Oh, what for?
Well, out with a married man
and you know.
Gee, this is the best circus
I ever saw.
It's the only circus I've
ever seen.
Get them while they're hot.
All right, Officer.
Here it's popcorn, right hot out
of the oven, excuse me, Sonny.
Peanuts, five cents a bag.
Isn't she lovely?
She's so graceful.
Oh, she's not so hot.
I saw her passing the garage
this morning.
Them costumes make a big difference.
That's what the doctor
calls muscular grace.
Muscular coordination.
Uh, honey, look over
at the ring there, see.
There you are.
You're all right now, you'll
be chasing bones in the morning.
What I've done for you I can
do for men.
If they'd let me.
Bye.
That's all, Honey.
I'm sorry it's over.
We'll never miss another circus.
What are you trying to
do drive that animal crazy?
Well, he's getting mean it's
the only way I can handle him.
Did you ever try a little kindness?
Nothing wrong with him, Nabu, come
here, Nabu old boy, come on now.
That's it. Yeah, well two
years ago he killed my old man.
And I ain't gonna let
him forget it, understand?
I know he did, I was right here when he did it
'cause he was abusing him, same as you're doing.
If you don't watch your step,
he'll get you too.
Why don't you mind your own business.
You boys wouldn't be gambling,
would yah?
Oh, no.
Sheriff, take me in.
That was a fine show you
fellas put on.
Yous was the funniest clown
I ever seen.
Oh, I rode a horse,
he was the clown.
He was?
Yeah.
Well, he looks like a judge.
Hey, Jim, Pete, let's give
them a hand, come on!
Can't handle it, sound an alarm!
Get the animals out!
Where's the nearest doctor?
Doctor Adrian, get something to
put him on, we'll take him there.
Get him on there!
Somebody better get after that ape
or he'll tear this town right open.
Pete, get a posse together.
Come on, Boys, let's see what
we can do about that fire.
Man badly hurt, sorry
to bother you, Doctor.
Bring him in here,
come on right in with him.
Oh, what happened?
An ape got him.
An ape?
Yeah.
Hope it scared him off in time.
This man's badly mauled.
Well, you better get
him into my laboratory.
Jane, you show them.
Well, now how'd it happen,
was he in the cage with the ape?
No, the circus burned
down and the ape escaped.
The circus burned down?
And the audience?
They'd all gone home.
Oh, thank heaven for that.
Now, will you want us any further,
Doctor? No, I'll take care of it.
Well, then come on, Boys, let's get
out and see if we can find that ape.
Don't let him get at me, Mister.
Don't let him get at me.
You're perfectly safe here.
I'm a doctor.
Am I hurt bad, Doc?
I'm afraid so.
I don't feel nothing.
Am I gonna die?
We all have to die sometime.
Oh, just don't let me die, Doc.
Man...
Are the highest kind of animal.
Hey, Doc?
What are you gonna do to me?
I'm going to write you
into medical history.
I'm going to keep a promise.
Wait here, keep your eyes open.
That sheriff ain't got no heart.
I'm so hungry I could eat hay.
Oh, there's a barn full, help yourself.
George, you take your fellas and search
the county up around Carter's farm.
Jim, you take your boys and
cover the west side of town.
Pete, you stay with me.
How about joining us, Mason?
Let the circus people do their own
work, why should we do it for them?
The circus has burned down,
they've had trouble enough.
Now that's their tough luck.
Well, if we don't find that ape
our own people might get hurt.
That's your job,
you're the law and order.
Why should I worry about
other people?
They don't worry about me.
You wouldn't be a little bit
scared would yah, Mason?
Well, don't be all day about it.
We're ready.
It gives a body the creeps to think
about that critter roaming around.
Better keep the doors
and windows all aboard.
No telling who he'll go for next.
Are you all right, Dear?
Mhm.
Want some more?
Whatcha thinking about?
I was thinking about that wonderful
woman aerialist I saw last night.
Oh, here comes Doctor Adrian.
Morning, Mrs. Clifford.
Good morning.
Frances.
Oh, good morning, Doctor Adrian.
I want to thank you again for the
wonderful time I had last night.
It was too bad about
that trainer, wasn't it.
Now don't you think about him.
This is the most
important day in your life.
Today, we are really
going to start her cure.
I found the serum that I needed.
I'm going to walk, Doctor Adrian?
I hope so.
I'm not just thinking about
you, Frances.
But of all the other suffers in the
world, all the little boys and girls
who can't go out into the
sunshine and play and have fun.
Who have to spend their lives
in a wheelchair like you.
I'll do anything I can,
Doctor Adrian.
I know you will, My Dear.
It's not going to be easy.
It's going to hurt.
But when it hurts don't be afraid, just
remember that when the pain is gone
it will leave... It'll
leave new life behind.
Huh?
I think we better get her ready.
All right, Doctor.
Now we've got him here and
there and here.
Now if we don't get any results tonight
we'll start in here and work west.
Change your mind, Mr. Mason?
I never change my mind.
You gotta have one first.
That's enough outta you.
Here's that Dispossess Notice on
Wilcox and I want it served tonight.
We're busy tonight it
will wait until tomorrow.
Your duty is to take care
of the citizens of this town
not fooling around chasing apes.
It seems you're in a mighty big hurry
to make people uncomfortable, Mason.
It's my business what I do.
Fine and it's mine what I do.
We'll get to this when
we have time, good night.
Oh, Doctor.
Well, Frances?
Oh, my legs, they feel like
lead I can't lift them.
But you never could lift them before.
Oh, I know but I never felt
them before.
You... You feel them, Frances?
You feel them?
They're so heavy.
Well, that's good news, My Dear,
that's what we were hoping for.
And it's only just the beginning.
If there's any change you
send for me immediately.
Yes, Doctor.
Oh, Mother.
Jane, Jane.
Jane!
Look, I succeeded, it's there,
life... Life in that tiny bottle!
It's working.
A child will walk again.
Just go.
It's Wilcox he's all torn up!
Oh, we better get a doctor.
It ain't no good,
he's been dead for hours.
Let's notify the sheriff.
Gladly.
Doc?
Hey, Doc?
Yeah, what's wrong?
The ape got Wilcox.
Well, is there anything I can do?
No, no, he's dead as a doornail.
You better be careful, Doc.
Thanks, I will.
Miss Jane, you're safe.
But only you and I must
know that he's dead.
Good night.
My legs hurt quite a little, Danny.
I know now Doctor Adrian
is really going to cure me.
Well, if they hurt you
how can you be getting better?
Oh, you don't understand,
Danny, they never hurt before.
There was no feeling at all.
Now they feel alive.
Just the same, I don't like it.
I don't like things I can't understand.
Well, I don't understand either,
Danny, but I believe in him.
Oh, I have so much faith in
him, Danny.
He says I'm like a daughter
to him
and well, I know he wouldn't
hurt me unless he had to.
It's part of the cure,
it's just got to be.
All right.
I'll try to believe too, Honey, but
I'd rather carry you around all my life
than have anything happen to you.
Hello, Sheriff, any luck?
Not yet but we'll get him.
Well, I hope so.
Come on, Boy, come on.
There, it looks like
they've picked up a scent.
Well, what got into them, hold on
to them for a minute, will yah.
Hello, Doc.
Hey, haven't seen anything
of that ape have you?
Well, no, I haven't, Sheriff.
Well, my dogs just acted as
if they picked up his scent.
Oh, well, I better be careful then.
Yeah, you better be.
Having trouble with insects, Doc?
Yes, this is just a
little mixture of my own
I'm trying to get rid of them with.
Well, if it works let me know.
My yard's full of them.
Certainly will.
Thanks.
Henry, supper's ready.
Were you going out?
Yeah.
Oh, but I made lamb stew and dumplings.
I don't care for lamb stew
and dumplings, thank you.
Besides, the Sheriff wants us
out early to capture that ape.
You needn't lie,
I know where you're going.
Oh, you do?
Yes, everybody knows.
So, you been listening to gossip, eh?
I can't keep people from talking to me,
and telling me you found...
A new interest.
Suppose I have. Well, there's
nothing I can do about it, I guess.
Well, keep that in mind.
But, if you just wouldn't
carry on here where we live,
so people would stop pitying me.
Even if you go somewhere else. Why
don't you try going somewhere else?
But, I have no one but you.
I have no folks.
I've got no place to go.
You got the river.
Poor Mason,
I feel sorry for his widow.
Ah, she's better off.
Ah, that ain't funny
when a man's been clawed to death.
I didn't like him when he was alive,
and I don't see any reason
to like him when he's dead.
Just the same, it ain't right,
even if he was no good.
We gotta give that ape credit:
He only picks out the ornery cusses.
What makes you think you're safe?
Well, Boys, you get
yourselves some rest today?
About 40 winks,
we're plumb tuckered out.
Maybe we can get some more
people in to help us out.
Why don't we go out in the daylight?
Because he don't come out in the daytime.
The circus people told us
we'll never get him then.
We got to catch him prowling
after dark.
Think he's still hanging around the
village? He got Mason, didn't he?
And we found new tracks
up around Dr. Adrian's house.
Uh, get me a sarsaparilla.
Quiet, you! Now, what do you
think of that, Sheriff?
Even the dogs don't like him.
Well, what got into him anyway?
Acted the same way around his house.
Don't make sense.
Maybe it's 'cause
the Doc looks so much like an
ape hisself.
This is no time for joking.
All of you'll be on the job tonight.
I'm scared, Mrs. Clifford.
She looks almost...
I'm really scared.
We must trust Dr. Adrian.
But, we don't know.
He ain't got a patient in this town.
People don't just hate a fellow for nothing.
Do you hate him, Danny?
No.
It's not hating him, it's...
It's loving Frances the way I do.
If anything happens to her...
I'm going down to see.
I gotta ask him.
I gotta know.
Danny.
Danny's worried, isn't he, Mother?
Now, you just rest, Dear.
Danny'll be all right.
Oh, if my legs didn't hurt so.
But, I'm not afraid.
You aren't, are you, Mother?
No, Darling.
I want my little girl to walk again.
You ain't going in there, Doc.
Now, what is this, Danny?
I'm scared about her.
I gotta know what you're doing.
Well, surely you want her to live
a normal life like other people?
Well, sure,
long as nothing happens to her.
I love her just the way she is, Doc. I can
take care of her... I wanna take care of her.
I don't want no experimentin'
on her.
Danny, if through her
I could rid the world of...
I'm not in love with the world,
I'm in love with her.
I get it,
she's just a guinea pig to you.
Well, you gotta stop it,
you gotta stop hurtin' her.
Have you been to your garage today?
No, I ain't, I been too worried.
Well, you take care of your cars,
and I'll take care of my patients.
Now, just you run along.
I ain't runnin' no place.
I ain't no doctor, and I don't know
enough about what you're doing.
But, if anything happens to Frances...
Nothing's going to happen to Frances.
Now, don't interfere.
Here comes Danny with the Doctor.
How do you do, Dr. Adrian?
Mrs. Clifford.
Well, how is my patient
feeling this morning?
I'm all right.
She's been in great pain, Doctor.
In pain?
Well, that's good.
Good?
Of course it is,
that's what we are looking for.
Now, you prepare her.
It's working.
You say the name is Mason?
Yeah.
Yes, Doctor, initial H. Anything in
your examination to go into my report?
No, I believe not.
Well, I just said,
"The death was caused
by fractured vertebrae."
I guess that about covers it,
doesn't it?
Yes, I...
I should say that it would.
The reason I sent for you, Doctor, is
because you examined the circus trainer
when he was sent North, and this
case being a similar one to that,
I thought probably in your examination
that you had discovered something
that I had over looked
to put in my coroner's report.
I see.
This Dr. Adrian, whose name
is on the death certificate,
is he the local physician?
Yes, if you can call him one.
Folks around here don't
like him much though.
And he was also called in
on the case of the trainer?
Yes, yes, that's the same fellow.
He came here during the
paralysis epidemic.
But, the folks around here
say that he experiments too much.
Thank you very much, Coroner.
I believe you've given me
all the information necessary.
That's fine, Doctor.
Oh.
Ohh.
Frances, what do you feel?
Oh, my legs.
They're hurting?
Oh, they hurt terribly. Feel more
sensation than you had yesterday?
Oh yes, much more.
But, you think perhaps you could walk?
Oh no.
Then, try to move your foot.
Oh, I can't!
You can, try!
No.
You can!
No!
Yes.
Oh my... Mother!
Ohh.
It's working.
Now, you rest, you rest,
and I'll be back later.
Mother.
I know I'll be able to walk again.
I know, Baby.
I know.
Dr. Adrian?
That's right. I'm Dr. McNulty
from the Robinson Foundation.
Oh, yes.
I had occasion to examine the
body of a circus trainer,
who was killed by an ape here
in this town. Yes, Sir.
I understand that you, uh,
administered to the wounded
man before he died.
I did my best for him,
but it was quite hopeless.
In spite of the spinal
injection you gave him?
I gave him no injection.
I just came from viewing
the body of this man Mason,
and I noticed a similar
spinal puncture.
Did you examine him also?
Well, they called me in, of course,
but it was too late, he was dead.
And you noticed no such puncture?
Well, the body was so
badly mangled that, uh...
Well, no, I didn't.
I see.
I understand they've had
an epidemic of paralysis here.
That's true. Many years ago,
the Robinson Foundation
found it necessary to
expel from the institution
a most promising young
research worker,
because of his daring, unorthodox
experiments with spinal fluid.
It was 25 years ago, to be exact.
Then, you are that
Dr. Bernard Adrian,
whose definite theories... And in spite
of what you did to me for 25 years,
I've been engaged in
proving those theories.
By what method have you been
doing this?
I'm not in a position
to disclose that at the moment.
I see.
Well, I'm afraid you leave me
no alternative but to report...
Wait.
If I could give you some small measure
of proof, will you change your mind?
I doubt it.
Let me show you.
I'll show you.
Now, you see?
Now, these two creatures
were completely paralyzed.
But, after my treatment, well,
you can see for yourself,
they're as lively and
healthy as ever they were.
All this has nothing to do
with the case. But, it has!
The serum I used...
What became of the serum
you took from those two men?
Well, you come with me.
Oh, Doctor.
Hello, Mrs. Clifford.
Now, this is Dr. McNulty.
How do you do, Doctor?
And he'd like to talk to Frances.
She's asleep.
No, I am not asleep, Mother.
Hello, Frances.
Hello.
But, now this child has
had a complete paralysis
of her lower limbs for 10 years.
Is that right, Mrs. Clifford?
Yes, it is, Doctor.
Have you had any feeling at
all in your limbs since, uh,
Dr. Adrian has been treating you?
Yes, they've been terribly heavy,
and I've had a great deal of pain.
Pain? Yes, and just a little
while ago I moved my foot.
Is that right?
That's right.
Will you do it again for me?
I can't.
Make an effort.
Thank you, that's all.
I think you'd better take
her out into the sunshine.
Is anything wrong, Doctor? Why,
no, Frances Dear, of course not.
Well, her foot did not move.
But, I did feel a definite
muscular reflex.
Congratulations.
May I notify the foundation that...
That you'll come back to us?
It's too late.
I have to stay here.
At least give me your promise
to keep us informed of your progress.
Every step of the way.
Thank you.
If it's not finished,
it's not finished.
Gee, look fellas,
do ya see somethin'?
Yeah. Yeah, so wait till you
see the white of his eyes.
Maybe they ain't white. I'm gonna
take a chance and shoot now.
Ahh!
Ah!
Come here, Willie!
I don't care how busy you are, Jeff
Halliday, I want my Willie found.
The idea of him wondering around
in the dark with that gorilla loose!
Which none of you men seem
able to capture.
Oh, it's all your nephew's fault: He's
always leading my little Willie astray!
Well, he's always under
Mickey's heels! Oh...
Now, Ladies,
we've got work to do.
Your kids are just some place
where they shouldn't be.
That ain't nothing new.
Have you looked down in
Jones's barn?
I caught 'em smokin' there
last week.
We searched the whole town.
Go take a look for 'em, Pete.
They ain't far away.
Sheriff! Sheriff!
Sheriff!
Where have you been?
Just a minute Mom, we got him!
We got him!
Oh, oh, what... What is it?
Mickey killed him, he shot him dead!
Bang, bang! Between the eyes!
Hold it, kids.
What'd you shoot him with, Mickey?
My.22, I got a good bead on him.
Where is your.22, Mickey?
He dropped it, Sheriff.
I did not! The ape grabbed it.
I'll ape you when I get you home.
Aw, gee, Ma,
don't you believe us?
Where did you see him?
On the pike,
about a quarter mile
from Doc Adrian's house.
All right, get 'em home.
Come on, Mickey.
Come on, Willie.
You're going home with me.
Come on, get out.
They probably shot a cow.
Yeah.
I'll look into it.
Where are the dogs? Red's got 'em
over on the other side of town.
All right, let's go.
Wait a minute, Boys.
I want a word with the Doctor.
I'll be right out.
Okay.
Is the Doctor in?
Yes?
Sheriff.
Well, good evening, Sheriff. Just
wanted to see if you were all right.
Haven't been out, have ya?
No.
I'm trying to think out,
Doctor, a lot of things.
That ape seems to take
a fancy to your place.
Now, don't take offense, Doctor,
I'm just trying to clear up my mind.
Them dogs of mine have been
sniffin' ape for days.
It's made 'em foolish, I guess,
else why'd they snarl at ya?
Well, there may be some chemical odors
on my clothes that offended them.
Uh-huh, but I ain't never seen
my dogs offended at anything.
Can't understand it, Doctor.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
Jane?
Just get me that torn coat
of the trainer's, will you?
Now, this is an idea that's just occurred to
me, I don't know whether it makes sense or not,
but perhaps it'll explain
your problem.
You see, this coat was worn by the
trainer when he was mauled by the ape,
and it's been in the house
ever since.
Now, that perhaps explains the
interest of the ape in this house,
and your dogs' in me.
No, no, no, I bet you're right.
Well, I'll get along. I think I'll
put a few men around your house
the rest of the night, Doctor,
just so you'll be protected.
Don't bother, I am perfectly safe
and they might interfere with
some work that I have to do.
Well, maybe I'll just
keep an eye out myself.
I'm just a bit scared, Doc,
but don't tell anybody.
I won't.
What's that? This here's the
coat that trainer was wearing
when the ape killed him.
Boy, did he rip that up.
Tear it up with one swipe.
Well, come on now, Boys.
Well, this isn't getting us anywhere.
We lay down on this job, our own
coats will be in the same shape.
Come on, let's get busy. Now, you
fellows get back to your positions.
You boys go up this way.
All right, Sheriff.
I'll stay here.
I can't fail.
Now, Frances Dear.
I want you to forget all the
hours you've spent in this chair.
Put them out of your mind.
You are not paralyzed,
you never were.
Fasten that firmly in your mind.
You're not paralyzed.
You'll do that for me?
I'll try.
Don't forget,
you are not paralyzed.
Now then,
move your right leg.
Move it! You can!
No, I can't.
Try, try, you can.
Stop it! You're hurting her!
Quiet!
I can't, Dr. Adrian.
Try it, Frances, you can,
you know you can.
Move... There, you moved it,
didn't you? You moved it.
Now the left one, now the
left one, now move it.
Try, try again.
There! You moved them, you moved
them both, didn't you, Dear?
Yes.
All right then,
stand up and take a step
towards me.
Do it! Do it!
It's only your mind holding
you in that chair, not your body.
Do it, I say, do it!
You see, I told you!
Go get her some water.
Oh, she's all right, Danny.
She's better than she was,
isn't she?
She needs more.
You take care of her, Danny.
I'll be back.
Oh, Frances Darling.
Frances.
Name is Halliday, Sheriff
over the Red Creek.
How did y'all find it here? Well, circus
jobs are pretty hard to get, Sheriff.
Oh, all jobs are kinda scarce.
Your boys get that ape yet?
That's what I come about.
Didn't get him, huh?
That's bad, he's a killer.
You boys got some responsibility
tracking him down, haven't ya?
Well, we did the best we could,
Sheriff, but fire broke up the circus.
Some of the boys stayed there, didn't they?
Yeah, but that's not what I come about.
I just figured when you're looking for
something, might help to know its habits.
Too many things about this
animal I don't understand.
Well, animals is all alike.
Lions, elephants, dogs,
they all got one track minds.
What do these gorillas live on?
He ain't killed any animals. Shucks,
no, they won't touch an animal,
'cept out of meanness.
They live on fruits,
vegetables and such.
That's what's bothering me:
What's feeding this fellow?
Maybe digging up a garden patch or
two, stealing a little bit of fruits.
No signs of it,
checked with all the farmers.
Do they prowl around much,
or do they stick to one place?
Well, the gorilla generally sticks to one
place, if he's got anything that he's keepin'.
We see evidence that this
fellow's hanging around one place.
Hey, that ape had it in for
the trainer.
Where'd he die?
In the house of a doctor
near the outskirts of town, and that's the
place we think the ape's been hanging around.
Say, how would he trace
the trainer to that house?
Well, sense of smell.
They're pretty good at that.
Did ya bury him in town? No, we sent
his body to his people up North.
That don't give us much, does it?
Any of his clothes around?
When that trainer was taken away, his
coat was left in the Doctor's house.
Would that draw the ape there?
It certainly would.
You'd better get rid of him.
I was afraid my time might be wasted
coming over here,
but I guess it ain't.
Thanks very much, Mr. Howley.
I better be gettin' on the road.
I'd like to make home around nightfall.
Anything I can do for ya,
let me know.
Two injections...
Should've been enough.
Take this record book
and keep it for me safely.
One more.
Pete, you two boys go
over there by that shrub.
Danny, take your men down there
100 yards by that rail fence.
Okay. Aw, Sheriff, we've been
watching there every night,
and so far nothing's happened, now
I'm gonna... Will you take orders?
All right, all right.
You two boys go over by
Wilcox's barn.
You mean Wilcox's barn?
Yes, Wilcox's barn.
All right.
You two boys go down the road
100 yards.
You two wait for me over that
stone fence.
All right, Sheriff.
Is the Doctor here?
You sure of that?
He's not in there?
Say, Sheriff, what's the idea sticking
around so close to the Doc's house?
Because that attendant told me that ape would
haunt any place where that trainer had been.
Ohh.
Hey, what's getting into that Sheriff?
He's... He's getting touchy.
Lost his sense of humor.
You know, when a man
can't laugh, it's just...
George, isn't this where we
found the body?
Mhm.
Um, do apes ever return
to the scene of a crime?
They're noted for it.
Well, we got something to
look forward to.
Ah!
George! George!
Archie.
George!
What's a matter?
He got me.
Fire a shot.
Come on!
Did ya hear that shot? Yes, but
you told us not to leave here.
Where was it?
That way.
Over that way.
What is it?
What's a matter?
Did you fire that shot?
Yes.
It's Tomlin. The ape twisted
his neck, but Archie knifed him.
Can you walk? Pick him up and
carry him... Oh, I'm all right.
Go and get him.
God, he can't be far away.
Come on, get out, get
on from here, Fellows.
You boys come with me.
Doctor!
Look out, Doctor! The ape!
The ape!
Doctor, the ape! Doctor!
Do ya hear that?
Yeah.
Doctor! Dr. Adrian!
Doctor!
Oh, let me go! Don't stop me! No, no,
Frances, I'll see what's happened.
Frances!
Let me give him one, Sheriff!
Hold on, that's enough.
He's done.
What are they doing? What are they
saying? Oh, Darling, I don't know.
It's the Doc.
All right, Boys,
take that off of him.
Let me through!
Did the ape hurt him?
Dr. Adrian.
Frances.
Come to me, Child.
Walk.
There, you see?
He's dead, Boys.
Ohh!
Hello, Danny.
No, wait, Danny.
Honey, you...
You mustn't over do it.
I'm doing better every day, Danny.
Oh, sure.
You're doing swell,
but you gotta take it easy.
I'll get your chair.
No, Danny.
Mother and I burned the chair yesterday.
I'm never going to use it again.
You bet you won't.