Give me a hand here, cash.
Ooh, you know I will.
Poor little cuss.
It appears to me
we'll be splitting our grubstake
three ways from now on, cash.
Yeah. I reckon so.
Ohh. What have we got
that'll fit his gizzard?
He can't chaw jerky.
Oh, you don't know nothin'.
Oatmeal gruel and a mite of bacon grease
will see him through.
Come on, partner.
Ohh.
Yes, sir.
Give me a hand here with the boy, cash.
You know I will.
- Hey.
- Hey, you little rascal, you.
Hey. Giddyap. Giddyap.
Here. You're going to get
your shirt on now, bill.
Here. That's right.
Pretty little cuss, ain't he, Jeff?
- He sure is.
- Yeah.
Looks just like me.
Don't you, bill?
Hmm.
- Here we are. Here we are.
- Hey.
- Here we are, boy.
Oh, jeez, that boy.
Hmm. Bill sure does love me, Jeff.
Mines.
Come on, baby.
Boy...
Attaboy.
Lovely boy.
Here. Take a swig of this, bill.
It'll put hair on your chest.
Don't be giving that Maverick poison.
And don't be calling him bill.
Once and for all, cash holbrook,
we're callin' him Daniel Boone Cameron.
And once and for all, Jeff Cameron,
we're calling him buffalo bill holbrook.
I've put up with your bullheadedness
about long enough.
Bullheadedness? Me?
Why, you hammer-headed old mule.
You're as stubborn
about branding that yearling as...
As you are about wanting
to settle down here
at this measly water hole.
Water means a grubstake
in this country, cash.
We're stayin' right here.
No. We ain't.
You are.
Grubstake's just about as far
as you can see.
I'm headin' west till I hit grazing land.
I've put up with your stubbornness
ever since we started out, Jeff.
Now I'm done with you.
If you're headin' west,
it seems to me you'd best get goin'.
Now, then, I'll take Dan.
- Bill's going with me.
- Oh, no, he ain't.
He's too smart for you, holbrook.
He's a Cameron,
and he knows where he belongs.
He's a bit young to know what a pigheaded
old hyena you are, Cameron.
But I'll learn him.
You wouldn't plug Dan...
Would you, Cameron?
And if you was to drill me in the back
while I was riding away,
why, you'd just naturally bust
bill's neck.
Mary Ellen?
- Yes, dad?
- They're comin'.
Put your ear to the ground.
- Cattle.
- Yep.
You see? I was right, Mary Ellen.
When I seen that big, ornery bill holbrook
riding the Ridge this morning,
I figured that him and his old man
was up to something.
Dad, them two are just alike,
meaner than two rattlers.
Cash holbrook ruined the boy, Mary Ellen.
He was a lively young'un when I found him.
Well, dad, if they think they're
gonna water cattle here tonight,
here's two winchesters say they ain't.
We'll get to the water hole
quicker that way.
All right, turn it.
You know more about it than I do, Kirby.
I ain't set foot on Jeff Cameron's land
in a good many years.
I wouldn't be doing it tonight
if this herd wasn't drying up on me.
Well, we won't have no trouble.
There ain't nobody at the water hole
but old Cameron and his daughter.
I don't care if there's 50 of them.
Cameron ain't keepin' me away
from that water no longer.
So long.
Listen.
What was that?
Someone afoot.
Stay where you are.
What do you want here?
Water. I can use some.
My name's rance Brett.
Had to shoot my horse today.
Prairie dog hole.
This is the first water I've seen since.
I don't know this country.
You don't know cash holbrook
neither, I suppose?
Who?
Go ahead, fill up.
Thanks, mister.
Well?
Who's this, uh, holbrook
you were talkin' about?
You never heard of him, I suppose.
Miss, I'm from Montana,
and I'm headed new Mexico way.
What was your name in Montana?
Brett. Same as here.
And I'm headed new Mexico way.
At least I was.
While I had a horse.
Seems like I've stepped
into something here, mister.
Might be you'd care
to enlighten me of what.
Cameron's my name. Jeff Cameron.
My daughter, Mary Ellen.
I'm honored to know you, miss Cameron.
This here is my livin'.
The only water hole
between the range and the railroad.
Cowmen all water here
on their way to the loading pens.
All but one.
This, uh, holbrook fella?
Yeah.
I make him go the long way for water.
Twenty-seven miles across the desert,
losing beef every mile.
Why?
Got a match?
When they smell that water,
they're going big for a lection.
Fire and brimstone won't stop 'em.
Neither will Jeff Cameron.
I got married and settled down here.
He kept on persecuting me.
Why, it wasn't a month after her ma died,
he tried to stampede me into selling.
It began right here,
and it's liable to end right here,
tonight.
- Meaning what?
- Meaning this.
Miss, do you aim to take aim?
I do if a holbrook crosses our line.
Well, the odds ain't with you.
Perhaps it'd even them up a little if I
might offer to throw in with you folks.
Thanks just the same.
Well, put it this way:
Maybe I could work it out around here
long enough to get me a horse.
Startin' tonight.
They're comin'.
Throw a saddle onto one of them broncs.
We'll ride out to meet 'em.
Good enough.
They won't get in here tonight.
They're gettin' mighty uneasy.
They're liable to start any minute now.
We'll tangle with them right here.
Mary Ellen, you get behind them rocks.
Brett, you go hold out
on the other side of that wash.
I'll stay here.
Don't take no chances with yourself, now.
There they go!
Whoa.
- It's a bunch of rustlers!
- No, it ain't.
Cameron's got men to help him.
They're stampeding the herd
away from the water hole!
What happened?
I'll tell you what's happened.
They're not holbrook's cattle at all.
But holbrook's got men running off stock
that's being drove to my water.
He's tryin' to break me.
Well, it might've been worse.
We only lost a few head.
Jeff Cameron declared war on me
when he drove them cattle off tonight.
Before it's over,
I'll drive him out of the country.
I wonder who those men was helpin' him.
I'll find that out too.
- And when I do...
- Take it easy.
I ran that herd out of there tonight, dad.
You ran that herd off?
What's to make of all this, son?
I'll tell you, dad.
I ran those cattle off to keep you
and Jeff Cameron from killing each other.
Hmm.
And who appointed you
to be my guardian angel?
You and Jeff split over me, dad.
Tonight, when I learned you
was gonna tangle, I had to stop it.
Yeah, and make a fool out of me
right in front of him,
to say nothin' of the cattle lost.
Dad, you and Jeff shared
your last flapjack once.
Since then, you've wasted
all those years hating each other.
But it's not too late.
I've got something to show you.
You see that?
Hmm.
Well, what is it?
What about it?
That is tungsten ore.
There might be a little gold
and silver in it too.
But the tungsten is what counts.
And I've located a rich deposit of it.
But there's a catch to it.
Just what are you driving at?
Well, the man that owns the land that
this is on doesn't even know it's there.
If he did, he couldn't mine it.
He's broke.
You've got the money,
and I know how to run a mine.
You can help him.
And he was once your friend.
Now do you know who I mean?
You mean Jeff Cameron?
Jeff Cameron.
He needs your help, dad.
He's old, and he's getting tired.
He'll give in if you'll let him.
Did I hear right?
You want me to make up to him?
I think it's about time you did, dad.
I raised you single-handed and alone.
I sent you to mining school
when you ought to have been punching cows.
Right.
I always let you have your say,
most always your own way.
But I'll see you eternally
in fire and brimstone
before I let you stand up there
and tell me to be friend to Jeff Cameron.
I didn't tell you, dad. I asked you.
A man sure gets punishment
for his mistakes.
When I picked you up on the desert,
I made mine.
I don't know what kind
of blood you got in you,
but I know it ain't my kind.
I'll say good night to you on that.
And when I get up in the morning,
I don't think you'd better be here.
You and Jeff...
Have spent half your lives
building a wall that separates you...
When you should've been friends.
But someday I'll break it down.
Good-bye... dad.
Whoa.
Afternoon, miss Mary.
You stay where you are, bill holbrook.
Is your father in?
I'd like to talk to him.
You must be craving trouble to come here
after what you done last night.
Last night?
Don't try to brazen it out.
I saw you and your hands
run them cattle off.
You must feel mighty proud of yourself,
takin' away our livin'.
If you'll excuse me now,
I'll go and talk to your father.
You'll not set foot on our land.
I'll take care of him, Mary Ellen.
You ride over
and get a hold of rance Brett.
He's stringing new wire up at the gap.
What are you doing here?
Mr. Cameron,
I'd like to have a little talk with you.
I ain't got nothin' to talk to you about.
You will have
when you've heard what I've got to say.
Your threats don't bother me none.
Get on inside.
Now, then, do your talkin',
and talk mighty careful.
Hi there! Mary Ellen!
Hello there, tonopah!
Hey! Come on, heliotrope.
See who's waitin' for you.
Look who's waitin' to see you, doggone ya.
Come on.
Well, Mary Ellen.
Why, you're gettin' prettier every day.
How's old heliotrope?
Oh, lazier than the deuce.
Where you in from this time, tonopah?
Tornado basin. Whew.
My gosh, I pretty near dried up
and blowed away.
Where you runnin' off to?
Oh, dad's got that bill holbrook inside,
and I'm gonna go over and...
- Bill holbrook?
- Yeah.
Oh, doggone it.
I knowed I had some news for you.
Hey, listen. Listen to this.
I came by holbrook's this morning,
and, uh, there ain't been a ruckus
like that around here
like they had in years,
and I went up and I...
If you... uh, doggone it, maybe I'd better
begin at the beginning, huh?
Yeah. Well...
On my land,
and it takes my water to mine it.
That's right.
Well...
I made out alone a good many years.
And I ain't takin' a holbrook
for a partner just yet.
If you can borrow money
at the bank to mine this stuff,
so can I.
Yes, you can, Jeff.
Say...
How come you have to borrow money?
Have you fought with cash holbrook?
With cash? After what he's done for me?
No, but he's fought with you.
Ain't that it?
I knowed it.
Cash wouldn't have no truck with me.
No more than I would with him.
But he's on the outs with you...
Over that.
Jeff, cash thinks he's right
in hating you.
Just the same as you think
you're right in hating him.
But you're both dead wrong.
I've told him that. Now I'm telling you.
And someday
I'll make you both believe it.
Never. Don't you try it.
- I'll never stop.
- Might as well.
That stuff can lay in the ground
till judgment day
before I have dealings with a holbrook.
Well...
That's what I am.
Hold on.
By the eternal, you ain't.
You're a Cameron by rights. I found you.
You pointed me out to be your pa
right here at this water hole years ago.
Did I, Jeff? You sure did.
And I knowed I'd get you back someday.
You belong right here.
I'll throw in with you, bill.
Mean Dan.
Water and all. Give me that stuff.
So, you see, Mary Ellen,
in doing what he allowed
was right about them cattle,
he riled cash holbrook
into throwing him out of the house.
Well, I've got to be in town a few days,
but we'll break ground in about a week.
When cash holbrook hears about this,
he'll have to be hog-tied.
Come here.
- See you in about a week.
- Good luck.
Well, Jeff, doggone it,
I'm glad to see you. How be you?
Hello, tonopah.
Say, bill holbrook, uh, was over here,
and you and him seemed
to be kind of friendly, don't you?
- You bet we're friendly.
- Yeah.
Say, did you hear about what happened
between he and cash?
- Yes, I heard...
- They had an awful rumpus.
Yes, I...
Cash throwed his own boy out of the house.
His own boy, mind you.
What do you mean? What?
What do you mean, his own boy?
He's my boy.
Your... how could you... would you...
He's my boy now.
I've got something to say to you.
I've got no use for you,
and I've been raised to hate
everything that carries your brand.
But I've got to tell you
that, well, I'm sorry for what I said.
I didn't know then why you run
them cattle off last night.
It's mighty nice of you to say that,
miss Mary.
You know, you had me a mite uneasy
with that Winchester.
What have you been talking dad into?
Lots of things.
So, you see, you and your dad will have
more money than you'll ever need.
You can have all the things
you've always wanted,
all the things you should've had.
Oh, it... it doesn't seem possible
anything so wonderful could happen to us.
It's always been out there,
but I'm glad I was the one
that found it for you.
Hmm. You know,
the desert's taken so much out of dad.
Gee, it doesn't seem possible
it's about to pay it all back.
I'm happier for him even than I am for me.
Mary Ellen,
look out there across the desert.
As far as you can see.
Way off there in the distance.
Do you see those big, lonesome pinnacles?
When I was a little boy,
I used to lie out there evenings,
watching the shadows cross over them.
I used to imagine
they were all sorts of things.
- Dragons fighting.
- Hmm.
Giants lying there, sleeping.
And great, big monsters
that might come down after it got dark
and get me.
I know. I used to think that way too.
You got over it though.
Over it? Why, sure.
As soon as I knew what they really was...
Just big rocks.
But before that, you were a little bit
afraid of them, weren't you?
Yes, I was.
Well, it's just that way with folks.
Now, way off in the distance
of you or mine,
there's a terrible man
called cash holbrook.
To you, he's been one
of those awful monsters
that you used to imagine.
But I've been up close to him
in the broad daylight,
and to me, he's been a kind man
and mighty good.
I never had anyone make things
so sort of clear to me before.
Hmm. Would you think I was kind of crazy
if I asked you to forgive me
for the thoughts I've held
about you all these years?
I can't do that, Mary Ellen.
There's nothing to forgive.
I hope there won't never be.
Well, we've done it, we've done it.
There she sits.
The first load ready to roll,
and it's right on time.
And none too soon.
You know something, Jeff?
Banks have a very funny habit
of wanting their money on time.
And they'll get their wish tomorrow.
And from then on, those wagons
will keep right on rolling.
And the mine will pay its way.
I guess I'm all ready. The wagons
are about to start, I guess, huh?
You're not sorry you're going,
though, are you?
Of course she ain't.
Mary Ellen always wanted to go to school.
Ain't you, Mary Ellen?
Yes, but it's gonna seem kind of lonesome
being away from all of you.
Shucks, it won't be no time
before a vacation comes around.
No, sir.
Come on.
Say, what's...
What's in you?
Friend... why... why ain't you
down there with the folks?
What for?
Well, to say good-bye to Mary Ellen.
I only work here. I got the teams ready.
I guess that lets me out,
as far as she's concerned.
Well, I know, but doggone it,
she's going away.
She's going to school.
- Yeah, I know.
- Yeah.
Great idea.
It took bill holbrook to think that up.
Eh? What?
That girl in town alone.
Oh, she's gonna live with old lady Gilroy.
She won't be lonesome.
And bill holbrook will have to be
gettin' in town every week or two.
Yeah?
That'll be great.
You bet "twill.
None of that, now, or I'll be smackin'
the daylights out of you.
Help her there, Carson.
I'm gonna launch
this here "pe-rade” right.
I'm gonna bust a bottle
of real old corn right on her nose.
Come on.
J and bury me not on the lone prairie I
I where the wild coyotes...
Oh. Oh, rance?
Hey, hold on there, everybody. Listen.
When they launch a cornerstone,
they christen it.
Uh, same as when they christen a ship,
they launch a cornerstone, you understand?
Well, uh, same as...
Same as you christen a mine.
And that's that.
Now I'm gonna christen
the... I'm gonna Chris...
I'm gonna... ohh. Hey. Ohh.
Oh, doggone you, I christen you.
Good-bye, rance.
Why, what's the matter?
Nothing.
All ready, boss.
All right, let her go.
- Good-bye, Mary Ellen.
- Good-bye, bill.
You'll come to see me soon,
won't you, bill?
What do you think?
- Good-bye.
I'll tuck him in bed every night!
Get!
There's cash holbrook.
Is this his land we're going through?
Yeah. Both sides of us,
from here to the canyon.
And ya get! Get!
Get out at it. Get.
Get out at it.
Well, it looks like the boy and Cameron
was doin' pretty good.
Think so?
Come on.
Get! Get!
Come on. Get!
There, look. There's someone on the Ridge.
Oh, just some of the cowhands
comin' in off the range, that's all.
Why don't they use the road, I wonder?
Oh, they ain't civilized enough.
Denver, look. There they are again.
Just don't fret yourself, now.
Hey.
What's the matter?
What's happened? What's wrong?
- Are you hurt, boy?
- No, ma'am.
But we're shy seven tons of ore
and two wagons
and quite some mule-power though.
Where'd they get to? Who was it?
We was kind of busy.
We didn't stop to ask.
Don't be squabblin' about that.
We want to get Mary Ellen out of here.
Come on, fellas. Hop on.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
Make it easier, now.
Roll on into town.
I'll beat it back to the mine
and tell bill.
Get! Get! Get! Get!
- What?
- Why, it's Tex.
What's going on here? Let's go and see.
What happened?
Easy, boss. Wait a minute.
- What's the matter, Doyle?
- Somebody's plugged him.
What happened, Tex? Are you hurt bad?
They... they got us at the rim.
Are you sure she's all right?
Yes. Got through. In town by now.
Boys, get him into my house quick.
Doyle, get both your shifts out.
We're gonna start loading.
Brett, I've got to have
two wagons and a tank.
- Get them mules on 'em.
- Okay.
And listen, a thousand dollars for the
shift that gets their wagon loaded first.
Bring down some torches.
Did you see anything of cash holbrook?
Yeah. Passed him, some of his men.
Crossing, he is, north 160.
I knowed it.
Cash holbrook done that.
Cash didn't have any more
to do with that than I did.
Nobody but him would ever...
That's enough, Jeff. You're wrong.
We've got to get seven tons of ore
into that railroad by morning,
or the bank will be in the mining business
instead of us.
And I'm gonna drive.
Is he hurt bad, Charlie?
Just creased a little, bill.
Oh, he'll be all right.
Take it easy, boy.
I'm goin' with you.
If cash holbrook thinks he can get away
with anything like this, I...
You're gonna stay right here on the job.
And I'll tell you something else.
I'm goin' through.
Nobody's gonna stop me.
Do you understand that?
Nobody.
Hurry up, boys.
We're comin' to the canyon rim!
Hang on!
- What about you, Flynn?
- I never thought of it.
Well, tiny, you ought to know.
Here comes Carson and the boys.
Set out a bottle, clem.
They'll be wantin' it.
Right, yes.
Seen the sheriff yet?
No, he's over to red rock.
Be back tomorrow.
- Gentlemen.
- Hi, judge.
The silver dollar welcomes you.
Have one on the house, boys.
Ah.
Well, how's the little lady feeling?
I, uh... oh, here's Denver now.
How's Mary Ellen, Denver?
Well, miss Gilroy finally
got to lay down for a spell.
Excited state. She's rare.
She wanted to start back
to the mine on horseback.
Worried about bill, huh?
Worried? She's loco about him.
Bill holbrook? Mm.
Yeah.
Wow. Wait'll his old man hears about that.
- Hi, Santa fe.
- All right.
Here's your bill of lading, Carson.
All right, Santa fe. Have a drink.
Sure! I never refuse.
- How are you, Santa fe?
- Howdy.
A lot of good that's gonna do us.
Seven tons of ore on the car,
and seven more
in the bottom of the canyon.
Yeah, if that old rib-pickin' buzzard...
Say, what is his name?
- At the bank?
- Stilson.
That's him.
He won't wait five minutes for his dough.
He'd love to get his hooks into that mine.
Well, that's pretty near now, yeah?
Time enough for another load,
if Tex got through.
Say, who do you allow done it?
- Dumpin' the wagons?
- Yeah.
Well, I'd say it was cash holbrook.
Don't you think that's
a pretty broad statement, young fella?
Well, givin' you a straight answer,
judge, I don't.
You talk a whole lot with your mouth,
don't you, Steve?
He's right.
Holbrook wouldn't stop at nothin'
when it comes to Jeff Cameron.
Hey. Cash holbrook just rolled in town.
Yeah?
What's that?
It's bill!
Give us a hand up here, Carson.
They plugged Sullivan.
Line them up.
I'll get on the other side.
Hand him down here, bill!
Take it easy, boy.
Did you get any of 'em?
Don't know. I didn't wait to see.
Hey, is Mary Ellen all right?
You bet. She's resting over at Gilroy's.
- Good.
- I'll get doc partridge, bill.
Okay, buck.
Well, did you see who they was?
No, they tried to stampede us
into the canyon.
That's what they done to me.
Carson, you get that ore
over there to the car.
Yeah.
Santa fe, go along with him,
and hurry that bill of lading, will ya?
Sure thing, bill.
I'll have it here in ten minutes.
Cummings, you can go in
and tell old man stilson
to write "paid in full”
right across that note of mine.
Bill! Bill, you're safe!
I knew you'd try and bring
those wagons through, and I...
Oh, bill.
The wagons had to come in, honey.
And I had to know how you were.
Oh, I'm all right, but...
Well, you'll have to go back there.
I won't let you, bill.
I couldn't stand it.
Honey...
Oh, judge Matthews,
do you think you could arrange
to marry a couple of people,
say, about, uh, 4:00 this afternoon?
If my suspicions is correct
as to the parties involved,
I should be most honored.
Hey, provney, will you ride out
to the mine and get a hold of Jeff?
Sure thing, bill.
Buck?
How's the chance of a loan
of a comb and brush?
Huh? =a comb and brush.
I got a good curry comb over at the barn.
All right, clear out of there!
You be all right here, dynamite?
Yeah, plenty far.
You know, Cameron, if I'm right...
Of course, I could be wrong...
But if I'm right...
Wait'll I get these Jacks
up to the corral, dynamite.
The blast won't bother them.
Go ahead, rance.
As I was sayin'...
Of course, I could be wrong...
But if I'm right,
there's somebody takin' dynamite
out of my powder house.
Takin"? You mean stealin'?
Yes, sir.
Now, today, I counted out what I had.
Then I figured out what I ought to have.
And there's somebody around here...
Say, by heck, you know,
that fits in with something
that happened last night.
Somebody around here's stealin' it.
Say, look here, Jeff,
I didn't sleep very well last night,
and I heard something,
because I couldn't do it
with the bad tooth I got here, see?
I did...
And if I find out who it is, I'll...
What's that?
- Somebody else shootin'?
- There hadn't better be.
- Who's using powder down there?
- Nobody. We don't know what's happened.
Clear, everybody! She's coming down!
- Anybody hurt?
- No, everybody got clear.
A minute ago, that was a producing mine,
payin' its way.
Now it's...
Nothin'.
Brett...
You'd better ride into town.
I don't feel quite up to it.
Tell bill... the Cameron mining company...
Ain't in business anymore.
Well, bill, looks like now they'll be
puttin' the old branding iron on you.
Oh, he ain't the first bronc
who broke a harness.
Maybe not the first,
but sure enough the luckiest.
- Yeah.
- My boy.
In my many years as presiding justice
in this here township,
I have never looked forward
to splicing the holy bonds of matrimony
unto no young couple
with more salubrious feelings
of admiration and esteem.
Hey!
To our...
Illustrative fellow citizen
William holbrook
and his charming bride-to-be.
- Thank you, judge.
- Folks, let's partake.
Hold on, fellers. Right after the wedding,
me and buck here is givin'
a barbecue up to the ranch,
and everybody in town's invited!
Does that take in cash holbrook?
Cash holbrook!
Hello, dad.
I'll take rye, bartender.
Holbrook, Jeff Cameron
sent me in town to find you.
- What's wrong?
- Plenty.
There's been a slide at the mine.
The mill's gone
and both shafts are filled.
There's nothing left.
Anybody hurt?
No, the first blast warned 'em.
They was all out when she let go.
Blast? What do you mean? What happened?
The men say it sounded like
four explosions, the number-two drift.
On the last one,
half the mountain cut loose.
Well, I guess we're all through.
What do they think happened?
They think what half this town's thinking.
What's that?
Cash holbrook.
Do you know cash holbrook?
No.
Well, he and Jeff Cameron have been
enemies for a good many years.
He had a boy that he'd raised.
Threw him out of his house.
Folks always said that he
was mighty fond of that boy.
Heh. Didn't look much like it
when he done that.
The boy and Jeff Cameron went partners.
Since then, he's hated Cameron
worse than ever.
He's had more reason to be back of this
than any man in the world.
Do you think he done it?
No.
Oh, uh, cummings.
When the bank opens up in the morning,
I want my account fixed up
so's it can be drawed on
right up to the last two-bit piece
by my boy...
I'll take rye, bartender.
Thanks, cash.
But one thing more.
Half my share in the mine belongs to you.
If that's the way you want it.
Can we step into your office a minute,
judge?
Indeed.
I want you to arrange something for me,
judge.
I'll be glad to.
Cummings.
I'm part owner in Jeff Cameron's mine.
That makes me part owner in the Wells.
Got a herd on the way
to the railroad right now.
They're going to water
at Jeff Cameron's Wells.
Tonight.
- What'll you have?
- Uh, small beer.
Bartender. Small beer?
Yes.
"To cash holbrook."
- Half interest?
- In my share.
- Jeff Cameron here?
- Yes.
I work for him, ma'am.
Sign it right there, my boy.
Judge...
I'd rather you'd give this to him.
Well, how about the wedding?
Don't you want him there?
Sure I do, but he'd never come.
I'll see you at the courthouse at 4:00.
All right, judge.
Judge...
I'm going to water beef tonight
at Cameron's well.
Don't let nobody tell bill.
It would only rile him.
There goes trouble.
Where is bill?
He went out.
=I'll find him. Wait a minute.
Hello, Jeff. Glad you got in all right.
It's the first time I've had a chance
to ask you about Mary Ellen.
How's for your partner
being your son-in-law?
You ain't my partner.
You ain't never gonna be nothin' to me.
What do you mean by that, Jeff?
One thing I hate to admit to
is being mistook in my judgment of a man.
I've always told myself
you wasn't a holbrook.
But you are.
The thing you just done
proved it to me once and forever.
The thing I just done?
Sold me out to cash holbrook.
But, Jeff, we were all through.
Cash offered us help, and I took it.
Of course you took it. Why not?
You'd side with him against me
and believe him when he lied
it was to help me.
"Help me."
He's been trying to get ahold of my Wells
ever since we split.
Now he's done it, and you've helped him!
- You're wrong, Jeff.
- Wrong?
And him drivin' his cattle
in there tonight? Answer that.
Say, how did you hear all this, Jeff?
You ain't answered me yet.
I said, how did you hear it?
Rance Brett happened to be right there.
You forgot that.
Mary Ellen...
You don't believe that I did anything.
We all better be gettin' over
to the courthouse, Bob.
It's almost time for the splicing.
Might not be any.
What's that?
Let's have a drink.
No, thanks.
Say, what are you gonna do, Jeff?
Don't let Mary Ellen out of the house.
Cash holbrook ain't gonna water no cattle
at Cameron's Wells tonight.
Oh, you're gonna...
Don't let Mary Ellen out of the house.
I just started out to find you, bill.
Yeah?
This fella Brett.
What about him?
He just said something
that sounded sort of peculiar.
What?
Well, it wasn't so much what he said
as the way he said it.
Yeah?
I've been waitin' for you, Kirby.
We're going to water cattle
at Jeff Cameron's Wells tonight.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I'll tell you what I just heard.
Jeff's lookin' for you.
- He is?
- Yeah.
With a.44.
Bob, I think you're right
about this fella Brett.
I know I am.
Is cash holbrook in the bar?
No, he left.
- Is Brett there?
- Yeah.
Don't follow me in there too soon.
You wait here.
We ain't leavin' town just yet.
Well, he was in the silver dollar
a little while ago.
Thanks.
Now, Mary Ellen, don't you take on
about something
you ain't got nothin' to do with.
Open that gate.
No, sirree Bob.
Jeff said you stay right here.
Tonopah, you open that gate.
No, sir!
- Hello, cash.
- Hello, Jim.
You lookin' for Jeff Cameron?
Supposin'I am?
Well...
He's headed for the silver dollar.
Thanks.
Brett?
I've got something to settle with you.
I never thought I'd have to kill a man.
But it may be that I will.
Brett, you're back of all this trouble.
And what you've done may cost the lives
of two of the finest men on this earth.
Now talk.
Out loud, so everybody can hear you.
And clear cash holbrook.
If you lie to me, I'll know it.
And, Brett, I'll kill you.
All right, holbrook. Here it is.
I did everything. Wagons, mine and all.
And I'd do it again
if you or any other man
come between me and what I want.
That enough?
Everybody hear that?
I think so.
Get movin'.
I don't know which one of you
did that, but...
You're both bad shots.
Give me a hand with the boy,
will you, Jeff?
You know I will, cash.
Bill, what's happened?
Only one thing.
We're going to be a little bit late
at the courthouse, honey.