(somber music plays)
Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
(airplane engines roar)
(suspenseful
militaristic music plays)
(suspenseful militaristic
music continues)
(airplane engine hums)
(suspenseful militaristic
music continues)
(airplane engine roars)
(suspenseful militaristic
music continues)
(upbeat music plays)
(upbeat music continues)
(gentle music plays)
(horse hooves clop)
- [Narrator] This
is a battlefront,
a battlefront like no other
in the long history
of mankind's wars.
This is an air front.
(dramatic music plays)
(dramatic music continues)
The working day begins as it
will end with the ground crews,
as much a part of the
Fortress as her wings.
If you are a mechanic,
you've got your own bomber.
You get attached to it,
but you know when your
ship goes out on a mission,
you may never see it again,
so you do your work as
well as it can be done,
perfectly,
because you wouldn't
want anything to go wrong
that would be your fault.
(dramatic music continues)
Today the bombs will be
taken from these bomb dumps
somewhere in England
and delivered to specific points
in Wilhelmshaven, Germany.
(dramatic music continues)
To deliver them is the job
of the 8th Bomber Command.
Just a hauling job,
yet one of the most
difficult and complicated
of military operations.
(relaxed harmonica music plays)
(suspenseful music plays)
General purpose
demolition bombs,
impact velocity as high
as 750 miles an hour,
pierce five inches
of armor plate,
destroy a factory.
Briefing at 08:00.
Pilots, bombardiers and
navigators take their places.
The group commander,
Colonel Stanley Ray,
steps up to the target map
and for the first time you
learn where you're going.
Sometimes your face turns
white when you find out.
Sometimes the feeling
you won't come back
tightens your insides.
Not so long ago, you
were sitting like this
in a college or high
school classroom,
not listening too hard,
perhaps even a little sleepy.
But you listen here
and as you listen, you don't
have time to think of yourself.
Fear fades.
You concentrate on the mission,
type of formation,
assembly point, zero hour,
route to target, weather,
enemy fighters, enemy flak,
route back home.
If forced down in enemy
territory, destroy equipment.
If taken prisoner,
give no information.
Name, rank and serial
number, that's all.
(emotive music plays)
These are the passengers
with one-way tickets
and this is the crew
of the Memphis Belle,
324th Squadron, 91st
Heavy Bombardment Group.
Just one plane and one crew,
in one squadron, in one group
of one wing of one air force
out of 15 United
States Army air forces.
Well fellas, we've never had
an easy ride over there yet,
and today won't
be any different.
No escort except unfriendly
so keep your eyes peeled.
Don't get excited and yell
when you're talking
on the intercom.
Save your ammunition and
make your shots count.
Let me know what goes
on back there, Quinlan.
Yes, sir.
Stay on the ball, gang,
and she'll bring us back
like she's always done.
Okay, let's go.
They have completed
24 missions in this,
the toughest theater of air war,
the big league of sky fighting.
Their experience is priceless.
And so if the Memphis Belle
comes back this afternoon,
they will be sent to bring
the vital lessons
they have learned
to thousands of aircrew
men in training at home.
Home is America.
(propellers whir)
This is a battlefront like
no other in this or any war.
No monster armies,
no booming cannon,
only the roaring engine
sound of the bombers
pounding through the
quiet English countryside.
This is an air front.
(propellers whir)
(airplane engines growl)
(airplane engines roar)
(airplane engines
continue to roar)
The wheels of the Memphis
Belle leave the soil of England
for the 25th time.
The friendly soil of England,
with its ordered farms
and rural hamlets,
its country estates
surrounded by formal gardens
and well-kept parks.
The England these Americans knew
only from the classics
they had to read in school.
The England of the
towns and cities
whose people have defended
their island's freedom
for over 1,000 years.
But today their
countryside has changed.
Today their island
has been converted
into a gigantic bomber field,
a super aircraft carrier
anchored off the shores
of fortress Europe
with hangers and machine shops,
with hundreds of
dispersal points,
perimeter tracks and
concrete runways.
This is England in
its fifth year of war.
(airplane engines roar)
And this is the new
battlefront, the air front,
from which we seek
out the enemy.
Not his infantry
or his artillery,
not his Panzer divisions,
but the greater menace,
the industrial
heart of his nation,
the foundation on which the
Nazi empire and its army stand,
the power behind the
German lust for conquest.
The steel mills and refineries,
shipyards and submarine pens,
factories and munitions plants,
pinpoints on the map of
Europe which mean rubber,
guns, ball bearings,
shells, engines,
planes, tanks, targets,
targets to be destroyed.
And these are the destroyers,
each with a belly full of bombs
and 10 men like the crew
of the Memphis Belle:
Pilot Captain Robert Morgan,
industrial engineer from
Asheville, North Carolina.
He's flown this ship
across the Atlantic.
The other pilot,
Captain Jim Verinis,
business administration student
at the University
of Connecticut.
Radio operator and gunner,
Sergeant Bob Hanson,
construction worker from
Spokane, Washington.
Navigator, Captain
Chuck Leighton,
chemistry student
at Ohio Wesleyan.
Engineer and top turret
gunner Sergeant Harold Loch
from Green Bay, Wisconsin,
used to be a stevedore.
Besides keeping
the bill in order,
he covers the sky above.
Tail gunner Sergeant John
Quinlan of Yonkers, New York,
clerked for a carpet company
but he quit December 8th, 1941.
Ball turret gunner,
Sergeant Cecil Scott,
pressman for a rubber company
in Rahway, New Jersey.
Pilot to crew,
10,000, put on oxygen.
They're climbing higher now,
300 feet a minute.
The strain on the planes
and on the men is mounting.
The rest of the crew, Bombardier
Captain Vincent Evans,
operated a fleet of trucks
in Fort Worth, Texas.
Waist gunners, on the right,
Sergeant Bill Winchell,
chemist for a paint
company in Chicago
and on the left,
Sergeant Tony Nastal,
used to repair washing
machines in Detroit
when he was a kid.
Now he's 19 and has two
Nazi fighters confirmed.
It takes all of a
pilot's strength
to keep a 30-ton Fortress
in tight formation,
but the formation is the
bomber's best defense
against enemy fighters.
The planes are deployed
to uncover every gun,
stepped up and down,
echelon to the right and left,
arranged to overcome
the danger of gunners
firing into friendly ships,
arranged so concentrated
cones of fire
from the caliber 50
machine guns cover the sky
for 1,000 yards in
every direction.
(airplane engines hum)
The friendly coast of
England slips by below.
It doesn't look like much now,
but in a few hours
when you come back,
if you come back,
this will be the most
beautiful view in the world.
Higher and higher,
climbing to reach your
best operational altitude,
25,000 feet,
five miles straight up,
so high you can't be
seen from the ground
with the naked eye,
so high that after one
minute without oxygen
you lose consciousness.
After 20 minutes, you're dead.
(airplane engines hum)
From now to the target, you
go about your routine duties,
plot your course,
check your equipment
and wait and think.
Higher and colder, temperature
40 degrees below zero.
Take off your glove and
you lose some fingers.
You look out at the
strange world beyond,
reflections in plexiglass
like nothing you ever saw
before outside of a dream.
(airplane engines
continue to hum)
Higher and higher into
the lightless stratosphere
until the exhaust of the engines
mixing with the cold,
thin air condenses
and streams the heavens
with paper trails.
To the men in the ships,
they're far from beautiful,
for they point like beckoning
fingers to the formation,
signposts in the sky for
the enemy to spot us.
For these bombers to
accomplish their mission,
a plan is needed,
carefully worked out,
timed to the minute.
The job is to bomb Wilhelmshaven
effectively and economically.
The enemy is strong, skillful,
determined to stop us.
Here are his defenses:
airdromes, well dispersed.
Each plane indicates a Staffel
or squadron of fighters.
Heavy anti-aircraft,
highly trained and accurate
all along the coast
and defending his
vital installations,
radar to warn him of our coming.
Here is our plan to
divide his defenses
and weaken his opposition.
At 13:30 hours,
shortly after takeoff,
six groups of planes will be
heading toward the enemy coast
from six directions.
The Blue Force, 100 B-24
Liberator four-engine bombers,
the White Force, 300
B-17 Flying Fortresses,
the Green Force, 300 B-17s
with an escort of six squadrons
of P-47 Thunderbolts,
a force of B-26 Marauders,
twin engine medium bombers
with six squadrons of
RAF Spitfires escorting,
almost 1,000 planes and
over 8,000 men in the air.
The enemy alerts
all his airdromes,
but which is our main force?
What are our targets?
Where should the Nazi
controllers send their fighters?
It's our job to make them
guess and guess wrong.
A half hour later
at 14:00 hours,
the Blue Force will be heading
east across the North Sea
with the White Force following.
These enemy fighters
are tied down,
waiting to meet them,
and will not be able to
attack the Green Force.
These fighters must come up
to attack the Green Force
and thus will be no threat
to the Blue and White Forces.
The B-26s and Spitfires
will bomb and strafe
a key rail junction,
diverting these six Staffel
and preventing the
enemy from concentrating
too many fighters
on the Green Force,
which is scheduled to bomb an
aircraft factory at Hanover.
At 14:30 hours the Blue
Force will threaten
this entire coastal area
of Northwestern Germany.
Which target will it be?
Flensburg?
The Kiel Canal?
Or will it turn suddenly
and bomb Hamburg,
Vegesack or Emden?
Actually, it carries
no bombs at all.
It's a decoy
and keeps the fighters
from the northern area busy
while the White Force,
the main effort,
heads for the submarine
pens of Wilhelmshaven.
At 15:00 hours,
while the White Force
is over its target,
only a fraction of the available
German fighter strength of
the area can intercept it
because of the Blue
Force diversion
and the simultaneous bombing
of Hanover by the Green Force.
This is the plan of
battle for today,
drawn up by the Combined
Operations Planning Committee
and approved by the
commanding general.
The White Force, lead
group, low squadron.
We've crossed the invisible
line of enemy radar.
The Hun is expecting us.
(airplane engines roar)
Steel helmets go on.
Watchful eyes strain.
Tight formations are
held tighter still.
Tense gunners more alert
because here it comes,
the enemy coast.
From up here it looks
the same as any other,
houses, roads,
green fields,
factories, waterways,
but they are the
houses and fields
of those who invade and oppress.
They are the factories
and roads of the people
who twice in one generation have
flooded the world
with suffering,
suffering in such quantity
as the history of the
human race has never known,
brought torment and anguish
into countless American homes,
gold stars and telegrams
from the War Department.
(exploding shells bang)
The first flak, just
harmless-looking
silent puffs of smoke,
only each puff is
a shell exploding,
throwing shrapnel
around the sky,
exactly the range,
accurate flak by
radio prediction.
Five miles down, Nazi
anti-aircraft batteries have
calculated the altitude
speed and course.
Where will the next one hit?
You try not to be there.
(exploding shells bang)
The docks and submarine
pens of Wilhelmshaven.
Approach to the target starts.
No smokescreen can protect it.
(exploding shells bang)
Now the enemy knows the
path of your approach
and walls that path
with a flak barrage,
but you fly right through it,
flak so thick you can
get out and walk on it.
(exploding shells bang)
Morgan changes course
every 15 seconds,
evasive action to confuse
the flak batteries.
Bomb site set for correct
altitude and speed.
Bomb bay doors open.
The bombing run begins.
Pilot to Bombardier,
okay, Vin, you've got it.
Now Evans flies
the Memphis Belle,
controlling it
through the bomb site.
And now we are most vulnerable.
Committed to our bombing run,
we can't dodge flak or fighters.
Here's the first.
(gunfire rattles)
(airplane engines whine)
Top turret fires at it.
Evans must ignore the battle,
crosshairs lined up on target,
adjustments for wind drift made.
Two more fighters diving
from nine o'clock.
(gunfire rattles)
Flak now has the range too.
(explosion bangs)
They've hit this Fort,
but he keeps on his bombing run.
As lead Bombardier,
Evans' aim must be good.
Every other ship in the
group will drop its bombs
when he drops his.
Now one pointer on the
bomb site moves toward
another stationary pointer.
The instant they touch,
bombs will release.
(airplane engine roars)
They touch,
bombs away.
(exploding bombs bang)
(airplane engine hums)
(airplane engine
continues to hum)
(exploding bombs bang)
The first half of the mission
is over, the easy half.
Now to get home.
The flak stops.
That means fighters
out there somewhere.
Are Staffel lurking
behind that cloud,
or hiding up in the sun
where the glare blinds you
and you can't see them
waiting to dive down on you?
Fighters at six o'clock.
This is what a gunner
sees, a speck in the sky.
That's a fighter,
and then a blink.
That means he's firing at you,
2,300 rounds a minute.
(gunfire rattles)
(airplane engine roars)
In a running battle,
one of the most important
instruments is the interphone.
(gunfire continues to rattle)
- [Crew] There's four of
'em, one o'clock high,
they're coming around.
(gunfire rattles)
Two fighters, six o'clock
up coming in, firing at you.
- [Crew] B-17 in trouble
our two o'clock,
watch it.
- [Crew] Got an engine on fire.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] There's two more,
diving through the 94th.
- [Crew] Three planes, nine
o'clock, coming around.
Keep your eye on 'em, boys.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] Firing at 10.
- [Crew] Watch 'em, Chuck,
keep your eyes open.
- [Crew] They're breaking
at 11, breaking at 11.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] There we go at two
o'clock, watch 'em, Scottie.
- [Scottie] I got
my sights on 'em.
- [Crew 3] Check that B-17,
Chuck, at three o'clock.
The motor's smoking.
Fighter at 10:30, coming around.
- [Crew] Are those
10:30 upper or lower?
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] B-17 out of
control at three o'clock.
- [Crew] Come on you guys, get
out of that plane, bail out.
There's one, he come
out of the bomb bay.
- [Crew] Yeah, I see 'em.
- [Crew] There's the
tail gunner coming out.
- [Crew] Watch out for fighters.
- [Crew] See any
parachutes, Quinlan?
- [Crew] Flak at nine o'clock.
- [Crew] Eight men
still in that B-17.
Come on, get out of there.
- [Crew] Come on, bail out.
- [Crew] There's
three more 'chutes.
- [Crew] Flak at 11 o'clock.
(airplane engines roar)
- [Crew] 109 at three o'clock.
- [Crew] Come on,
you son of a bitch.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] He got him, chief.
Look, he's bailing out.
- [Crew] Damn it, don't
yell on that intercom.
- [Crew] Fighters, 10 o'clock.
- [Crew] Watch those
two, they're coming in.
- [Crew] They're coming in.
- [Crew] Let's get that
ball turret on them.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] Save the ammunition
as much as possible.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] Watch that fighter
coming in at three o'clock.
(airplane engine roars)
(gunfire rattles)
- [Crew] He's coming
in on a half roll.
Pull her up, chief.
Pull her up, hurry.
(gunfire rattles)
- [Narrator] This
Fortress is hurt,
engine on fire, losing
airspeed and altitude,
drifting into the flak alone
and helpless, a straggler.
In a minute, Nazi
fighters will swarm in
like buzzards for the kill.
You can watch, but you
can't go down to help.
You keep your formation.
(pensive music plays)
Here too, the mission
is being flown,
none the less real for being
in the minds and hearts
of these men behind.
Ask anybody who's been
to a field in England
or anywhere else our
bombers are based,
and he'll tell you that
there's drama here too,
waiting to see
who's coming back.
To watch them, you
might not realize
how tense these
ground crews are,
but they are tense
and plenty worried.
In Air Force talk,
this waiting is known
as sweating out the mission.
These men know the flight plan.
Their watches told them
when the bombers were
running into enemy flak,
when they were over the target,
when they left the enemy coast
and now their watches tell them
the bombers should
be nearing the field.
Every ear strains for the
first sound of the engines
and then somebody hears them
and somebody sees the
first faint specks
in the distance sky.
(pensive music continues)
Every face turns to see
and count.
The watchers try to read
the numbers on the ships.
These planes have
priority to land first.
The colored flares
mean wounded aboard.
In the hospital window,
these watching men
know what that means.
They know what it
feels like to lie
on a bouncing Fortress
floor for hundreds of miles
through the frozen stratosphere,
in great pain,
with the other men in your
crew fighting to keep you alive
until they hit the field.
The field,
home.
It'll be okay then
because there'll be
medical care, the best,
as soon as the wheels of
your plane stop rolling.
(engines hum)
(pensive music continues)
Head wound, concussion.
20 millimeter cannon
shell exploded
in his radio compartment.
Shock, internal injuries.
He'll be all right, though.
Flak bursts scattered
flying shrapnel.
He's full of steel splinters.
This pilot's leg is
not a pretty sight.
Neither are the docks
at Wilhelmshaven.
These men will all
get the Purple Heart
and this man too, posthumously.
A transfusion
right in the plane.
This gunner's too
weak to be moved.
The new, life-giving blood
flowing into his veins
might be the blood of a high
school girl in Des Moines,
a miner in Alabama, a
movie star in Hollywood,
or it might be your blood.
Whosever it is, thanks.
(airplane engines hum)
36 planes left this
field this morning.
Now six more arrive.
That makes 20 home
and this one's 21,
more wounded aboard.
(airplane engine hums)
22, coming in with his
left inboard engine dead.
(airplane engine hums)
23, with a feathered prop
on his left outboard engine.
24, Southern Comfort,
with a chunk of tail gone.
25, they flew home
on their luck.
26,
not a scratch.
The control tower learns
that two more landed
at a British field to the south,
one a crash landing, crew safe.
That makes 28.
29, a rough landing but
her pilot's badly hurt.
It's a wonder he
brought her back at all.
29 planes back so far,
29 out of 36.
Our losses were heavy,
but the enemy's
were far heavier.
We destroyed a German
aircraft factory,
a rail junction, submarine pens,
docks and harbor installations.
That's specific, known damage,
but who can tell the
number of German torpedoes
that will not be fired,
the number of our convoys
that will get through now,
the soldiers' and seamens'
lives that will be saved
or the battles that will
be won instead of lost
because of what these
bombers and airmen did today?
(heroic music plays)
Pilot and tail gunner,
they can laugh now.
Fire on the inboard
engine did this.
Flames streaked back and
burned the stabilizer tool.
Another crew luck brought back.
(heroic music continues)
Here's Old Bill,
a pretty good airplane
when it took off,
lost its nose,
lost its navigator,
bombardier wounded,
top turret gunner and pilot hit,
hydraulic system shot
out, no brakes, no flaps,
but Old Bill came back.
Now among the
returned crew members
talk flows like a river,
talking out every
detail of the mission.
These are the faces of combat,
faces of Americans who have
watched their comrades die,
faces that can never
forget the enemy,
and they are in no mood to
have their picture taken.
In the control tower,
Colonel Ray, Group CO,
is still watching and waiting.
(heroic music plays)
And he spots the last
flight, three more planes
and one of them is the ship
everyone has been pulling for,
the Memphis Belle.
The last few miles of this
trip have been a joy ride.
The strain is over.
They can leave their guns now.
Now they know they're
going to go home,
to Spokane, Green
Bay, Asheville,
Detroit, Chicago,
Fort Worth and Yonkers.
(airplane engine hums)
The Belle comes
in for her landing
but first Morgan
buzzes the field,
cuts the grass with
a giant Fortress.
It's against the rules, but
this is a special occasion.
(airplane engine roars)
(suspenseful music plays)
(braking wheels squeak)
(joyous music plays)
The wheels of the Memphis Belle
come back to the soil of
England for the 25th time.
(joyous music continues)
This is a day they
will never forget.
Another great day soon after,
Brigadier General
Hansell visited the field
and presented the
Distinguished Flying Cross
to every member of the crew.
(car engine hums)
And then there was another day.
(military drum rolls)
(majestic music plays)
Their Majesties, the King
and Queen of England.
(majestic music continues)
Johnny Quinlan never
thought anything like this
would happen to him
when he left Yonkers.
The ground crew were a
little self-conscious
about being dressed in fatigues,
but the Queen thought
they were very nice.
(military drum roll plays)
Finally, two more visitors came.
General Eaker, commanding
the 8th Air Force,
and General Devers, US Commander
of the European Theatre.
The Belle crew received
them in flying clothes
as General Eaker read the order
for what he called their 26th
and most important mission,
return to America
to train new crews
and to tell the people
what we're doing here,
to thank them for
their help and support
and tell them to keep it up
so we can keep it up,
so we can bomb the enemy
again and again and again
until he has had enough.
And then we can all come home.
(triumphant music plays)
(airplane engine roars)
(triumphant music continues)
(airplane engines roar)
To the men of the 8th Air Force
who are now flying
deep into Germany,
bringing destruction to targets
almost 1,000 miles
from their bases,
destruction like this,
and who have never once been
turned back by the enemy,
to those men, this film
is gratefully dedicated.
(serene music plays)
(serene music continues)
(no audio present)