Taxi!
Charles!
Maurice.
You're fat!
- And you are thinner.
Jeanette! Jeanette!
Jeanette!
Look!
Charles!
Charles Wills!
English, Mama, English.
She loves you in French.
We all miss you in any language.
He does not look well.
That means she wants
to feed you.
You're away too long.
Almost two years, huh?
Thanks, Maurice.
You remembered.
Bourbon straight,
water on the side.
You and Mr. Gamble!
Only people who speak English
would put things like that
in their stomachs.
You're back on business,
perhaps?
No, no, just to see
my little girl.
Ahh, little ballerina.
She don't go back with you?
No more for me, thanks.
The world has changed.
Uh, yes.
It's not so crazy anymore
like it was after the war, huh?
You remember?
We had much laughter together,
eh, Charles?
Maybe we had too
many laughs, Maurice.
[Crowd cheering and singing I
Maurice, how are you?
Some big day, huh?
This calls for a very big
and very cold bourbon and water.
No bourbon, no gin,
no cognac, no anything.
How are you celebrating?
For me, I keep the Perignon.
For you and me.
That, uh, lady over there.
I do say, uh,
she gives you the eye.
That one?
She's not even smiling at me.
The eye without a smile
is the most dangerous eye.
Excuse me.
- Charles!
- Claude!
Ah, I knew you would make it.
Ooh, but you --
I was afraid that --
Nah, don't you know
that bad characters
never die in a war.
Excuse me, I saw my old friend
and I --
This is my dear
and crazy friend,
Charles Wills, Miss Eliswirth.
- Miss Eliswirth.
- Marion, please.
American?
You've been here
all through this?
Oh, we never left.
Dad and I stayed on in an
unoccupied France, Lyon mostly.
How do you know Claude?
Oh, he was an observer
with our outfit.
Haven't seen him
since D-day in Normandy.
I parted company with
the US Army after Saint-Lo.
Back into the FFI?
With the General de Gaulle.
Um, quite a-a coincidence
meeting here.
Well, if I hadn't seen you
in the mirror --
uh, I thought some stranger
was giving me the eye.
But no, no, I didn't see you.
Am I interrupting
anything important?
Well, uh, Marion and I are --
Uh, you must have
influence around here.
You have a drink.
Power of the press, ma'am.
Let's see what my influence and
lots of money can accomplish.
Maurice!
- I've got a better idea.
Let's go to
my father's celebration.
Well, where would he get
enough whiskey for a party?
You don't know my father.
To fathers!
To men!
To Frenchmen!
- We'll continue our celebration.
Bonsoir.
Bonsoir, monsieur.
Marion, ah!
You, my boy, you have a thirsty
look in your eye.
Oh, does it show?
It might go away
if you have a drink.
- Andre!
- And, uh, who have we here?
Charles Wills.
He's a reporter
for the Stars and Stripes.
This is my father.
- How do you do, sir?
- A reporter?
We don't need a reporter,
we need a bartender here.
I invited him here
because it seems to be
the only place in town
where you can get a drink.
And do you know that
all these people came
to precisely
the same conclusion.
What is Helen doing here?
Uh...
- Hi!
- What are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
Well, the fact
of the matter is --
Your sister has made me
very proud.
We couldn't tell you
the good news before
but Helen has been expelled
from the university.
- What?
- If we're going to have a scene,
either ask this young man
to leave or introduce us.
- Marion, please.
- Helen --
Ah, now look, let her alone.
After all, I was expelled
from Harvard, wasn't I?
Why shouldn't a girl follow
in her father's footsteps?
Excuse me a moment.
I'll talk to you later.
I have a feeling
she'll be talking to me, too.
Name, please?
Uh, Charlie something
or other.
He, uh, says he's a bartender.
- Ah, yes!
- Charlie what?
- Uh, Wills.
I wish were a bartender,
a nice civilian bartender.
- Oh, merci.
[Speaks French I
- I told him we knew each other.
- Well, we do in away.
We were only kissing
an hour ago.
We were?
Let me see now,
you were one of the ones
at the Ritz bar.
Ha, no.
Unh-unh.
- No!
I know!
Near the Dhingo Café.
You do remember.
No, it's the only other place
I ran into more uniforms today.
Are you rich?
No.
Does that finish me off?
No, but it does slow us
up a little.
We're not rich either,
we just live that way.
Daddy says it's the same thing,
only it's much cheaper.
I think I like him.
That's good, because he'll try
to borrow money from you.
And I don't want him
to be disappointed.
I like the way you kiss.
Really?
My dear, I'm afraid
I've underestimated
the alcoholic capacity
of our guests.
I'll only be a few minutes.
Uh, get the bartender here
to help you with it.
Say, Wills, Wills,
are you one of the wealthy
Willses from Maryland?
No. No.
- Ah!
- This way, Lieutenant.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.
[Crowd singing "Alouette" I
- Where are you from?
- Milwaukee.
- Would you help me?
- Sure.
Noted for good beer,
women with lovely legs,
and practically
no millionaires.
And you?
New York till I was 12.
then Daddy moved us to Paris.
When the Germans came in 1940,
I was sent to school
in Switzerland.
That's where the loot's kept.
No!
Daddy put it there so
the Germans wouldn't drink it.
Very resourceful man.
- And lots of fun.
- Is he?
That's his eleventh commandment,
having fun.
Especially now.
He says that after a war,
everybody should always be gay
and have fun.
Isn't your father a little old
for this war?
Oh, he wasn't in this one.
He was in the 1918 war.
And he's been celebrating
ever since.
Now that the war in Europe is
over, what are you going to do?
Try to stay out of the war
in the Pacific.
That's very sensible.
That ought to be enough
to tame the tiger.
Charles, I was wondering
what had happened to you.
Nothing, yet.
Everybody's waiting to meet you.
Well, I've really got --
got to report back to the paper
with some sort of story.
Oh, can't you stay
just a few minutes?
I'm sorry, I've got a deadline.
Oh, Lieutenant,
don't take the party with you.
Oh.
That's a nice laugh.
Do you think someday soon
you might be rich?
Could you come back later?
All right, I'll try.
Uh, better yet, I'll meet you.
You call and tell me where.
All right!
Hello!
Who is this, please?
Who?
Oh, Helen,
this is Charlie Wills.
No, no, Charlie the bartender.
The Army bartender?
That's right!
Could you give Marion
a message, please?
Tell her that the lights
of Paris go on tonight
for the first time
since the war began.
Well, she wanted to meet me,
at the Arc de Triomph,
right by the Shrine
for the Unknown Soldier.
Thank you!
- Hi!
I thought that --
- Disappointed?
No, but --
The ordinary unnerving,
you know.
[Bells ringing I
Do that again.
Thought you were asleep?
Only my eyes.
And my arm.
They're weaklings,
your arm and my eyes.
Mm-hmm.
Not worthy of us.
Mnh-mnh.
They're not bad eyes.
It's a nice arm.
I'll take you home.
Did you read Thomas Wolf,
"You Can't Go Home Again"?
It's late.
All right.
[Bells ringing I
Promise me something.
Promise?
Don't ever let
the celebration end.
There will be
another celebration
when the rest of the war
iS over.
But it is over.
For us it's over.
I'm sick to death of death.
I want to enjoy things
and have fun.
And live like every day
is the last day.
Wouldn't that be nice?
A lifetime full of last days.
Except there never really
would be a last day.
You're too serious.
Make that nice smile.
That's better.
I don't care if you're not rich.
Chocolate!
Hi!
Oh, how wonderful!
[Charles laughs I
- Look!
- Mmm, mmm.
You didn't have to this, my boy.
Oh, yes he did.
He's trying
to make time with me.
- Spam!
What is it,
animal or vegetable?
Powdered eggs!
Chocolate!
You shall not go unrewarded,
my boy.
Come to think of it,
your generosity
shall be repaid this very day.
Now --
- Good morning!
- Look, meat, eggs.
About the powdered eggs,
you see, they look
something like eggs --
- Never mind.
We'll cook them in sherry.
That will make them
taste like eggs.
Helen, please!
I wish to make some small token
of appreciation.
Charles, my boy.
A golden opportunity awaits us.
Now, the question is,
are we equal to the challenge?
Well, what is it, sir?
Benedictine
in the fourth race today.
He'll go to the post at 10 to 1.
At a mile and 3/8,
he can't lose.
- Why not?
- Um, it's a trade secret.
Daddy means he has
a hot tip, right?
Another hot tip?
Look, we have less than
two hours to become wealthy.
I think I can come along.
I'll make a phone call.
Excellent!
Now, If we pool our resources --
uh, what is your capital,
my boy?
Oh, about $40.
Let's see, that means if we
pool our resources we have $40.
- What a pity.
- Maybe I can borrow some.
Don't you do it, Charles.
He'll keep you as broke
as he is.
Opportunity, my dear,
is concerned with the future,
not the past.
Look, if it's collateral
you're worrying about,
I happen to own oil leases
in Texas
that are worth,
uh, well, you know Texas.
Oh, Daddy.
The oil leases
are a family joke.
Plenty of leases
but not one drop of ail.
- Charlie!
- What?
I feel lucky today.
I'll see what I can dig up.
I have the utmost confidence
in the courage
and ingenuity
of the United States Army.
To horse, my boy, to horse.
Destiny hates a laggard.
Ah! Uh!
- The paper said that --
- Don't be nervous.
Daddy's really very brilliant.
Well, what could possibly
make me nervous?
If we lose the race,
I'll owe half a year's pay.
The money belongs
to four captains
who fought their way out of
Bastogne with their bare hands.
- We won't lose.
- Well.
Did you bet it all?
Every penny.
And at 12 to 1!
Why did the odds go up?
The suckers think
that Benedictine will lose.
What can you expect
of agnostics, my boy?
Over this way, what?
Which one is Benedictine?
Uh, Number 4.
He'll lay back
for the first half-mile.
He looks scrawny.
Lean, my boy!
Lean and ready and fit!
Who gave you this tip?
Where's Benedictine?
Running beautifully.
But where is he?
Sixth.
In perfect position.
- Is Benedictine --
- Seventh!
He's outsmarting them.
Helen!
I think I'll buy a new dress
with my share of the winnings.
[Screaming I
He won!
Benedictine won!
- Of course he won.
- Why should that surprise you?
He won!
Not so much surprise as relief!
You know, at 12 to 1,
that makes your share...
Maybe there's another race
fixed today.
If you could --
- Fixed? Fixed race, my boy?
You mean this race
wasn't fixed?
You've been reading
too many crime novels.
There was no hot tip either,
was there?
Well!
You just picked a crazy
long shot out of a hat!
Intuition and experience,
my boy.
But we could have gotten killed.
It's a wonderful way
to make a living, isn't it?
This is the American
Forces Network in Paris.
A pall of black destruction
and chaos still hangs
over Hiroshima.
Events are now moving swiftly.
The President --
- Hey, Maurice!
Leave it on!
- Did you hear the news?
First things first.
It'll take more one bomb
to end this caper.
One will get you 20
it's over in a week.
Will you cover
60 bucks worth?
You got it.
Don't do it.
Barney just came
from the office.
Japan offered to surrender if...
- What? Where? Who?
...if we let the Emperor
stay in his throne.
- When are we going home?
- Yeah.
Charlie, what's the dope
on discharges?
Well, if you start right now
you're already behind
10,000 other guys.
I'll have to get right back
to the office.
Why?
I tried to phone you.
Don't ever phone me if you
can possibly come yourself.
And don't ever leave
if you can stay.
Maybe we can meet for
late supper or something.
We'll see.
Is it really over?
The war?
Because I want to buy you
silk shirts and silk socks
and silk shorts.
Oh, darling!
Taxi!
What did you do
with my umbrella?
I had it when I started
over here and stopped a second.
Must have lost it.
We've got a Special Edition
coming out.
- You better hurry.
- I'll get you a taxi first.
Taxi!
Now, you stop fussing about me.
Will you --
Will you wait for me?
I think I'll go home early
and give Daddy a shock.
But in this rain?
I may not be able to cook
and to sew,
but I really can
find myself a taxi.
It's the first thing I learned
at finishing school.
Now you go on ahead.
You're a girl
after my own heart.
Make no mistake about it.
I'm after it, all right.
Taxi!
Violet.
Merci!
Marion!
I phoned, and they said
it was all right for visitors.
Did she get my flowers?
Every day.
All my messages?
Every one.
Can I go in now?
- Charles.
- What?
Hi!
How do feel?
The nurse answers
all the stark questions.
The patient improves, but it
is required not to really hurt.
Uh, I was going to ask you
to dance,
but I guess that's out, huh?
I was expecting a younger,
more attractive nurse.
She's the fourth in two weeks.
Daddy's a pincher.
For heaven sakes,
get that guilty look
off your face.
I lost your umbrella.
I gave you the flu.
Don't be silly.
It was raining, I got wet,
so I got the flu.
And it's not your fault.
I was wondering how you would
look out of uniform.
Isn't bad.
It's my fault.
I would have caught this,
anyway.
I catch cold even
from weather forecasts.
Thank you for
the lovely flowers.
Oh!
What's the matter?
I don't know.
You look so pale
and sweet and faceless.
Remember, the nurse
is right outside the door.
Not that I'll call her.
One thing I learned
these last weeks,
I love you.
You loved me the first day.
I did?
You sure did.
We should have
told each other then.
Look at all headway
we could have made.
For the first time in my life,
I wish I had lots of money.
Oh, money!
Daddy says it isn't what
you have, it's what you owe.
I don't even owe enough.
And what are your prospects,
young man?
Prospects?
My old job on the news
at $65 a week.
Please!
I'm only suppose to think
beautiful thoughts.
Doesn't DuPont or General Motors
need a president or something?
Well, the Paris office
of the Europa News Service
needs a reporter.
Paris!
It doesn't pay as much
as the New York job.
But you don't need money
to have fun in Paris.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, I've been working
on a book.
I should get back to the States.
Why can't you write
your book here?
Oh, Charlie, darling, please
marry me and let's stay here.
Please?
Oh, it sounds so wonderful.
But isn't it a little crazy?
Yes, it is crazy.
If you had any sense, you would
walk right out that door
and never see me
or call me again.
Maybe send back my umbrella
and call it quits.
But I haven't any sense.
No sense at all.
You have no sense,
I have a one-degree temperature.
If I were 98.6,
this would never happen.
Forgive me, but, uh,
I'm rather enjoying
playing the anxious father.
After all, it's Helen's
first marriage, you know.
- Only marriage, sir.
- Tut, tut!
No arrogance, please.
Helen tells me that you are
a very serious-minded person.
You know, both feet
on the ground,
hardworking, industrious.
Well, I try to be, sir.
I tell you frankly,
these are not the qualities
I'd hope for in a son-in-law.
I'll, uh, go even further.
They're, uh, not the qualities
to make Helen happy.
Oh, well, sir, I, uh --
I'm going to work
on a Paris news agency.
I'll be surrounded by carefree,
irresponsible characters.
Some of it is bound
to rub off on me.
Hm.
Well, let us hope so.
Tell me, do I, uh, do I strike
you as being an unusual father?
You certainly do.
That's a very
straightforward answer.
Try to overcome this tendency.
You understand, of course,
that I can't afford
to give you a large wedding.
I don't care for one, thanks.
- Care for a drink?
- Oh, yes.
I'd love one, thank you.
- Oh, it's too bad.
You know, I'm getting a little
low on this stuff and I was --
- Oh, that's all right, I'll --
- Here you are.
Oh, thank you.
Do you know what you're
getting for a wedding present?
Well, Helen told me
what not to expect.
My dear, sir, you are
getting the old family joke.
4.000 acres of
invaluable oil land.
- Thank you, very much, sir.
- Not at all.
You know, after all it's not bad
being an oil baron,
even if there's no oil, uh?
Well, did you give Helen
your permission?
I had to give her
my permission.
- Huh?
- Claude has asked me
to be the mother
of his children.
Really?
That -- That -- That seems
a bit irregular, doesn't it?
Dad, Claude has asked her
to marry him.
Oh!
Well, then I suppose
I must kiss you.
Do you, uh, say best wishes
to the bride?
Or congratulations to the groom?
Or which way is it?
I've forgotten.
You just go ahead
and kiss each other.
What did you put
into that kiss?
Well, why don't you come here
and find out.
Helen getting married,
Marion getting married.
A father abandoned
in middle age, ahh.
Hmm!
What man could ask for more?
Give me a rewrite
on that, will you?
How you feeling?
- Pretty good!
- Good, good.
That -- That beard looks good.
Ah, Charlie, if you're getting
around to asking for money,
not a chance.
I haven't got a franc.
If I had any, I wouldn't
give it to you anyway.
The prices aren't going up
here like in the States.
- Neither are the --
- Fellas, please!
I've got a wife and baby
waiting in the hospital.
I need 500 bucks
to get them out of hock.
Why don't you
leave them there?
It's the healthiest place
in town.
Ah, you can make jokes,
you're not a father.
Oh, I don't know.
All the returns aren't in yet.
[Baby cryi
ryin
- Ahh! .
How about it, Your Highness?
There's nothing like a hot tub
after a long day's
hollering, is there?
Ahh, there.
Look at those legs, will you.
A regular man-killer.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
This is not
the Follies Percheron, you know.
I beg your forgiveness.
What can you expect from
the common herd, my lady?
Huh?
- Claude!
- Charles!
- Well!
- I have good news.
Fine, fine! Where's Helen?
Charlie?
Oh! Oh, how's Marion?
- She's fine.
- Oh, that's fine, fine.
Hiya, fatso.
Fatso is right.
Look at me,
bulging out of my own clothes.
I happen to be insane
about each every bulge.
Where's Vicki?
- Being bathed.
Mm.
I just can't help it.
You look so pretty to me.
Of course, I've been looking
at my editor all day.
Oh, did you hit him
for the bonus?
- Mm-hmm!
- I got it, too.
Only it's not a bonus,
it's a loan.
I sent it right off
to the hospital.
So you can tell your daughter
to come out now,
she's all paid for.
I'll never,
never be a size 10 again.
Vicki will be
exactly like you.
Then I'll be surrounded
by beautiful women.
That compliment and a martini
would just about square you
for putting me in jail
for nine months.
Mm, martini coming right up.
- Charles?
- Yes, Claude.
I was appointed to the
prosecutor's staff yesterday.
But what about
your private practice?
But this is more important.
There are many collaborators
must be brought to justice.
Sure.
And the lawyers who defend them
will get rich
and you'll get convictions
and be broke.
Ta-da!
Gentlemen, the Queen.
- Ah.
Hello, Highness.
Well, what happened to her hair?
She had some yesterday.
Wishful thinking, that's alll.
You know, she's not bad
for a first try.
You had better be beautiful.
A genius and terribly rich.
The beauty she got
from my daughter.
The genius she inherited
from me.
You had better get busy
with your contribution, my boy.
The last nine months
I've devoted to you.
Now, I'm going to have fun.
What do you say, sweetheart?
Whee!
- Hey!
No guts, eh?
Ah!
I was wondering
if you could uh, uh --
Thank you!
[, uh, trust you're keeping
a record of these loans, huh?
Good night!
Good night, angel.
Sure you won't come along?
You hate me for not holding your
hand while you have your baby?
If you held my hand,
the next thing, I'd hold yours,
and the next thing,
I'd kiss you.
And the next thing, uh --
Mm, I like that.
You're a glutton.
Coax me not to go out.
I can finish this thing tonight.
Please, it's not a thing.
It's a great American novel.
Charlie,
will you still worship me
when you're famous?
Well?
Say it.
It's even better
than the first book.
It's beautiful.
It's too good for them.
Let's send it off tonight.
Come on, wake up.
Spit on it for good luck.
That a girl!
This Christmas night,
it is five years since
the end of World War Il.
Veterans everywhere
pray that peace
will come with the new year.
["Oh Come All Ye Faithful"
plays I
Daddy?
Daddy.
Well!
Ah.
English, darling, English.
Oh!
I had a bad dream.
Grownups have them too, darling.
I'll get you a glass of milk,
huh?
One kiss for the road.
You're not Ben Hur.
You lost the race.
I need consolation.
Hiya, Charlie.
I lost the race,
and your wife won't console me.
Hi, Charlie!
Next time win the race, huh?
Good night!
Look, Gruyere.
- Mm!
- I didn't forget.
Good night, everybody.
Hi!
- Hi!
Charlie!
You're not Charlie.
Where is Charlie?
You haven't told her yet, huh?
Why spoil her fun?
Why let it spoil yours?
I'm peculiar, that's why.
I used up a year of my life
trying to write a book.
For some unaccountable reason,
I thought somebody
would want to publish it.
My boy, you're not
in the least peculiar.
You're merely naive.
Now, I knew a publisher once,
and he made it a rule
never to read a manuscript.
Oh, he would smell it and weigh
it and feel it and taste it.
But read it? No.
Now, if this manuscript
smelled and weighed and felt
and tasted like garbage,
then he published it.
Would you like to know
the secret of success?
Mediocrity, my boy.
To be a rich writer,
you've got to remember
your three R's --
riches, ruffians, and rape.
♪ Should auld
acquaintance be forgot ♪
♪ And never brought to mind? ♪
♪ Should auld acquaintance
be forgot ♪
♪ And days of auld lang syne? ♪
♪ For auld lang syne, my dear ♪
♪ For auld lang syne ♪
Hey! Hey!
Saturday Evening Post
bought my serial, 15,000 bucks!
- How about that!
- Yeah!
- Goodbye!
- Thanks, thanks.
Unh-unh-unh.
Farewell, hacks, forever.
$15,000, tax-free too!
He could have at least
thrown a party for everybody.
Merci beaucoup.
Charlie, uh, run down
to the police station will you?
What for?
They're holding
some crazy American dame.
Seems she held up traffic
by taking a dive
into a fountain at noon today.
Not much of a story, is it?
No, but you know how Americans
in Paris
love to read about
Americans in Paris.
Oh, all right,
what's her name”?
Helen Wills.
That's my girl.
No use acting as if
you didn't know me.
I'm your wife.
In sickness and in health,
in dry clothes and damp.
You know how you are
with colds.
You had better go home
and change.
We can't go home.
Vicki's at the Dhingo.
- Again?
- Isn't she better off
in a nice respectable bistro
then all alone at home?
This gonna get in the papers?
One more crazy American
jumping into
one more beautiful fountain.
That isn't news any more.
Is that why you did it,
to get into print?
I guess it was
silly and stupid.
But it was fun.
- Was it?
- Well, almost fun.
On the verge of being fun.
Only it never is, quite, is it?
No, somehow it never is.
I don't know why.
Maybe it's something
about Paris, or me,
or the times, or something.
It's as if you gotta hurry up.
Hurry before -- It's like you're
trying to find out something
terribly important only --
- Only you never do.
Oh, come on now, you always
laughed at these things.
It took a little time,
but you laughed.
It isn't that.
Campbell just sold a serial
to the Saturday Evening Post
for $15,000.
And you hate him for it?
Oh, darling, I think
that's wonderfully human of you.
- Finally.
What's he saying?
He's talking so fast.
This is Marcel.
How do you do?
Who are you?
He says he's going
to immortalize me.
What, are you running for office
or something?
Oh, you know me. Always good for
a couple of laughs.
Mrs. Wills,
it's a good thing
to make people laugh.
Don't I get anything?
I paid the fine
to get her out of jail.
Papal!
Anglais, sweetie, English.
Papa, I have been waiting
to show you, this morning...
[Speaking French I
- No, Vicki.
Not half and half.
All English.
Watch, Daddy, watch.
Hold it!
I haven't been kissed yet.
- Hey, Charlie.
- Barney!
You want to see something great?
Go on.
Oh!
Pretty young to be
hitting the bottle, isn't she?
It's the floor, darling.
Even Pavlova couldn't dance
on a floor like this.
Are you all right?
I'm sorry.
- Say something nice.
- It's swell, kid, great.
The boss wants me on an
interview at the Royal France.
I can't handle it,
got a heavy date.
Cover for me, will you?
Uh, the woman's name
is Lorraine Qual.
- Who's Lorraine Quarl?
- Café society.
So long, kid.
You got a great act there.
Great!
All it needs is a finish.
You've got the right finish,
haven't you, sweetheart?
Right into my arms.
Mr. Wills!
Mrs. Quarl!
I am Wills from
the Europa News Service.
I hate to be late.
I'm sorry.
And I need a drink.
Leon!
- The same, Mrs. Quarl?
Please.
You can skip the usual.
Paris is beautiful.
American women love French men.
French men love American women.
Prices are too high.
I haven't picked out
my next husband yet.
Might be the bartender.
At least he has talent.
You've been interviewed before.
The last time, an hour ago.
He wasn't very young
or very attractive.
The interview was
very, very short.
But then, take your time.
Oh. First trip to Paris?
Oh, no, no.
First divorce here, that's all.
Why did you choose Paris?
I get saddle sores in Reno,
and I lose too much money
in Las Vegas.
According to our files,
you were married four times.
Three.
Annulments don't count.
Leon!
- Is something wrong?
Is something right?
You -- You really can't tell one
of my marriages from another.
But that's the problem.
Husband number one, for love.
Failure.
Husband number two, for money.
Failure, except for the money
and the name Qual.
Husband number three, annulment.
He forgot to tell me
he already had a wife.
Husband number four,
a bulifighter.
Four times I bet,
haven't had a hit.
Any children involved?
No.
And that's my only contribution
to humanity.
I told you I was a failure.
Mm, shouldn't you be
writing this down?
Oh, the interview
stopped long ago.
Thank you.
I'm hungry.
What about dinner?
Uh, I am not on
an expense account.
I'm just a struggling
newspaper man.
Oh, well, stop struggling.
The dinner is
on my four husbands.
I'll change and
I'll be right down.
- But what about the --
- Please, Mr. Wills.
At home my analyst charges $50
an hour to listen to me talk.
[Indistinct conversations I
Hey! That's my taxi!
- Charles!
- Hello, Claude!
I'm glad to see ya.
How have you been?
- Fine.
- You look fine.
How are ya, Marion?
- Fine.
- You look fine.
I'm fine, too.
Oh, excuse me.
My sister-in-law, Mrs. Matine,
Mr. Matine, Mrs. Quarl.
How do you do?
Uh, Claude's with
the Prosecutor's Office.
Oh? I hope we haven't done
anything wrong.
Uh, Mrs. Quarl
just arrived in Paris.
I'm, uh, interviewing her.
- How's Helen?
- Fine.
Fine.
Oh, and you should Vicki.
She's -- You know, we really
should see more of each other.
After all, family and --
I'll get in touch with Helen
in the morning.
Goodnight, Mrs. Quarl.
- Good night.
Charles, I really would like
to see you again.
Good night.
- Good night, Claude.
Thank you.
How is Helen?
Oh, now what's one little wife
among all your husbands?
I'll imagine you'll catch it
when you get home.
From Helen? Not Helen.
She's the most wonderful,
most understanding --
Do you mind if we don't go on
with the interview?
Somehow,
I'm suddenly cold sober.
And it's awfully late.
And if I don't get back to
the office and do this story --
Can I go with you?
To the office, I mean.
Why?
I don't know.
We'll probably never see
each other again, and I --
I'd like to drag the night
out a little.
And I should see that story.
Oh, that office is awful cold
and dingy
at this hour of the morning.
You would be surprised
how often I feel cold and dingy.
I'll be simpatico.
Well, good morning.
Now what's the matter?
Oh, Charlie, how could you?
Don't Charlie me, sister.
What about you?
I'm sick and tired of you
sitting around these
crummy cafés day and night,
the darling of every phony,
petted by writers
who don't write,
adored by painters
who don't paint.
And what do you write?
Interviews with
useless, sloppy women.
Well, at least I don't
jump into fountains
and lap up
all the liquor in Paris!
Well, why don't you ask me
why I drink,
why I jump in the fountains?
That's right, blame me.
Blame me.
Did I want to stay in Paris?
What right have you
to criticize me?
You're suspicious?
You? Ah!
That's a laugh!
Now you just listen to me!
Morning, darling.
Helen.
Do you realize what time it is?
Mm.
Mm, does it matter, darling?
It's 8:00 in the morning!
Mm, it's your turn
to take Vicki to school.
Do you realize
I've been out all night?
Mm, poor darling.
All right,
I'll take her to school.
Well, don't you care
I've been?
You look awful!
Was it a tough assignment?
I was interviewing a woman.
Mm, that's nice.
You have much better copy
than that.
She was a rich, beautiful,
exciting woman.
She was interested in me.
Well, don't you even care?
What are you trying
to say, Charlie?
I'm trying to say
that I love you.
What kind of a woman
did you say she was?
How many kinds are there?
Was she really pretty?
I'd lie about it,
but Marion saw her, too.
Yes, she's very pretty.
Marion?
Oh, we ran into
Claude and Marion.
She'll probably try to build it
up into something, but --
Just how rich
and how pretty was she?
Oh, shut up!
Mm, that's nice.
[Telephone rings I
- I don't hear a thing,
do you?
- I'll be back in a minute.
Hello? Marion.
What?
Say that again!
It's a lie!
You know how Marion
has never liked me.
Charlie, we're rich!
We're rich!
- Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- You old fraud!
Why didn't you tell us?
I am not old.
I couldn't tell you last night
because I was celebrating
last night.
I stopped by Marion's
on my way home this morning
and had breakfast.
And then told her then.
- How much are we worth?
Marion said that you said
that we're stinking rich.
Oh, Marion always
editorializes.
Money has no odor.
- Oh, especially lots of it!
- English, Vicki, English.
- Are we millionaires?
Insanity, there's a wide
streak of insanity
in this family, Vicki,
on your mother's side.
We have hit an oil gusher!
- We what?
- Qil, darling!
It's about to put Texas
on the map.
You mean, those worthless
oil leases of ours?
A generous wedding present
from me,
which I trust you'll remember
and keep in mind.
- How rich are we?
- Well, there's this state law
about only pumping out
80 barrels a day.
Now at $2 a barrel,
that's, uh --
That's only $160 a day.
- Seven days a week?
- Of course.
Oil is an act of God.
That -- That's $1,100 a week!
And 27 1/2% tax-free.
- What if we sold out?
- My thoughts exactly!
A capital gain.
But if we didn't sell out,
we'd have an income for life!
Is everybody from
Milwaukee cautious?
Sensible, just sensible.
We'll redecorate everything
from top to toe.
Me too.
I'll have my hair cut.
We'll take Marion's room
and turn it
into a writing room for you.
Do you suppose we really could
run through $50,000 in a year?
- Well, we could try.
- We?
- Oh! Mm.
- You know what?
Of course,
we could drill another well!
Marion never said a word about
running into you last night.
Mama, what's oil?
Oh, Vicki! Oh!
How do you like it?
It's mine, all mine!
Off with the shroud.
No more deadlines,
no more journalism.
The job is dead.
Lower away.
Catch it!
That's wonderful.
What are you gonna do now,
Charlie?
Now?
Now I'll finish my third novel.
If this one doesn't
get published --
It'll get published.
I got no money worries,
I got no job worries.
What would I use for an excuse?
If you got enough money,
nO excuses are necessary.
Good luck to you, Charlie.
- Thank you.
- Good luck, there.
That will be 5,000 francs,
please.
Oh, I should like
to do more for charity.
- Oh, well, that's nice.
- Helen.
Uh, pardon me once,
s'il vous plait?
Uh, 6,000 for another kiss.
I'm really worth
much more, you know.
But --
I never expected to see you
at a charity event.
Neither did I.
- Something wrong?
- Yeah.
- Vicki?
- No, Charlie.
Look, he hasn't moved
from his room all day.
He's still there.
He won't eat anything,
he won't say anything.
Just sits there
in the dark, alone.
Charlie?
What's the matter, darling?
Have you had dinner?
Do you want me to fix something?
Go away, Helen.
Let me alone.
Is it something I've done?
Please, Charlie, whatever it --
All right, I'll admit it.
You're a good wife.
You're devoted and loyal.
You've done your duty.
Now please go back to your party
and let me alone.
I'm only trying to help.
Help what?
You, me, us.
I don't know.
Help what? This?
Can you help another rejection?
Can anybody help that?
Why?
Because some publisher
turned you down again?
Yes. Again!
Again, Helen. And again!
Can you help it that I'm stupid
enough to spend five years
writing three stupid books?
Can you help it
that I'm no writer?
But you are!
You're wonderful.
They're the ones
that are stupid, not you.
"Dear Mr. Wills,
we regret to inform you --"
I'm no good, Helen.
Go away and let me alone.
Oh, Charlie!
Please! I can't explain
my failure to you.
Now be a good girl
and let me alone!
But you're not a failure,
not to me.
When I was 20, I used to think
I would write great books.
I would be able to do this,
because I was different.
I wanted perfection,
and that made me different.
Well, I'm not 20 anymore.
And it's too late now.
But we'll try again.
No!
I just don't have what it takes.
All I need to do now
is get used to the idea.
I'm rich.
For the price of a few drinks,
I could buy fame and friends,
or something like them.
Why spend years writing?
I can hold court in some
noisy bar and criticize writing
and talk about writing and --
You'll never make it, boy.
25 bucks says I do.
Stop this.
We've already got $75 bet.
Make it $100.
All right, $100.
Sucker.
Charlie.
- Oh!
Watch this, baby.
Come on, Charlie!
Pull, pull it, Charlie.
A-ha!
Hey, Charlie, you beat me.
- Voila! Ah!
- That a boy, Charlie!
All right, Charlie.
Winner and still champion.
And this is the arm that did it.
Take me home.
Waiting for the car.
It's getting souped up
for the race.
- Race?
- Sports car event.
Monte Carlo to Paris.
["The Last Time I Saw Paris"
plays]
♪ The last time
I saw Paris ♪
♪ Her heart was warm and gay ♪
Take me home now, please.
♪ ...in every street café ♪
That's what I thought
you said.
♪ The last time
I saw Paris ♪
♪ Her trees were dressed
for spring ♪
♪ And lovers walked
beneath those trees ♪
♪ And birds found
songs to sing ♪
Uh, anybody phone?
- No.
- Kind of quiet, isn't it?
- It's nice, though, isn't it?
Why hasn't Vicki come in
to say goodnight?
Your daughter is in
a compete state of crisis.
One of her front teeth fell out.
How's she taking it?
Oh, life is completely
over for her.
She says she'll come in
if she doesn't have to smile
or open her mouth.
Sure. I know a big, dramatic
situation when I see one.
You don't really mind
staying in tonight, do you?
Of course not.
How's it going?
Uh, it's not easy
getting started again.
But you promised.
And I'm trying.
And you'll make it.
Poor little ballerina.
Ha, thank you, very much.
Not a bad kiss at all
considering.
When will you smile again?
At least can you give me
an estimate?
Teeth grow back in a few months,
you know.
But by that time, those muscles
will be all set hard
and you won't be able to smile.
They say you're
the wickedest woman in Paris.
You know what I'll look like
pretty soon?
Daddy!
May I borrow
a pair of cuff links?
I can't seem to --
Both of you put
your upper plates back in,
you're making me self-conscious.
Can I dance for you, Grandpa?
In the morning, my dear.
I have to get up
at 6:00 tomorrow.
Well, now that will
work out fine,
because I should be
getting in by then.
Good night, darling.
Bon nuit.
Milk, literature,
what's the meaning of this?
I'm supposed to be working.
- Your idea?
- It's a fine idea.
Don't you corrupt him.
- I wouldn't think of it.
But we will miss you
at the Wilsons'.
Can you imagine throwing
a white tie party
simply because it's Thursday?
Couldn't we go?
Oh, Charlie.
Really, it would
be good for me.
And tomorrow morning,
I'll chain myself to that chair.
Please!
Why do I always end up saying
yes when I really mean no?
By the way,
I'm bringing a friend.
He's an international
tennis bum.
Paul.
Now don't worry about him
at the Wilsons',
he's invited everywhere.
Come to think of it, that's, uh,
how he makes his living.
You mean he gets paid
for being a guest?
No, no.
Uh, he steals the silverware.
Charming.
Paul, my, uh, my daughter
and Charles Wills,
my son-in-law.
How do you do?
Enchante.
I hear you played in Rome.
I play all the tournaments.
How do you make out?
Brilliantly,
until the second round.
Then invariably some
young Australian
or American school boy beats me.
But nobody beats him
in jumping over the net
and congratulating the winner.
I'm the champion graceful loser.
Forgive me, but you're the lady
in the fountain
in the Café Dhingo.
Why, it's my favorite painting.
Whenever I'm in Paris,
I go there to stare at it.
Well, you're in luck.
Now you can stare
at the original.
Come with me, Paul.
Until later.
Sort of appealing, isn't he?
- What?
- Appealing.
Yes, in a revolting
sort of way.
Enchante!
Well, my dear, it was
the funniest thing you ever saw.
All those gangsters
on the television,
and it's DuFour asking
all those questions.
Nobody in New York works at all.
- What?
What did George Bernard Shaw
die of?
Mostly old age.
You're going to drive
in this race yourself?
Certainly.
- What do you get if you win?
- What do you get?
You get to be winner,
that's what you get.
Well, what do you know.
It's my wife.
Hiya, wife.
All right, sporting blood,
run along to the locker room.
Come back in a few minutes,
Paul.
It's only his guilty conscience.
It won't take long.
Hey, what kind of a wife
are you, dancing with other men?
- The average kind, neglected.
- Oh.
What's with Mr. Tennis and you?
Oh, we're Paul and Helen now.
- Mm.
- He's sweet and attentive.
Doesn't think it's terrible
at all that I'm married
and have
a seven-year-old daughter.
Maybe he just wants
to be mothered.
- Not exactly.
He's made several conjectures,
but that wasn't one of them.
Well, let me know
how he makes out.
Lorraine!
Lorraine Quarl!
You've forgotten me?
Oh, believe me, the only thing
I've forgotten about you
is your name.
Wills, Europa News Service.
Charlie!
Oh, it's so good to have
my arms around you again.
Oh, well, you've got me
confused with somebody else.
We never got that far.
- Why not?
You get married again?
Of course.
And I'm embarrassed now
to get rid of him.
Are you still married?
- Yes, of course.
To the same woman?
To the same wonderful woman.
I have to say that, 'cause
she's standing right here.
May I present my wife, Helen,
Mrs. Quarl.
Oh, it's Mrs. Johnson now.
Oh, but not for long.
How do you do?
- I'm not quite sure.
You're much prettier
than I expected.
And you're much less beat up
than you have a right to be.
Uh, is it all right
if I, uh, come back now?
Oh, Paul Lane,
this is the, uh,
temporary Mrs. Johnson.
The best mediocre tennis player
in the world.
I've seen you around my hotel.
Oh, I always stay
at the Royal France here.
Tennis anyone?
Yes!
Your hair is like wine.
It keeps you drunk.
Charlie, I'd like to go home.
Home?
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I'd just like to go home.
Does that sound reasonable
to you?
- Are you going to take me home?
Oh, I would, but I can't.
I promised to show Lorraine
how fast the car would go.
Do you mind if Paul
takes me home?
Paul?
- Paul who?
- Paul anybody.
A party like this,
there must easily be six
or seven Pauls around.
You can't hold
a serious discussion with her.
I can get up to 60 miles an hour
with this baby in second gear!
[Door slams I
I've been up for hours.
Well, that -- that's a habit
you must try
and grow out of, kitten.
Why do grownups drink milk
when they have all 32 teeth?
Well, we develop butterflies
in our stomach,
and milk seems
to quiet them down.
How do they get
in your stomach?
They usually hide
in the bubbles of champagne.
- But --
- It's a well-known fact
of hydrodynamics.
Good night, my dear.
Good night.
[Door bangs I
Get your coat, Vicki.
Can Daddy come with us
to the bois?
We're going to church first.
Is it Sunday already?
What happened to Friday
and Saturday?
Run along, Vicki.
Are you coming, Daddy?
I'll meet you
at the bois later.
Church on Friday?
What happens at church
on Friday?
The usual thing.
Well, as long as you're in
that sort of mood,
can I expect a little sympathy
for this head?
Heads?
Very little.
What did I do?
That, I'd be
very interested to hear.
I'd like to go for a ride
on that thing myself.
How about it?
Must you look so grim?
I'm waiting to hear the end
of the midnight ride
of Paul Revere.
You got the car up
to 103 miles an hour
and then started back, right?
Right.
Then what?
Then nothing.
I dropped Lorraine at her hotel,
or she dropped me at the house.
I forget which.
You sure that's alll
you've forgotten?
I'm sorry to disappoint you,
but nothing happened last night.
Tonight's another night.
She'll be beautiful again.
You'll be full of wine again.
And nothing will happen again.
Who took you home last night?
That tennis player?
He didn't exactly take me home.
Oh!
He asked me back to his hotel
for a nightcap.
I went.
Did you have to
fight your way out?
Oh, there was a battle,
all right.
But it wasn't Paul I had
a fight with, it was myself.
Did you win?
Now you listen!
I'm under the same strains
and stresses you are.
I live in Paris, too.
And I'm bored, too.
And all that time,
I had a picture
in my mind of you
and that woman.
And don't underestimate Paul.
He's charming and attentive
and...
And I'm so unhappy.
Charlie, let's go home.
All right, as soon
as Vicki finishes with --
I mean really home!
America! Home!
It won't work, running home.
Charlie, let's go back,
before we crack up.
Please.
If you love me,
let's go back home.
You used to say
"Let's live it up a little."
And you were right.
There's lots of time to go home.
Plenty of time for everything.
Suppose time runs out on us.
You're just having
a bad day, darling.
Tomorrow will --
- I've been having a bad day
for a year now.
Maybe I'm growing up.
It's too late to grow up.
I'll tell you what.
Come racing with me.
We'll go to Monte Carlo.
Why is winning a race
so important?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe I could do a short story
about racing.
Why not?
Oh, all right, all right.
I get a kick out of racing.
It's fun.
To quote
your illustrious father,
nothing is more important
than fun.
Does that make me sound stupid?
Is that what you want me to say?
Come with me, Helen.
No, Charlie.
Well, maybe I'll take
somebody else.
Wouldn't that be reasonable?
You'll find a reason
to make it reasonable.
Look out for Vicki, will you?
Well, where are you going?
To do something important --
buy a new hat.
[Engines revving I
[Tires screech I
Can we stop for a while now?
Please?
Cognac, quickly, two of them.
Mr. Wills.
Mrs. Wills, is she here?
This ought to be good.
Well, look who's here!
What's the news
from the racing world?
I called you at the house.
You weren't there.
Of course not.
I'm here.
That's not funny.
You haven't been at that house
for a week.
I didn't think that was
very funny either.
Now I think
it's very, very funny.
You remember Paul, don't you?
No?
Well, that's sort of funny, too,
because I remember Lorraine.
Uh, will you join us
for some dinner?
Ah, shut up!
I'd love to join you.
What time does he drink
champagne from your slipper?
We've already done that.
How do like him?
Don't you think
he makes me look drunker?
I hope you don't mind
a harmless little dinner.
Oh, come on, Paul.
You can do better than that.
You could tell them to go away,
for instance, leave us alone.
Not me, dear.
He's your responsibility.
Oh, please.
We're all very civilized, no?
No.
That's my boy.
Touch me again
and I'll take a poke at ya.
I wouldn't do that, Charlie,
because then I'd have to
take a poke at Lorraine.
- What's funny?
- Why, you, me, all of us.
Very funny.
Please Charles. Charles.
Please.
Wiseguy!
The world's full of wiseguys.
Helen!
Oh! Oh, Helen!
You're beautiful.
And married.
And exciting.
And rich, too.
Ah, love, old soul.
Of course I love you.
Love is never of course.
Is it?
Please, I'll never
let you be lonely.
Paul?
Hm.
How are we going to tell him?
Tell him?
Tell him what?
About us.
That you love me.
I'm not going back to him.
Why, that's silly.
Well, of course
you're going back to him.
Well, if you don't go back
to him,
well,
he'll spoil everything for us.
You can see that, can't you?
Of course, darling.
I stay married
and keep you on the side.
And when I'm lonely -- ha!
Oh, brother!
The idea wasn't invented
just now.
It's done all the time.
Half your crowd
have arrangements.
Is that what you expected of me?
Helen, listen.
What's the matter with you?
Suddenly,
I've got very cold feet.
Charlie.
Please, Charlie.
Do you want me to go away?
Is that what you want?
[Doorbell ringing I
Just a minute.
Helen!
I am sorry.
I couldn't find a taxi.
I-l couldn't --
Doctor.
Go and see Wills.
[Speaks French I
He's outside.
He can't see her.
I won't let him.
Marion.
You took my umbrella.
I'm sorry, darling.
So sorry.
Please forgive me.
- Shh.
Take care of Vicki.
Don't let Vicki make
the same mistakes.
I'll always love you.
Please, Mr. Wills.
Leave us alone.
Mr. Wills --
Get out.
You'll have to leave here.
Now, Mr. Wills,
this no way to --
Get out of here!
Out in the hall, Doctor.
You had better go, son.
Vicki's alone.
Charlie, what are you
going to do, son?
You've got to talk to Marion.
If you don't,
you're going to lose Vicki.
She's going into court today
and going to ask for custody
of Vicki,
charging you are unfit
as a parent.
She's right.
I'll hurt Vicki,
just as I did Helen.
What will you do?
I want to go home.
All the way home.
A thing of beauty, huh?
Oh, Maurice.
I'm sorry, I'm late now.
Americans!
Always in a haste.
And as a rich American,
it's even worse.
Not rich anymore, Maurice.
What happened to the, uh, oil?
No?
- No, Maurice.
It changed back to salt water
a year ago.
Oh, that's unfortunate.
Maybe not.
You must dine with us tonight,
like old times, Charles.
I don't know.
It depends.
Jeanette will be
very disappointed.
You have many things
to remember together.
Come back, Charles, please.
Oh, I'll try.
Charlie.
Hello, son.
What happened?
Oh, a slight stroke.
When?
Eight or nine months ago.
But you never wrote me
about it.
Oh, it wasn't serious.
Mostly old age.
Charlie, I read your book.
It's good.
Very honest.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
I liked it.
I liked it, fine.
Uh, here.
For you, Havana cigars.
The kind you like.
Shall I open them for you?
Oh, later.
Uh, doctor says
when I'm better, huh?
Where's Vicki?
You've come for her?
If I can get her back again.
Good. Good.
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
You're taller.
Daddy.
What?
You're not gray.
I told everybody at school
you'd be gray.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, here.
- Thanks.
Claude!
Welcome, Charles.
I'm very happy to see you.
Thanks.
For everything, thanks.
As soon as I got
your telephone message,
I went to school and got Vicki.
Look, Daddy! Look!
Uh-oh! Oh! Oh!
It's wonderful, as usual.
- Daddy!
“What?
Could we go to the bois?
Remember the railroad train?
- Well, I --
- Oh, please?
Please?
That was the very first thing
I wanted to do when you came.
You've got about an hour
till Marion comes back.
I'll wear my new coat.
Okay.
How is Marion?
She's fine.
I want you to know, Claude,
how much I appreciate --
- Oh, I didn't do anything.
I showed Marion your letter.
She couldn't stop you
from seeing Vicki.
I was hoping she would
let me have Vicki back.
I've got to have her, Claude.
I need her.
Yes, I think she needs you, too.
Daddy!
Daddy! Hurry, Daddy!
The hour is almost up.
I bought your book.
And about Marion,
if we are careful,
it may be all right.
- Daddy?
“What?
What's wrong?
Why, nothing, darling.
Why?
You didn't even look at me.
You didn't even wave at me.
Oh.
Will you give me another chance?
You get back on that train
and I'll --
Daddy, may I sit out
the next ride?
Oh.
I'm really getting too old
for that sort of thing.
- Don't you think so?
Yes, you're real old now.
Darling, do you ever think
of your mother?
Oh, yes.
I don't want you
to forget her.
I have a picture of her
in my room.
Grandpa says I look like her.
Do you think, so, Daddy?
Yes.
Very much like her.
That's lucky for me.
- Daddy?
“What?
Why don't I live with you?
Why? Aren't you happy?
Yes.
But not perfectly happy.
Do you know what I mean?
Yes. I know what you mean.
Then I can come
and live with you?
I don't know.
Don't you want me to?
Oh, of course, darling.
Oh, Daddy!
If you really love me,
please let me
come and live with you.
Please!
We'll see.
Say yes, Daddy.
Yes.
There, you see?
It wasn't so hard to say
yes, was it?
Hello, Uncle Claude.
From the bois,
we went to Hermes,
and we bought something
for you, Uncle Claude,
and for Aunt Marion.
And something for me, too.
It's a wonderful store
and a wonderful day!
Oh, Aunt Marion!
You ought to see
what we bought for you.
It's a surprise.
Look!
You're late for your nap.
- But I thought today --
- Go on up to your room.
Don't you want to
see your present?
Do as I say, please.
Hello, Marion.
Hello, Charles.
It's good to see you again.
I'm sorry about getting back
so late with Vicki.
Oh, well, she would have been
too excited to sleep anyway.
And it's very important.
You've done a wonderful job
with Vicki.
She's grown up.
How do you find Paris?
Well, most of the old crowd
is gone.
Funny,
I dropped in at the Dhingo bar
this afternoon,
just to see how it looked.
There wasn't a man I knew.
I should think
you've had enough of bars.
As I wrote you,
I take one drink
every afternoon, but no more.
And I take that drink
deliberately.
Just so the idea of taking
a drink won't get too big.
Of course, Charles.
We understand.
Sometimes I forget
and don't take the drink.
But, well, I went to the Dhingo
to see how it looked.
I went to a few
other places, too.
Places where, uh, Helen and I...
Look, Marion.
I just can't keep on talking.
I'm all tied up in knots here.
Marion, can I have Vicki back?
I don't know.
It's all very well to talk
about one drink a day,
but what guarantee
have we that --
Well, when I --
I think of those wasted years.
But I think about them too!
I'm working hard now, Marion.
I've, uh, got a contract
for several short stories.
And I'm -- I'm starting
on another book.
And my sister's coming
from Milwaukee to --
to keep house for me.
I want Vicki.
Please, Marion.
If we wait much longer, I'll --
I'll lose her childhood
and my -- my chance for a home.
I-1 just can't lose her,
don't you see?
It would be almost like
having Helen back.
Marion.
I can't help it.
I'll never, in my life,
be able to forget that morning
when Helen, soaked and --
and shivering.
You locked her out!
Marion!
But you only remember
one night.
How long are you gonna make me
pay for that one night?
What about those years
Helen and I loved each other?
I don't want to hear about it!
Marion, you're not gonna
let me have Vicki?
No.
Marion, please.
I don't want to talk
about it anymore.
I'm sorry, Charles.
What will I do?
We'll see.
Thanks.
- I'll get dinner started.
- Marion.
There's no use
talking about it.
He's not getting Vicki.
Not now, not tomorrow, never!
Why?
Do you hate him that much?
Yes.
For what he did, yes!
It's true.
He committed
an unforgivable crime,
against you, personally.
He's guilty of never knowing
you loved him.
You found him,
but he married Helen.
And yes, he's guilty
of that, too.
And being guilty, of course,
he must be punished.
The penalty?
What would hurt him most.
Take away what he loves most,
his little girl.
My poor darling, we can't
have everything we want.
Take me.
I wanted all your love.
I wanted our own child.
A child out of our love,
not out of your disappointment.
Charles.
May I see you outside
for a moment?
I don't think Helen would have
wanted you to be alone.
Daddy!