(Woman): Let me die.
Let me die.
(ominous music)
I should've known
he was as good as dead
when they wheeled him in.
You did everything possible,
everything you could,
Dr. Cortner.
Everything?
Everything except
save my patient.
Everything in the books.
Now, Dad, do I have
permission to take over
and try things my way?
The operating room is
no place to experiment.
He's dead;
I can't do any harm.
Very well.
The corpse is yours.
Do what you want to do.
All right.
Make an opening into
the chest cavity.
Apply 100 milliamps of
current directly to the heart,
then massage by hand.
I'll handle the brain area.
- By yourself?
- By myself!
(ominous music)
I've got to work fast,
if it isn't too late.
You talk as if
he's still alive.
(Woman): He is!
I just picked up a
faint pulse beat.
Keep massaging the heart.
I am, I am.
These electric shocks
should stimulate
the motor area enough to
enervate the heart again.
Then he won't need
any external stimuli.
Keep away from
the motor area.
You'll paralyze him for good.
Which would you rather be:
Paralyzed or dead?
Don't try to play God.
Some choices are
not yours to make.
When the obstetrician
has to decide which to save,
the mother or the child,
who plays God then?
It's part of the game.
The game?
The human body is not a jigsaw
puzzle to experiment on.
Still playing it safe
like the other doctors, hmm?
Might as well save my breath.
Keep massaging the heart.
You've already lost
your patient, doctor.
I'm going to save mine.
(Woman): His pulse is coming
back stronger than ever.
It's unbelievable.
(Man): Nothing is unbelievable
if you have the
nerve to experiment.
I've been working on
something like this for weeks.
In your laboratory?
I knew this would work,
if only I had the opportunity—
You don't conduct
experiments on people.
You should be sure
of the results first.
I am now.
Stop massaging the heart.
Let's see if it can
take over by itself.
(deep breathing)
All right.
Close up the chest.
I'm about finished
with the cerebral area.
How's his pulse?
(Woman): Strong and steady.
(breathing continues)
(sighs) Yeah, you
did perform a miracle.
I may not approve of
your methods but...
I am proud of your results.
(calming music)
That was an amazing...
Even an extraordinary
operation, son.
But it still is too risky.
Too uncontrolled.
Saved his life.
And the aftereffects,
what about them?
You've lost the
urge to experiment.
To explore.
You don't explore on people.
Before you put a scalpel to one,
an operation like this needs
testing under every condition.
Over and over again.
Rabbits, mice, monkeys!
Not people!
That man who should be
dead now won't think so.
There's more to
surgery than just being
a carpenter to patch up walls.
Or a plumber to drain pipes.
Our bodies are capable
of adjusting in ways
we've hardly dreamt of.
If we can only find the key.
I'm so close now,
so very close.
The key to what?
Complete transplantations.
To be able to transplant
limbs and organs.
To be able to replace
diseased and damaged parts
of the body as easily as
we replace eye corneas now.
So that the new parts will
join together as though
they were born there.
It can't be done!
It can be done!
With my new special
compound I've created,
I'll do it,
I know I can do it!
Sure, sure,
that's what you say!
That's what I know!
I know I'm close!
Darling, I'm so proud
of you I could kiss you!
Promises, huh?
Always promises.
Careful, your father
is liable to report us.
(laughs)
And stop the floor show?
When you two are
married it won't be fun
to watch anymore.
Well, I can promise
you one thing.
Your grandchildren won't
be test tube babies.
You better hurry
if you wanna catch
that plane to Denver, Dad.
And you know that
medical convention
can't start without you.
Um, Jan, you'd better
check about my reservations.
Oh yes, I'll call the airport.
I'll be right back.
Bill.
The line between scientific
genius and obsessive fanaticism
is a thin one.
Now I want you on
the right side of it.
If I don't experiment,
how can I hope to perform
operations like the one
you almost messed up?
But I can't cover
up for you anymore.
The superintendent
had it out with me.
He thinks it's you
who's been stealing
those limbs from the
amputee operations.
So what if it is?
I've got to have limbs for
my transplant experiments.
Well, you said test and experiment,
test and experiment!
Yes, but limbs and
organs taken from people!
I've got to have
them to work with.
Sure, I've made a few mistakes.
But I've learned from them,
I've learned!
Your reservations
are all set,
3:30 take off.
Well, what have you two
planned for the weekend?
Oh, nothing much.
Just a quiet weekend.
Are you sure
you're not going up
to the country house?
You're always
sneaking off up there.
That place gives me the creeps,
I should've sold it
when your mother died.
You can't sell that place!
Well, I mean it's nice to
get away from the city,
I can work without
anyone snooping around.
You spent too
much time up there.
All right, I'll see
you both in a few days.
I've got to clean up
and get out of here.
Fine operation or not, Bill,
you're walking on thin ice.
But don't go too far!
Oh, every time
you touch me
I go out of my mind.
I wanna kiss you.
Bill, I wanna get married,
I can't stand not having you!
You've been wonderful!
Oh, I'd rather be a bride.
In a few more weeks.
Then nothing will keep us apart.
We'll be together.
Dr. Cortner!
I'm so glad you're here.
I was afraid you'd gotten away.
There is a very
important phone message
that came to you;
it sounded quite urgent.
I have been looking
everywhere.
it was from
a man called Kurt.
He called from
the country place,
and he said something
terrible had happened,
and he wanted you
to come right out.
Thank you.
Well, you've always
wanted to know
what's kept me away from
you so many weekends.
Have you got the
keys to your car?
Why haven't you ever
taken me up here before?
Because the things
I'm working on
don't need
an audience.
That telephone call,
what about it?
All right, all right,
hold off the questions.
Why the mystery, Bill?
What's this all about?
We'll be there soon
enough, you'll see.
I've got to hurry.
(anticipatory music)
(screaming)
(crash)
(urgent music)
(Bill): Kurt? Kurt!
(knocking)
All right, all right!
For God's sake open the door!
I'm coming!
(knocking)
What's the matter?
What's happened to you?
There's been a
terrible accident.
I've got to save her,
I've got to save her.
What is it,
what have you got there?
Kurt, please!
Sterilize the tubes and
instruments, quickly!
Well what are
you going to do?
Aren't you going to have a
look in the closet first?
Oh, I can't now,
this is more important.
But you don't understand!
For God's sake,
Kurt, this is urgent,
do as I tell you
before it's too late,
I can't waste precious
time arguing with you!
(anticipatory music)
The eyelids!
I saw them move!
It can't be!
My eyes are deceiving me.
What you see is real.
What's done is done and
what I've done is right.
It's the work of science.
(whimpering)
I remember...
Fire.
Burning.
Let me die.
I've had success
with transplants,
now I can do it for her.
Transplant her onto what?
I brought her back,
she'll live,
and I'll get her another body.
I can make her complete again.
Only a madman can believe
that she could ever
be like before!
Don't argue with me.
I love her too much to
let her stay like this.
I'll restore her as before.
You'll see.
Can't you realize?
Can't you see?
There's a pattern
to all that lives!
An order,
an arrangement.
She had a heart,
and a brain,
and her spirit was in both,
not in one
or the other!
No.
I'll give her a
brain and a heart.
Yes, and what of her soul?
You say you love her and...
you can remember
her love for you.
Then how can you make of
her an experiment of horror?
All the skill and science
I possess was meant for this.
Life has a pattern.
The whole pattern of my
life is shaping itself
to save her now.
Then you intend to
go through with it?
Yes.
Sleep, my darling.
Rest and grow stronger.
(whimpering)
How long do you think
we can keep her alive
under these conditions?
48, 50 hours
at the most.
Yes.
And you really
believe you can work
a transplant on her?
Successfully?
Yes.
Like my arm?
(ominous music)
Withered and deformed.
Yours was an early
experiment that failed.
With her I'm using
my new Adreno-Serum.
It must work.
I...
I've got to go now.
If the police,
or anyone, call,
tell them you don't
know anything about it.
I don't think anyone
will trace us here
because her body was
burned in the wreckage.
Yes, yes,
of course, of course.
Look, Bill,
before you go,
do have a look in that closet.
It's the reason why
I called you up here.
(gurgling)
Keep it locked!
Last night it go so violent,
it almost broke out!
Oh, no, not through that thickness.
Keep it closed.
I've got to think about her now.
I've got to find her a body.
How are you going to
go about getting one?
Bill, how will you do it?
There are ways.
(ominous music)
(groaning)
(swanky jazz music)
(applause)
(seductive jazz music)
(machines whirring)
What took you so long?
What made you
think I'd come?
You know a good
thing when you see it.
Yeah, there was plenty to see.
I liked your act.
Is that all you liked?
Well your costume,
what there was of it,
was interesting.
Is that all?
The rest of the
equipment is standard.
But, uh, the arrangement
is pretty special.
You're no tourist just
looking at the sights.
What are you doing
here, slumming?
Oh, I get my
allowance once a week.
Okay, if you're so loaded,
you pay for the drinks.
I already did.
Are you hustling for the house?
I hustle for myself.
I'm the leading
lady around here,
I can sit with
the squares out front
or I can relax back
here with my friends.
I'll bet you you don't
have an enemy in the world.
Hmm?
(ominous music)
(machines whirring)
Let me die.
(whimpering)
Where are you from?
Oh, around.
Just looking around.
When you get done
looking, then what?
I operate.
I get your message;
you're coming across.
You could flip any chick
in the house; why me?
Well, like I said,
I'm looking.
Well, you don't have
to look any further.
I'm not gonna fake it for you.
When do you go
on again, huh, when?
Relax, I got another show yet.
But it could be for you.
Oh, I was just asking.
Try taking.
Are you getting nervous?
I'm over 21.
Oh it isn't that, it's...
I've just got things to do.
Things to take care of.
Well, if that's anything
that makes you sick
what could be more important
that could be taken
care of right now?
Oh I've, uh,
I've got to see about
helping somebody.
Somebody who needs
my help very badly.
You can't cut out
on me now, baby.
Not when you've got
me feeling so good.
I'm so warm all over.
I'm good for you.
I know I'm good
for what you want.
You may be just
what I'm looking for.
You've got your nerve.
Oh, look who's talking.
Why don't you haul
your beat-up body
back to the bar with
the rest of the flies?
Keep your g-string on.
I only came in here
to change my clothes.
I got admission.
Now I'd like to see
the rest of the show.
Come back in half an
hour and maybe you will.
Get lost.
Hi, loverboy.
I see you've met the queen.
(laughing)
Hey.
Come here, don't hide.
You know you've got
the kind of face
a girl doesn't mind looking at.
Even out front all
the other girls
were asking about you.
Get out of here.
Two's company,
three's a crowd.
Who's to tell me to
blow if I don't want to?
This here is my dressing
room too, remember?
It kills her to see
me make time.
You're the only thing
that's going to be made
around here tonight, honey.
Eat your heart out.
- Yeah?
- Yeah!
Yeah, well, uh,
I'd better be going, hmm?
What for?
Look what you've done!
You come busting in here
with your two cents.
Let me see you later.
I'll make everything up to you,
I swear I will.
Yeah, come on back later.
I'll remember you.
Yeah, that's
what I'm afraid of.
(upbeat jazz music)
You lousy tramp.
Once in a blue moon
I latch onto a guy
with class and you mess it up.
Eh.
What makes you
think you had him?
He wouldn't have you on a bet.
Says who?
Says me.
What's a guy like that
want with leftovers for?
Leftovers?!
Why, you cheap
third-rate stripper!
(incoherent screaming)
Let go!
There.
No!
I'll mash you like a bug.
Don't you cry.
Watch out.
(cat meowing)
(foreboding music)
(machines whirring)
You.
Inside the closet.
What has he done to you?
I know there's someone there.
Knock once if you hear me.
(knocks)
Then I'm not the first.
Knock twice if
I'm not the first.
(knocks twice)
He should've let me die.
I hate him for what
he's done to me.
If he only knew what it's
like being like this.
Do you know what it's like?
(knocks)
Together we could have revenge.
You want revenge?
(knocks)
Yes.
You the thing inside,
and me the thing out here.
My brain is still untouched.
And his keeping me alive
has given me a power
he didn't count on.
A power that you can feel.
Across this room and
through that door.
Can't you?
(three knocks)
Together we're both
more than things.
We're a power as hideous
as our deformities.
Together we'll
wreak our revenge.
I shall create power
and you will enforce it.
You, the thing inside.
Me, the thing out here.
(pounding at door)
(laughs)
What's locked behind that door?
Horror.
No normal mind can imagine.
Something even more
terrible than you.
No, my deformed friend.
Like all quantities,
horror has its ultimate.
And I'm that.
No.
There is a horror beyond yours,
and it's in there.
Locked behind that door.
The paths of experimentation
twist and turn
through mountains
of miscalculation
and often lose themselves
in error and darkness.
Behind that door
is the sum total
of Dr. Cortner's mistakes.
He had no right to
bring me back to this.
Perhaps not.
Who knows?
But you should know...
that before he injected
the serum into that,
it was but a mass
of grafted tissues.
Lifeless.
It just lay there,
weighted down
with its transplants of broken
limbs and amputated arms.
But with this serum,
it began to breathe.
That's impossible.
Would you have
thought possible
what he has already done?
Take yourself.
He has brought you back.
You live!
And only a few years ago,
all transplants were impossible.
That's what he's
been doing up here
where no one could see his work?
Yes.
Experimenting with
transplants on that...
and on me.
Letting him
tear away my flesh
time after time,
test after test.
My hopes shattering
with each grafted arm
he fastened to me.
Watching it wither and warp.
Instead of strengthening.
Now you see,
he's learned from his mistakes.
And you stayed with him.
Helping him in his grotesque work
that he claims is for science.
Was there a place
for me on the outside
with this?
In a world where eyes
would look upon me
with pity and people
would turn away from me
in disgust.
No, the alcoholic
has his bottle.
The dope addict his needle.
I had my research.
I used to be a surgeon.
It was my life.
Then one night in
the laboratory,
there...
there was an accident.
They had to amputate my arm.
And...
He has used you, too...
I had no choice.
He was my only hope.
A surgeon needs both
his arms, not just one.
Well, you see,
my transplanted
grotesqueness stayed,
and so did I.
I live only for the day
he can work a successful
transplant to my body.
That is why I stay.
Transplant...
my head onto another body?
Yes.
And he's insane with
the belief he can do it.
But the tissues of
my body would reject
the tissues of another.
Reject it as the
foreign substance it is.
The transplant would
never take,
it would never
stay in place.
My blood's antibodies
would attack it
as they attack any
invading matter.
Yes, but his new discovery,
this new serum,
may change all of that.
This serum,
injected into the bloodstream,
affects the lymphoid tissues.
Here in the neck,
the lymphoids
that provide the
antibodies for the blood
that detect foreign
transplanted matter.
It was untested, untried.
Until we used it on you.
So that liquid in the blood
that's being pumped
through what's left of me...
is what makes me feel the...
(laughs)
He may produce results
he didn't ask for.
Results?
You mean,
like this?
Results more
terrible than your arm
of relative beauty.
Results of power.
Of magnitude.
Power?
What power?
Can't you see that you're
at the mercy of every
element of the universe?
How can you speak of power?
I have a power.
This liquid that's
he's pumped into me,
my brain burns with it.
That thing inside
and I are in touch.
Want me to prove it?
Oh, you can prove nothing.
You're powerless!
I'll show you
how powerless I am.
You.
Behind that door.
(doorknob rattling)
Let me know if you hear me.
(knocks twice)
Whoever,
whatever you are...
I command you.
(knocks)
You understand me?
I'm only a head and
you're whatever you are.
Together we're strong!
More powerful than any of them.
(anticipatory music)
(door creaking)
What are you running from?
What's wrong with you?
Oh, it's you.
There's something wrong,
something beyond control
in that room.
There's nothing
beyond my control.
She's alive and
I'll keep her alive
until I find her a body.
I can't talk anymore,
I'm tired,
I've got to go to sleep.
Then you...
you didn't find her a body?
Well, I've got to be careful.
I can't afford to be
identified as the last person
seen with a girl
before she disappears.
Do you think you'll get one?
There are many things
left for tomorrow.
(swanky jazz music)
Hi, I was about to call a cop
the way you were
looking me over.
How have you been, Bill?
Oh, just fine, Donna.
I haven't seen you
for quite a while.
Too long, I'm still
waiting for that call you
once promised me.
Ah, you know how
it is with interns.
All work.
All work and
no play even makes
for dull doctors.
You're gonna lose that
bedside manner of yours.
Say, how about a little
side course in anatomy?
Yours, anytime!
No, not mine.
A Body Beautiful
contest, you know,
bathing suit models, plenty
of females on the hook.
Your eyes will have a
field day, interested?
Oh, why not?
You're just what
the doctor ordered.
Come on, jump in.
Ah, on second thought...
I just remembered I've
got to stop by my place
and take care
of a few things.
It'll only take a minute.
You don't mind, do you?
I always follow
the doctor's orders.
Anything you
prescribe, I'll take.
That's what I like
about you, Donna.
Always so obliging.
Hey Donna, where are you
going, what's the hurry?
Hey Jeannie,
we're going to look
for some bodies.
You mean the contest?
Yeah.
Got any room for me?
Oh sure, plenty.
Bill, this is Jeannie Reynolds.
Jeannie, this is
Dr. Bill Cortner.
- Hi.
- Hello.
Hop in, but first we
gotta stop off at his place.
Sure.
Well as a matter of
a fact, that can wait.
Now that there's two of
you, it will have to wait.
Guess he thinks
there's safety in numbers.
Oh, this time there is.
We promise not to hurt you.
And I promise
not to hurt you.
(laughing)
(car engine revving)
(chattering)
Oh Bill, there's a seat.
Oh, there looks fine.
(applause)
Oh, thank you.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
Well, it looks like
we're about ready to go.
Backstage are five of the
girls who have reached
the contest finals, and
we are here to choose
Miss Body Beautiful.
Now we've eliminated
everyone except the five
finalists and they will be
judged solely by your applause.
So let's bring them on.
First...
Helen Appleton.
(applause)
(swanky jazz music)
Betty Brockton!
(applause)
Terri Lund!
Peggy Howard!
(applause)
She has the second
nicest body I've ever seen.
What, second to you?
No, another girl,
a figure model.
You remember that one
in school, years ago.
The one who had the accident.
Oh yeah, yeah,
Doris, uh...
Doris Powell.
Yeah, is she still around?
Few people see her nowadays.
She just stays in her studio
posing for art classes
and camera bugs.
(foreboding music)
(thinking)
A figure model.
Poses for art classes.
The nicest body she's ever seen.
The nicest body.
Maybe this is the one.
She's got to be!
I can keep Jan alive only
for a few more hours.
I've got to find her a body.
He... he intends
to kill somebody.
To rob them of their body.
Do you hear me?
(knocks)
Yes, you hear me.
You know how Bill's
egotism drives him
on and on.
To infamy upon infamy.
How can good ever
be born of evil?
(knocks twice)
Yet he claims his
work is for science.
For humanity.
To be joined to
flesh not your own.
What's human in this?
Of how you must exist?
Locked behind that door.
We've got to stop him!
(loud knock)
(swanky jazz music)
Okay, boys,
I've had it for today.
Come on baby, one more.
Just one more, please!
Another five minutes, baby!
Time's just about up anyway.
Okay.
Say, Doris?
Would you like to
have a drink with me?
Just you and me,
away from everybody,
some place where
nobody will butt in,
where you and I can
really be alone.
No, thank you.
How about posing
for me, private-like?
I'll pay you real money,
real good money.
The kind of money they
don't throw at you
everyday and for doing
hardly nothing at all.
I do my posing
for classes only,
Wednesdays and
Saturdays 8:00 to 10:00.
Yeah, I know,
but we can—
Goodnight.
See it all, mister?
The show's over.
Next time bring a
camera and buy a ticket.
I'm not running a charity!
You don't remember me,
do you, Doris?
Every guy on the make
gives me that same tired line.
I'm Bill Cortner.
Bill Cortner.
Long time ago, that fight.
You almost tore
that wise guy apart
for making fun of me.
After my accident.
Look, uh, can't we
go somewhere and talk?
No, I don't date men.
Because I pose like I do,
your mind works overtime.
You get ideas.
You're all alike.
No, not all of us.
I'm not on the make for you.
Okay, so maybe
you're better than most.
Maybe not.
I still hate all men.
I hate them for what
one did to me once.
Have you forgotten?
Well, have you?
No, I haven't forgotten.
Well, neither have I.
I carry the memory
around with me.
Yeah, but you can't hide
yourself away here forever.
Posting bare in front
of a bunch of neurotics.
Listen, Galahad.
I trusted a man once,
all the way!
What did it get me?
He gets his head full of
jealous lies and I get—
You've got to
forget what happened!
How can I forget?!
I carry the memory
around with me.
Permanently!
(ominous music)
Am I so appealing to you now?
Still so interested?
Doesn't it make you sick?
You don't even
turn away from me,
like everyone else does.
To me you're not ugly.
I see only beauty in you.
You have a lovely
body and a face
that can be made
beautiful again also.
Yeah.
I've heard that song before.
I'm a doctor, I know.
My father is one of the
leading plastic surgeons,
if anyone can help you,
we can, I know I can.
I've been to doctors;
it's no use.
The scar tissue's too deep.
No one can help me!
Ah, ah, that was
a few years ago.
Today nothing is hopeless.
Yeah, we can graft scar
and skin tissue that...
Why we can even freeze
areas of the skin,
and sand away
damaged skin tissues.
The way you say that,
that look in your eyes.
I almost wanna believe you.
I almost wanna believe you!
Well then start
believing, hmm?
Even if your
father could help me,
I couldn't pay him the kind
of money it would take.
Oh, don't talk about money,
he does a lot of work
without any charge.
Why should you
wanna do this for me?
What's in it for you?
I'm gonna make your
face beautiful again,
cut it off and give
your body away.
(laughs)
I'm sorry.
Bill...
I have been knocked
around so many times...
I've lost count!
It's tough living with this.
I don't mean to
sound ungrateful.
Well, because you've
been battered around,
don't go sour.
You shouldn't lose
your trust in people.
Not all of us.
I believe you, I want to.
Do you really think
something can be done?
Only my father knows.
Look we have a country
place just out of town.
He's visiting for the weekend.
I could take you there
now for a consultation.
You mean tonight?
Well, if you'd rather
wait till he comes back,
if he comes back.
Oh no, no, I mean,
he wouldn't be annoyed,
being bothered with
me so late at night?
Well, you let me
do the worrying, huh?
I'll do anything
that'll help me
get rid of this face.
Well, that's where I come in.
Remember the last
time I helped you?
Where are you going?
Who are you calling?
My girlfriend, I want
to tell her the news.
Before you know what
the verdict is gonna be?
(ominous music)
You're right, I
shouldn't talk until I know
what's going to happen.
My girlfriend, she's
supposed to drop in later,
I'll have to leave her
a note or something.
Well, just tell her
you'll see her later.
Otherwise she'll ask a
lot of nosy questions.
We wanna be sure first.
Just throw something on, huh?
I'll be with you in a minute.
Just tell her
you'll keep in touch.
I'll leave it on the
table, she'll see it.
Had to go out with
old friend Bill Cortner.
I'll call you tomorrow, Doris.
Here.
I'll leave it on the lamp.
She'll see it, won't she?
That's the first
place she'll look.
I'll leave the
lights on for her.
Hmm.
I have waited
so long for this.
So have I.
(door creaking)
(banging)
Again!
Hit it again!
(door banging)
I've got to see
your hideousness.
And you've got to see mine.
I wonder which of
us is more awful.
Nothing you can be is more
terrible than what I am.
A head without a body.
A head that should
be in its grave.
I hate him.
I hate him for what
he's done to me.
Can your horror match mine?
(door banging)
Quiet, someone's coming.
I have come to
feed your friend.
While you feed yourself
with hate, it prefers food.
Your former sniveling
fear becomes you more.
Eh.
What makes you think I'm
afraid of what's in there?
Or of you?
A mere head in
search of a body.
People fear what
they don't understand.
And what they can't see.
Oh, what are
you talking about?
You're nothing but
a freak of life!
And a freak of death!
Why should I be afraid of
a few knocks on a door?
But last night you ran.
You were afraid of what you
imagined lay behind that door.
I?
Imagined?
It was I who helped graft
together the bits and pieces
that were stolen
from the hospital.
An amputated arm,
a leg, a torso.
It was I who helped
piece 'em together
like a monstrous jigsaw puzzle!
And that same medicine
that he's fed to me
to activate my lymphoid tissues.
Has he fed it to that?
No.
No, on that he used
an earlier formula.
It wasn't as successful as
the serum he's using on you.
But it was enough to allow
the transplants to take.
If your experiment
is successful...
oh, then it'll be my turn.
And what else
has happened to it?
What do you mean,
what else?
Well, it's...
It's mutated some, of course.
It's changed considerably.
Why don't you open the door?
Then we'll both see
how it's changed.
Listen, you.
I warned you.
You better stop pestering me,
do you hear?
I'm getting fed up with you
and your insidious talk.
He should've cut out your
tongue while he was at it!
Afraid?
Afraid of whom?
Of you?
No.
Not anymore.
But of it?
Nor of it.
He only keeps it
locked in there so that...
it will be safe,
that's all.
Safe?
From me?
(laughs)
Oh, you beast.
I hope he prolongs your
existence into a lifetime
of agony.
Then we'll see who's
laughing at whom!
You miserable fool!
(Jan): Get him!
(frightening music)
(screaming)
Get him!
Oh my arm, oh!
(screaming)
Kill him!
(gasping)
(laughing)
You and your
father live here?
Only on weekends
when we wanna get away
from the city.
This place
certainly is lonely.
Well, the further from
prying eyes the better.
I mean it's nice
and quiet here,
we can get away from
the noise and telephones.
Oh, I guess it is.
Well, sit down, sit down,
I'll fix us a drink, huh?
My father should be back soon.
You mean he's not here now?
Oh, come on now, Doris.
Do I look like a maniac who
goes around killing girls?
Now, you've got to
learn to trust people.
Well, people like me, really.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I trust you.
I trust you with my life.
Well, I can't ask
for anymore than that.
I'll be right back.
(ominous music)
(gasps)
Oh, I was beginning to think
you'd forgotten about me.
Forgotten you?
Oh, Doris, you've become
very important to me.
Very important.
I put a little water in
it, so it wouldn't be
too strong for you.
Fine, I'm not a
very heavy drinker.
Neither am I.
Well, um,
here's to your future.
Whatever it may be.
I'll drink to that.
(glasses clink)
(machines whirring)
(swanky jazz music)
Oh, it's getting
awfully warm in here.
(swanky jazz music)
I feel kind of funny.
Bill?
You put something in my drink!
Didn't you?
(glass shattering)
I told you I'd
bring you a body.
A beautiful one.
Soon it will be yours.
(Jan): Bill, you can't!
Yes, I can!
I want you as a complete woman,
not part of one.
Is it a crime to
wanna keep you alive?
Is it a crime for science
to jump ahead by years?
This kind of thing must be done.
When it's over, you'll see.
I've got to hurry now.
The drug will wear off
soon and she'll be awake.
When she does come to,
it will be your head
consciously awakening for her.
(anticipatory music)
You must be stopped!
You must!
And who's going to do it?
Now it's got to be quiet here.
You can't stop me.
Very well.
(banging on door)
(banging)
(rumbling)
(gasping)
(chemicals exploding)
(scuffling)
(screaming)
(fire crackling)
I told you to let me die.
(Jan laughing)