Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Mornin', stranger.
How are ya, old timer?
Guess you don't remember me.
Can't say as I do.
But there's somethin' mighty
familiar about you.
Well, Jake, I guess it's a
long time
Since you taught me how to
trap coyotes and ride broncs.
Jerry Mason, as I live!
Well, well, man, how you've
grown.
I say, you're a regular
mountain, ain't ya?
Sit down here and let's talk
it over.
Well, there's not much to
tell, Jake.
I finished college.
True to your dad's last
request,
You've come to live with me.
That's right.
I can't tell you how happy I
am to see you.
I'm happy to be here, too,
Jake.
How about the ranch? The
cattle?
There ain't no cattle, son.
Rustlers got most of 'em.
I sold what was left.
Can't we stock it up again or
start in some other business?
Itchin' to get to work, huh?
Well, I was figurin' on
openin' up the blacksmith shop.
What do you say we go in and
fry us a chicken
And gargle some coffee?
What do ya say, huh?
Sounds like a good idea,
especially that chicken!
( Laughs )
Jerry: well, no wonder this
horse was limpin'.
Well, got him fixed up?
Yep.
Horse picked up a sharp rock.
No, no, there ain't no charge.
Looks like you been through
plenty of water.
Yeah, tried a shortcut about
12 miles back yonder and got
stuck.
Yeah, tried a shortcut about
12 miles back yonder and got
stuck.
Yeah, tried a shortcut about
12 miles back yonder and got
stuck.
Had to come right down through
the middle of the crick.
That's why he went lame.
Well, good luck to ya.
Hey, Jake!
I just picked this up at the
post office.
I bet I know who it's from.
I was right.
Ha ha, it's from Betty.
Well, I was right.
It's from Betty.
Betty?
Yeah, my granddaughter.
Didn't you know I had a
granddaughter?
I certainly did not.
Yes siree.
I'm her only livin' relative.
I been sendin' her to college
for a couple of years.
She'll soon be here to live
with me.
Let's see what she's got to
say.
"Dear Grandy,
"I just received my monthly
check, and thank you so much.
"I can't wait until school is
over
"So I can come and live with
you.
"Gee, just three months more
and I'll be keepin' house for
you.
"Gee, just three months more
and I'll be keepin' house for
you.
"Gee, just three months more
and I'll be keepin' house for
you.
"Please write me a nice, long
letter.
"I do so enjoy hearin' from
you.
Lovingly, Betty."
Heh. She's a fine girl, Jerry,
And I'm gonna do everything I
can to make her happy.
Well, hello, Friday.
Ha ha ha!
She's the town dog.
Everybody feeds her.
Oh, so you wanna play, eh?
Say, Jake, take a look.
That's a piece of quartz that
came out of the horse's hoof.
It's gold!
Say, there's a stringer in
there bigger than a ten-penny
nail.
Say, there's a stringer in
there bigger than a ten-penny
nail.
Say, there's a stringer in
there bigger than a ten-penny
nail.
If we only knew where it came
from.
I do know.
That prospector said he was
forced down the middle of a
crick
12 miles out.
Well, there's only one crick
out there, Jerry.
It'll be a cinch to backtrack
it.
Well, we're on our way right
now, and if we find anything,
I know a dog that's gonna have
A porterhouse steak and a home
for life.
You said it!
Right there's where he left
the crick.
Wait a minute. Look at that.
Say, that's the real stuff,
son.
Accordin' to this sand, the
crick's full of color.
Hello. Hello, Benson.
What can I do for you?
First place, do you fellas buy
gold?
Certainly. That's part of our
business.
Weigh this up and let's see
what we got.
Say, that's the pure stuff.
It's as good as I've ever
seen.
You've made a great strike
somewhere.
Let's see.
$16 an ounce...
That'll come to $848.
Okay, we'll take that in
currency
If it's just the same to you.
Okay. All right, Joe.
Now listen, we expect to bring
in many times that amount.
We think we've got a rich
strike.
But we don't want anybody to
know anything about it.
You'll tell us, won't you?
We're not tellin' anybody,
Harris.
But when we do get ready to
let the location be known,
You'll be the first ones in on
it.
Thanks.
Come on, Jake.
We gotta go buy a dog a
porterhouse steak.
They made a rich strike,
And it's up to us to locate
it.
I wouldn't mind having old man
Benson's ranch, either.
He used to run cattle.
Huh! Course, he doesn't know
it,
But I got most of them.
Ya know, Jake, it's a good
thing
We didn't file on that claim.
It'd have tipped the whole
town off to the location
And confined our operation.
As it is, we can work the
whole crick.
Yeah. Your idea of crossin'
windy flats
And enterin' the town from the
other side
Sure had 'em puzzled. Hah!
It sure has. They been
back-trailin' the trail
For two months,
And they always get stuck at
windy flats.
They think this mine's out in
the middle of the desert.
Supposin' we take a little
rest, huh?
Just a few more days
And Betty'll be comin'.
Don't you think we better be
gettin' back
And gettin' some of this dirt
out of our hides?
Yeah, I reckon you're right.
You know, you wanna sure look
your best.
Hiya, pete.
Man: well, well.
Hello, hank. How's your old
woman?
It's all washed up, boys.
No pay dirt this time.
( All grumbling )
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
I tell you, we didn't get a
bit of color.
What?!
You was gone all this time?
Hold on. Now wait a minute.
Tell you what I'll do.
I'll give you every nugget you
find on the pack.
Yeah. Go on ahead and search
it.
Here comes old Benson now, and
Mason isn't with him.
Good. Are the papers all
ready?
Everything.
-Hello, Jake. -Hello, Hanson.
Well, what luck this time?
Not so bad.
Yeah, not so bad.
( All talking at once )
Let's see, at $16 an ounce,
That's, uh... $2,335.
How will you have it, in coin
or bills?
Bills is easiest to carry.
All right, Joe.
Sit down, Jake.
I've got to have your
signature this time, Jake.
The government demands that I
get a receipt
For all monies paid out for
all gold.
Sure.
Uh, Joe?
Stamp the date on that, will
you?
There you are.
And here's your money.
Thanks. Gimme my canteen, will
ya?
I'll be seein' you fellas
again mighty soon.
Good-bye.
Well, we got the deed to the
ranch,
And when he eventually
disappears,
We'll have this recorded.
Let's see what we made on the
nuggets.
Well, how much we get this
time?
$2,335.
Ooh!
I'm gonna hold out 500 of
that.
Pay on this blacksmith shop
tomorrow.
You know, Jerry, I got an idea
This is gonna be a valuable
corner someday.
And we ain't gonna let go of
it.
I think it's a good
investment, Jake.
Hello, dad.
Say, you got a couple of bucks
you can spare?
Gambling again, eh?
Well, that's about all there
is to do around this town.
Gee, I wish I had a job.
So do I.
And remember, can't keep this
up forever.
There's an end to everything.
Hey, Al. Come here a minute.
If you don't kick through that
dough you owe me,
I'm tellin' the town
everything.
That'll just about throw your
old man out of office.
Where am I gonna get it?
That's not up to me.
I don't care where you get it
or how you get it,
But get it.
Mr. Williams in?
Yes, Jake. You'll find him in
his office.
Thanks.
Come in.
Hi, Mr. Williams.
Well, Jake, I'm glad to see
you.
I wanna pay off my debt on the
blacksmith shop.
That's fine. Sit down.
Thanks.
I'll give you a receipt for
your money.
We'll put it into escrow.
You'll get your deed in a few
days.
Good-bye, Mr. Williams.
How's the claim coming?
Oh, still coughin' up a few
colors.
Won't be workin' it again till
next spring though.
Howdy, sheriff.
Hello, Jenkins.
( Sounds of scuffling )
( Glass breaking )
Better send for the doctor,
sheriff.
It's too late.
You've killed him, Jake.
I killed him?!
You're not trying to deny it,
are you?
Didn't I hear you fighting?
You were the only one in here,
Mr. Benson.
Somebody must've come in
through the back door.
That's the only way it
could've happened.
Don't worry, old timer.
I'll have you outta here in no
time.
This is Mr. Benson's ranch,
isn't it?
Why, yes. Are you Betty?
And you're Jerry Mason.
Why didn't you let us know you
were coming today?
I wanted to surprise Grandy.
Where is he?
Oh, uh...
Well, uh, you see,
When he gets out in the hills
prospecting,
Why, he...well, it's pretty
hard to tell when he is coming
back.
Why, he...well, it's pretty
hard to tell when he is coming
back.
Why, he...well, it's pretty
hard to tell when he is coming
back.
Why, he...well, it's pretty
hard to tell when he is coming
back.
Won't you come in?
Oh, gee, you don't know how
glad I am to be here.
I just can't wait to see
Grandy!
I'm gonna ride out and see if
I can't locate him.
I hope you find him.
Now just make yourself
comfortable, miss Betty.
Thank you, and I'll have
dinner ready for you when you
come back.
Thank you, and I'll have
dinner ready for you when you
come back.
That'll be great.
-Good-bye. -Good-bye.
Got any news, Jerry?
Nope. I'm just gonna give this
bank the once-over.
This may not mean anything,
But Al the sheriff's son has
been flashin' a roll of bills.
I know he hasn't done anything
to earn it.
He just paid me for a horse I
sold him.
Did Al Miller give you this
money?
He sure did.
Where'd you get that money,
Miller?
I don't think that's any of
your business.
I'm makin' it my business
Because that's part of the
money Jake Benson paid the
banker.
Because that's part of the
money Jake Benson paid the
banker.
Just where did you get it?
I told you before... it's none
of your business.
Tell these boys where you got
that money.
None of your business!
Oh, no?
I did it, I did it!
Let me go!
Hear that, boys?
( All exclaiming )
( Clamoring )
I tell you, sheriff, Jake is
innocent.
( All agreeing )
Wait a minute then.
If what you say is true
And my boy is guilty of this
crime,
I'll see that he gets the full
penalty of the law.
Here comes Mason now.
Yeah, there he comes.
Alton Miller, I arrest you for
attempted murder and robbery.
And I'm going to do my duty in
helping to exact the full
penalty
And I'm going to do my duty in
helping to exact the full
penalty
And I'm going to do my duty in
helping to exact the full
penalty
For your crimes.
Sorry, sheriff, that it had to
be your son.
I'm sorry, Benson.
That's all right.
I know just how you feel.
Here's the rest of the bank's
money, sheriff.
( Crowd clamoring )
Never keep me caged up in one
of them things.
( Laughter and chattering )
It's a mighty good thing
you're out
Because Betty's home waitin'
for you.
Betty?
Well, jumpin' jehoshophat!
Maybe you think I wasn't
worried.
Grandy!
Betty!
Well, well, well, well. Ha ha
ha!
I thought I was never going to
see you.
Thought so myself for a while,
But thanks to Jerry, here I
am.
I have dinner all ready for
you.
I'm sure ready for dinner.
Ha ha ha!
By cracky, that's the best
dinner I've had in years.
And that goes for me, too.
I can see it isn't going to be
very hard
To please you two.
Well, son, we won't be workin'
the mine again
Till next spring.
We can't afford to miss meals
like this.
I think I'll go out tomorrow
and hide the sluice box.
In fact, I'll stake out three
claims along the crick
And you can file on 'em.
After all, you know, better be
on the safe side.
While you're gone, I'll take
Betty around the ranch
And show her the town and our
blacksmith shop.
And you can figure on me bein'
here for dinner.
All right, Grandy.
This town is located about six
miles off that spur.
Whoa!
Hey, Mason, can I see you a
minute?
Pardon me a moment, Betty.
You know they're takin' young
Miller over to Cedar City?
Is that so?
I thought you might like to
know
That banker Williams is gonna
pull through okay.
Well, that is good news. Yeah.
Is Jake Benson around?
Why, no. He went to his claim
this morning.
But he'll be back this
afternoon.
Oh. Thanks.
Benson's out at his claim.
He won't be back till late
this afternoon.
This is just what we've been
waiting for.
Friday, there's some nuggets
that Jerry don't know nothin'
about.
Friday, there's some nuggets
that Jerry don't know nothin'
about.
Friday, there's some nuggets
that Jerry don't know nothin'
about.
Friday, there's some nuggets
that Jerry don't know nothin'
about.
Ha! Won't he and Betty be
surprised
When they hear that?
Ha ha ha!
Come on, Friday.
Guess we got here just in
time.
( Barking )
Drop your hands, Benson.
We've decided it's about time
You were tipping us off to
this gold field of yours.
Oh, so that's your game, eh?
Well, Jerry and me found that
gold field.
We ain't tippin' it off to
nobody.
( Barking )
He's done for.
Yeah. There's a canteen on
that pack.
Come on, we've got to catch
that mule.
There's the canteen sure
enough.
No use, Harris.
I can't get it.
Come on, we got to get outta
here and get back to town.
We can't afford to be seen
here.
Get your horse.
Now listen, Friday.
I want you to go get Jerry.
You understand?
Go get Jerry.
Go get him.
Why, that's Grandy's horse,
isn't it?
It sure is.
Say, here comes his pack.
There's Grandy's pack now.
What do you suppose has
happened?
I don't know, but I'm gonna
find out.
( Men murmuring )
What's all the excitement
about?
Old Jake's horse came in
without him.
Is that so?
Maybe we oughta organize a
posse.
( All talking at once )
Man: he never did this before.
Friday!
Where's Jake?
( Barks )
You better go back home and
wait till you hear from me,
Betty.
You better go back home and
wait till you hear from me,
Betty.
All right, Jerry.
( Barking )
( Rattling )
What's the matter, old timer?
Are you all right?
I'm only a little dizzy.
I'm gettin' better every
minute.
They only nicked me.
What are you talkin' about?
Who nicked you?
I'll tell you all about it on
the way home.
Come on.
Remember now, son, not a word
to Betty.
What happened, Grandy?
Oh, you're hurt!
No, tain't nothin' at all.
Horse throwed me and hit
square on my head.
What I need is a good feed.
I'll run right uptown and get
you something nice then.
Don't tell anyone that your
granddad is here.
Oh, all right.
Say, son, open up that trunk
and get out my makeup case,
Will ya?
Makeup case?!
Yeah.
This? That's right.
This here'll stop the
bleeding.
What in the world's this?
Oh, that's just a souvenir of
my old theatrical days.
I didn't know you were an
actor, Jake.
Yep. I wore that when I played
in a show
Called Charlie's aunt.
-Yeah? -Yeah.
What the heck is this?
Son, that's the thing that
helped make
Anna held and Lillian Russell
famous.
Oh, I see! Up here like this.
No!
You durn yearling. You got it
in the wrong spot!
Oh! ( Knock on door )
Hello, Mason.
Has Benson come in yet?
Not yet.
If he doesn't get in by night,
I'm goin' lookin' for him.
I reckon his horse threw him.
We just called to find out
When we could take possession
of this ranch.
Take possession?
I don't understand.
Well, maybe Benson didn't tell
you,
But we bought this ranch a few
days ago.
That's strange.
Funny he didn't tell me.
You got a bill of sale?
Why, certainly.
It's at the office.
Then I'll have Jake drop in
tomorrow
And he can advise you when
he's gettin' out.
That'll be fine.
We're anxious to get started
on
The improvements on the place.
What are they talking about?
I ain't sold no ranch.
Have you signed any papers
lately, Jake?
No. I don't think so...
Wait a minute.
Yes, I did.
I signed a receipt for the
money we got from them last
nuggets.
I signed a receipt for the
money we got from them last
nuggets.
Did you look at it closely?
No.
That's it then.
You probably signed a bill of
sale for the ranch.
That's why they were tryin' to
get rid of you.
They figured they could claim
the ranch then and nobody could
deny it.
They figured they could claim
the ranch then and nobody could
deny it.
Them dirty, lowdown polecats.
We'll get 'em.
You wait till my headache's
better tomorrow.
We'll give them the surprise
of their life.
Say, but you better go file on
them claims.
Take that canteen of nuggets
And leave it at the bank this
time.
Here's the location of them
three claims.
There's one for Betty, one for
you, and one for me.
All right. You better lie down
and get some sleep, Jake.
Don't you forget yourself.
Remember, I'm supposed to be
dead.
Oh, I ain't forgettin'.
There's Mason.
Isn't that old Jake's canteen
on the saddle?
Let's go see.
He must've taken it off the
burro before we got there.
What have you got there, boys?
Oh, hello, hello.
I...uh...
You see, sheriff, we
recognized this canteen.
It belongs to old Jake Benson.
Whenever Jake brought in his
nuggets to us,
Unknown to anyone else, he
brought them in this canteen.
We thought it was kinda funny
that old Jake's disappeared
And Mason should have this.
Where is Mason?
He went in the courthouse.
Pete, go in there and see what
Mason's doing.
I reckon he can explain this.
He's filing on a mining claim,
sheriff.
Probably old Jake's claim.
Well, we'll just wait till he
gets here.
Howdy, boys.
What's all the powwow about?
Just how did you come to have
this canteen of nuggets?
I don't care to answer that
question, Harris.
Whose claim were you just
filing on, Mason?
My own claim.
Do you know anything about
Jake Benson's disappearance?
Yes, I know he hasn't come
back.
I'm sorry, Mason, but I'll
have to hold you
Until we can locate Jake.
That's fair enough.
When do I get my preliminary
hearing?
First thing tomorrow morning.
You better take charge of
those nuggets, sheriff.
( Murmured conversations )
What are they gonna do to
Mason?
They think he killed old Jake.
They do?
What's happened? What's wrong?
Mason's up for murder.
-Murder?! -Yes.
Sheriff, may I please have a
moment with Mr. Mason?
Yes, I guess so.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Oh, Jerry...
Now listen, Betty.
They think I've murdered your
granddad.
Don't say anything to anyone,
But hurry home and tell Jake
That I have a preliminary
hearing in the morning,
And for him to get there
without being seen by anyone.
All right, Jerry. Good-bye.
Good-bye.
( Giggles ) bye.
( Door closes )
Grandy, they've got Jerry
locked up in jail.
What's that?
They think he murdered you.
Jerry says he's to be in court
in the morning
And for you to be sure and get
there without being seen.
I understand.
Ha! Will I be there?
And how! Ha ha ha!
The way I see it, we haven't a
chance in the world to lose.
In a couple of weeks, we'll be
gettin' outta here,
Be on top of the world.
Yeah.
Pardon me, gentlemen, but I'm
looking for the courthouse.
You're standing right in it,
madame.
For goodness sake!
I do love murder trials. Don't
you?
But if I were a murderer,
I'd much prefer the electric
chair
Than to have a rope around my
neck,
Wouldn't you?
Listen, lady, we're not
interested.
But you're going to be.
Man: here comes the sheriff
and Mason now.
My goodness, what big feet.
( Laughter )
Just a minute, boys. Check
your hardware.
Come on, let's get in here.
This thing is just about to
start.
( Pounds gavel )
Bailiff: Hear ye, hear ye,
hear ye.
The court of Sonoma county is
now open,
Judge McGill presiding.
Everybody be seated and come
to immediate order.
Your honor, before you proceed
further with this case,
There's a few words I'd like
to say.
What is your name, madame?
Veronica Mehitabel Benson.
Any relation to Jake Benson?
Oh, yes.
I'm his dearest relative.
What do you want to say,
madame?
I wanted to say that I've
known the accused
Since he was a babe in arms.
( Laughter )
Quiet, please.
As I was about to say...
I knew him years ago, and he
was the sweetest thing.
( Laughter )
Come to the point, madame.
Well, I know who shot Jake
Benson.
The men are in this court,
your honor,
And I advise the sheriff
Not to let anyone leave this
room.
They tried to steal his mine.
They tried to steal his ranch.
And they shot him down in cold
blood.
How do you know this, madame?
Because I was there when it
happened, your honor.
Sheriff, swear miss Benson in.
Order in the court!
Please put on your dress!
I ain't an old lady!
I'm Jake Benson!
And there's the two coyotes
that shot me!
Come on, Benson!
How do you run this thing?
I'll do the driving.
All right now, folks. That
looks fine.
Just a minute. Relax a minute.
Here we go.
You must remember that I spent
most all of the afternoon
Trying to get you in position.
Now hold it just like that.
Hold her, hold it.
Hold it!
Ready now...