- Can I come in now?
- No!
Well,
- I believe that's everything.
- I hope so.
- Yes, it's a lengthy
business. You must be tired.
I'm so excited.
I wish we could take the
youngster right home with us.
- When do you think we
can expect to get him.?
Well it's...
Just a minute.
I'm afraid I forgot something.
You have to sign these.
These give admission to check into
every detail of your private life.
- There.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Well, that does it I think.
I'm sorry to have kept you so long,
but you understand that we
must be most careful.
After all, it's a child's life. Our
investigation can't be too thorough.
How long will it be?
- A matter of months
perhaps, but we'll keep you...
- Thank you very much.
Eve dear, we'll be late.
- Good bye and please hurry.
- Adiós.
- Good bye.
- Good bye, thank you.
- Now can I come in?
- Yes.
Interview report to the directors.
Names of applicants...
Harry and Eve Graham.
She is 32, he's 38.
Occupation... traveling salesman
for the Setter Sales Corporation,
dealing in electrical appliances.
The company is owned by the Grahams
and was started about four years ago.
Mrs. Graham appears to be very
capable. She handles the office work.
Mr. Graham covers the Los Angeles area
Where they hold a sales franchise
for the deep freeze concern.
Their income...
presently about $20,000.
Married... eight years.
They... you don't need to wait
for me. I'll straighten up.
No, I tried that once before
and nearly lost my job.
You and your cleaning up.
Go on. You're not disturbing me one bit.
Mrs. Graham is unable to have a family.
Her problem is of undetermined origin,
But we'll check several
physicians
who have examined her
during the past eight years.
They will take an older child,
four, or five years of either sex.
From the preliminary interview,
it's my opinion they
would make fit parents,
But something bothers
me about Mr. Graham.
He seemed impatient
during the interview...
a chip on the shoulder sort of attitude.
He behaved rather strangely when signing
the permission to investigate form.
Perhaps this is my imagination.
I'll report further when I visit
the Grahams home
for the
customary inspection
next week.
Well that's that.
If all the others was
like you there wouldn't be
any babies given away
in this state at all.
Why are you such an old fuss budget?
If you had made a mistake once
you wouldn't want to
ever let it happen again.
Not where a child is involved.
Well,
good bye dearie.
Eve Graham,
22 Sutter Street,
and Harry Graham.
- What goes on?
- I couldn't resist him.
He's the beginning of a collection.
There's a whole army that goes with him.
- But you haven't heard anything yet.
- But we will. You'll see.
Mr. Jordan looks like Santa Claus.
Just like a man who gives babies away.
And anyway it's good practice for
you being awakened by mechanical toys,
or a teddy bear in the face. Maybe
later on a football in the tummy.
You'll learn to love it.
You will love it, won't you?
Of course I will.
Why do you ask?
Then it's just by imagination.
The other day in Mr. Jordan's office
I thought maybe you were sorry
we'd started the whole thing.
I wasn't sorry. It's just
that Santa Claus was such
a deliberate old codgie he
got on my nerves, that's all.
How about undoing my blouse?
How about getting
yourself pulled together?
This is Tom Morgan's Saturday with us.
- You can do the Caesar salad.
- What else is cooking?
Everything you hate.
Roast beef rare, potatoes brown...
How does that sound, master?
Sounds like the perfect wife. Good
in the office, great around the house.
I wonder if it will like him?
Well, if it doesn't I'll keep it myself.
I remember other Saturday afternoons.
When it was always like this.
Long time ago.
- This really is a
beautifully planned apartment.
Yes, we think so.
Immaculate!
- You sure you won't
have something? A Coke?
Could I have a glass of milk instead?
- Yes, surely sir.
- Thank you.
My stomach, it's my work...
all the tension.
If you don't mind my
saying so Mr. Jordan,
I think you take your
work much too seriously.
- It's not worth it.
- I think it is.
By the way,
we've begun our investigation on you.
How does it look?
Everybody speaks very highly of you.
But?
I've been a salesman
too long not to recognize
Sales resistance when
I see it Mr. Jordan.
I have a feeling you don't
want us to have the child.
I wouldn't say that.
Thank you.
Well?
I don't know whether I do
or not, at least not yet.
I understand you spend a great
deal of time In Los Angeles
- on business.
- Yes, that's right.
Then perhaps you would
give me the names
of some of the people down
there with whom you work.
- It's all routine
nothing more than that.
- You're very conscientious
aren't you Mr. Jordan?
Well, I'll drop you a line and refer
you to lots of people in Los Angeles.
There's something else about
me I think you should know.
I have a small mole on my right
shoulder. Would you like to see it?
- Mr. Jordan, I'm sorry I'm late.
- That's all right. I was early.
- What are you two doing in the kitchen?
- Mr. Jordan's been looking us over.
I've seen your home.
- It's pleasant, very pleasant indeed!
- Won't you stay for dinner?
Thanks, I can't I
have to get back to the office.
Lots more paperwork to do there.
- I'll see you to the door.
- Thank you.
Good bye, Mr. Graham.
Thank you, Mrs. Graham.
- What happened between you two?
- I'm sorry.
- I don't know hit me.
- Sorry?
He said he liked you but
didn't think you liked him.
Anything else?
That we could start fixing up that room,
and he thought I'd be a good mother.
For once Mr. Jordan is right.
Well, the star salesman of the Sutter
Corporation had better get on his horse.
What time's your plane?
9:15, I've got a date with
a Clark Company
buyer first
thing in the morning.
By the time your a father,
just think you can hire
one salesman or even two
the way things are going.
- And you can stay
home and run the show.
What's this? Are you resigning?
- No, I'll be around to heckle a bit.
- That's a woman's privilege.
Now I've got to pack.
No, I'll do it for you,
but there's not much to pack.
Everything's in Los Angeles.
Don't you ever get a hole in your stock?
And how do the buttons
manage to stay on your shirts?
You never bring them home.
I've found a laundry that does
it, saves a lot of trouble.
I'll only be a minute packing your bag.
Yes, I know Harry Graham very well.
Like him.
He handled our product
for several years until...
Until what?
We didn't fire him if that's
what you're getting at.
He fired us...
got a better deal.
I see.
I'd give my shirt to get Graham back,
and you can tell him I said so.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
The Grahams wish to adopt a child,
and we must have certain information.
Well isn't that nice.
They want to adopt a baby?
How long has Mr. Graham
made his office here?
I guess about two years.
Where does he live when
he's in Los Angeles?
I guess he just lives around...
hotels, motels, wherever he can get in.
It's cocktail time,
honey! Are you with me?
Mr. Jordan, this is Roy Esterly.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
What line are you in?
Mr. Jordan is getting some
information on Harry Graham.
Harry's not in any trouble.
Mr. Jordan's not a cop.
I'll tell you later.
OK, sweetie. You fill him in on Mr.
Exclusive and, when you get through
come on back and have
a little shot with me?
Excuse me, but could I
ask you a few questions?
Why sure, sure, fire away.
What do you know of Mr. Graham?
He's a good guy.
But you called him
- Mr. Exclusive.
- I was kind of kidding I guess.
We never see him except
here in the office,
and of course when he's
here he's buried in work.
I can't understand how a
guy can live without a little
social life.
So he's not a playboy like
some cornballs I could mention.
Playboy! He's the
original Invisible Man!
You never see him anywhere.
He's not at the hotels, restaurants,
nightclubs. Man comes to town
and just like that he disappears.
Mr. Jordan,
I have an idea.
I'm sure Harry will be calling,
and you can get everything
you want right from him.
I'll call the hotels for you.
Why don't you just sit
over there at Harry's desk.
Thank you, Miss.
Maybe I should see Mr. Graham after all.
Yes, I'll wait.
As long as you're going
to all the trouble,
would you kindly ask
the hotel people when Mr.
Graham was last registered?
Surely, I could do that.
Mr. Jordan,
your throat must get pretty dry
asking all those questions.
How about a little slug?
No.
Thanks.
Very kind of you.
No.
Bob Vance never called, did he?
- That's good because I
don't want to talk to him.
Hello?
No, he's in Redland.
He'll be back the day after tomorrow.
Yes, I'll have him call you.
Harry Graham.
Harry...
Harrison Graham.
Good night.
You've really got Harry
Graham on your mind.
I'm sorry I took so long
but the hotels had to check.
It's funny but he hasn't
registered any of them for months.
Several of them remember him.
He could be staying at
a rooming house,
but that doesn't sound like him.
He likes everything nice.
You're very kind.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
By the way, is Mr. Graham known
by any other name than Harry?
No, his name is Harry.
Look, Mr. Jordan,
he was in yesterday, and I know
I'll be hearing from him soon.
Give me a number and
I'll have him call you,
or maybe you've gotten
everything you need?
No, not yet.
Excuse me, it's that board.
Thank you.
Graham Harrison.
Harrison Graham.
132...
Wait for me, please.
Good evening.
Hello, aren't you a
little off your beat?
Well, I was coming to Los
Angeles for a meeting tomorrow.
I'm reading a paper at
a welfare convention.
How nice.
So while I was here I've been
doing a little checking up on you.
Tell me,
why are you listed
in the telephone book
under Harrison Graham?
Harrison Graham's my real name.
You changed it?
Some time ago. I thought it sounded a
little formal, if you know what I mean.
Yeah, but in San Francisco
you're listed as Harry.
The phone company got it mixed up.
Look, I'm dead on my feet. I just got
home from work a couple of hours ago.
Suppose we meet for lunch tomorrow.
Maybe we can learn to get along.
Well, I'm busy tomorrow, but...
I'm sorry I bothered you,
but after all it is my job.
That's right, I understand.
- Good night.
It's all right.
You'll wake them both up.
My wife's sick, too.
She's in the other room asleep.
She's been up with the
baby two nights in a row.
How long has this double
life of yours been going on?
8 months.
And you tried to adopt a child!
- What are you going to do?
- Call the police.
You can't, not now.
Not with her like this.
Please, I've got to try
to make you understand.
I can't believe it.
I can't be...
How could a man like you...
successful, admired...
get into a position as...
as vile as this?
How?
I don't know.
I don't know how.
Loneliness, I guess.
Have you had to spent half
you life living in hotel rooms,
eating in restaurants
with only a newspaper for company,
walking the streets
looking for a movie you haven't seen?
Well,
that's the way it was
one Sunday afternoon
when I was
stuck in Los Angeles.
I couldn't get home to
spend the weekend with Eve.
I'd called her,
but we didn't talk about us.
She was in one of her
executive moods... career woman.
You've never seen her that
way. She's different now.
When I got off the phone
I was twice as lonely.
I felt as if the walls of the
hotel room were closing in on me.
So, I decided to go out of a walk.
Some men on the road
escape their loneliness
with women who are easy to get,
but that didn't work with me.
In all the years of my marriage
I never looked at another woman.
Eve was my whole life.
Yet sometimes in those years
I felt a distance between
us which was more than miles.
When we found out we
couldn't have children,
Eve was bitter and restless.
It was my idea her
coming into the business.
She caught on fast,
so fast she'd doubled
our sales in no time.
And our marriage,
it became a business partnership.
So on that particular Sunday
my aloneness
was like a pain.
Visit that fabulous Beverly Hills.
It's only $3.25 including tax,
and it'll give you something
to talk about
when you get
back to your hometown.
Hey, folks the just
about ready to leave.
See the homes of all of
Hollywood's greatest movie Stars.
Visit that fabulous Beverly Hills!
It's only $3.25 including tax.
It'll give you something to talk about
what you get back to your hometown.
I liked movies, though I really
didn't care where Clark Gable lived.
But here were people going someplace,
and I went along with them.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is glamorous Beverly Hills.
Here are the most
beautiful homes In the world
where your favorite stars
of screen live and play.
Over there is the home of a
woman who knows Hollywood best,
a lady who shares her secrets
with millions... Louella Parsons.
Thanks.
Here we are.
On your right
is the home of that
shy and modest man...
Harvey's friend and
yours... Jimmy Stewart.
Now take a look on your left,
and you'll see the home
of that funny, funny man
Jack "The Miser" Benny.
Who was Santa Claus
to the whole world...
...Edmund Gwenn.
Remember
"Miracle on 34th Street?"
That was a wonderful
picture. Did you see it?
You missed something.
I'd like to know where my
favorite Neil Francis lives.
What's that?
- Excuse me.
- That's all right.
Haven't you any interest
in how the other half lives?
No, not particularly.
I'm just crazy about bus rides.
Gives me a chance to get off my feet.
And here is a home of a man
who's good with the jokes
and a genius at the piano...
...Oscar Levant.
I heard him play a Gershwin
concert once. He was just great.
What is this, the story of your life?
Were you wondering where
our glamour girls are?
All right, here's your answer.
On the right
you see the home of that
fine actress Barbara Stanwyck.
The white house, also on the right,
is where lovely Jane Wyman lives.
You know, you just like me
for my lighter, that's all.
I could give up smoking.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
If this is a sample of your work,
you're not very good at pick-ups.
I know.
I haven't had very
much experience at it.
This is the first time I
ever tried to pick up a girl.
Gee, that's too bad.
I should be better at it.
How's that?
I'm of those terrible fellows that
frightens the farmer's daughter.
I'm a traveling salesman,
only a kind of backwards one.
Yeah, you could use a few tips, like
"I'm sad and lonely", just
want someone to talk to.
Don't know any nice girl
in this great big town.
How about a few laughs?
You know,
I wanted to say all those things
to you just now, only on the level.
Thanks, coach.
Do you mind if I sit here?
There's not much I can
do about it. You're here.
- You know something? I was
a farmer's daughter once.
Really?
Yeah.
I don't know what it is, but
you don't scare me at all.
Well, thanks for the
use of the lighter. Bye.
Just a minute.
In case,
you ever need a deep freeze my name's
Harry Graham from San Francisco.
That's nice.
- And mine's Phyllis Martin, from here.
- From here?
This doesn't look like
very good farm land.
You told me you were
a farmer's daughter.
Yes, well that was a long time ago.
Thanks.
Whoops, doesn't work.
Remember me to Jack Benny.
And there's something else you
should know about traveling salesmen.
You kill me.
They have very large expense
accounts and frequently
buy dinner for pretty
girls they meet on buses.
I must say your style's improving fast,
- but I'm afraid I can't, sorry.
- I'm sorry too.
Yeah, well...
Do you like Chinese cooking?
Sure, why?
Have you changed your mind?
I know a place that has
the greatest water chestnuts in town,
if you
can stand water chestnuts.
- I'm mad about them.
- Let's go.
Early American Chinese...
You're going to love it.
Little place isn't it?
Cenaremos aquí?
Yes, it's a must. Now why don't you
relax and I"ll be back in a few minutes?
Hi Sam.
- Good evening Miss
Martin. Good evening sir.
- Will you take care
of the gentleman for me?
Right this way sir.
I'll have a drink at the bar
while I'm waiting for the lady.
Scotch and soda please.
- Here you are sir.
- Thank you.
Dinner's ready. Table's over there.
What are we playing, charades?
The offer came with a job. I work here.
- I don't believe any of this.
- The pain will wear off in a minute.
Just follow me.
Egg soup, very healing. I ordered
the rest of the dinner for you, too.
- Aren't you allowed to
sit with the customers?
Maybe later.
Go on, eat your soup.
It's the only genuine
Chinese dish we serve here.
Guy who owns the place used to
run a string of hot dog stands.
His name's Hannigan.
- You sure you can't sit down?
- No, I can't. Try it.
How is it?
Tastes good.
Where are all the people?
Sundays are quiet, and
all the rest of the week.
- How long you been working here?
- About 6 months.
I needed a job and Hannigan needed
someone to liven up the joint.
You can see I've been a howling success.
- Come on, sit down?
- No, I can't.
Where'd you say that farm was?
I didn't.
A little place called Pennsylvania.
- How'd you get all
the way to Los Angeles?
I wanted to see the world.
- So you started with China?
- That's right.
- You know something?
- What?
They've never heard
of chop suey in China.
- You don't say.
- That's right.
It's the House Specialty
here, and the next course
If you can stand it.
This isn't as nice as Barbara
Stanwyck's but it's closer to my work.
Here, let me.
Thanks.
Well,
- thanks for a lovely evening.
- It was nothing.
Drop in again sometime.
- So long.
- You know,
we've been together seven hours, and
I still don't know a thing about you
except that you're the nicest
stranger I ever met on a bus.
I don't know anything about you either.
- Let's leave it that way?
- All right.
I will tell you one
thing about myself though.
What's that?
On that bus this afternoon I
felt just as lonely as you did.
I feel better now.
I guess all traveling
salesmen aren't alike?
Some of us are quite harmless.
Yeah, you're kind of special.
Good night.
I never expected to see Phyllis again,
but I knew I'd remember this day
when two strangers helped each
other through a lonely Sunday.
I felt good again,
not very sleepy.
We're ready with your
call to San Francisco.
Thank you operator.
Eve.
My, two calls in one day!
Well never mind darling,
this is deductible business.
Monkey business,
I cheated on you today. I thought
you should be the first to know.
Haven't you heard, the wife
is always the last to know?
I'm serious, a beautiful brunette,
all curves and soft shoulders.
How wonderful! I hope you'll
be very happy together.
What kind of talk is that?
Aren't you even jealous?
You won't spoil my sleep one bit.
You're mighty sure of me aren't you?
I'm very sure of you my darling.
She wasn't really beautiful, just
nice, kind of a funny little mouse.
- Don't you want to know how I made out?
- I forgot!
I heard that Duff's may open three more
retail outlets in Los Angeles county.
Got a pencil handy?
Better write down this name and address.
Are you listening?
Here it is.
He's the merchandise manager.
Yes, I'm listening Eve. I've got it.
I wish you were here with me right now.
I didn't even touch her.
Touch who?
You know, the funny little mouse.
What a shame. Better luck next time.
Harry, I got a special
delivery from mother today.
What's the news?
Father's quite ill. Nothing serious
I suppose, but I'm a little worried.
I wouldn't worry darling.
I'm sure he'll be all right.
Eve...
I've got to make the rounds.
I'll call you in a couple days.
- Good night.
And in a couple of days
I did get home, dead tired
and a little bit sick of
the deep freeze business.
I only wanted a weekend with Eve,
but she had other plans, big plans.
Tom Morgan, our lawyer,
and Carl Forbes,
who's a buyer for the Redmond chain.
I'd never been able to sell him.
Then Eve decided she'd
try the woman's touch.
Why didn't you ever send your wife in
to sell me? She packs quite a punch.
Haven't you heard? Eve's
the brains, I'm the brawn.
Don't listen to him. I'm just Harry's
little secretary trying to get along.
I was afraid you'd ask
me how the thing worked.
Well, how does it work?
Would you like some more coffee?
No thanks, now tell us all about
the superior mechanical features.
All right, but stop me if this
gets too complicated for you.
In the home size there's a special
condenser that eliminates the fan noise
and the outside moisture.
The single phase motor
it is completely sealed
so it has greater efficiency,
and we can prove to you,
that our product will save you,
in electricity, $0.025 per hour.
And the lid is counterbalanced.
We just happen to have
a model in the kitchen
and, if you have your combination
Phillips Screwdriver handy Mr. Forbes,
I'd be happy to take the
freezer apart for you.
Any questions?
No, ninguna, ni demostraciones,
me ha convencido...
at least almost. Perhaps
another little brandy?
Harry, Mr. Forbes would
like some more brandy.
Harry.
Of course. I'm sorry.
- Tom?
- No thanks, no more.
How about a little poker?
The evening's so nice we
might play on the terrace.
- I'm afraid of you, but I'm game.
- Me too.
Come on Harry, let's have at it.
I think we're really on our
way. I'm sure we got Forbes.
That's the power of a woman for you.
I'm so happy.
I'm so sleepy. Good night, darling.
Eve.
I just figured something out.
In the last month we've be
together six days and 14 hours,
not counting when we're asleep.
It doesn't make any sense.
Did you hear me?
6 days, 14 hours.
Eve, let's go away tomorrow.
Doesn't matter where, just
as long as we're together.
Of course we'll go away sometime,
we'll go to all those glamorous
places that Holliday writes about.
And we'll do it first cabin, too.
Let's not wait, Eve.
A marriage is the only
thing that really matters.
I love our marriage.
Good night, darling.
So I hit the road again,
and when I got back to Los Angeles
One tea coming up. Rice cakes
and your fortune free. Shall we...
- Come on, sit down. Just for once.
- You want me to lose my job?
What does it say?
You will travel far. That's right on
the button for a traveling salesman.
Here's another one.
Money and fortune await
you. That's better.
And the last one.
Dance and the world dances with you.
Wow,
things are warming up.
Do you like to dance?
I don't know, it's been a long time.
Do you want to take a chance with me?
All right, when you finish tonight.
Where will we go?
Why don't we stay
here? It's so romantic.
You're a little character.
Miss Martin, over there.
Sorry.
See you later.
That night we danced.
There were other evenings
with Phyllis, too.
We asked nothing of each other.
I had never kissed her,
never touched her.
Just being together was enough.
But all the time I suppose
we were fooling ourselves.
Ready.
- Good night.
Good night.
Well...
- Phyllis.
- Yeah?
Tomorrow's my birthday.
Do you want to have dinner
with me, help me celebrate?
I'd love to, and tomorrow's my day off.
I'll pick you up at 7:00.
Sure you haven't anything better to do?
I'm sure.
OK.
Phyllis.
Good night, Harry.
Good night.
- See you tomorrow then?
- At 7:00.
Bye.
I spent my birthday trying
not to think of Phyllis.
Still I felt her closeness.
I was finding out that I was
not the take it or leave it kind.
I knew then I couldn't see Phyllis
again, that night or any night.
I felt like someone who
walks away from the edge
of a cliff
back onto solid ground.
I feel pretty low, too,
about walking out on her,
but it was better this way.
Much better.
Come in.
Tray's over there.
Not much of a way
to spend your birthday.
Didn't you get my message?
Well sure I got it. That's
why I came over. I was worried.
What's wrong?
Nothing serious, I think I'll live.
Just a headache I couldn't shake.
Yeah?
Feels better, lots better.
I brought you a birthday present.
It's nothing much,
just a Cadillac.
- Why don't you want to open it?
- Sure, I'll open it.
A bit flashy, but I
thought you'd like it.
Smells good. I do like it.
Thank you, Phyllis.
Well, may as well put a gift to work.
Just close your eyes now.
We'll take that headache away.
It's working already.
Many happy returns.
You know something?
The headaches all gone.
We're going to have
that dinner after all.
No, we're not going anywhere.
You're going to take it easy.
Lady,
you have healing powers
that are miraculous.
I can already hear a soft
piano, champagne corks popping,
and I know just
the place we're going to.
We're going to Acapulco.
- You're crazy.
- Yes, and I need a shoot, too.
Look,
I'll go home and get into something
slinky, then pick me up in 15 minutes?
All right, I'll get into
something real uncomfortable.
You kill me.
See you.
It's such a lovely night.
This is going to be even
better than the last bottle.
I'm glad your birthday
only comes once a year.
This once was worth it.
Acapulco.
I never thought I'd make it.
And only 30 minutes from downtown.
You fall in love here,
it goes with the check.
- When did you make that up?
- Just now.
Have you ever been in love?
I've tried it.
You know what I think?
I think you feel in love once, got hurt,
and have been running away ever since.
Am I right?
I bet you read poems, too.
Yeah, he was with the
occupation forces in Germany.
You've heard of those Dear John
letters haven't you?
Well I got a Dear Phyllis.
Seems I lost out to a little Fraulein.
I guess all men are no good?
I don't know. I think there are one
of two nice ones left in circulation.
Here's looking at you Phyllis.
Thanks.
- Well you're a funny one.
- Why?
Don't you want to know if
there's someone in my life,
whether I'm married, divorced,
or have six children,
wehether I've spent any time in jail?
No.
Por qué no?
What could would it do me if
I did know all those things?
I like you as you are, the way we are.
I don't want anything from you,
and I'm afraid of being in love again.
You know I'm going away again tomorrow.
Tomorrow's a long time off.
Eve!
Eve.
- What's wrong?
- Darling, I'm so glad you're back.
What's the matter?
Father's had a heart attack.
His condition's critical,
and I have to go at once.
Poor baby.
I'm sorry.
He's such a great guy. Do
you want me to go with you?
Thanks, but you better stay
here and take care of things.
Anyway I got the last seat on the plane.
What time?
10 o'clock, I change planes
at New Orleans for Miami.
What about money?
We're out of cash to check.
How was the trip?
Pretty good. We got the Barlow
account, but it took some doing.
- Hunt, Hills and Ventura is
complaining about factory deliveries.
I got that all straightened out.
Fine.
Well I'll take care of the
office here until you get back.
If you need any help,
call. I'll hop a plane.
Maybe he'll pull out of it?
I hope so.
I almost forgot.
How lovely!
You like it?
I'm crazy about it!
Put it on for me, will you?
What do I have to thank for this?
All that new work with Barlow's or that
cute little mouse you told me about?
- Did my boy step out of line?
- Thank me.
And I'll do it like this.
Eve.
This last trip...
It's no good being away from each other.
How would you like me to be around
all the time? Could you stand it?
- What do you mean?
- One of these days
soon we'll put a man on.
I've got my eye on a fellow.
I think I'm going to cry.
I should be so happy
if it weren't that...
Finish your packing, darling.
I'll make us a couple of drinks.
- I've been thinking about something.
- What is that?
About your being here
with me all the time.
I didn't realize home
meant that much to you.
I've been so wrapped up in the business
that I thought you liked
things the way they are.
I did, but I've had it.
Now I want to stay put.
- And I was wrong about
something else, too.
Wrong?
For nearly four years, ever
since the doctor said no baby,
I hated myself, and you, and everybody.
I was resentful when you
suggested adopting one.
I couldn't see taking care
of somebody else's child.
- Remember that?
- Yes, I remember.
I was wrong.
What made you think of it
now, after so much time?
Maybe it was the telegram from home.
I suddenly thought how
much my family meant to me,
and how much they loved me,
and it seemed selfish not to pass it
along to a little child that needed it.
Even if it isn't your own?
That doesn't seem to
make any difference.
- Do you still want one?
- Yes, of course I do.
Well then would see maybe about
getting one while I'm away?
Tomorrow morning, the very first thing.
I thought you'd forgotten all about
it, that the business was our baby.
- Will you forgive
me for taking so long?
Yes, I forgive you.
Announcing the departure of
American Airlines flight 516
to Atlanta and New Orleans,
connecting with Miami.
All aboard please.
Well, that's us.
So that's how I first
crossed your path Mr. Jordan.
I called you on the phone
wanting to know how to start.
We wanted a little boy or a little
girl, Didn't make any difference which.
And we wanted it faster than any
child had ever been adopted before.
But you told me it wasn't
as easy as all that,
and how right you were.
Yes.
You wanted to ride
roughshod over all our rules.
Then what changed you?
What happened after that?
I stayed close to the business except
for three flying trips to Florida.
You see Eve's father
had improved, but it
took a lot out of her
mother and she collapsed.
It went on month after month. There was
nothing Eve could do except stay there.
It had been over three months
since I'd seen any of our accounts.
The business showed it.
I had to make the rounds.
I did my work.
I didn't see anybody but
the customers in Los Angeles.
Of course I thought of Phyllis.
I wanted to see her,
but not the way I saw her the last time.
Anyway,
before I left town I dropped
in at the Canton Cafe.
Hi Sam.
Hello, Mr. Graham.
- We missed you.
- Thanks, Sam.
Miss Marin here? Phyllis?
No, she doesn't work here anymore.
When did she leave?
About a month ago, maybe a little more.
Was anything wrong?
She says she wasn't
well. See was going away.
Where?
She didn't say. Will you have
dinner here tonight, Mr. Graham?
No, no thank you.
Thanks, Sam.
Yes?
Is Miss Martin in? Miss Phyllis Martin.
What do you want?
My name's Harry Graham.
I'm an old friend of hers.
Does
she still live here?
She still lives here, but,
she isn't feeling well.
She doesn't want to see anyone.
Well, I've got to see her.
You remember me
don't you? Mr. Graham?
I've spoken to you on the
phone several times.
- Y... yes I remember. Come in.
- Thank you.
I think she needs you. Her room's
right up there, first on the left.
Come in.
Harry.
Hello, Phil.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
It's good to see you again.
I just go back from San Francisco,
I've been working there
for the last few months.
I went to the restaurant
and they told me.
And I had trouble getting
past your guard downstairs.
Well, now that you found me again,
how are things in the
deep freeze business?
What was it, hot water heaters?
Phyllis.
What did the landlord mean just
now when she said "she needs you?"
I don't know.
Come on.
Look, I don't need anybody.
I can take care of myself.
I'm a big girl now.
Was it that night?
My birthday.
It's yours if that's what you mean.
I know.
Harry,
you don't have to do anything about it.
But I want to do something about it.
No, I don't trap my men this way.
You're free just as you always were.
Why didn't you want to see me?
What were you afraid of?
I don't know,
I guess maybe I was afraid you
wouldn't want me to have it.
I don't think I could stand that.
I never had anything of my own
until now.
Don't be afraid.
Of course I want you to have the baby.
I'll take care of everything.
Don't worry.
I've got some things to do.
You stay here and rest a while.
I'll be back later.
Good.
And Phil,
I'm glad,
terribly glad I found you.
So am I.
You get some rest.
Mr Graham, this is Dr. Wallace.
He's taking care of Phyllis.
- I was just going up to see her.
- How is she, doctor?
- Could I speak to you for a minute?
- Yeah, sure.
- Excuse me.
- Of course.
I think she's going to be all right.
She's had a rough time
of it this last month.
Two transfusions,
and she's not very strong to start with.
Then there's the mental
emotional state to contend with.
You can understand?
Yes, I understand.
I think things will be
better now that you're here.
I'll take care of everything.
Please give her the best.
I'm glad she means something to you.
She can be hurt just
like the rest of us.
Fooled me at first with
that flip, hard act of hers.
But that's not the real Phyllis.
You must know that.
How can a man call a
woman his wife for 8 years,
someone whom you love and who loves you?
That you must have a divorce?
Worse than that,
you've been unfaithful.
You're going to be a father.
How can you hurt someone so much?
Hello?
Eve.
Harry, I've been trying to reach you.
What is it Eve?
Your father?
About an hour ago.
I'm sorry darling.
I'm sorry.
I'll have to stay with mother a
while, and then I'll come home to you.
Can you hear me?
Yes, of course I can hear you.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right, Eve.
Give your mother my love and...
And take care of yourself.
Good bye.
Hello, Phyllis.
Hello.
I forgot to ask you something.
Yeah? What's that?
Will you marry me?
No,
not this way.
I'm not asking you.
I'm asking you.
I hate to take you out
of circulation like this.
There must be a waiting line.
There's nothing like that,
and no one like you.
Are you sure you want me?
I'm sure.
I do love you, Harry.
And I'm so glad I do.
I stayed with her until she fell asleep.
You may laugh Mr. Jordan,
but for the first time I felt needed.
I loved Eve, but I
never felt she needed me.
How did you expect to get away with it?
I didn't.
What did you do when Mrs. Graham
came home a few weeks after
your other marriage?
Why didn't you tell her plainly?
Wasn't that the plan?
Yes, that was the plan.
That was also the time when
you came in again, Mr. Jordan.
Will you have some cream?
I have been away a long time.
I never take cream. Remember me?
I'm sorry, I forgot.
I have a surprise for you.
A surprise?
A sentimental surprise.
Come on, bring your coffee.
Eve...
there are some things
we've got to talk about.
Father wanted you to have this watch.
It was grandfather's,
and then when father and mother
married It was a
wedding gift to the groom.
Grandfather said that having a watch and
chain made a man feel more like a man.
Sort of like a I suppose.
I wish I could have thanked him for it.
Well he told me to tell
you to take very good care of it,
because it should
be passed down to our son.
He said it was a lucky watch and
should be kept in circulation.
Our son...
I'm glad he didn't know
how I'd let you down.
You haven't let me down. You couldn't.
Yes I did.
When I learned I couldn't have a child
that's when I became the little
efficient white collared girl.
I forgot some things.
You didn't forget. Maybe
I became absentee husband.
We wanted to show the business
world We were smarter than the rest.
And we did show them.
Come on, I've got another
nice surprise for you.
The light doesn't work. Leave
the door open so we can see.
I cleaned it up today.
Don't worry about your golf clubs.
I put all our junk in the closet
and I stored the suitcases.
I think it's going to be very
nice when we get it fixed up.
Go a little slower
Eve, I'm not with you.
Remember Mr. Jordan?
Mr. Jordan.?
When I left for Florida you said
you'd look into the adoption business.
And you told you about Mr. Jordan.
Yes, now I remember. I
spoke to him on the phone.
What about him?
Well that's the surprise!
I called him this
morning.
He said he wanted to see us both,
but he thought he could help us.
Of course, it may be a while.
So you decided to go
ahead and fix the place up.
I know it was impulsive,
but I couldn't wait.
I thought we'd put the bed here and,
the chest of drawers over here.
And one of those little rubber tubs
In cases he's too small to use ours.
Like it?
You still do want a child, don't you?
Is adopting a baby
terribly important to you?
Yes, more important
than I ever knew before.
Except for you, it would
mean everything to me.
All right then.
I guess we'll go see Mr. Jordan.
So that's how I crossed
your path once more.
What was in your mind?
Did you think you could
live this lie for a lifetime?
Well,
when I realized how much a child
meant to Eve I decided to help her
by staying married until
the baby became legally ours.
Then I'd get out of her life.
I must say, that was both a
gallant and a foolish scheme.
Those were months of panic, fear.
Like the night my son
was born prematurely
just as the doctor predicted.
Mr. Graham.
Mr. Graham, you have a little boy.
You can see him through
the window down there.
The axe began to fall
one day not so long
ago when I'd just gotten
in from San Bernardino.
I'd stopped by the office
to clean up my desk.
It was Eve's and my anniversary.
I had tried to get home,
but I couldn't make it.
Is there a man in this joint
that's been married 8 years?
Eve!
Don't look so shocked. I'm
your anniversary present.
I almost didn't find you.
I called all over the state.
And where are you staying?
I'm not. I just got
back from San Bernardino.
Did you get my flowers?
I didn't wait for that.
I got your wire
and decided something
should be done about it.
So here I am, aren't you glad?
I was just about to call you.
Never mind that. How about, closing
up the store and buying me a dinner?
As a matter of fact we're doing so
well I'll put it on the expense account.
Let's get started on our ninth year.
After dinner
Eve wanted to take a walk.
I was afraid every step of the way.
Yet I tried to get into the
holiday spirit for her sake.
For a moment it was
like old times, until...
Mr. Graham!
If you're going home,
could you give me a lift?
Some other time.
See you Ricky.
Who's he?
Store executive's son. I have
dinner at that place now and then.
What did he mean by home?
The Chapin Park Hotel.
I stayed there a while
back. They live nearby.
How about a nightcap?
Love it.
After I put Eve on the
plane for San Francisco
I came home to Phyllis and
more of my insane double life.
I was beginning to act
and think like a criminal,
afraid to be found out
yet sick of deceit and lies.
Hello Phil.
Danny asleep?
That's right.
All right, Phil. Out with it.
- Surprised you came back.
- What do you mean?
Let it go.
No Phil, I won't let it
go. I want you to tell me.
All right,
if you must know I'm feeling
a little cheap, that's all.
Ricky?
Worse than that... Ricky's mother.
She couldn't wait to phone
me all the grisly details.
Made a wonderful story out of it.
You know, just like the Sunday papers.
"Husband supposed to be out of town
secretly meets another woman."
You might have done a
neater job of it Harry.
Yes...
yes, you're right.
Getting awfully excited
over one, aren't I?
There must have been others.
No, no others.
That's a comfort.
I'm behaving like a fool.
After all I dragged
you into this marriage.
Stop it, don't say that.
It's not true and you know it.
Leave me alone, will you?
Listen to me.
There's something I've got to tell you.
Please,
just leave me alone.
Phil... Phil you must listen!
Harry,
get out will you?
- Phil!
- Get out.
I stayed at a hotel that night.
Made a date to see Phyllis the next day.
There were things we had to talk about.
She said she'd meet me in
the park near the house.
It's hard to explain my
thoughts as I sat there.
I had my way out.
Now I could put an
end to this nightmare.
I loved Phyllis and our child.
I didn't want to lose them,
and I hated to bring them pain.
Hello, Phyllis.
Hi.
Cigarette?
No, thanks.
How's Danny?
He's fine.
I had Miss Higgins come
over and sit with him.
You look tired.
Yeah?
Well I didn't sleep too well last night.
Neither did I.
What did you want to talk about Harry?
I've been thinking.
I could manage $85 a week.
Can you and Danny make it?
Sure.
You can get the divorce and all
that, and I'll pay for everything.
I'm sorry it had to happen this
way. I never meant to hurt you.
I'll come around later
and get my things.
OK, any time.
Good bye, Phil.
Good bye.
Harry!
This is crazy.
I can't go through with it.
I guess you just gave my ego a kick.
Will you forgive me?
I do love you so
you big lug.
You know why I didn't sleep last night?
I kept thinking about our marriage.
You know, the way we got into it.
I wasn't fair to you.
Don't say that Phil.
Never.
Please,
take me home will you?
You really want me to?
Yes.
We need you.
Come on.
So you had your out
and couldn't take it.
And yet all the time you
knew it had to end this way.
And now you're going to call the police.
Well,
maybe I ought to thank you.
I'd like a taxi at 132
Brinkman Street please.
That's right, thank you.
I'm not a policeman.
It's not my duty to do anything
but see that the juvenile wards
of the state of California
are given decent homes.
I'll pick up my taxi outside.
I can't figure out my
feelings towards you.
I despise you
and I pity you.
I don't even want to shake your hand,
and yet I almost wish you luck.
Dearest Phyllis,
just a moment ago I watched
your sweet face as you slept
knowing I had to hurt you again.
When I tried to say good bye to Danny
it was almost unbearable.
I cannot expect you to understand
what I'm about to tell you.
Darling,
how wonderful you're here!
why didn't you tell me?
- I couldn't. I have to go away.
- Go away? Where?
I can't explain now. There isn't time.
- There's isn't time...
What do you mean?
- I wanted to tell you.
That's why I came back.
There are people waiting
for me downstairs.
People? What are you saying?
All I can do is pray that
one day you'll forgive me.
Try to remember one thing. I love you.
I've always loved you.
But you can't go away
like this. I love you too!
Dearest, it's the only way. Tom Morgan
will call you. He knows all about it.
Harry!
Harry.
Hello?
- Eve, it's Tom.
- Yes Tom,
tell me now.
Harry's been married in Los Angeles.
Harry Graham is in no
sense a hero, certainly.
But neither is he a monster.
He's an ordinary man
that made one terrible mistake.
In this case there's a
peculiar sense of irony.
If Harry Graham.
had taken Phyllis Martin as his mistress
some people would have winked
an eye and turned their head.
But because he gave her
and the child she bore him
his name and an honorable place
In the community he must
be utterly destroyed.
I don't deny
that the defendant should be punished,
But I do believe that in this case
punishment might well
be tempered with mercy.
Thank you.
As the prosecutor has pointed out,
there are many bigamous marriages
going on that nobody knows about.
The prosecutor is also quite correct
in observing that this
is a condition
which strikes at the very
roots of our society.
Please, stop it. I'm guilty.
Why go on talking about it?
As the counsel for the
defense has brought out,
there's irony in this case...
tragic irony.
I suspect that the defendant may
have even loved both these women.
Perhaps he even needed them both.
I also suspect
that he may now have lost them both.
When he's once more a free
man it won't be a question
of which woman he'll go back to, but
rather which woman will take him back.
That decision is theirs.
Under any circumstances,
he'll be forced to continue
to support them both,
and he will legalize the status of
his son by naming him in his will.
These are decent women, Mr. Graham.
You're basically a decent man.
When a man, even with
the best intentions,
breaks the moral laws we live by,
we really don't need man
made laws to punish him.
He'll find out that the penalty of the
court is always the smallest punishment.
Sentence will be passed for this court
one week from this day, at 11:00 AM.
The court is adjourned.