Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
At the next intersection,
why don't you turn south?
Chocolate Mountains were east last
time we headed that way. Who needs
the mountains? Head for San Felipe.
There's nothing to do in San Felipe
but fish. Well. . .
That was the idea, wasn't it?
Yeah, I guess so.
We might just pick up a drink
in Mexicale.
Remember Floribel
at the Alhambra Club? Yeah.
She's probably dead by now. It was a
long time ago. Yeah. Poor Floribel.
Well, there's no harm
in drinking a toast to her. OK.
Except for the war, this is my first
time away from Maudie and the kids.
D'you wanna turn back?
No, no. We've come this far.
Mexicale's beginning to sound good.
Guess maybes.
I remember that joint.
Bienvenidos, cavallieros!
Bienvenidos a Mexico. . .
This is the place, senors, come in.
Juanita's starting her famous
fan dance. You're just in time.
We might as well take a look.
. .Hey, Gil. Gil?
Sorry, friend, no sale.
Oh, well. San Felipe, here we come.
Out of gas? Yeah. Hop in.
We're going to San Felipe.
You can pick up gas there
and hitch a ride back.
Waiting out there long? Yeah.
Light me a cigarette, will you?
Smoke?
No.
What are you doing, rolling 'em?
Face front.
And keep driving.
Sure, I'm Emmet Myers.
Do what I tell you. . .and
no fast moves. A lot of dead heroes
back there got nervous.
From now on, when you're driving,
keep both hands high on that wheel.
You, keep one hand
on the top of this seat,
the other hand high on that window.
All right. Now turn off
the next side road we come to.
Pull up.
Open the glove compartment.
What's the box?
Cartridges, 22s. Give 'em to me.
Close it.
Now this is how we get out
after this. First, give me the keys.
Stand away from the car. Then you.
Let's go.
Drop your jackets
around your elbows.
Turn around.
We're gonna open the trunk.
Move.
Pull your jackets up.
You, open the trunk.
Both of you,
keep your hands on the lid.
Throw me the keys.
Now get the blankets.
You'd never make it!
Get the groceries.
Whose gun is that? Mine.
Do you like to shoot? Yeah.
So do I. So I'm warning you,
don't try anything smart with me.
Move!
I told you my name. What's yours?
Mine's Gilbert Bowen.
He's Roy Collins.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a draughtsman. He runs a garage.
That makes you smarter.
Or does it?
CLICK
You're lucky. It hit an empty
chamber. I used it a while back.
No fast moves!
The last guy made that mistake.
When are you due back?
No particular time. We told our
wives to expect us when we got there.
You got wives, huh? Any kids?
I have. Just keep thinking
how nice it'll be to see 'em again.
There's a checkpoint. Slow down.
No talking.
If I give you the word, step on it.
This car rides pretty good.
When I get where I'm going,
I think I'll sell it.
Where are we going?
Pull in at the next pump.
We'll fill up and get a road map.
I got an idea. . .
a pretty good one.
Aqui estas, senor. Gracias.
Speak English. He doesn't understand
English. I don't understand Mexican.
Leave the change. Let's go.
Loco!
Gimme the map.
Take the first side road we come to.
Pull up.
Keys.
All right,
now get out like I told you.
Here, you're the smart guy.
Spread the map out on the hood.
Get your hands up on the car. Look
for a town called Santa Rosalia.
How far is it?
About 500 miles. Is it on the Gulf
of California? Yeah. Does it talk
about a ferry across the Gulf?
Friday.
Not bad.
We're loaded with time.
We can make that easy.
After that,
I won't need you guys any more.
I guess we won't be having rabbit
for dinner.
I wasn't trying.
Collins.
Put the can out on that rock there.
Gimme the map.
Not that one! The other one.
That's it.
All right, Collins.
Put the can back on the rock.
Don't forget, this is loaded too.
You try. Let's see how good you are.
Go ahead.
Not bad.
Collins.
Pick up the can.
Take it onto that point there.
If you don't,
I'll let Bowen have it.
Onto the point, that's right.
Further.
Now hold it up. You won't get hurt,
your buddy's good with guns.
You're crazy! I won't do it.
It'sjust a game. Go ahead.
Collins, hold it closer to you.
What's the matter, are you scared?
Hold it closer.
You want me to try?
I might miss this time.
Shoot.
Come on Gil, get going.
Nervous? Relax.
All right, Collins, come on in.
Fun's over.
You guys worked up quite a sweat.
Collins.
Collins! What do you want?
Turn on the radio. Why bother?
All you get is Mexican commercials.
Never mind. . .Turn it on.
Get something else. Like what? One
of those news guys from the States.
'. .Scheduled for 10am
at the White House.
'On the crime front, the police of
nine western states, from Washington
in the north to Colorado and Utah,
'have been alerted to keep a lookout
for Kansas desperado, Emmet Myers.
'Reports have placed the killer
in Florida, Detroit and Seattle,
'although the police have discounted
most of these. His latest victim,
'William Johnson, a salesman from
Portland, Oregon, was found yesterday
in Imperial County, California.
'The victim's car, possibly with
Myers in it, has not yet been found.
'The United Nations. . .' Shut it off.
'. .unanimous resolutions. . .'
They're not even close!
You guys don't have to worry.
Not yet.
You can start sweating when they put
me in this car. . .if they ever do.
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen,
Sam Hayes reporting.
Hitch-hike murderer, Emmet Myers,
is still at large. Yesterday,
the devil thumbed another ride
and William Johnson of Portland asked
him to hop in. Now, he is dead. In
an all-out effort to apprehend Myers,
'the police have set up roadblocks
on all major highways, and all border
stations are being closely watched.
'Myers is slight, 28 years old,
is wearing a dark shirt, grey
trousers and a black leather jacket.
'His right eyelid
is partially paralysed. If you have
any information on his whereabouts,
'please contact your
nearest office of the police or
the Federal Bureau of Investigation.'
Pull up.
Keys.
Out.
Move.
Each of you take one.
Get around the car.
We'll camp here tonight.
I know what you're thinking,
Collins.
You haven't got a chance.
You guys are gonna die, that's all.
It's just a question of when.
Santa Rosalia,
that's the end of the line.
If the cops find out we're together
or if you try to cross me up. . .
You know, you make pretty good
targets from where I sit.
Anyway, you couldn't tell
if I was awake or asleep.
I've one bum eye.
It won't stay closed.
Pretty good, huh?
We're getting out here and buy
some grub. We get out like usual.
You guys go in the store ahead of
me. No Mexican. I'm talking to you.
When he tells you how much, you pay.
Is that clear?
One other thing. I'll have my hand
in my pocket. So far, my record in
Mexico's clean. Let's keep it clean.
Let's go.
Buenos dias, senores.
Buenos dias, senores. Provisiones?
. .in Tijuana. What did he say
about Tijuana? He said their prices
are about the same as in Tijuana.
Never mind the kid.
What do you want?
Some beans and stuff. And tomato
soup. I like that. Get four cans.
He wants four cans of beans and
tomato soup, three cans of chilli.
It's no use. He doesn't understand
English. You're not talking Mexican.
Take the cans. Give them to Collins.
I can take some more.
Go on, load it up.
That'll hold us. Pay him.
Quince pesos, diez centavos, senor.
Deme una manzana. Deme una manzana.
Deme una manzana.
Get her away from me.
Put the kid down. Let's get outta
here. Come on, Collins.
Muchas gracias.
Vaya usted con Dios.
What did you say? You wouldn't
understand. What did you say?
I said,
"Go you with God, little one."
Get in.
Hey, mister.
You live in El Centro. I live there
some time. Nice place, huh?
Where'd you get the watch, Bowen?
My wife gave it to me.
Throw it over here.
Didn't you hear me?
I told you to throw it over here.
I had a watch like this once,
when I was 17.
Nobody gave it to me.
I took it.
I knocked off a broken-down
jewellery store outside of Tulsa.
It was a cinch.
You guys are soft.
You know what makes you that way?
You're up to your necks in IOUs.
You're suckers.
You're scared to get out
on your own.
You always had it good,
so you're soft.
Well, not me.
Nobody ever gave me anything.
So I don't owe nobody.
My folks were duff.
When I was born, they took
one look at this. . .puss of mine
and told me to get lost.
I didn't need 'em.
I didn't need any of em.
I got what I wanted my own way.
When you get the know-how
and a few bucks in your pocket,
you can buy anything or anybody.
Especially if they're at the point
of a gun. That really scares 'em.
You ever been
at the other end of a gun? No.
And I never will be.
I'm gonna listen to the news.
Turn it up. We'd like to hear. You
just get the grub ready. Anything
interesting, I'll let you know.
We've got to raise the hood and
put that radio out of commission.
When he finds out they're looking
for us together, we're through.
Never mind the radio. We gotta get
HIM. You can't beat him that way.
Give him one good reason and he'll
kill us. We gotta take the chance.
As long as he needs us, we'll stay
alive. When he's ready to jump us,
we'll jump him. Not before.
Maybe today, maybe tomorrow.
All right, now.
They've found Johnson's car.
They know I'm in Mexico.
And they're looking for you, too,
in the Chocolate Mountains.
Where are the Chocolate Mountains?
In Arizona, near home.
Not in Mexico? No.
Well, what d'you know?
That's where you told your wives you
were going? Then you came to Mexico.
What for?
Dames?
You boys should be ashamed
of yourselves.
Causing all that trouble.
Telling lies.
You've got everybody looking for you
in them mountains.
I told you, turn the radio on.
I did.
It takes time to warm up.
Try another station.
Stop it. Stop it! I can't. I gotta
pull up and disconnect it. Pull up!
Raise the hood.
Keep your hands on it.
Come on, Collins, get to work.
Get the right one the first time.
Don't pull the radio wire!
Faster!
I thought you were a mechanic.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Watch it.
Come on.
Throw the tools in the back.
The radio, remember? Make it work.
I can't.
Pull up.
So you did bust it, Collins.
Cut it out! He didn't do it.
It's the static in the hills.
The stations aren't strong enough
in the daytime. Tonight it'll work.
It'd better. Take the wheel.
Now, in Punta Prieta,
on August 7th, three Americans
stopped for provisions at a store
owned by Jose Andrare.
Andrare gave a description of Myers
as being one of them.
Another witness stated
that three men left the store
and drove away in a green sedan
bearing the same plates.
This confirms our theory that Collins
and Bowen are with him. He seems to
be heading south, avoiding highways.
Exactly. To the west,
this is more or less barren
and would afford no means of escape.
His most logical move
would be Santa Rosalia.
Then Guaymas.
Make sure that fire's out.
Pour the coffee on it.
Get down!
I've gotta get a closer look
at that car. On your feet.
Through there. At the other end,
lie flat. Get going!
Get a move on! Are you trying
to wreck it? Drive like I tell you.
Out!
What did I tell you? Shut up!
Get that spare tyre out. Move!
Keep working. Keep your traps shut,
no matter what. I'll be watching.
Buenos dias, senores.
Son Americanos? Do you need any help?
The search for Gilbert Bowen and Roy
Collins, believed to have been last
seen with Emmet Myers, mass killer,
'is being stepped up. Helicopters
are scouring the area from El Centro
south to the Gulf of California.
'Planes are maintaining
close liaison with the ground,
reporting isolated cars and campers.
'The Mexican police have now joined
this strange race against death.'
Hold it right there.
Around.
Break the lock.
OK, one of you on the pump.
"Maudie and Gilbert Bowen."
Si, si, pronto.
Now, as you will notice,
when interrogated at the road block,
the man and his wife were definite
that they only saw two men.
There is a point, however,
which we feel is of importance.
The couple said the behaviour
of the men seemed strange.
They refused to talk to them.
It's possible that Myers my have been
concealed nearby, covering them.
We'll consider that possibility.
Now, on the assumption that Myers
is listening to the radio,
we're issuing these broadcasts,
containing false information as to
his whereabouts and not connecting
the two men with him.
This ought to be the main highway.
It isn't. What do you mean?
Looks like an abandoned airstrip.
It's OK for tonight. Go over there.
No, you're wrong! It's no use
trying to talk me out of it. Tonight
I'm gonna chance it. You're mad!
I've played it your way long enough.
We've got to stick together.
You do whatever you want. . .
Across the runway, there's trees.
Keep going.
You guys are really dumb.
Why, you dirty. . .
You thought I was asleep, huh?
You're beginning to get ideas. . .
I don't like that.
Load him in the car.
Your buddy's all washed up
for tonight.
Over there.
Move!
You, Collins,
throw a rock down that shaft.
Nice and deep.
This is fine. Cut it out! If you're
gonna kill us, do it. I thought
you never killed without a reason.
Go get the rest of the canned goods
out of the car.
We'll have a real good meal.
Save 'em for the next guy
that picks you up.
Anything you say.
'We interrupt this hour of music
to bring you a flash bulletin. The
police have abandoned their theory
'that Emmet Myers
is connected with the disappearance
of Gilbert Bowen and Roy Collins.
'They have been missing since last
Sunday, supposedly on a fishing trip.
'The police now feel that Myers
is travelling alone and has abandoned
his intention of seeking escape
'by way of Santa Rosalia.'
What d'you know? !
This kind of changes my plan.
Looks like you and me
are going fishing after all.
On your feet. Back to the car.
Let's go.
We're not going anyplace.
Stand up!
What did you do to it? There's
a big hole in that crankcase.
All right, we'll walk.
Just what that sore ankle of yours
needs - a nice, long hike.
Get up!
Now get the fishing gear
out of the back. Move!
Stay with it. He'll never leave you
out here alive. Yeah.
Cut the gab.
Get down!
Let's get going.
Maybe we'll have to leave you here.
Too bad(!)
Come on, Roy, try.
Here we are! Here we are!
Can't you see us?
Look! Here we are! Down here.
Oh, please, God! Hear me!
Hear me!
Come back!
Come back.
Leave him alone.
Can't you see he's praying?
Get under the bridge, quick!
Relax.
Go ahead if you can stand the stuff.
You know, Collins?
You're just about my size.
Put you in a black shirt and dark
pants. . .with a leather jacket. . .
. .you'd look just like Emmet Myers
to anyone who never saw him.
Nobody in Santa Rosalia
ever saw him.
Let's change.
COCKS RIFLE
Get up on the bank
and take your clothes off.
Come on, get up!
Looks great, doesn't it?
You won't be there long. Collins!
There are cops down there. In
those clothes, they might shoot you.
That'd solve your problems,
wouldn't it? Not if they found
they'd made a mistake.
We'll hit a joint on the outskirts.
I might even buy you boys a beer.
Get moving.
Buenos tardes, senores.
Buenos tardes. Give us three beers.
No hablo ingles.
He doesn't speak English.
Tres cervezas. Si, si.
You can talk Mex when I say. Sit
down, Collins. Rest your sore foot.
You can talk it now.
Ask about the ferry to Guaymas.
I'll be watching his face.
If he looks frightened, I shoot.
Friday - that's today - and Tuesday,
9 o'clock. Ask where we catch it.
You're out of luck. The ferry burned
up. It's being repaired in Guaymas.
You're lying.
Ask if he knows anyone
who speaks English.
He says his cousin speaks English.
Follow him. Up.
Jose!
Jose, Jose.
What can I do for you?
We wanna find out about the ferry
to Guaymas. You wanna go fishing?
Too bad. No ferry no more for the
next two months maybe. She burned up.
Thank you. Fishing is good here. Not
as good as Guaymas or La Paz, but OK.
You have motor boat?
You know someone who has one?
Sure, sure. My friend Jime has one.
Motor runs good.
Where is this Jime? In the mine,
where he works. Let's go. He's not
finished until six. Maybe tomorrow.
I wanna go now.
At six, then. By the time he gets
the boat ready, there is no sun.
My friend does not like using
too much boat at night.
He sees his wife and kids
only at night. Give him some more.
For me?
Yeah. You pay my friend too? Yeah.
You be at pier at 8.30.
The name of the boat is Estrella.
A thousand thanks, senor.
Good.
We'll go to town and wait
by the water till dark. Let's go.
Hold it a minute, will you? Hang on.
Go fishing while you've the chance.
It's what you came for.
You guys are really fools.
If you wanted,
one of you would have got away.
But you kept thinking about each
other. So you missed some chances.
You got tired. You slowed down.
Now it's pretty late.
Yeah, tomorrow I'll be in Guaymas.
Too bad you're not making
the whole trip with me.
That'd be kinda silly, wouldn't it?
You stink, Myers!
You smell. Just like your clothes.
Sure, you'll get to Guaymas,
but they'll catch you
and put you out of your misery.
You haven't got a chance. You haven't
got a thing except that gun.
Better hang on to it, because without
it, you're nothing. You're finished.
Shut up!
Gracias, Carlos.
Caramba!
Pronto! La policia!
Bueno. La policia.
No, no, no, la policia!
Hold it.
All right, Collins. Now you get
to take a nice walk all by yourself.
Down the alley and out on the dock.
Me and Bowen will follow. If you tip
anyone off, I'll let Bowen have it.
You wouldn't want that, would you?
Get going.
Go ahead, Collins.
All the way out.
Keep under the lights.
Alto!
Alto ahi! I'm not Myers!
I'm not Myers! D'you hear me?
I'm not Myers!
Alto! Alto!
Alto! Alto ahi!
Put your hands up. Walk this way.
Do as he tells you, Myers.
You're all through.
That's enough!
I'm sorry.
We have to have full report.
We understand. Gracias.
It's all right.
Watch Full HD Movies & TV Shows