Downloaded from
YTS.MX
[music playing]
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
You made good time, Yak.
How long you wait?
Oh, I got here last night.
What'd you find out?
Two men gonna hold up
stage, Coyote Canyon.
Much money on stage.
Well, it looks like we're
gonna have our hands full.
More trouble, more fun.
Ha, well that's one
way to look at it.
But there's been two sheriffs
killed in Little Rock,
and it's our job to
find out who did it.
We do 'em.
Well, I reckon we'd better
get started. [inaudible].
Gentlemen, I've
called this meeting,
that you may all know Al Davis.
He's to be sworn
in this afternoon
as sheriff of this county.
[applause]
Mr. Davis, I feel that we should
acquaint you with the fact
that this vicinity
is being terrorized
by a band of outlaws, ruled by
a man whom they call the shadow.
He's a very clever man.
Many traps have
been set for him,
and he's always evaded them.
Our cattle are stolen,
night after night.
Has absolutely no
regard for human life.
Stage coaches are held up
and robbed, the drivers shot.
Well, looks like we're gonna
get through this time, Dave.
You stay out of
sight and follow me.
Don't look back.
Drop that gun and keep driving.
You meet me in town.
HENCHMAN: Throw down that bag.
STAGECOACH DRIVER:
You're too late,
a lone rider beat you to it.
HENCHMAN: Yeah?
[gunshots]
(SCREAMING)
Heya, look, boys,
something's wrong.
Hey, what's happened?
What's the matter?
You'd better get him to
a doctor, boys, quick.
Where can I find Mr. Matlock?
He's my uncle.
I'll get him for you, miss.
Thank you.
Well, miss, you had
quite an exciting ride.
I certainly did.
And gentlemen--
MAN: Matlock!
Matlock, the stage was held up.
Joe is dead and
Dave was wounded.
There's a girl on the stage,
claims to be your niece.
She's asking for you.
So you are--
I'm Anita, Uncle Matt.
My dear, this is certainly
a pleasant surprise.
So tell us, what has happened.
Well I don't know, exactly.
I was heading for town
when I saw the runaway.
And I happened to be
close, so I caught it.
This young lady can probably
tell you more than I can.
Well, first we were
held up by a lone rider.
And then shortly after,
two men held us up again.
And they shot the
guard and the driver,
and then the horses ran away.
And this gentleman caught them.
And I'm mighty grateful, too.
And so am I.
You see, Davis,
it's things like this
that happen every day.
[gunshot]
Look, see that smoke.
The bullet came straight
on, but from where?
That's just the way the
other man was killed.
MAN: I reckon this is
the end of law and order.
Won't nobody run
for sheriff now.
If it's just the
same with you folks,
I'll take this job as sheriff.
You say you could
see the whole street?
Unh, me hear shot, look
quick, see no one, only smoke.
It's certainly mighty strange.
Unh.
I'm sure those are the
hombres that held up the stage.
Wait here.
[knocking]
THE SHADOW: You
needn't explain, boys,
I know everything
that has happened.
Keep your eyes on
this new sheriff.
Watch every move, and
report to me in the morning.
Cover my trail, Yak, I'm
going back for the money bags.
Unh.
It's the stage bag.
Do you suppose he just found it?
I don't know.
But here's where we
get it, and him too.
Unh, two men follow,
look through glass.
Ah, well I figured as much.
Here, take my horse and meet
me at the express office.
Keep this money.
[gunshot]
Hey, it's empty.
Where did he go?
I don't know.
Look!
I know we got him.
He can't get far.
Come on, let's find him.
Oh, you stay here and watch.
Recon the express company will
be glad to get this money back.
Unh.
[knocking]
We trailed him and saw
him pick up the money bags.
Park, here, shot
him of his horse,
but we couldn't find him.
THE SHADOW: He just rode in town
and went in the express office,
probably with the dough.
This is twice you've
gummed things up.
Another fluke like this and
you two guys keep riding.
It's 10 to 1 he knows
who followed him.
So you'd better get
back to the hideout
and stay there until
I send for you.
All right, Yak, let's find
out where they'll lead us.
Loco Frank.
He'd cut a man's
throat for a dollar.
And Flash Burton, a
lifer from Walla Walla.
And there's Chuckawalla
Red, he's wanted
in every state on the border.
And Slippery Williams,
and Spike Morgan.
(WHISTLE) What a
nest of hornets.
And Matlock's ranch
only two miles away.
Wonder if he knows
what's near him.
Maybe we tell him.
No, it might spoil our
chances of getting them.
Well, my dear, what do
you think of the ranch?
Oh, fine.
But I haven't seen any cattle.
There are no cattle.
They were all stolen
several weeks ago.
That's why I've tried to bring
law and order to this valley.
Seems useless.
Three men have been
mysteriously shot down.
And the outlaw
activity continues.
Well, can't you appeal
to the government?
The ranchmen have
written repeatedly,
but nothing has happened.
Oh, where is the
foreman and your boys?
They were in with the rustlers,
and left with the cattle.
And you live here alone?
Yes, except for
old Jake, the cook.
I'm going over to Matlock's.
Now you stay here and keep
an eye on whoever passes.
Unh.
Under the circumstances,
I think we should
try and dispose of this ranch.
Or at least let
me buy your half.
This is certainly no
place for a woman.
Well I quite agree with
you there, Uncle Matt.
I didn't expect to
find it like this.
How many for
supper, Mr. Matlock?
Just the three of us, Jake.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, here comes
someone, Uncle Matt.
Well, it's our new sheriff.
Come right in, Mr. Travers.
How do you do?
Miss Matlock.
Just wanted to tell
you about my good luck.
I found the express money
near the scene of the holdup.
Well, that is good luck.
You see any sign of the robbers?
Well, I can't make any
promises right now, Mr. Matlock,
but I hope to have the Shadow
and his gang behind the bars
in a very few days.
Well, my boy, I
certainly wish you luck.
I'm afraid that
never can happen.
The shadow is clever.
His men are the most desperate
criminals ever banded together.
How do you know?
Why, uh, the cold blooded
manner in which they operate.
Oh, I see.
But I still think I can do it.
Well I certainly hope you do.
Will you excuse me a moment?
I suppose you're glad to
be home again, Miss Matlock.
Well, this isn't
exactly my home.
In fact, it's the first
time I've seen the place.
You see, my father and
Uncle Matt owned this ranch.
But two years ago
dad was killed.
I inherited his half.
Uncle Matt has
offered to buy me out.
He says this is no
place for a woman.
Oh.
He says strange things
happen here at night.
And there are only
the three of us.
Old Jake, Uncle
Matt, and myself.
And I'm almost afraid.
THE SHADOW: Hello,
the sheriff will soon
be leaving Matlock's ranch.
Wait for him at the crossroads.
There's a girl at the ranch.
No harm must come to her,
but scare her away tonight.
All right, I'll have
the boys attend to it.
And don't be afraid to use it.
I won't be.
Won't you stay for
dinner, Mr. Travers?
No, thanks, I have to be going.
I'll see you in the morning.
Good day, Miss Matlock.
Goodbye.
A fine fellow, isn't he?
Yeah.
It's too bad that he's sheriff.
How you skookum, big fun.
You boys been a
little too careless
with your shooting irons.
So we'll just send you
up for attempted murder.
We're be outta here
by noon tomorrow.
Yeah?
Well thanks for the information.
[bang]
[clatter]
There must be a secret entrance.
I distinctly heard
a third voice.
That's a funny place for a safe.
[knocking]
Here it is.
It's a fake safe.
This must be where the
shadow gives his orders from.
[knocking]
YAK: (SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Well, this is interesting.
It's a tunnel.
Come on, let's see
where it leads.
Well, what do you think?
They've hollowed
out this old stump.
This is where those
mysterious shots came from.
Through this hole, a man could
cover the entire northern part
of the street.
We've got work to
do tonight, Yak.
The first thing is to
find a crosscut saw.
(HOWLING)
(SCREAMING)
[gunshot]
[man screaming]
[gunshots]
Good morning, Anita.
Good morning, Uncle Matt.
Did the disturbance
bother you last night?
Oh, not a bit.
In fact, I rather enjoyed it.
You should have seen
these so-called ghosts
run when I opened fire on them.
Did you do that shooting?
I certainly did.
And I intend to
keep on shooting.
You know, Uncle Matt,
I've decided not to sell.
I think I'll stay right
here and fight it out.
Well, I, I admire your spirit,
and if that's your decision,
I'm with you.
But your breakfast is ready.
I must hurry to town.
Goodbye.
MATT MATLOCK: Goodbye.
Morning, Sheriff.
Morning.
The ranchers are all
here, as you ordered.
Good.
Ask them to stay off the
main street until I'm ready.
I've got a surprise
in store for them.
OK, Sheriff, we'll be waiting.
Come on, Yak, let's go.
Come on out, Parker.
Don't worry, it's empty.
Yak, walk the street,
like I told you.
Come on, get going.
I'm warning you now, do as I
say or take the consequences.
Now listen.
[knocking]
THE SHADOW: You're late.
What happened last night?
He had men covering his trail,
we couldn't get near him.
THE SHADOW: Well, he's
in his office now.
Get him out in the
middle of the street.
The [inaudible] is waiting.
At 11:00 this
morning, I personally
will head the boys into town.
Machine gun will be under the
straw of the covered wagon.
We'll cover one end of the
street, and the boys the other.
We'll take the bank
for a clean-up.
You'll take your
position in the stump.
Get going.
Now take off your hat.
Put this one on.
Take off that scarf.
You're not gonna send
me out there, are you?
You guessed it.
But I got the stump covered,
so I guess you'll be all right.
Get moving.
Get the boys.
-Unh.
Come on.
Come.
Sheriff say keep eye on stump.
Take it easy, Parker.
Don't move.
Get him, boys.
Get him out of there.
We've got you.
Listen, up, you.
You've got just
one chance to live.
Who's the sheriff?
Oh, don't shoot, I'll tell.
I'll tell.
It's
[gunshot]
Ooh!
Boys, we just
missed the shadow.
But he's coming back,
he and his gang.
They have a machine
gun, and they
intend to wipe out the town.
What's to be done?
-We'll fight.
Yeah!
All right!
They must never reach town.
We'll surprise them
and head them off.
Pick up all the men you can,
and let every rider wear
a white cloth around his
head so we can distinguish
ourselves from the outlaws.
Get you guns and we'll
all meet at Red Gulch.
Men, I was sent here
from Washington,
and I'm swearing you all
in as deputy marshalls.
Today you're riding for the
United States government.
Everyone raise his right hand.
Do you solemnly swear?
It just doesn't seem possible.
But it's true, Miss Anita.
The night your dad bought
your uncle from the east
was the night this man and
his gang raided the ranch.
Both your dad and
uncle were killed.
He took all your uncle's
papers and his clothes,
and passed himself off
in town as Matt Matlock.
The sheriff must
know about this, Jake.
I'm going to tell him right now.
Yak here will signal
us from that mountain
when they're coming.
We'll let them get by us, and
then attack them from the rear.
Now everybody scatter
and stay hidden.
Are the boys ready?
Yes.
Well there's no time to lose.
Who's that coming?
It's that fool girl.
Stop her.
Take her to the hideout.
Put her in the wagon, Pat.
I reckon the sheriff
won't do much shooting
with her in there.
Stand ready with
that machine gun.
Stand ready, men,
they're coming.
Ha!
[gunshots]
[machine gun fire]
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
(SCREAMING)
[crash]
All right, boys, let's go.
BOY: Daddy, Daddy.
Daddy, Daddy, I'm winning.
Well, now, what's happened
to you, young fella?
Daddy, now you watch.
(SINGING)
American papoose have
hi you skookum fun.
You'll get a lot
more than hi you
skookum fun if you
leave our child alone.
[music playing]