Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
To we so long for you.
Every day.
The new song for you.
We all Mississippi, we all work.
Loading up.
Are there.
I have God such a wonderful
show with the greatest dramas
and jolly comedies. Stephen
Baker of a handsome,
misleading man and beautiful
Julie Laverne has welcome.
Dozen.
Cares. If my boat goes upstream
or if the gate bids me with the rivers.
I.
The with my fancy.
Sometimes I thank my lucky stars.
And.
Other times I wonder where the mate
for.
Hello.
How do you do?
Are you an actress?
Oh, no, but, but I'd give
anything if I could be.
Why?
Well,
because you can make believe
so many wonderful things that
never happen in real life.
Well, if you like to
make believe one thing,
why can't we make believe
we know each other?
The game.
Our dreams are more romantic
than the world we see.
And if the things we
dream don't happen to be,
that's just an, an important technicality.
The you and I have never met.
We need not mine. Mind conventions,
if we,
we
love you
that you love.
Magnolia.
Yes, mother.
Goodbye.
I hope I see you again.
Life upon the wicked stage ain't
ever what a girl suppose as
stage door. Johnny's aren't
raging over you with gems.
And rose says, when you let
a feller hold your hands,
which means an extra beer or sand,
which everybody whispers ain't her life a
though,
you are warned against a rue
ruining your ation when you
played around the one night
trade around the great GNA
nation.
Wild only men who give you
jewels and saveable only living
ESOPs, Fs life.
Ed ain't nothing for a girl.
You.
We do.
Not believe you.
There is no doubt you are crazy about.
Your.
Full stage.
If some gentleman would talk with reason,
I would cancel all next season.
Life on the wicked stage ain't nothing.
Listen, sister, I love my Mr.
Man and I came tell you why.
There ain't no reason
for me to love that man.
It must be something
that the angels done.
Fish gotta swim.
Birds.
Gotta fly.
I got a love one man to die.
Tell me I'm crazy.
Maybe I know can hurt.
Loving that
he goes away,
can come home as late as can be.
He must know something.
But don't say.
You'll run over a year. Well, all.
That was a swell show, Mr.
Kind.
Well, thank you Joe.
That too. The Waldorf Mr.
Kind.
What was that, Joe?
That Big s Shinda get thrown for you.
It's down at the Waldorf, ain't it?
Mr. Kind?
Yes.
But first I'd like to stop
off at the house of an old
friend. Yes sir.
Just for a moment, Joe.
Turn right at the next crossing.
It's not very far.
I'm looking for an old brownstone house.
It was the home of a very
great and good friend tonight
during the show. I couldn't
seem to get him off my mind.
Yes, listen.
And I'd like to be alone
for a few minutes, Joe,
before we go down to the
Waldorf and face that crowd. Oh,
I get you. Like, like a minute of silence.
Something like that, huh?
Yeah, it's Joe.
Something like that.
Here, stop here, Joe.
Here at the corner in
front of that radio shop.
Oh, there it is.
See you.
You mean that that lodging
house sandwiched in there?
Well,
of course it didn't have that
room to let sign of the window
then.
Other than that, it
hasn't changed very much.
The street has changed.
It changed quite a bit since
I first walked down it years
ago.
Joe, as you notice this radio shop, well,
that was a bicycle shop the
first time I ever saw it.
I remember the day very well.
It was spring and I might have
been any American kid coming
down that street.
I had a song under my
arm. My hopes were high.
And the world was wonderful.
I was ambitious and I was eager,
but I needed a little help.
I'd been told that the best
man to give it to me was a man
by the name of Hassler.
James Hassler.
Come in. Come in.
You're an hour late already.
I suppose you'll realize that
you can start on the upstairs
bedroom immediately.
Mrs. Mueller daddy wants
some more roast beef.
I'll.
Be there in a second, Mr.
Hessler, and see that
you get to their nest.
Young man. He's.
Not the more killer.
I'm a songwriter.
A songwriter.
I see you entered under
false pretenses. Well,
it won't do you any good young man. Mr.
Hestor isn't seeing songwriters anymore.
He's going in for better things.
Maybe he.
Should have a rose beef. He's
very, don't mention rose beef.
In front of a songwriter.
Gimme a snack here.
No. So it's, so.
It's you feel like a fall
down thing, don't you Dear.
Dear?
Well, you can come in for a while.
I can't have people fainting in the house.
Not even songwriters. Thank you.
Come in. Come in.
Daddy.
He's starving to death. Mr.
Ler.
Mr. Maxey.
Yes. Yes, I know.
I know. Mr.
Max Dreyfuss of the harms
company sent you grit.
Little tune. He thinks
it has possibilities.
If it's properly arranged now
I'm to help you arrange it.
Look.
How skinny his neck is, daddy.
Well,
he said that he told you that
I was the greatest arranger in
American. I should give
you a few lessons though.
Oh, my friend.
He is right. There's only one
catch I've given up arranging.
I'm through dressing up silly
little tunes for girl shows
and beer halls.
I'm gonna write some
real music for a change.
Oh, I hear Mrs.
Set it down here.
The trouble with you songwriters
is all you ever think about
is making money.
Here. Sit down, have some roast beef.
Oh, well, no, thank you.
Go ahead. Sit down.
Sit down.
Oh, you never think of doing anything big,
anything worthwhile like
Brahms or peach? Oh no, don't,
don't sit down there please.
That's Mrs.
Kessler's place rest is So we
always keep it set for, oh,
I'm.
Sorry. Yeah.
Sit down here.
No,
all you fellas want to do is
write sugary little tombs and
make a lot of money.
Did you ever hear Beethoven's
Roka or Mozart's Jupiter?
Didn't they do something to you? Great.
Evans, doesn't genius
touch you fellas at all?
Daddy's a genius.
Yes. Daddy's a genius.
No, my friend.
In three weeks I'm going to
England where I can work.
I have some peace and quiet.
No mushy little melodies
to be fancied up for public
consumption.
I'm gonna write a symphony.
Daddy's gonna write it
off for just for me.
Here. Go ahead.
Go ahead. Eat up.
Maybe we'll give you some gumption.
Well, I'm terribly sorry Mr.
Hesler. I had a big lunch with Mr.
Dreyfuss just before I left.
It was roast beef too.
Yeah, well I, oh, it's matter.
Just 'cause you're not hungry.
You don't have to go to,
you have some brandy with me.
Help me celebrate my
liberation from mediocrity.
Mrs.
Get a couple of liquor
glasses. Will you, Sally,
will you show Mr. The
gentleman into the parlor?
I'm going upstairs and see
if I can find that bottle in
Napoleon.
Have you a song in there.
I'm taking piano lessons.
Daddy wants me to be an
opera singer when I grow up.
Why don't you write an opera?
Well, Sally, I'm afraid I only
write the silly little tunes.
You know the ones your
father doesn't like?
Let me see if I can play
your song. Do you mind?
I wish you would. It's very easy here.
Color, color, color.
What's the name of the.
Song? Kaa.
That's a funny name. Sounds like candy.
Like gun drops.
Well,
it's the name of a very
romantic beach in a wise Sally.
No, that's b b natural.
Here, let me show you.
Now the melody.
Should.
Be played with clarinets.
Oh, no, no, no.
Wait a minute.
No, that's not right.
You've got to use
clarinets to play the vamp.
Oh, I was thinking of using brass there.
Brass. And spoil your finish.
Good heavens, man.
You've always got to save
the brass for the finish.
Oh, well, what do you think?
Think I know. This is a romantic song.
Sit down. It's sentimental.
You got to start the melody
off with your strings deza.
Here I'll show you. Start that vamp again.
Sally.
It's perfect for clarinet.
See not in the strings.
Center de.
And you hear how wonderful that is.
Not in that trombones trombones.
That's great. Can't you
just hear that, Sally?
No, no, no, no.
Wait a minute.
We ought to add flutes
there. Light and easy.
Now then add your breath strength too.
Yeah. You see?
Isn't that easy?
It's a good song too. It's very good.
Is that yours? Yes.
That's, that's alright.
What's your name again?
Kern. Jerome Kern.
Well, I'm glad to meet you, Kern.
Make yourself at home.
And I did.
My life became a pattern
of notes, clips, tempos,
and modulations. We worked
hour after hour, day after day.
It was the beginning of a friendship.
It was the beginning of a lot of things.
And now not only did I have a best friend,
I had a best girl.
Sally.
And what a girl.
Oh, those were never to be forgotten days.
And I hated to think of the mending.
But at last,
the time came when Jim
had to leave for England.
Oh, here Jim.
Lemme help you.
Those, those symphonies of yours.
They're as heavy and bulky as
let Nice, they're not tinny.
Like some tunes I've heard.
Oh, Sally, honey, come here.
Alright, here we go.
VTIs.
Got it.
Oh, you carry a lot of weight, Sally.
It.
Was easy.
Come along, Sally.
At least we are not gonna
miss the boat. Goodbye Mr.
Kern. Goodbye.
Mrs.
Goodbye. Sally.
Bo.
What.
Does that mean?
Happy journey.
Bye Uncle Jerry.
Be a good boy.
This will be the end of it, boys.
Don't forget to pack my song. Daddy.
No, I'm good.
She means Kaa. All that is her song.
Jim, you know, if it
hadn't have been for Sally,
I wouldn't be here now.
Well, she's very fond of you, Jerry.
I'm gonna miss her.
I'm gonna miss all of you.
We, we may not be gone so long.
It all depends on, you won't
mind living here alone,
will you? Oh, no, no.
I'll get used to it, Jim,
in case I don't get a chance at the boat.
I just wanted to tell you that.
Oh, forget it.
I, I like arranging now
that I'm through with it.
Glad to have been some help.
No, it's more than that.
It's been your kindness in your home here.
Look, Jerry, I just want you
to write some good music,
some real music.
That's all the thanks I want. Don't,
don't waste your time fussing
with those squeezy little
tunes. Think big.
Try to be somebody I will. Jim.
I'll try to be as big
as I can. Yeah, good.
It's fine.
Well, you better be on her way.
Oh, good Heaven Sally song.
You know, I'm so tickled
that she remembered that.
Remember, that's your song, dear.
She couldn't do that.
I stood there watching that
boat pull out of the harbor,
and I was lonelier than
I'd ever been in my life.
I walked through the days
that followed from office to
office, theater to theater,
always getting the same
discouraging answer.
The big hits were all English or European,
where the local talent just
didn't seem to have a chance.
Broadway was closed to an
American from 23rd Street at Times
Square. They were all
playing Follow the leader.
And.
The leader was Charles Ro.
The.
Moment.
He's with Keller, Cecil
Keller, the English composer.
Mr.
Pearlman's not interested in
American songs at the moment.
He's leaving for England in a few weeks.
Good day.
How do you do? My name
is Kern Jerome Kern.
Oh yes. How do you do, sir?
I see you have the deeds with you. Mr.
Pearlman's. Very anxious to see them.
Deeds.
You're the man from the
real estate office, aren't.
You? No, I'm a songwriter.
These are some of my songs.
Your name isn't Kernan.
No. Kern, Jerome Kern.
I'm sorry. Mr.
Fryman hasn't a minute
to waste, I'm afraid.
I must say good days. Well, maybe.
If he'd listened to one of my songs,
I have one that could
be made Very English.
Good days, sir.
Goodbye Mr. Proman.
Goodbye Mr. Keller.
I'll see you in London soon.
I'll call you when I get there.
Thank you. I'll be waiting for your call.
I made up my mind that I was
going to try to write music
with an English accent.
So I sailed for London.
I wish I could say with flags
flying in my courage high.
But the sea and I and the boat
get along to well together.
I was mighty glad to see land again.
Excuse me. Could you tell me where Mr.
Hessler lives?
Kesler. We have a Jay and we have a Smith.
No hessler. Mr.
Jim Hessler.
Uncle Jerry.
Sally.
Oh, honey.
It's so good to see you.
We didn't know you were coming.
Well, I didn't know I was myself.
Daddy will be so glad to see you.
Oh.
Nevada there.
Oh, Sally, you're getting
prettier every day.
Yes.
Well, the tables are turned.
American songwriter invades England.
That's pretty good, Jerry.
That's daring. Very original.
You're thinking big. Anyway.
It's a chance I'm taking Jim.
So you've gotten a little
skinnier, haven't you?
I haven't been getting enough
roast beef lately. I guess.
Jerry, I,
I look at you sitting there
and it's just hard for me to
believe you haven't been here
all the time. Thanks, Jim.
It's sort of like being home again.
How was the symphony
coming along? Alright.
Oh, well, yes.
I'm, I'm still in the note making stages.
Of course, I always believe
in making plenty of notes.
It's, it's kinda like
planting seed wonder.
They start to grow and
then for, you know, it,
lo and behold, your symphony's
all written simple and easy.
Not as difficult as writing
those silly little tunes.
Well, no, it's, it's the
quiet here that does it.
Jerry Peace in this place is
just so thick that you can
float on it. There's a,
it's a rustic pastoral.
Wait, wait.
Now answer that telephone.
Oh, the doorbell.
Will you get the door? Please?
Do something about, yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, there's a, there's
a picturesque pastoral.
Hello. So sorry.
But you know the who sometimes they're.
On.
I can't, she's waiting for piano lessons.
Oh, Mr.
Edwards. Oh yeah.
Put him on. Come Sally.
It's time for Hello George.
Fine.
I don't.
Want tomorrow. I'll be glad to.
I'm not.
Gonna have a lesson.
For dinner. Good behavior.
Alright, I'll be there.
Bye-Bye.
George Edwards, the producer.
Yes.
He wants me to come up and
sit in on a rehearsal of a new
show.
Piano lesson. I'll Jerry's here.
You've got to talk to your daughter.
I can't do a thing with her anymore.
Well.
This is Uncle Jerry's first day here,
and I shouldn't be made
to take lessons. Should I?
Should I Uncle Jerry?
Well, I, I think you
should have one day off.
Maybe. Huh?
That's the end of her.
There was some hope for her
until her uncle Jerry arrived.
Now she's spoiled for good and all come.
We get myself a cup of tea.
Oh, Sally, I'm inclined to agree with you.
I think Uncle Jerry's arrival
does call for a celebration.
Now.
Will it be London or the fair?
Oh, the fair Daddy, please.
The fair.
Right.
The fair it is, is.
Hey.
Oh, I could be wonderful.
Could be wonderful.
Oh, no, no, Jerry,
I don't want Sally to go up in the swings.
Not until she's a little older.
The whole stage full of swings
and a boy and girl in each
swing and all of them singing.
Oh, you you mean for a production number?
Yeah.
That's not a bad idea.
They could swing from the states
right out over the audience
and back again.
Make a good production number.
What, what song would you use for it?
Spoon With Me. Be Perfect.
Spoon with me. That sounds fine.
Suppose I take that up to
George Edwards for the G Sure.
I'm gonna have dinner with
him tomorrow night. Oh, Jim.
I don't know why I am so very shy.
I always was imu.
I never knew what silly lovers do.
No flirting.
I, in all my life, I never kissed the man.
I never my but now at
Ice.
So try
spoon.
I liked spoon.
Whi.
Well.
Tree. Lord, call me
how you.
Like to spoon with the name.
How would you like to spoon
with the name beneath Oak Tree?
Large and shiny?
Call me to say what?
See, by you like to, and.
Pardon me for intruding.
You can point it out to
me as the composer of that
delightful number with
the swings in my name.
Isro Charles Roman.
Mr. Kern, I wanna congratulate you.
Roman.
I'm sorry sir. It isn't my number.
My name is Curry.
There's Mr. Rnr down the far bit.
That gentleman there, but
he can't be the composer.
It's him, sir.
Sipping Sherry and a very nice
gentleman. He is too, sir,
for a musician.
Mr. Proman, I have something
here, which I know you'd like.
It's a beautiful number with Parasols,
with all sorts of parasols.
Mr. Kern.
Oh, Mr.
Reman, how do you do?
I'm very glad to know you.
Mr. Kern.
I want to tell you, I think
your swing number is delightful.
It has such beautiful English charm to it.
Really delightful.
Oh, by Joe, Mr.
Truman. That's, that's rather nice of you.
It's.
A pleasure to know you Mr. Kern.
You know, you fellas
over here have a style,
all your own as English as the
center of the May Blossoms.
Would you join me in a glass of Sherry.
Writer?
Miss
believe.
I'd give that one up if I
were you one song at the gate.
I think you can afford to take a rest.
Or if I could finish it,
I know I could interest Roman in it.
You ought know by now that
Charles Forman is only interested
in English music and English composers.
I only had a piano. I know I
could work this out right now.
Flat.
Well, it looks like you do
have a little work to do.
That town we passed wasn't
very far back, was it?
No, not very.
Well,
let me take your bike and
I'll go back and see if I can
borrow a repair kit. No,
I think I'd better go.
I can talk with the natives
better than you can. Well,
let me do it. I can use my accent on them.
That's just what I was afraid of. No,
you wait here and whistle
yourself a little tune till I come
back.
I'll make sure you can find
this place again. I'll find it.
I say, is anyone there?
How do you do?
Did Mr. Timkin sent you?
Well, I was passing by on my
bike and I got a flat tire and.
Oh, then you don't work for Mr.
Timkin?
No, no.
I happen to notice your
piano through the window.
So I thought I'd come in
and try a little tune.
I see for a minute. I thought
you were the piano tuner.
No.
Well, I'd better go before the owners.
What do you do here? Gardening.
A little.
Oh, well, I don't know
whether anybody's told you,
but for a working girl,
you're very pretty.
Thank you.
You are an American, aren't you?
Yes.
Yes. I'm a songwriter.
As a matter of fact, that song
I was playing as you came in,
it was mine. Do you like it?
Oh.
What? You wrote it yourself?
Sure. Well, I write lots of songs.
Maybe.
Maybe you've heard this one.
Why? That's from the Ities.
Everybody's singing it.
Huh?
Now this is the one I was working on
that I'm gonna try to
place with the gaity too.
Of course I would if I were you.
Don't you believe I wrote these songs?
Tell me, when you compose,
do you always break into
people's houses to borrow their
pianos? Oh.
Alright. I'll tell you what I'll do.
If I place this with the gaity,
I'll send you tickets and you
can come and see for yourself.
Will.
You? I'll tell you when I get the tickets.
I beg your pardon, miss.
But your mother would
like to speak to you.
She's in the upstairs sitting
room. Thank you, Katie.
I'll be right up.
Well, I'm terribly sorry,
but I still wrote those songs
and I'll still be waiting for
the tickets.
Will you?
Wonderful.
I I I won't forget.
And you were the Ladd who
wasn't gonna fall in love with
anybody for a long, long time.
Well, this girl is different.
Sure. I know.
Well now don't joke
about it. It's serious.
Don't you believe me?
Yes, of course.
I believe.
And she really is different.
I know, I know.
Her hair is like spun
gold shining in the semi.
I know about her hair. She had
a kerchief on, but her eyes,
her eyes were, were like
pools in the starlight.
I see. Even with her working clothes on.
She's the prettiest girl I've ever seen.
I'm sure of it.
Seriously, Jim, don't you believe me?
Yes. Yes, I believe you.
It's spring, isn't it?
Tomorrow morning.
And I think I'm gonna give
you a great big dose of sulfur
and molasses.
Good night.
They didn't,
your.
Lips.
Your.
Eyes, your cheeks,
your hair are in a class beyond compare
you the loveliest girl.
That one could.
And I
that I
day.
You'll be.
They'll
that from.
Jerry. Isn't it lovely?
Oh, well, I had noticed
when I look at you,
I can't seem to see anything else.
Oh, writing songs again.
Perhaps we better stop
and have lunch. Alright.
You can move in under those trees there.
Isn't it a beautiful day?
Beautiful.
Now let's see.
You've seen Westminster Abbey
and the Tower of London,
and you've seen Buckingham
Palace and Hampton Court.
Maybe there's something I can
tell you about this place.
Eva, let's drop the
history coast for a while.
Do you mind? Not that it
isn't interesting, but, well,
there are a few things I'd
like to know about you too.
Well, all right.
What would you like to know about me?
Oh, just the ordinary things.
Things you like and things you don't like,
and where he went to school
and who was your first bow and
oh, what you want out of life.
Mm. That's a tall order.
Where shall I start?
The things you like.
Oh, I, I guess I like what everyone likes.
I like books and, and picnics
and dancing and music.
What about musicians?
Oh, certainly musicians.
And what do you want out of life?
Oh, I guess again, what?
Everyone wants happiness.
Have you ever given any
thought to getting married?
Why? Of course, doesn't everyone?
Are you set on any particular type of man?
Mm, I have been at different times.
When I was 16,
I desperately wanted to marry
the star cricket player at
rugby.
And now.
Now, oh,
now I don't really know except
that he must have a sense of
humor and he must be kind and
he must be intelligent and
good company.
And of course, he must love me very much.
Well, I,
I know somebody with at least
one of those characteristics.
Someday I'll tell you all about it.
Oh, good afternoon.
Good afternoon. Good afternoon.
And how have you been
this afternoon? Well,
I'll tell you how I've been.
Oh, that's, I've been looking.
Nevermind. Nevermind.
You feel wonderful. You feel great.
How could you be otherwise?
After such a beautiful day?
Tell me, my friend,
how is your knowledge of English
history? English history?
Did you know that London happens
to be the largest city in
the world? Yes, I know that.
Did you know that within
the county of London,
there are 14 road bridges
across the Thames.
Now there's the Waterloo, there's lap.
Do say sounds dull, huh?
Well, it's far from dull, my friend.
When you're a history teacher
is as beautiful as all the
sirens of history put together.
Did you know that all the swans
on the Thames belong to the
King of England? No.
Fancy that. And the male
swan is called a cob.
Oh, what does that get?
And did you know that when
you walk into Hampton Court,
you're walking right
straight into history?
Oh, my dear friend,
you have so many things
to learn about England.
Have you ever heard of a man
named Charles Roro Forman?
Well, now that's a familiar name.
The face escapes me.
How can you talk about Roman
when I'm talking about love?
Oh, so that's been the theme
of this little dissertation?
Yes. Well, I'm glad you informed.
Oh, that's all right.
Because the next time
Roman's office calls,
I'll tell him that you're
too busy to be bothered. Yes.
You tell him that I'm too busy.
Did you say the next time
Roman's office calls?
That's what I said. They've
been calling you all day.
But why should I bore you with
such trivial details? Well,
what do they want? No, no.
Dear friend, you return to your archives.
Why? Think of the future
when the past is so glorious.
Oh, come on.
I quit clowning. What happened?
Nothing. Nothing.
Forman just wants you to write
four songs for his new show.
If of course you can spare the time. Well,
why didn't you tell me about it?
Why didn't I tell you
about it? Well, come on.
Let's get going. There's no time.
We've got to do that on the ship.
On the what? On the ship.
We're sailing with Charles Roman.
Tomorrow we have to start
rehearsal in six weeks in
New York.
Oh, Tim, I, I am.
Oh, no, no.
Look, Jerry, this is the
chance you've been waiting for.
You certainly are full of surprises.
I bet you'd be up in the clouds.
I feel like I've just been
yanked out of the clouds.
Jerry, aren't you coming down for lunch?
Oh, no.
No. Jim, I'm not very hungry.
Oh, look, you've got to snap out of this.
It isn't the end of the
world. It's the beginning.
Here you are on your way back
home with a Charles Fullman
contract in your pocket.
Well, you ought to feel wonderful.
I know it. That's what
I keep telling myself.
You go back England.
If I just could've seen her once more,
Jerry was all we could
do to catch the boat.
You couldn't help that. You
talked to her on the phone.
On the phone.
What can you say on the phone?
Hello. It's nice seeing you.
Take care of yourself.
Oh, Jim,
there were so many things
that I wanted to say to her.
Now look, Jerry, you've got
to think about your career.
Things are just starting for you. Yeah,
you can say that over and over again.
And you know what happens, son?
Nothing, Jim.
You know, for the first
time in my life, I'm lonely.
Here I am on a ship
full of people with you.
And I might as well be on a
test that island don't all by
myself.
Did you ever feel this way?
Yes. Once.
What did you do about it?
I married the girl.
Hell, Mr.
Reman.
Hello there. I've been
looking for you too.
You weren't down at breakfast?
No. I, the first day out is always.
Rough. Well,
good Englishman should
have his sea legs by now.
Come and have lunch.
With me, Mr.
Reman. There's something I must tell you,
I'm not an Englishman, Mr.
Karen, there's something I must tell you.
I never thought that you were
at least not after the first
15 minutes.
Matter of fact,
I'm very proud to be able to
present a new American composer
to Broadway.
Thank you, Mr.
I have a lot of faith in your journey.
Just received a wireless
from Julius Sanderson.
She's accepted the part of
the girl from Utah. Wonderful.
Now I've got to have.
A great song for him.
If it's a love song, he's got one.
When I told how wonderful you're
they, believe.
Me.
Your lips, your eyes, your teeth,
your hair are in a glass beyond
handsome.
When I tell, and I'm
certainly gonna tell them
that you wife,
you've chosen.
Here.
I've got the clouds number.
Worked out pretty well now.
Huh?
I never realized that riding a
complete score was such a job
before.
Well, one good all
night session like this.
There's wonder I could use another week.
We went three weeks late already.
I hope he likes it. Tim.
Rolling.
I'd be crazy about it if he
hasn't gone out and bought
himself another show
while he's been waiting.
Good morning.
Sally. What are you doing up?
I'm gonna have my breakfast, right?
It is in morning already. No, it can't be.
Sally, you'll be late for school.
I'm coming.
Say Jim,
don't you think I better call
Roman's secretary and get an
appointment? You better call him at home.
It's a little early.
Morning.
Brian. 2 4, 4 6, please.
Do you think it's in good enough
condition for him to hear?
Oh yeah. Sure.
It's in good shape. For first draft.
Hello. This is Kern.
Jerry Kern.
Mr. Fryman was expecting me to
call today about an appoint.
He, he's leaving for England.
Well, but he promised that he
was gonna listen to my show.
Oh boy. For his next
per deck saying today.
Oh, alright.
Thanks.
Well, that's it.
He's going over to buy
himself another English show.
Well, he can't.
No. No, he can't.
We worked like dogs on this score.
Jim and I had all my plans
made too. After he bought it.
I was gonna jump the
next boat for England.
I'd forgotten about that young lady.
Wait a minute, I've got an idea.
My passport is still good.
Why don't I take the same boat
he's taking today? Wonderful.
Get him on board ship. But
he can't get away from ya.
That's right. Then I
can sell him the show.
Wonderful.
Then I can go and see Eva. Sure.
Sure. You can get married.
Well, yeah.
Probably have to ask her
first. Well that, well, I,
I'll go and find the
steamship company. Right.
I'll go back.
Why you think you'd make it.
All right?
If we get a break in traffic
and the old engine holds up.
Oh.
Uncle Jerry.
Jerry, come on now.
We've only got a few minutes.
Jerry.
You wanna miss that boat? Come on here.
Child's falling.
It's like watching an era
crumble in front of him.
The theater's gonna miss him.
Yeah.
You were very lucky to
miss that boat. Jerry.
Seen Max around. Oh, hello?
Jim. Victor.
No.
I think he went over to
com. Stuck in Elliot's.
What a terrible tragedy. Yes.
Yeah, that's unbelievable.
Jerry and I were just talking. Oh, Jerry,
you know Victor Herbert, don't you?
This is Jerry Kern Victor.
How do you do, Jerry?
It's a great honor to meet you, Mr.
Herbert.
Charlie Furman spoke of you quite often.
He had great hopes for you.
Well, he was very kind.
He liked you, but more
important, he respected you.
And it's easy to see why
you've got a song to sing.
Thank you, Mr.
Heaven.
Look down at that city, Jerry.
It's made up of millions of people.
The music is played a
part in all our lives.
Lullabies, love songs, hymns, anthems.
Must be pretty wonderful, Mr.
Herbert,
to realize that people you
don't even know and never will
know are singing your songs
and all of them asking for more
of the Victor Herbert music.
It makes me feel grateful,
Jerry, and very humble.
One of these days, you'll find
out yourself how it feels.
What is it?
My publishers call me the
Dean of American Music.
Well, I think you are
going to be the next dean.
One thing I must admit you've
got a better figure for it.
Keep riding, boy.
Don't let anything stop you.
Good night.
Good night, Mr.
Night. Victor, Jim.
Good night, Jim.
Good evening. Mr.
Ha.
It's a deal. Gentlemen, congratulations.
Comstock and Elliot are
going to produce. Oh boy.
Max just sent me over with a check.
What's.
The matter? Aren't you for us happy?
Yeah, thanks.
Turn out those lights again, will you?
Well, there it is in lights.
How does it feel? Well,
it feels pretty good.
If I could just get rid of
some of these butterflies in my
stomach.
How do you feel? Well,
I've got a little butterfly
trouble myself, I suppose.
You think we're standing in
front of a theater on 39 from
No. What do you take me for?
This isn't 39th and Broadway.
This is the top of the world.
Pretty nice world, isn't it?
Yeah, it's great.
It's wonderful. What a difference.
Seeing your name and lights
can make isn't come on.
We better go in. We miss the show.
The red comes a better,
and I'd like to be safe in bed
while the world is trouble
to remain and
for a clearer.
And
are we big?
Well, this is it, Jerry, you're in my boy.
Listen to that applause. It's for you.
Don't wake me up. Don't
anybody wake me up,
figured out how you're
gonna spend your money yet.
Well, for one thing,
I think I'll buy an interest
in harms for another.
I think you might take
a little ocean voyage.
Well, good luck.
I don't see how she can
possibly say no. Well,
that's what I'm worried about.
I'm afraid she is going
to say no, Jim, you know,
I can't get her out of my mind.
She's well, she's, yeah, I know.
I've been through this before.
She's everything you've ever
dreamed of on this earth.
She's everything I've
ever dreamed of in heaven.
Well, Jerry, let's stop here, shall we?
Alright,
Jerry. Hmm.
You know, you did write very often.
Well, my letters weren't
very interesting, Eva,
so I told them up.
As a matter of fact, you didn't
write very often yourself.
A lady doesn't correspond with
the gentleman unless it's a
reason other than a personal one.
Oh, well, now doesn't it
sound a little silly to you?
No.
It, it sounds altogether
fitting and proper.
Oh.
Wanna fight?
A lady doesn't fight.
Well, what does a lady do?
Oh.
You are impossible.
Well, you're right.
If I were you, I'd have
nothing to do with me.
In fact, if I were you when
I asked you to marry me,
I'd say no. Just on the grounds
that a lady never says yes.
Now.
See here, are you going
to ask me to marry?
You.
Might. With a little encouragement.
A lady doesn't in my country.
If a lady wants to be asked,
she has to be encouraging. In my country.
In your country, what?
In your.
Country. Well, there are,
there are proper ways to go
about such things in every
country. Oh.
Well then, let me put it this way.
From the very first moment I
saw you when you walked in from
the garden, I knew that out
of all the women in the world,
I'd finally found the right one.
The only one I wanted to tell you.
Then I wanted to say hello. Funny face.
I don't know your name
or anything about you,
but I've loved you all my life.
You were my first school
teacher. My first date,
the first girl I ever kissed
and everything in the world to
me.
You see, I recognized you immediately.
You thought all that.
That's right.
I stood there thinking that.
Wondering what you'd do if I kissed you.
What would you have done?
What would you do? Now,
will you marry me?
Thank you so much.
I'd love to.
Hello, Mrs.
Hello my darling.
They're.
Here. Daddy, they're coming up the stairs.
Welcome home, Jim.
What you old. You really did at this time.
Nothing my boy. Nothing.
Just a little gesture.
Jim.
This is even.
Hello, Eva.
Hello.
Well, you've married the
nicest guy in this world,
but the craziest, oh, now wait a minute.
I was keeping that from her.
Isn't she sensational? Jim, Jerry, honey,
turn around and let him
look at you. Oh, Jerry,
look at that hair on those eyes.
Have you ever seen a woman
like that in your life before?
Only once.
No. I I hope that both of you
have all the happiness in this
world. Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Jim. I think we have already, but getting.
Me and the music.
Oh, Sally, yes.
I, I'm sorry.
Dear I Sally.
On behalf of my father,
Jim Hessler, myself,
on behalf of my father,
Jim Hessler and myself,
I wish to congratulate you on
the start of your voice into
the great sea of life.
Oh, Sally.
Well, on behalf of my wife and myself,
I thank you very much.
Okay.
Hello, Mrs.
Hello.
Mr. Curry.
Sally.
It's so wonderful to see you.
Why you have grown up, haven't you?
Sally? This is your aunt Eva.
On behalf of my father. Thank you, Sally.
We're going to be real
good friends, aren't we?
Yes. I expect we are.
Well, what do you say?
Let's, let's all go in and have
something to eat, shall we?
Oh, Jim, it's so good to be home again.
Yes, it was good to be home.
I felt I had everything in
the world, happiness, success,
and the wife I had dreamed about.
I wanted to put it all into music.
Eva's smile and her eyes and
what it meant to be with her.
And at last, it seemed to me
that the clouds had rolled by.
First there was, leave it to Jane.
Leave it to Jane. Jane.
I don't dunno why you should
make me pot plan for you.
She is a girl with.
I always try to do everything
I can for you. No problem.
You can wish on her gifts for.
She'll tackle ga.
A score or more daily.
If.
Something is on your.
Heart, and I can see that
there is not a dot of it.
Comfort.
You soon.
It to me. I'll soon get you out of it if.
You,
and just hand over the
whole thing to Jane.
Well, Jane, why don't you
tell us how you do it?
Yes. Come on, Jane.
Tell.
Oh. But it's really very simple.
I just study up on the
famous women of history.
You mean like Lucrecia Borja?
Well.
No, not exactly.
Listen.
In days of old beside
the Nile of famous queen,
there dwells her clothes.
Were you but full of style.
Her figures slim. And on
every man that wandered by,
she pulled the theater bearer out.
And everyone observed with
awe that her work was sw,
but never wrong.
I be likely your, if I could
have my way, each man she met,
she went and kissed, and
she dozens on her list.
I wish that I had lived there
beside the pyramid for a girl
who did, or
she danced new dances now and
then the sword that make you
blood.
Each time she did them,
scores of men got injured in the rush.
They'd stand there gaping in
a line and watch her agitate
her spine.
It simply used to knock them
flat when she went like this.
And then like that cat dancing, Clee.
Oh, patter was always on the spot.
She gave those four. Egyptian
gained something else
that what first made him.
The
something is on your mind.
We'll find if you have
Father.
Once again, Broadway
belonged to the Americans,
to George Kohan, Irv Berlin.
George Gershwin, Vincent, buddy DeSilva.
I was working in mighty great company.
And in one of my own shows, Sally,
I was fortunate enough to
have the reigning queen of the
era, the wistful, lovely
unforgettable, Marilyn Miller.
Alright, Larry.
Thank you, Hazel.
My, we're gonna have to hurry.
How's it going?
I was never so nervous.
See more flowers?
Mr. Fel Lovely says the first
act was a dream sign flow.
Well, she said the second act.
Don't worry about the second.
Act second better than first
Q. Hazel is everything
ready for the quick change?
Everything's ready in the
stage dressing room. All
Thank you.
We got everything? Yes.
Everything's here.
Go.
Good luck Ms. Miller.
Thank you.
Keep.
It up. Keep your fingers crossed.
You.
Bet.
Oh, here, you, everything is ready.
I got a nice and warm.
Put it right here.
As I wash my dishes,
I'll be following a plan
till I see the brightness in
every pot and pan.
I'm sure this point of
view will ease the daily
I in my mind,
the silver line when
somewhere the sun is shining.
And so the
shine for you
of joy and glad
and
look for silver lining
and try to find.
I never thought I'd ever keep a scrapbook,
but it was nice to know that
people were singing my songs
and asking for more.
Night boat. Good morning, dear.
The zig fell follies, curtains
went up, curtains came down.
But I think,
and we got to look a little
more like a musician.
Eva grew laier with every passing year.
Our life was rich and
full and very satisfying.
And Jim and I, well, we
grew a little grayer.
More seven perhaps.
He was still working on
his symphony, so he said,
but on the whole, the years
didn't change as much.
However, they certainly did change.
Sally, she was quite a young lady.
Now.
She'd been away at school.
In fact, many schools.
Well, Sally.
Hello.
Darling.
Well, Sally, I thought you were at school.
Well, I, I was.
Oh, what happened this time?
I just can't stand that
school anymore. Uncle Jerry.
I've left and, and I'm not going back.
What does your father say about that?
Well, he, he hasn't said anything yet.
He, he doesn't exactly know you see,
I just left there this morning
and I came right out here to
talk to you.
Oh, uncle Jerry.
I had to leave. I hated it so much.
I couldn't eat or sleep or anything.
This is the third school you've
left now, isn't it, Sally?
Yes.
Well, no,
it seems to me that you ought
to be able to make a go.
One of them.
Oh, I just don't seem to fit in very well.
The kids all seem so, oh, I don't know.
All they're interested in
are parties and clothes.
They seem to think that's
all there is to life.
Oh, uncle Jerry, I I wish
you'd talked to dad for me.
He'll, he'll listen to you.
Well, Sally, you know
your father isn't well.
Then I ought to be home
where I can take care of him.
You ought to be at school
completing your education.
You want to make something
of your life, don't you?
Oh, I've had an education and,
and now I wanna get down
to something serious.
Oh.
Uncle Jerry,
you did promise you'd help me
get a start in the theater.
Ah.
Ah, ah, I said I'd help
you when you were ready.
Your father wants you to
complete your schooling first,
Sally, and he's the boss.
Jerry Dad's forgotten what
it's like to be young and feel
like this. But you haven't,
you haven't forgotten what
it's like to stand on Broadway
and look up at the light and think.
Someday.
I'll see my name up there.
You remember that feeling,
don't you Uncle Jerry?
Yes, Sally.
I've got to admit it. I do.
Well, well then that's more
important than school or,
or anything else in the world, isn't it?
Isn't it Uncle Jerry?
It's the third time Jerry.
Yes. I know.
Maybe we shouldn't have
made her go back before,
after all if she hates
it so much. Oh, Jerry,
you can't keep on running
away from things all your life
time. Sally found that out.
Well, you can't live another
person's life for them either.
Jim isn't fair.
Sally's grown up now and I
think she ought to be allowed to
do what she wants to do.
I want her to finish her
education and get a chance to
finish mine.
I, I always said that any
kid of mine was going to,
to get the right start in life.
Well,
what's right for one person
isn't always right for another
Jim. You know that Jerry,
the trouble with that girl is
she's just plain stage struck.
She comes by that, honestly enough.
Doesn't she?
Remember how we used to pound
the sidewalks and knock on
doors? Nobody could stop us.
Goodness. Only knows enough people.
Tried to remember how thrilled
we were when we finally
realized we were in.
So what? Right.
Have you or I to interfere with Sally?
Yeah.
Well, what, what are we gonna do, Jerry?
I give her a pound. And Sonny,
That's so cast Father Gwen
hasn't been cast yet, Gwen.
Well, that's, it's only one line.
Gwen is going to have a song.
The doctor's here. Mr.
Hes Oh. Oh, finally, doctor,
I'll be with you upstairs in
just a minute. Good evening,
Mr. Carter.
Hello, doctor.
You know when you, you get to be my age,
you start collecting pills about
Jerry. I hope that works out alright.
Who.
Stole my heart away?
Makes me dream all day? Dreams
I know can never be true.
Seems as though.
I'll ever be blue.
Hello, Mr.
Hammerstein. How are you?
Very well, Ms.
Miller. And you?
Fine. Hello, Oscar.
Jerry.
This is a charming number.
I was just telling Jerry
how much I liked it.
What a fine lyric you've written. Oh.
Thanks Jerry.
I've just been talking to Mr.
Dillingham and he thinks that
who should be a big production
number instead of a solo.
And that, of course,
Merril ought to ing it.
Oh, well then of course
we'll have to do it.
It puts me in rather a tough
position though, Oscar,
after all, I did write it for Sally.
I know you did Jerry, but we'll
give Sally something else.
Well, she's gonna be awfully disappointed.
It's a wonderful song
and I'd love to sing it,
but I hate to take it away from her.
Well, it's for the good
of the show, Marilyn.
I think you're right. Oscar.
Have you thought though how
you're gonna tell Sally it's not
gonna be easy? Oh, I thought
you should tell her, Jerry.
Oh, I was afraid you would.
Well, after all you know her so well.
It shouldn't be too difficult. Well,
it would be a lot easier if
I didn't know her so well.
Would you like me to tell her?
I'm sure she'll understand.
Would you do.
That, Marilyn?
Certainly.
Ask her to meet me in my
dressing room and don't worry.
Thank you, darling.
But Uncle Jerry wrote
that song for me. I know,
and I know how disappointed
you must be too.
But Sally Disappointments
are part of the theater,
and you've got to be able to
take them for the very same
thing happened to me in my first show.
I had to give up my song with a star.
I think I felt pretty much
as your feeling right now.
Then I think it's a pretty
low miserable trick for you to
pull on someone else.
Sally, listen to me a minute.
This is your first show.
You're just starting and
there are gonna be a good many
songs and a good many shows for you.
It may be difficult for
you to understand now,
but one day you'll realize
you've got to give and take
whether you like it or not.
I'll never take a song
away from anyone else,
especially if it's
their first real chance.
Sally, please don't put
this on a personal basis.
I don't wanna take the song away from you.
Then why are you doing it?
Mr. Dillingham thinks
it's best for the show.
And what's best for the show
is more important than what I
want or you want or any
personal feelings involved.
Don't you see that, Sally?
Yes, I see it.
All right.
You're trying to take my song
away from me and you aren't
going to get away with it.
Uncle Jerry wrote that song for me,
and I'm going to sing it.
I don't care whether you are the star.
You're not gonna take
it away from me, Sally.
You can't have my song Uncle Jerry.
Don't let her talk you into it.
I don't care what happens.
She can't have my song.
I am sorry, Jerry.
What is it, Sally?
Am I still in the show? Uncle Jerry.
If you want to be, you
won't have a song though.
I took my song away from me.
The song you wrote for me.
Sally, there's a little thing
called the Good of the Show.
Apparently the show didn't
seem very important to you this
afternoon.
What important?
You didn't care what happened
to the show just so long as
you got your way.
The theater doesn't work that way, Sally.
Nothing works that way.
I learned something today.
I suddenly realized that you
are not ready for the theater
yet.
But.
Not ready.
Who all you have to
offer is a small talent,
great deal of conceit in return
for which you want success.
Sally,
I've known you and loved you
ever since you were a little
girl.
I couldn't love you anymore
if you were my own child.
But I must say this to you,
you're not gonna get anywhere
in this life by using people.
And until you realize that,
you're not gonna add
the respect of anyone.
Sally, I I'm.
Back into my memory side.
The.
My heart away makes me dream more day.
Dreams I know can never come true.
Seems as though I'll ever be. Boo
means my happiness.
Would I answer yes to where you ought
no one, but you.
The one.
Hello?
Yes. Hezbollah.
And you send for the doctor.
Is Sally there?
Oh, well, you be sure he stays in bed, Ms.
Muller, and I'll be right over.
Dogs get here. He's upstairs in Mr.
Haslers room.
It is his heart.
I wouldn't stay very long. Mr.
Hessler could use a little rest.
Well, good evening, Jim.
Oh, Jerry, we missed you
at the theater tonight.
How are you?
Sally's gone. Jerry.
Yes, I know.
Mrs. Mul told me.
I she didn't come down for dinner, so.
Went.
Up to a room.
Dear Daddy, I'm going out on my own.
Don't worry about me. Someday
you'll be proud of me.
I'll always love you dear.
Tell Uncle Jerry I still love him.
That's all my fault. Jim.
I shouldn't have suggested
that she'd be in the show. No,
no, no.
Jerry. Sally is Sally.
It's time. Both of us face that.
Yes, I know, but I think I heard her.
Well.
She's got Spunk.
Jerry. She's young.
She's, she's way too young
to be out on her own.
Well, now look, Jim, don't
you worry about this.
I'll bring her back.
I wish you'd do that. I promise you.
I'll try my most.
Yeah, just as soon as you can.
Yeah.
Goodnight. Jim.
Why don't you get back in the
bed and get some rest. Yeah.
I left no stone unturned trying
to find Sally personal ads,
private detectives.
But the answer was always the same.
No one had seen her.
It was a futile hunt.
I tried to keep Jim's hopes
alive, but I think he knew.
And then one night,
please don't mention the right telephone.
I think Mr. Curry, you'd
better go up right away.
He's been asking for you.
Jim.
I I was just driving by.
I thought I'd drop in and say hello.
Yeah.
You forget I've known you a long time.
Feeling.
Better, aren't you?
Yeah.
Yeah. I'm.
Good. All you need now is a little rest.
Kinda quiet around here now.
Yeah, seriously.
It is.
But things will be popping again
just as soon as Sally comes
back.
Have you heard from a jury?
No. No.
Not directly, but I've got
a couple of very good leads.
I've got a hunt that
won't be very long now
then I'm gonna see the one thing, Mr.
Hela, you are going to
finish that symphony.
I've kept you from that too long now.
Oh, I forgot about that symphony.
Forgot, forgot about it years ago.
What about your notes?
I never made any notes.
I was just pausing as usual.
You know, I used to,
I used to go around hollering
about being a genius.
You are a genius, Jim.
And you with your wheezed little tunes,
you are writing the real music.
The.
The Folk Music of America.
Thanks Jerry for letting
me kind of stick around.
No, wait a minute.
Let's get something straight. Jim,
I didn't let you hang around
if it hadn't been for you.
When your faith in me, I
would've quit half a dozen times.
You know that.
And.
If we're gonna start handing out bouquets,
I just want you to know that
I don't know where to begin to
Thank you.
You're a great man, Jerry.
It's been a privilege
getting in on that music.
It's been a lot of fun.
Now, let's not talk that way, Jim.
A couple of weeks you'll be
back at that piano screaming for
more and more brass.
Jerry, this looks like time for strings.
Jerry, if I,
I want you to look after s for me.
Jim, you are going to be All right.
So is Sally in a couple of
weeks where we'll be laughing
about this.
Is it better perhaps
if I made some coffee?
Oh, no.
No. It can't be.
Mr. Kern had hardly
closed the door when he,
I was completely lost,
completely helpless.
Jim was gone and I had failed
him. Was still failing him.
I'd lost a world with Jim's passing.
And everywhere I walked,
I walked with ghosts,
reliving lost hours,
pacing a world of memories I
couldn't even think in terms of
music.
I began to feel that I
might never write again.
How long has this been going on.
For? Weeks Oscar?
Ever since Jim died, he's
a scorer to write me.
Has he done one song?
That certainly doesn't
sound like Jerry. He.
Seems to have completely lost heart.
Have you had any word of Sally?
No, but he has every friend
he ever had in show business
looking.
Well, don't worry about it.
You'll turn up.
It's Jerry. I'm worried
most about, you know, Oscar.
I believe he's beginning to think. He,
he can't write music anymore.
It's heartbreaking to watch him.
Well, I, I have a book here
I'd like him to take a look at.
I've been commissioned to
adapt it and write the lyrics.
And I think Jerry's a man do the music.
I don't think he'll do it, Oscar.
Well, that's hard to believe.
There's never been a time as
long as I've known Jerry when
you couldn't excite him with a good story.
There's never been a time
in his life like this.
But I'll, but you can try and
I'll tell him you're here.
Hello.
How's it going, dear?
Oh fine, darling.
Fine.
I was just tinkering a
little bit with a melody,
but it's going to be all. Of course it is.
Hi. It is raining, isn't it Jerry?
Oscar Hammerstein's here. Oscar.
Oh God. Why didn't you tell me?
Oscar, come in.
Oh, Jerry, this is good to see you.
Watch you sit down.
Sit down. Thanks, Jerry.
Well, what's, what's new?
I'll tell you what brought
me out here, Jerry.
I came across a novel that I
think is gonna make a great
show.
Now, if you do the music,
I'd like to do the book.
Oscar. I, I'd love to.
I really would.
But I have so many commitments
right now that I don't think
it, I wouldn't be fair to
you or anyone concerned.
Suppose I leave the book with
you when you glance through it
when you have time.
Oh, it's no use Oscar.
Well, I'll leave it anyhow.
See you next week. Won't
you stay for dinner?
I certainly like to, but I
have to get back to town.
Bye Eve. I'll see you to the door, Oscar.
Bye bye.
I get it.
Hello, this is Mrs.
Curry.
Oh.
Just a moment. Mr.
Kelly. Jerry.
It's Arthur Kelly. He's got news of Sally.
Hello Arthur.
Yeah.
Oh, that's wonderful.
In Memphis.
What was the name of that club again?
Club Elite. All this week?
Yes. Well, I get right on.
Thank you very much.
Sally is singing at the Club
Elite in Memphis all this week.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Shall I pack a bag for you?
Yes, you do that now call me.
One.
One more night if you'll one more flight.
One more one.
Will.
You dance with me?
Oh, no.
Thank you. No, go ahead
and dance with that.
Charlie.
Will.
You dance with me?
I sure will. Baby.
What this.
Think of what you are losing
by constantly refusing to dance
with me.
You'd be the idol of brands with me,
and yet you stand there
and shake your foolish head
dramatically while I wait here.
So ecstatically, you just look and say,
empha.
Not this season.
There's a reason I won't
dance. Don't ask me.
I won't dance. Don't ask me.
I won't dance.
Madam am with you.
My heart won't let my feet
do things they should do.
You know what?
You are lovely.
So what?
I'm lovely.
But what you do to me,
I'm like an ocean wave
that's bumped on the shore.
I feel so absolutely stumped on the floor.
When you dance, your
charming and you're gentle,
especially when you do the body.
But this feeling isn't
purely mental for heaven.
Resto, I'm not as best, and
that's why I won't dance.
Why should I? I won't dance.
How could I, I won't dance.
I know that musically
is the way to romance.
So if I hold you in my arms, I.
Come in.
Sally.
Oh, good, Jerry.
Oh, good Jerry, I so glad to see you.
What are you doing here?
Well, I, I was up front watching the show.
Did you see what we did
to your number. Yes.
I bet you like the show.
Not at all. As a matter
of fact, I liked it.
I wish that some of the
people who think my music is
highbrow could have seen it.
I, I'm so excited.
I I don't know what to do.
You look wonderful. Uncle Jerry.
More handsome than ever.
How's Aunt Eva?
Oh, she's fine.
But of course she misses you.
Oh, I miss her too.
I miss you both.
Is she with you?
You haven't told me yet
what you're doing here.
No. Your Aunt Eva's in New York,
and I'm here because somebody
told me I could find you here.
I've been looking for you
for a long time now. Sally.
Welcome. Jerry.
You shouldn't have
bothered. I'm all right.
Oh, I'm.
Sure you are. But I promised
your father I'd look after you.
Sally, I want you to come
back to New York with me.
I can't, uncle Jerry.
I, I'd like to, but I can't.
When I, when I heard about my father, I,
I never realized he was so
ill Uncle Jerry. You know,
I never would've lived him.
Do I know that song.
When I, when I heard
about him, it was as, oh,
someone had forced me to look
into the mirror for the first
time.
I loved him very much, and
I knew I'd broken his heart.
I was spoiled and selfish,
and I knew that I,
I could never have any respect
for myself again unless I did
what I said I was going to do.
So, you see, I can't go back right now.
I'm making my own way now,
and I'm pretty good at it too.
Well, Sally, I,
I just don't like the idea of
you being here and all along.
This is just a stepping stone
from where I've been to where
I hope I'm going.
I'm making $50 a week now
because management thinks I'm
worth $50.
If I'm worth more, I'll get more.
And if not, I'll have to
find it out for myself.
And Uncle Jerry.
I'm not using anyone.
Five.
Minutes.
Thank you, Jimmy.
You understand. Don't you look at Jerry.
Well, Sally, you know, darling,
I'd give anything in the world
if you'd let me help you.
But I must say that I've never
been quite so proud of anyone
in my life as I am of you at this moment.
Good.
Luck, Alec.
Gradually, I felt the old
heartache misting away,
and I was at peace.
The promise I had made,
Jim had been fulfilled.
Sally was going to be all right.
I walked along the river that
night with a river wind in my
face and the taste of it on my lips.
And I stood there listening
a sudden excitement thrilling through me,
listening to the song of a
River that makes its way right
through the heart of America.
And the voice of that river
was the laughter, the tears,
the joys,
and the sorrows and the hopes
of all America's people.
Well, Joe, that's my story.
It's too bad Mr. Hesler couldn't
have been there tonight,
Mr. Kane.
Oh, he was there, John.
He'll always be a part of
any music I ever write.
Whatever happened to Ms. Sally?
Well, I don't know exactly.
She's on her own now.
Maybe I'm just getting tired of something.
But ever since Jim's been gone, I,
I feel like everything
is sort of ending for me.
Maybe my music is ending too.
Joe ending after that show tonight.
Hey, hey, I gotta get
you back to the Waldorf.
You got some vows to take Now, sir, Mr.
Kind.
Your music ain't ending for you.
In my opinion.
It's just the beginning.
She didn't.
Say yes. She didn't say
no, she didn't say stay.
She didn't say go. She
wasn't so sure about it.
Be good.
She wasn't even sure that she'd
be good. So what did she do?
I leave it to you.
And.
The.
Last time I saw Paris,
her heart was warm and
I heard the laughter of
her heart in every street.
The.
Last time I saw Paris,
her trees were dressed for
spring and lovers walked beneath
those trees and birds on songs to sing.
I dodged the same old taxi cabs
that I had dodged for years.
The chorus of their
squeaky horns was music to
the last time I heart was warm.
And no matter how.
Do sit down, Mr.
Curry. Oh, you sure we
won't be in the wave?
Oh, certainly not.
Not at all.
Well, I can't get over this, Mr.
Ed.
We certainly don't grow
stages like this on Broadway.
Darling. Look at the
size of that orchestra.
Well, you have everything in
the world to work with here.
That's.
Right. Mr.
Can we've tried to give
you the best of everything.
Yes, that.
So what was the number
you were gonna do today?
Well,
we found an old song of yours
that you did first in 1917
called The Land Where Good Songs Go.
Oh, I'd almost forgotten about that one.
We're using it as a frame
for some of your other songs.
What Star is gonna sing this?
Well, well, Mr.
Kern, as a matter of fact,
we are trying out a newcomer.
Oh, a newcomer.
This girl did a test for us in
New York and it impressed us.
So we flew her out here.
She hasn't done much yet, but
we have great hopes for us.
Quiet.
Hi girls. We're ready.
Ready for a take? Alright, let's try one.
Places, please.
Okay, Charlie, hit the lights.
Quiet.
Okay, roll.
Action.
It's land of April
with Sun Shining.
With.
Roses.
And.
River.
Mr.
Like him, I love her.
I'd rather hear her sing one
of my songs than anyone else in
the world.
And.
And fall away.
I dream.
I dream one day and that dream is here
beside.
A fine romance, my friend.
This is a fine romance with no kiss.
I might as well play
bridge with my old maid.
I haven't got a chance.
This is a.
The promise.
Of that,
the brink of a
the
will
moment.
When all.
Was I born?
Why am I living?
Do, what am I,
what can I,
I.
Man river,
he must know something,
but don't say nothing.
He just, he keeps on
he dawn plant and he dawn plant.
And what soon
body All
I'm tired, but I'm.