- 18 hours out.
Destination unknown.
A military secret.
The largest overseas expedition
ever discarded by the blue
ensign at the American Navy.
Southwards from Britain,
some 3,000 miles away,
an even greater convoy twice the size
moves in its appointed
place across the seas.
Shielded by the white
ensign of the British navy.
Destroyers in close support,
cruisers on the flanks,
and beyond the horizon,
the battleships.
From the decks of aircraft carriers
and from the shore, planes
of the fleet air arm
and Costal Command patrol the
skies and search the skies.
Advance outposts of an
elaborate protective screen.
- East
nor'east, the American convoy.
- Sou'west
by west, the British.
Nothing like these two armadas
had disturbed the waters
since the world was made.
This is a combined operation.
An operation that began
some four months earlier
in Washington DC.
The President of the United States
welcomed the Prime
Minister of Great Britain.
The gravity of the moment
had brought them together.
The lights burned all night
that night in the White House
where the two leaders met with their
combined chiefs of staffs.
For this was the picture
taking all too-definite form
in the minds of the civil,
military, and naval leaders
now locked in secret conference.
Two Axis spearheads were headed east.
In the north, von Bach was hewing his way
through the Ukraine to the Caucuses.
In the south, Rommel was driving toward
the Egyptian border.
These two spearheads were
intended to meet in Iran
and head eastwards towards India.
In the orient, Japan had
occupied the coast of China,
the East Indies, Malaya, and Burma.
In preparation for the drive
westward through India.
If these two enemy spearheads
were allowed to meet,
Russia and China, except for
their remote arctic ports,
would be completely isolated.
Japanese raw materials
and German production
would be combined.
The peoples of Europe, Asia, and Africa,
7/8ths of the world's
population, would be enslaved.
By morning a decision.
Both bold and revolutionary.
Bold because in this our darkest hour
we dared to take the offensive.
Revolutionary because that
offensive was conceived,
planned, and executed by
the peoples of two nations.
The time and the place
had been agreed upon.
Code name of the combined
operation was Acrobat.
The two great elements
were time and secrecy.
125 days in which to plan
and launch an offensive
from bases 3,000 miles apart.
An operation involving
hundreds of thousands
of American and British
soldiers and sailors.
Millions of American and
British working men and women.
Only by whose combined
efforts could the plan
become a reality.
But from whom the plan
itself must be kept secret.
A few score men and no more
knew in its entirety the plan for this
greatest of combined operations.
In London and Washington,
British and American officers
were placed at adjoining desks
to work through the days
and nights of grind and toil
that lay ahead.
And gradually in the
enforced daily intimacy,
men grew to know and respect each other.
Thus was born the
relationship out of which
an Allied army came into being.
To them came hourly reports
on the vast undertaking
of forging the striking weapon.
It was a race against time.
In the United States, men
and supplies poured eastward
toward the Atlantic seaboard.
- In
Britain also, by road and rail,
an army was on the move.
By day and night, the dockers worked.
Records were broken in tonnage
put aboard in one shift.
For every soldier, British and American,
10 tons of equipment.
On both sides of the Atlantic,
the effort was tremendous.
Guns, trucks, aircraft,
petrol, water, food,
barbed wires, locomotives.
Of ammunition alone we
shipped 520 different kinds.
And every ship sailed on time.
And in absolute secrecy.
- And the convoy
continued its hidden way.
- My name is McAdams, Joe McAdams.
Kansas City, Kansas.
Private first class.
I was on one of those
ships you're looking at.
Part of the biggest show on
Earth and didn't know it.
Too darn many ships to see all at once.
Well, we'd been hollering for action,
now we were gonna get it.
But we didn't know where.
Norway, France, Italy, China.
Finally, on the fifth day we got the news.
I mean what we been waiting to hear.
They handed out little guide books
and I remember the first line,
you are to do duty in North Africa
as a soldier of the United States.
Gave me kind of a kick.
- Why North Africa?
What was the plan called Acrobat?
The convoy from America was heading east.
The one from Britain heading south.
At a given point west of Gibraltar
the British convoy would divide.
For 12 hours the two halves would proceed
in opposite directions.
Then the second half
would reverse its course
and follow the first.
Passing Gibraltar 24 hours behind.
Thus with clock-like precision
the combined operations would begin
with simultaneous landings at Casablanca,
Oran, Algiers.
Casablanca to protect our
flank against an Axis attack
through Spanish Morocco.
Oran and Algiers to secure bases
from which to press eastward.
Then the occupation of Tunisia,
from which we could cut
Rommel's supply lines
across the Mediterranean.
Next trap and destroy
Rommel's Afrika Korps
between our Allied forces
and the British Eighth Army.
- Thus
one arm of the Axis pincer
would be amputated, and supply lines
around the Cape of Good Hope
would be shortened by half
through winning control
of the Mediterranean.
North Africa would be
ours with bases from which
to stab at the heart of the Axis citadel.
Those were the main objectives
of the plan called Acrobat.
In both convoys, the men kept fit,
now knowing the task that lay ahead.
For most of them this
voyage was a new experience.
They'd never been so far from home before.
- That's certainly true of me.
My name's George Metcalfe.
I was a greengrocer in civvy street,
we had a shop a long time.
Only we're a military family, really.
My dad was at Passchendaele
and I was at Dunkirk.
Never met such a collection of blokes
as we got on this ship.
Chaps from Glasgow, New
York, London, Melbourne,
Cape Town, Montreal, Chicago,
Birmingham, Wellington,
Bethnal Green, the whole issue.
I reckon it's about time
this team of internationals
got cracking.
When I was peeling spuds just now
I made up quite a letter to my girl.
All about the way these ships zigzag
and about flying fish and whales.
Course we haven't seen any yet,
but I reckon she'll like to
know I'm enjoying myself.
And now I got something
else to tell her too,
the best news for a long time,
they just put it up on the ship's board.
- But
the Eighth Army's offensive
was only one phase
of a larger strategy.
Included therein, the bombings of Genoa,
Naples, Turin.
Precision bombings of the Renault factory
turning out Rommel's tanks.
All these a part of
the plan called Acrobat
of which the enemy still knew nothing.
Nothing of the submarine trip to Africa
by General Mark Clark with a message
to be smuggled into France.
Nothing of the arrival at
Gibraltar of General Eisenhower,
where he was joined by
General Henri Giraud
who had received General
Clark's smuggled message.
The enemy knew nothing until
the last possible moment
when the first half of
the convoy from Britain
steamed past the fortress of Gibraltar.
- It was
at night that the ships passed
through the Straits.
The time had been carefully chosen
for here in narrow waters
attack seemed certain.
Aboard ship and on the
rock, everyone stood to,
but the ships moved steadily on.
It was as though for the
moment the enemy's sword
had fallen from his
hand through indecision.
This time, it was in Rome and in Berlin
that the lights burned all night.
For the first time since
the war's beginning,
somebody else was calling the tune.
But before the enemy
could collect its wits
or its forces, our ships lay as planned
off their appointed destination.
Events planned four months
earlier moved to a climax.
Off Casablanca stood
the convoy from America.
To the troops aboard spoke
their commander General Patton.
Soldiers and sailors.
It is not known whether
the French African army
will contest our landing.
But all resistance by whomever offered
must be destroyed.
However, when any of the French soldiers
seek to surrender, you will accept it
and treat them with the respect
due a brave opponent and future ally.
Remember, the French
are not Nazis or Japs.
November the 8th, 1942.
Orders of the day.
The words play ball
transmitted by the task force
commanders signifies that
all forces are to take
vigorous and offensive
action against the enemy.
A large searchlight shown in
a vertical position at night
signifies that the enemy has agreed
to the terms of the Allies.
Zero hour.
From America, the president
broadcast by short wave.
We do not want your land.
We fight a common enemy.
From London, General Charles
de Gaulle, do not resist.
From Gibraltar, General Giraud.
We welcome the Allies to French soil.
How would these pleas be answered?
- Play ball.
- The
fight was on in Casablanca.
- In the meantime,
at Algiers our landing craft
also met fire from shore batteries
which were soon silenced by
ships of the British navy.
Here too the French troops ashore
were asked by radio to
indicate a friendly attitude
by throwing their
searchlight beams vertical.
It wasn't long before here
and there along the coast,
searchlights were seen
pointing to the heavens.
As dawn broke, fighter
planes from Gibraltar
fitted with extra fuel tanks
took off without even waiting to hear
whether the landing fields
at Algiers had been captured.
By seven AM, resistance
at Algiers was finished.
British and American troops had landed
east and west of the city,
penetrated 10 to 15 miles
and held the heights
and all vantage points.
In Algiers on that famous November the 8th
was Admiral Jean Darlan,
French Vice Chief of State
under Marshal Petain.
It was after consultation with him
that the French commanding general
agreed to surrender the city.
- Meanwhile, at Oran.
American paratroops and airborne infantry
flown from Britain 1500 miles away
had landed to capture airfields
while other American troops had
poured ashore on the beaches
protected by the British navy.
Here as in Algiers the fighting lasted
for only a few hours.
But at Casablanca the battle still raged.
Shore batteries and the heavy guns
of the French battleship Jean Bart
and several cruisers,
destroyers, and gun boats
put out a devastating fire.
Gunnery from American ships
coupled with precision bombing
silenced those guns.
Striking inland from the
beaches north and south
of the city, shock
troops cut the railways,
other lines of communication,
then converged upon the town.
Two days later, the Germans
invaded unoccupied France.
Whereupon Admiral Darlan declaring Petain
a prisoner of the Axis
and himself Chief of State
ordered the cessation of hostilities.
In proof of the surprise of our landings,
German armistice commissions
were caught flat-footed
in each city.
Their jobs, to bleed North
Africa of her raw materials
and farm products.
The people of North Africa were evidently
not sorry to see them go.
- Events moved swiftly.
To Algiers came General Anderson
commanding the British First Army.
General Giraud took command
of the French land forces.
United under General Eisenhower,
they were ready to take the field.
Once more the Tricolour,
the Stars and Stripes,
the Union Jack flew side by side.
But the enemy had lost no time.
Across the Mediterranean by sea and by air
he was pouring men and equipment
into Tunis and Bizerte.
Despite this, we determined
to start the campaign at once,
hoping to reach the distant
cities before the enemy's grasp
had become too strong.
This was a bold decision
for the British First Army
was as yet little more
than one division and the
bulk of the American forces
were needed to safeguard
our position in Morocco.
We had other disadvantages.
Roads were poor.
Railways inadequate.
The enemy beyond the mountains
had short supply lines
from Sicily and Sardinia.
Our own, stretching
forward from the improvised
base at Algiers were
four times the length.
Even more important, we lacked
as yet forward air fields
whereas the enemy in Tunisia had all
of the permanent air fields he needed.
In less than a month
the weather would break.
Could our slender force,
in the last days of autumn,
achieve a flashing success against time
and a stronger enemy?
With immense energy the attempt was made.
By road, Allied infantry,
tanks, and artillery
moved towards the hills.
By rail went General
Giraud's men with mules
for mountain transport.
By air flew British and
American parachutists
to capture suitable ground for air fields
and the tactical points nearby.
By sea went commandos to Bougie and Bonn.
The latter 300 miles to the east
and only 60 miles from
the Tunisian border.
Here the air field which
our parachutists have taken
was already under attack
from the Luftwaffe.
It was our only permanent
forward air field
and had to be fought for repeatedly.
In three columns we advanced
towards Tunis and Bizerte.
And still the enemy poured into Africa.
By mid-November 1,000 a day.
Among them Marshal
Kesselring, Mediterranean
Commander in Chief.
The man who had made his name infamous
at Warsaw and Rotterdam.
November the 18th, 10 days
after our first landings,
our mixed force of Allied troops
had crossed the frontier into Tunisia
and skirmishes were frequent.
On we went.
Small units of French, British, Americans.
Held out here, gaining
there, fighting roads
as well as Germans but pushing on.
By November the 22nd, we were in Beja.
450 miles on the road to Tunis.
News came that 30 miles on
the French under General Barre
were holding Medjez el
Bab against the Germans.
The French were fighting stubbornly,
equipped with little more
than machine guns and rifles.
General Anderson promptly
moved to support them.
Together we held Medjez,
henceforth a pivotal point,
and forced the Germans back.
But now we went into the plains
and were increasingly
exposed to the enemy's
more numerous tanks and aircraft.
November the 25th, the
first real tank clash.
15 enemy tanks destroyed
and the rest withdrew.
And on we push towards Tunis and Bizerte.
Racing against time and the weather.
60 miles from Bizerte, 50 miles.
40 miles.
Our supply lines inexorably thinning,
our reinforcements fewer and fewer.
30 miles from Bizerte.
20 miles.
18 miles from Tunis.
16,15.
And from the hills, our
patrols saw the city.
But now the enemy attack
rose to a crescendo.
From the skies a
bombardment to which we had
no adequate answer.
Our supplies were far outrun.
Our casualties heavy.
Even as the goal was in
sight, the race had been lost.
This first thrust, this
adventurous gamble had failed.
We fell back to the
protection of the hills.
But even as we withdrew
to regroup our forces
we encountered a new enemy.
Winter was upon us.
Our hastily-improvised
air fields were flooded.
Our planes earthbound.
The roads became running streams.
Our tanks immobilized.
All hopes of a quick victory
had finally foundered in a sea of mud.
But the race for Tunis and
Bizerte had not been in vain.
For our battle lines now stabilized,
ran south from Medjez el Bab
through Ousseltia, Faid,
Maknassy, and Gafsa.
Along the barrier ridge of mountains known
as the Great Dorsal which separated
the German-occupied coastal plain
from the mountainous regions to the west.
German expansion was possible only through
a series of passes
traversing the Great Dorsal.
And all through the winter months,
we held those passes against
incessant German attack.
This was the period
referred to by the world
as one of military inactivity.
A period during which
we sustained nearly half
the total casualties
incurred during the whole
North African campaign.
- That's right.
When you're reading
your papers about lulls,
that don't apply to George Metcalfe
and the poor bloody infantry.
It never did.
We're on the job every night.
Patrols in the hills and in the woods.
Off we go with some brands and tommy guns
and a few loose bombs
and if we're lucky we scupper a few Jerrys
and bring a few prisoners in.
Old Fred Parker's the
best, he was a poacher.
It's second nature to old Fred.
When we get back we're camouflaged
so you can't tell whether we're men
or walking lumps of mud.
We picked up about half of Tunisia
when we got back this morning.
And we'd just about scraped it off
when we had to go out again at dusk
and pick up the other half.
Great life.
You'd think mud'd be different in Africa.
Different from France, say.
Old Fred says it weighs heavier here
and don't smell the same
but me I can't tell any difference.
It turns white bread into brown
just like the other stuff.
Keeping your automatics and
rifles clean is the worst.
Old Fred's only got about
half a tail of his shirt left.
There's one thing we do
thank God for, the mules,
fancy that.
Mules.
If it wasn't for the mules
we'd just about starve.
Not that we eat 'em, I don't mean that,
but they bring up the rations, see.
Nothing but mules or
eagles could ever get here.
Mud, just mud.
I told my girl I'll stick to her like mud
and I can say more than that.
- Whenever
the fields were dry enough,
our planes took off to
tackle the Luftwaffe.
Though still outnumbered, in four weeks
they shot down 241 enemy aircraft
for a loss of 89 of our own.
Further back, day after day,
the Strategic Air Force was taking off
to kill the enemy's effort
at its starting point.
Liberators from the east.
Fortresses from the west.
Went forth to destroy
enemy bases in Italy.
Sardinia.
Sicily.
But on land, no offensive
could be launched until spring.
Against its coming there
was to be on either side
of the Great Dorsal a
building up of power.
Over supply routes that
spanned on the German side
150 miles of water and on our side
hundreds of miles of land
and then thousands of miles of water.
The longest assembly lines in the world
were in operation.
From the factories of the
United States and Britain.
From Birmingham to Algiers.
From Detroit to Iran.
From Manchester, Los Angeles, from Leeds,
from Pittsburgh to Casablanca.
Full trains were assembled on the spot,
loaded with freight, and sent forth.
The south Atlantic became an
airway as well as a seaway.
From Brazil flights of
P-38s equipped with extra
fuel tanks were flown across the seas.
Each flight led by a Flying Fortress
which provided navigation.
From Gibraltar, aircraft
which had been brought by ship
from Britain and reassembled on the rock
were flown off to Chamaze.
Nearly 1500 planes reached
the front by this route.
Roads to the front were being built
where none before existed.
On wet, still-unfinished landing strips,
giant planes sat down
with cargoes of material.
Our reservoir of power was filling up.
Tunisia was to be the
theater of a major campaign,
a campaign to be fought
where Scipio had fought,
and Hannibal.
Where already three times in history
great armies had been destroyed between
the mountains and the sea.
These hills and plains were again to echo
to the tempest of battle.
Not now the trumpeting of elephants,
but the crash of tanks and artillery.
Not now an empire, but
way of life at stake.
♪ Oh come let us adore him ♪
♪ Christ the lord ♪
- On this Christmas
1942, our soldiers and airmen
in Tunisia at the western desert
gather together in little churches
or under the open sky.
And doing so, they thought
of their homes and loved ones
hundreds or thousands of miles away.
Our soldiers thoughts were of
New York and the Middle West.
Of the cities and villages of France.
The plains and hills of India.
Of homes in Cape Town
and the African veldt.
Or among the snows of Canada,
or in the Christmas sunshine
of New Zealand and Australia.
And among the fog and rain
of London and Edinburgh.
And they thought of their comrades
who had already been killed
and of the cause for
which they'd been killed,
the cause that had brought
all them across the seas
to fight.
The cause of liberty and
tolerance and dignity and peace.
And of how the horizon
was brightening a little,
as though a new day were being born.
- A lot of us guys
got packages at Christmas.
You know what was in mine?
Stuffed dates.
Stuffed dates in Africa
under the date palms.
Can you beat that?
One good thing about Christmas,
you may get homesick, and we did,
but you also get Christmas dinner.
♪ You'll get no promotion
this side of the ocean ♪
♪ So cheer up my lads bless them all ♪
♪ Bless them all ♪
♪ The long and the short and the tall ♪
♪ Bless all the sergeants and WO1s ♪
♪ Bless all the Corporals
and their only sons ♪
♪ We're saying goodbye to 'em all
and back to their billets they crawl ♪
♪ You'll get no promotion
this side of the ocean ♪
♪ So cheer up my lads bless them all ♪
Everybody fed well at Christmas.
Including the pets.
Along about now we began
to take notice of the kids.
First off they were kinda shy.
But Arab kids are no different
from the kids back home
when it comes to candy.
A lot of them look about half starved.
The Germans had picked the land clean.
So we gave half our milk
ration to the Red Cross,
they ladled it out.
Off-duty we just roamed around, looked.
And we saw some mighty strange sights.
We wondered what the
Moorish girls looked like
behind their veils.
Wondering was about as far as we got.
One Sunday.
The middle of January.
We were hanging around,
catching up on the news from home.
When we were roaded out for assembly.
They told us to polish our
brass and shine our leather.
Some of us said, what's the big idea?
Well, we found out.
And you coulda knocked
me over with a tank.
It was the prez himself.
Riding along in a jeep.
When we saw Mr. Churchill come
in, not puffing his cigar,
we knew something big was cooking.
- In
a small seaside hotel
at Casablanca, discussions began at once.
Their purpose, to design
the shape of victory
in Africa and beyond.
First, a meeting was arranged between
Generals de Gaulle and Giraud
who had succeeded Admiral Darlan,
assassinated a month earlier.
Out of the meeting was to grow the union
of a fighting French
who had never lost hope
and the French for whom
hope had been reborn.
Second, the united command
for the new Tunisian campaign
was created.
The Allied troops in the
area were now predominantly
British, but by common agreement,
General Eisenhower continued
in supreme command.
As his deputy commanders,
three British officers.
General Alexander on land,
Admiral Cunningham on sea,
Air Chief Marshal Tedder in the air.
Under them, British, American,
and French officers and men
serving side by side.
The whole scheme a dovetailing of command
unique in military campaigns.
Third, we fixed the terms
which would end the fighting.
Unconditional surrender.
Of all these decisions, our
Russian and Chinese allies
were kept fully informed.
The conference ended, Mr.
Churchill flew on to Tripoli
to greet the victorious Eighth Army.
And explain its vital part
in forthcoming events.
For the decisive hour was at hand.
Battle lines were drawn.
In the north stood the British First Army.
In the center, General
Giraud's French troops.
In the south, the Americans.
Further south, a small
group of fighting French
had completed its historic 1500 mile march
and taken up positions on the left flank
of the British Eighth Army
which faced the formidable Mareth Line.
Behind which barrier Rommel's army,
after its long retreat,
had entrenched itself.
Tunisia was gray with German troops.
15 full divisions.
No scratch troops these.
But battle-wise veterans of
Poland, France, the Balkans.
They, together with
seven Italian divisions,
were armed with the most
modern types of equipment,
including the newest fighters and bombers
of the German Luftwaffe.
The German orders were
hold Tunisia at all costs.
Keep control of the Mediterranean.
Rommel, standing behind
his Mareth Line,
saw that he must soon be faced
with an attack in the rear
from the Allied armies
along the Great Dorsal
as well as an assault by
the Eighth Army at Mareth.
He therefore struck first
in an endeavor to remove
the menace behind him.
On February the 14th, the blow was struck.
Heavy armored columns
burst out of Faid Pass
in the mountain barrier
and through into the valley beyond.
In the face of their onslaught,
Allied armor withdrew with heavy losses.
By the 21st, the enemy had forced his way
through the Kasserine Pass
and his armored columns were advancing
in a three-pronged thrust.
One main column aimed at Tebessa,
our supply base in southern Tunisia,
and another at Thala,
key town in our lines of communication.
Almost within sight of his objective,
he was halted.
American, British, and French forces
all stood immovable
against the final impact
and in counterattack broke it
while Allied airpower pounded Rommel's
lines of communication and supply.
The threat was ended.
Advancing past destroyed German armor,
we reoccupied Kasserine Pass
and by March the 17th,
the original battle lines
had been restored.
As soon as Rommel saw
that his westward thrust
was doomed, he made an
abortive attack south
against the Eighth Army.
The Germans unveiled the new Tiger tank.
The British, the new
17-pounder anti-tank gun.
52 Tiger tanks were left burning husks.
From then on the initiative was ours.
- Of
the various strategies
which might now be
employed against the enemy,
General Eisenhower chose
one which envisaged
the entire military situation
in terms of a cylinder.
The western wall, Allied land forces along
the Great Dorsal.
The northern and eastern,
Allied air and sea power
concentrated in the Mediterranean.
The seaports of Tunis
and Bizerte were to act
as the intake valve through
which those enemy troops
that escaped the
devastating attack of planes
and submarines based at Malta were to be
sucked into the cylinder.
At the bottom of the
cylinder stood the powerful
British Eighth Army
to serve as the piston
which, in its upward stroke,
would push the enemy into
an ever-smaller space.
Still in possession of the
enemy were certain high hills
to the west of Tunis and Bizerte.
Their capture was an essential
part of the entire strategy
for these hills were the spark plug
which, when the piston
had forced the enemy
into a state of high
compression, would explode
the combustible mass.
That was the final strategy.
To succeed, perfect
coordination would be necessary
between land, sea, and air forces.
The Northwest African Air Force
commanded by General Spaatz
was divided into five major groups
of which three were combat.
The Strategic Air Force
under General Jimmy Doolittle.
These were the big boys,
the long-range bombers,
pounding away at enemy bases and shipping.
The Coastal Air Force
under Air Marshal Lloyd.
Day and night fighters, these,
protecting ports and convoys.
And finally the Tactical Air Force,
a new conception of air power.
Developed by the British
in the Middle East.
All fighters and attack bombers,
British and American, were
placed under one command
so that we could strike
with the full force
of our flying artillery when and where
it would do the most good.
Air Marshal Cunningham,
in command of this group,
and General Alexander, in
command of all ground forces,
lived and worked side
by side in a tent camp
in the Tunisian mountains.
Theirs was a complete partnership
and in it lay the pattern
of ultimate victory.
By the middle of March, the stage was set.
The first move was up to
Air Marshal Cunningham.
In a continuous 24-hour assault,
the Mareth fortifications
were pounded from the air.
Then General Alexander gave
the signal for the piston
to begin its upward stroke.
Montgomery, looking ahead,
had planned the Mareth
battle three months before.
He would strike after a
barrage and in moonlight
as at El Alamein.
But simultaneously he
would begin an outflanking
movement on the left.
The frontal blow had to cross
a gorge, the Wadi Zig-Zaou.
And create a bridgehead
under cover of which
tanks and artillery could cross the Wadi
before the enemy's counterattack
in force could be made.
Three days before the
attack it rained heavily.
Next morning, our men were
holding on like bulldogs.
Only four tanks had got across.
But with these and their own arms,
our infantry kept the bridgehead intact.
The enemy, fearing another El Alamein,
now withdrew armor from other
sectors and threw it in.
Whilst this battle raged,
our outflanking left
hook by General Freyburg
and his New Zealanders, reinforced by
the First Armored
Division, was racing across
150 miles of desert towards El Hamma.
The blow was now struck by
50,000 men on the ground
and by bombers, fighters, and
tank busters from the air.
The Germans, pinned down by
the Northumbrians at Mareth,
moved their armor too late.
The New Zealanders,
thenceforth to be known
as the left hookers, drove through.
- The
Mareth Line had been turned.
The piston was on the move.
Its speed made possible by
the feats in road building
of the South African engineers.
Air and naval forces
shelled and bombed all along
the seawall.
Our fighters struck at
their transport planes,
still pouring men in
through the intake valve,
knocking them out of
the sky by the hundreds.
And on land, the British First Army
was a constant threat in the north
while in the center, the
French had attacked at Pichon
and further south the
Americans had broken through
to El Guettar and Maknassy.
Thus enforcing constant pressure all along
the land wall of the cylinder.
April 7th.
American patrols of light
tanks striking eastward
met patrols of the British
Eighth Army advancing northward.
- We got quite a bang
out of meeting these guys.
2,000 miles they'd come,
fighting all the way.
Yes sir, we got a real bang out of it.
These are the guys that broke
the back of the Afrika Korps.
- Still the piston
pushed relentlessly on.
April the 10th, Sfax.
April the 12th, Sousse.
And on April the 20th,
after exactly 30 days
of fighting and pursuit,
the Eighth Army had driven
the enemy into the hills
beyond Enfidaville.
And in its wake was a great homecoming.
- What got me was
watching those villagers
coming back.
Mostly on little donkeys
piled up with so much stuff
you'd wonder how they carried it.
It reminded me of the Bible somehow.
You know, the donkeys and the hills behind
and these folks, trekking home.
There was one old chap
spoke a bit of English
and he comes up to me and old Joe McAdams
and he says, "Thank you, thank
you, thank you, thank you."
And then he started shaking hands with us.
I thought he was never gonna let go.
And as we watched him going
down the hill, Joe says to me,
he says, "You know George, I had a buddy
"killed the other day and
I was pretty sore about it.
"But now all these poor devils coming home
"gives the whole thing
a kind of a meaning."
Well then when we went down to the village
it was just the same down there.
Little Jewish boys taking
off the yellow stars
they'd been made to wear
as if they was lepers.
And then our army doctors
attending to the women
and the youngsters just as if they was
on the panel back home.
I certainly felt less brown north.
I certainly did.
- The rapid
advance of the Eighth Army
had left the American divisions
at Maknassy and El Guettar
far behind the battle area.
General Alexander now switched
these divisions to the north.
This remarkable 200 mile march
across the heavy traffic
streams of the First Army's
lines of supply was
accomplished without once
interrupting the eastward flow.
And this in complete secrecy.
The piston had completed
its upward stroke.
The desired state of
enemy high compression
had been achieved.
Now to capture the spark plug,
the vital hills west of Tunis and Bizerte.
- This led
to a number of major battles
of which five were typical.
Hill 609, Longstop Hill, Goubellat Plain,
Djebel Mansour, and Takrouna.
The Eighth Army struck at Takrouna.
The French 19th Corps
attacked Djebel Mansour.
On the Goubellat Plain, the
British Sixth Armored Division
striking towards Tunis had drawn upon it
most of the enemy's remaining armor.
In three days of struggle,
our main purpose was accomplished.
The drawing to this battlefield
of von Arnim's tanks and guns
and their destruction.
Meantime, the British
Seventy-Eighth Division
was pressing the attack on Longstop Hill.
For 12 days, the hills
echoed with gunfire.
Positions were taken, lost, and retaken.
When the German lines broke at last,
their dead lay in hundreds
unburied on the battlefields.
As our infantry went forward,
engineers and pioneers
built roads across the mountaintops
for vital supplies to reach them.
In 14 days they built 11 miles.
Meanwhile, further north,
the Americans had embarked on their phase
of the campaign.
This started with the assault on Hill 609.
Long-range artillery started the attack.
- Directions all batteries.
Left Eighth.
Baker.
- Baker.
- We took Hill 609.
There weren't as many of us guys
when we got to the top as
there'd been at the bottom.
We took it.
- Thus one
by one von Arnim's strongholds
in the mountains fell.
The Germans had been outfought;
now they were to be outwitted.
General Alexander knew their
fear of the Eighth Army
so he reinforced that fear
with heavy bombardments
and local attacks from Montgomery's front.
At the same time, he secretly transferred
the Fourth Indian
and the First and
Seventh Armored Divisions
from the Eighth to the
First Army in the north
whence the main attack was to come.
The spark plug was ours,
and we were now ready to
explode the combustible mass.
Now to pour on the power.
Now to give the apostles of power
an education in the use of it.
British and Americans in the air
with everything that could fly.
The British and Americans on the ground
with everything that could shoot.
French artillery.
French infantry.
The British navy.
All poured forth their concentrated fury.
This was blitz warfare such
as the inventors of the blitz
had never dreamed of.
The Nazis' challenge to the free world
to fight or surrender was being answered.
After only eight hours fighting,
the hard crust of German
resistance shattered.
Our armor crashed through.
The Americans blitzed
their way into Bizerte.
The British smashed
right through the center
to capture Tunis.
Then a British armored
column crashed across
the neck of Cape Blanc to Hammamet.
Another British column raced
around the tip of the cape
to prevent any evacuation.
The whole Axis mass was
split into four segments.
The end came quickly.
- By tens, by hundreds,
by thousands they came.
On foot.
In trucks.
And behind their bands.
The greatest mass surrender
of fully-equipped troops
in modern history.
We had lost nearly 70,000 men,
dead, wounded, and missing.
35,000 British, 18,000
Americans, 15,000 French.
But for every man we had lost,
the enemy lost five.
And at the end, 15 full divisions,
266,000 of their best
men, laid down their arms.
- No
Bataan this, no Crete,
no men riddled with disease
and shrunken with hunger,
fighting to the last, bare-handed.
Educated in the school for power,
they were quick to
recognize superior power,
and when they did, they quit, quit cold.
This is the end of the
Axis African adventure.
- After all
the racket, seems funny,
don't it Joe?
So quiet.
- Yeah.
- What's biting you, Joe?
- I dunno.
I can't helping thinking all the hard work
that went into those burnt-out tanks
and half-tracks and
aeroplanes, gone for nothing.
- Had to be done.
- Oh sure it did.
But still and all,
think of all the trucks
and automobiles and things
all that junk mighta been.
- I know.
Bloody shame.
- Just because he was told
that he was a superman.
- Well he never
figured things out for hisself.
Never argued the toss same as we do.
Too bad he didn't hear
some of our arguments
at the old Dog and Fox back home.
- You know I guess
that's the real difference
between us and them.
We argue the toss, as
you say, and they don't.
- Yeah, and when you don't argue
the toss anymore you
aren't half a man anymore.
- Right.
- You're just
a blooming tool, like a
spanner or a saw or a gimlet.
- Maybe they like it that way.
- Maybe they
do, but s'pose somebody
tried to use you or me like that, Joe.
S'pose somebody said, "Put
that fellow's eyes out,"
or "Turn a hosepipe on
that Jew or on that woman".
Would we do it?
- What do you think?
- You and me Joe, we
may not always think alike,
but we do think.
You and me and old Alphonse and the rest,
we certainly think alright.
- You know George, I got an idea.
Why can't we, after the war,
the same work gang I mean,
keep on swinging together?
What couldn't we do?
- You mean build
more houses than ever was?
- Yeah, that's it.
- And ships, thousands of ships.
- Right.
- And food so's
nobody be hungry no more.
- Yeah, building things up
instead of blowing things up.
Like, I don't know,
like dams in the desert
and roads through the jungles,
maybe bridges across all the oceans.
We could do it, I bet you!
- Yeah, do all the jobs
that wants doing, and knock the block off
anybody who wants to start another war.
And bring the smiles
back to the kids' faces
all over the world.
- Boy what a job.
- But just now Joe
it's the same rough road.
The same road you and me have just come.
The same bloody hard road,
and for quite a while yet.
- Boy oh boy, what a job.
Bringing back the smiles to kids' faces.
Vive la France!
- Africa is free.
- And Europe,
that much nearer freedom.
Liberating hosts are on the wing.