www.caseway.ai is for people
who can’t afford a lawyer
You got to hammer faster.
Get going.
Yeah, hurry up there.
I'm getting hungry.
Come on Roy!
Hey somebody is shooting.
No.
Why they are too, I heard 'em.
Sounds like it's over at the dam.
Let's get going.
What's that?
Yes follow my orders.
Use all the forces necessary.
I'll have the sheriff over
from his ranch right away.
Hello operator, give me 21, Pottingham.
- Hello.
- Hello, sheriff.
There's another fight at the dam.
Those rangers have broken loose again.
Well, why don't you give 'em
some water then?
That's our business.
Are you going to do your duty,
or do we have to kill some of those fools?
All right I'll get out there
as soon as I can.
I bet that's Lamb and Hank,
they wasn't fooling when they said
they's gonna raid the dam.
I guess you're right.
Hey, there's a couple more
of them company guards.
Yeah, well I'll stop them.
You might as well surrender.
Hold it!
- All right, keep 'em up.
- Hey yo!
Come on, let's get to that bell.
Hey, wait a minute!
There's some horsemen coming down there.
It's probably the sheriff.
You got to go home and
take care of that arm,
I'll get the water to you.
Alright, Roy.
Well we got to work fast.
Blow the lock and open that valve.
You boys, turn them guards loose.
Wait a minute Sheriff! Hold it.
Don't you point that gun at me, Roy.
I don't know how else to
keep your waiting sheriff.
The old timers getting this
water need it mighty bad.
I'm gonna have to take you in.
Take it easy, we'll go
along to jail peaceably
as soon as we get enough water,
but not until we do.
I said take it easy.
That's a fine way for you to act.
Roy Rogers, son of a congressman,
fighting the water company.
If my dad had lived there wouldn't
have been any water company.
Just the same, the law is the law,
and property's property.
And there goes ours.
100 feet a second.
Make them turn off that water.
Hey! I dropped the valve wheel!
You fellas got any other way
of shutting that water off?
There ain't another valve wheel
like that in the whole county.
All right, Roy. There ain't no use
in you holding us here any longer.
Don't be downhearted, Sheriff.
You won't be so chipper when
you get behind bars, Roy.
Behind jail bars, huh? Well
Sheriff, that reminds me.
Send my mail to the county jail
Send my mail to
the county jail.
Tell our saddle-pals tonight,
if they've got some news to write...
Send my mail to the county jail.
Say goodbye to your favorite gal.
Say goodbye to your special gal.
We're supposed to have a date
but we reckon we'll be late.
Say goodbye to your favorite gal.
Tonight when coyotes howl,
and mountain lions prowl.
I'll be watching the moon
and countin' the stars.
Can't you see me looking
through the jail house bars?
Pass the hat and collect our bails,
if they ask you where I am,
say I'm in an awful jam.
Send that bail to the county jail.
Ho, ho, whoo!
Whoa, Nelly, whoa!
Stop ringing that bell.
What do you want on here?
I said stop ringing that bell.
Huh?
I thought you said you was
coming along peaceably?
Well I did, but Nelly didn't.
Once a fire horse, always a fire
horse, Doug.
You mean every time that
knot-head hears a bell
- she's going to act like that?
- That's right.
She ain't with me. I'll give her
a
good sellin' 'fore anybody finds
out about them tricks.
Stop this noise! You're
disturbing the meeting.
Well, Roy, my boy I'm glad to see you.
- How are you mayor?
- Fine.
I see you brought all your boys
in town for the meeting. Come
right in boys.
They can't. They're under
arrest.
What's the charge? I
don't want Roy to miss the meeting.
He's charged with
trespassing on the water
company's property, fighting
with the guards and stealing their water.
Hooray for Roy!
Silence!
If that's the case, I'll hold court
right here and now. I'm sorry boys,
but I'll have to punish you.
I fine you for disturbing the
peace. $1 in court cost.
No, no, you can pay the clerk
later. Come
on, you're late already.
Before we criticize the
congressman who has represented
us so bravely for two terms in
Washington,
let us remember... Let us
remember!
Just a moment. Just a moment!
Wait a minute. Pardon me, but
there happens to be a meeting
going on here.
I'm sorry, Richard.
As the son of a former
congressman, you should have
more respect for a public
meeting. It seems to me that you
should get here in time in order
to be posted.
Well, I'm already posted.
Oh, you are, are you?
Sure, Mayor Biggs started out by
talking about high water rates.
Then he showed a picture of
Congressman Scully and denounced
him plenty. And Mayor Jenkins of
Hilton City, founded in 1848,
said the water was free then,
that it ought to be free now. And
it was time the federal
government did something about
it by gosh. And you as manager
of the water company said I'd like
to lower the water rates, but
we're losing money.
Marvelous Roy, marvelous.
Practically word for word. But
- how did you know?
- That's easy. You've
all been saying the same thing
since my dad was Congressman.
Wait a minute. I still have the
floor. As I was saying before I
was so rudely interrupted. Let
me remind you that Congressman
Scully is the only man among us
fitted to go to Washington and
- represent...
- The Great Western Water and Power Company.
The Great Western...
I mean...
I still say that the best man
fitted to represent you in
Washington is the man whose face
you see on that poster!
The people's friend?
Folks, I
just held court for a man who
really deserves that title.
He was brought before me for
fighting the water company. Now,
are we going to send him to
jail? Shall we send him to
Washington like we did his father?
Yes!
Take a wire. Mr. John B.
Fairbanks, president the Great
Western Water and Power Company,
Washington, DC.
Look at that, Admiral.
- Rogers for Congressman. He hasn't a chance.
- What do you know
about Western politics? You're a
Washington attorney. Why with
beating up our men and stealing
our water, that boy is a hero to
those people out there.
They'll forget all about it
before election
day. See no cause for alarm.
You don't, eh? Then you need
glasses. We're
leaving for Saintsville tonight
with Congressman Scully.
But dad, we can't leave tonight.
Oh, we're just mailing out the
- invitation to our reception.
- Postpone
it. Postpone it!?
- Helo, Richard.
- How do you do, Mr. Pembley?
You know my daughter. Mr.
Andrews and Congressman Scully
- of course.
- Richard.
Welcome home, congressman. Your
campaign is on
full blast.
Campaign my butt. Posters never
elected anybody.
- A lot of votes he'll get that way.
- You bet your life he will.
Don't forget there's plenty of
Women Voters. What do you think
Eleanor? Would you vote for him?
He has a nice voice.
- And that's all he's got.
- He can't campaign without advertising. He
has no money for that.
I know this western country and
I promise to the throne... I'll
prove when he's elected that my
steers are never wrong.
- You don't need money for advertising if you have brains.
- Brains?
Yes, brains.
Get ahold of Rogers, tell him I want
to see him at my hotel. Important and
- personal business.
- Yes, sir.
- Now Roy, you're doing fine.
- Thanks.
I'm out of a campaign manager.
Well, everything's under control.
- Hi.
- Hello Rogers, can I speak to you privately for a
minute?
Anything you have to say to me
is all right for my friends to
hear.
- Hello, boys.
- Hi.- Hello, friend. -Hi-
Very funny, boys. Very funny.
Mr. Fairbanks would like
to see you over at his hotel. He
said it was very important and
personal.
Sure. Why not? Tell him I'll be
over tomorrow.
Okay.
I bet that guy, Fairbanks is
scared. He's gonna talk turkey,
you'll see.
Maybe.
Anyway, it'll give me a chance
to tell him what I think
of him. And that'll be plenty.
50% cut on water rate. Don't
make me laugh. Mr. Fairbanks.
Let me tell you something, you
cuckoo. You run this country into
the ground long enough. 60%. Now
I didn't come here to haggle Mr.
Fairbanks. It's 75% or nothing.
So, I'm driving a hard bargain
am I? Well, that's too bad.
Here's my last word. If you
don't knuckle down, we'll run
you and your cutthroat crowd
right out of business.
Bravo! Bravissimo!
Keep going partner, you got him
on the ropes.
Hello. I don't generally talk
myself like this. I was just
sort of rehearsing.
And doing very well, too. But
how about putting a little more
emphasis on your exit line?
Because I presume that is your
exit line?
Probably. Old man Fairbanks is
apt to kick me out when I get
that far.
I gather you're not exactly an
admirer of John Fairbanks. He's
plenty tough.
Probably the kind of a man who
beats his wife.
He does. I heard he schlags his
daughter on occasion, then she
probably deserves it though.
No doubt she does. If I'm
elected, I'll get federal water
for this state if I have to hog tie
every politician in Washington.
- Good for you. I hope you're elected.
- Thanks.
Well, I guess I'll be going.
I'm going that way too, we could
ride along together.
Swell.
What is your daughter doing with Rogers?
How do I know?
Well, I don't like it.
Tell that to Eleanor and see
what happens.
Gentlemen, may I present Mr.
Rogers. This is Tom Andrews. Mr.
Richard, your worthy opponent,
Congressman Scully. Oh, and my
father, Mr. Fairbanks.
- Your father?
- Yes.
Oh, by the way, dad, Mr. Rogers
considers you a skinflint, a
penny pinching pirate, and what was that?
Sounds to me like you just about
covered the territory.
Beat it rat. We want to talk
business.
Well, that reminds me Fairbanks.
Is it true you beat your
daughter?
No.
But it's a darn good idea.
Well, sit down. You seem to have
a lot of
common sense, Rogers. I think
you're the man I need to look
after some of my business interests.
That would mean giving
- up my campaign for Congress, wouldn't it?
- Well, yes, it
would. But your salary would be
three times as much as you'd
make as a congressman.
Thanks, but I have a family
weakness for going to
Washington. I'd like to see some
of the places my dad told me
about.
- Would four times as much money interest you?
- No, nor 10
- times as much.
- You might regret passing up a mighty good
proposition young man.
Now I'll make you one. Either
your company cuts water rates to the
bone or I'll get federal control
of water in the state when I go to
Washington.
When you go to Washington? Well,
you're not there yet Mr.
Rogers.
Imagine a congressman dressed like that.
Take off those
- clothes.
- Well, what's the matter with them?
This for one thing...-Say-
...and this!
- What?
- Even those
pretty spats. The voters want a
man who represents them, not a
city dude. You're going to be a
man of the people. You're going
to wear western clothes and ride a horse.
- A horse? -Yes!
- I can't ride!
- You will ride!
- What?!
Whoa, Nelly!
Just now pray, the people are
giving Congressman
Scully a grand ovation. Just
listen to all those cheers. You
know, two days ago, I thought that
Rogers was their choice. But now
it looks like a landslide for
Scully. And now ladies and
gentlemen, you will hear from
your candidate for reelection,
William P Scully.
Friends,
my friends, it's great to get
into these clothes again. I can
feel a horse beneath me once more.
Ladies and gentlemen,
here's a round by round
description that Scully's
saddled horse has just run away
with him and Congressman
Roy Rogers has rescued him from
the horse trough.
What a mess we're in now with
Rogers elected. Let a hick
- rancher out-smart us.
- You insisted that I ride a horse. I
- told you I...
- Shut up and get out of here.- Well if that's the way
- you feel about it.
- Get out before I lose my temper! -
No you don't.
Whipped by a smart-aleck yoke.
How does it feel to take a licking dad?
Licking? This is only round one.
We're leaving for Washington
too. Buck
him there at every turn.
- Here's a letter for you, Roy.
- Thanks.
You know any cow-hands that uses
perfume?
Thanks for the send-off, folks.
And don't worry, I'm gonna see that
that water bill goes through
pronto. I figure I'll be back in
about a week.
Now me, being Congressman Roy
Rogers' here personal execute,
even Secretary, I promise that if Roy...
Hey! Wait for me... wait for me!
Congressman Marlowe's office
please. Good morning, Congressman
Rogers calling Congressman Marlowe
again. Oh, when do you expect him?
Yes, please have him call me
back... I don't know what Marlowe has
an office for, he's never in it.
Well, he's got to have some
place where you can find out
- that he ain't in. -Anything important?
- Oh, no, just the usual 4011
constitutions wanting to know
where that federal water is you
- promised them.
- So do I.- Ain't there nobody else you can see about
that water bill?
No, sir. Marlowe is the money
man and he has to be seen.
Huh? Who's that from, Marlowe?
No, it's not even signed. Let's
say, listen to this. If you want to
meet Congressman Marlowe, join
the foxhunt near his country
estate next Saturday.
Hey, sounds like a jailbreak.
We've got to get out of here.
Them bloodhounds is vicious.
The hunt's started. Come on.
All them hound dogs against
one poor little fox. Ain't no justice.
Tally ho!
Hey, that horse is running away with her!
Are you alright?
What in the world do you think
you're doing?
I thought your horse was running away.
No, but the fox is. I'd have won
his brush in another 100 yards if
you hadn't played Lochinvar.
I'm awful sorry.
Doesn't matter.
So tell me,
how's this stinking Congressman
making out in Washington?
Not so good. The only luck that
I had so far is meeting you
again. I've tried to follow your
advice about seeing Congressman
- Marlowe, but he dodges me like a wild mustang.
- My advice? - Nobody
else I know uses perfumed
writing paper. It's mighty nice of you
to show me the ropes, even if
Marlowe is too busy crashing society.
Not crashing society.
Congressman Marlowe gave this fox
hunt because he wanted a
political favor from one of his
guests.
Like a medicine man putting on a
show to get his customers in
line to buy.
Yes, that's it.
You see, here in Washington
that's the trick to get the
ear of the right person.
Well I couldn't very well give a foxhunt.
No, no, but you can give a party.
Well, who'd come?
Oh... look!
Get these loud dogs outta here!
Go away!
Hey, what's happening?
Go on away! Get out of here.
Shew! Get on away from here. Get
outta here!
Get these hound dogs out of here.
Dad, you remember Mr. Rogers,
don't you?
What? Oh yeah, sure. How do you
do?
Oh, Congressman Marlowe, this is
Congressman Rogers.
- I'm glad to know you, Mr. Rogers.
- How you do, Congressman?
I'd like a few words with you. I
want to ask you to...
Oh, um, to be
his guest next Tuesday evening
at the Fairview Country
Club. All of you... Mr. Rogers
is giving a surprise party.
Doesn't that sound exciting? Oh,
well, you'll be there won't you
Senator Wilson?
- Certainly Ms. Fairbanks.
- And no party would be complete
without you and Mrs. Marlowe,
Congressman.
A surprise party, of course
we'll come, won't we Edward?
Why, I think it's perfectly sweet
of Mr. Rogers to invite us all.
Don't you dear?
I don't know anything about
these eastern parties.
Well, make it Western.
Swell, I'll send a wire to Larry
and the boys.
All join
hands, circle down south. Another
little moonshine in your mouth.
You're home and grant field back to
the lady in the lead. The man to your left
and right. Your partner right and
left in a hurry up boys. Don't be
slow, the chicken in the bedpan
picking up dough. To meet your
partner, all's floor. Meet your honey
and pat her on the head. And she
don't like biscuit, feed her
cornbread and chew on tobacco
and squirt it on the wall. And
swing that gal, lean and tall.
Rogers certainly has a peculiar
idea of entertainment.
Yes, isn't it quaint?
I don't know when I've had such
a good time.
So far, folks, all you've seen
of ranch life has been a lot of
fun. But there's another side I
want you to see. And that's a
surprise I promised.
These first scenes are the way
our ranches
used to look. Every range had
dress like that in the summer.
When winter covered it was snow.
We had plenty of that good
alfalfa for feed. We flattened
our beef on that green. Every
valley and every canyon had a
stream of running water. Then
nature took a handle. Every year
we had less and less rain. This is
what happened: dry spells, drought
and dust storms. After the dust
storm, this is what is left.
That's Glen Saunders' house, he
lost his two children from dust
pneumonia. That's Luke Chalmers
place. He just gave up, moved
away and never even stopped to dig
up his equipment... Those cattle
are Dave Peters'; he lost 150 head
which meant every cent he owned.
All of this tragedy and ruin ladies and
gentlemen, because of lack of
water. In times like these, folks
just naturally turn to prayer.
Dust... dust...
Dust in the skies. Dust on the trail. Dust
in my eyes. Dust. Can't see the sun can't
find my way. The dust has won. The cattle
and the sheep put down to sleep, better
realize their pain. The vultures in
the sky know the time is nigh, will
- it fly away? Away?
- Oh no...
We were the home
where the buffalo roam, where
the deer and the antelope play.
Here was a place where
the cattle would graze. The corn
and alfalfa once waved. Where are
the ranches, the cow hunting
crowd? What has become of the
range? Out of the blue came a
threatening load causing this awful change.
Oh lord we're in your range and
sunshine. Dust. Dust.
Must it be? Can it be? Can it
be?
Oh lord have mercy on poor me.
- We've got to get busy on that bill, Marlowe.
- I agree with you.
Rather unethical, but very
effective. I'm going west in
about 10 days and I'll get you
relief if I find those
conditions existing. Do you have
my support on
that water bill too, Rogers?
Dad, it looks as though you've
lost round two.
- You needn't rub it in. Think it's funny do you?
- Fairbanks,
I had no idea that conditions in
your state were so serious.
They aren't. I'll take you out
there and show you that Rogers
- misrepresented things.
- I hope you're right for your own good.
After all, it's your water company that's
on the spot, you know...
Young woman, you helped stage
this entertainment. You realize it
might ruin my water company? Oh,
one of your water companies.
- Are you in love with this cowboy?
- Oh,
I don't know.
Well, you tell him from me that
he's in for the dog-gone-dest
- licking he ever had.
- Oh, yes, I'll
tell him, but he won't believe me.
Say, that was swell. And the way
you was calling them ranchers out
by their names you even had me
fooled. You'd think they's neighbors
of ours.
Oh, weren't they?
No, those pictures were taken in
another state, Eleanor. I
couldn't get a newsreel of our
own dust storms.
Tell me my friend, is your
middle name Barnum by any tune?
Oh no. His middle name's James.
Oh, I see after Jesse. Oh no.
Leaving soon Mr. Fairbanks
Yes. I'll wipe that grin off
your face yet.
Nevermind, you were grand.
With your help. When will I see
you? I'm leaving for the West
pretty soon.
Now what a coincidence. So are
we... Oh yes daddy, I'm coming...
And so I take great pleasure in
introducing to you the most
important man who ever hit old Sage
County. And the only man who can
give us federal control of
water. Congressman Marlowe.
Citizens, as chairman of the
Appropriations Committee, I am
authorized to announce that we
are here to make a study of the
drought conditions in this
section... Better cover up fast
Congressman, before the
newspapers get wind of this.
However, we have already learned
that conditions are not as bad as
we were led to believe. And we
find that existing utilities are
quite adequate for the present.
Now that is, all thank you for
your kind welcome.
I said your methods were
unethical but I underrated you.
You're nothing but a cheap
trickster. I admit the film I
showed you wasn't taken in this
state. But conditions here are
just as bad, if not worse. As far
as I'm concerned young man, that
bill never will be passed.
I'll back you up on that, Marlowe.
I had a right to trick you when
the lives of these folks depend
on water. If you don't think
this country is dry, just look it
- over and see for yourself.
- Sorry, but I'm not interested.
I came all this way to see the
conditions of the dust storm. Don't
be silly dear, there aren't any.
I told you I'd wipe that smile
off your face.
You've had very capable help. I
should have known better than to
trust a woman with a secret.
Edward, I'm so hot and dusty.
Perhaps we'd better not go any
farther after all.
Sorry dear, but it's too late
now. You wanted to go, so I
promised Mr. Fairbanks I'd meet
him at the dam.
But Edward...
- Get out, all of you. Set the drivers, we're taking the cars.
- This is an
outrage, I'm Congressman Marlowe.
You can't leave us out here on foot!
You can use our horses.
Well, there's only one thing to
do. Take the horses and ride back to
Sageville.
My mercy, what a dry country. I
don't see how people live here.
It wasn't always like this. Wouldn't
be now if the farmers had water.
Evidently you still believe in
motion pictures. Listen. Listen,
there must be a camp ahead. And
that means a drink of water.
The old Chuck Wagon's rhythm
starts about noon. Then you'll
hear those cow hen sipping soup
very soon. And there's music,
music to the rhythm, music to
the rhythm of the range.
- Nice of you to drop in.
- Hello, Congressman.- Don't tell me
you're making an official tour
of the drought section after all.
We're making a tour, all right,
but not an official one.
We were held up by bandits and
they took our cars away from us
and made us ride these horrible,
bumpy horses.
We'll tell you about that later.
Right now we are too thirsty to
- talk.
- That's too bad.
Yeah, ain't that tough.
We only got about a pint of
water left. We done
give it to the horses.
You see, we didn't expect to have
any visitors. You mean you can't even
give us a drink. Well, we might
find enough for the ladies but
the men will have to wait till
we reach Larkins place tomorrow.
Get the canteen Frog. You folks
just make yourself at home. Boys
go saddle the horses and fix
them a bite to eat.
That's all there is.
Much farther to this lock and ranch?
- Not so much, just the other side of the river.
- River.
Did you say River?
- Where?
- Right there. Used to run bank full when everybody got the
water from it.
- But what happened?
- Your company built the dam and dried it
- up.
- Dried it up? Well everything seems dried up in this country.
That's what I tried to tell you.
Looks like a water wagon. Hey
stop!
Can we have some water?
I reckon you can, mister.
- Right around behind.
- Come on.
For Mrs. Marlowe. Marlowe?
Ain't you the Congressman that
was going to do so much for us
- ranchers and then change your mind?
- Yes, but
then conditions were
misrepresented and...
You sure fixed it so I got to
haul water 20 Miles. None of you
get a drop.
Listen, that's not right.
We've got to have water.
Why didn't you help me
- stop him?
- He has no right...
As much right as your company
had to refuse the ranchers water.
Look, what is it? A cyclone?
- It's a dust storm and it's coming our way.
- What do we do? - You saw
pictures of one, Mr. Marlowe.
Now you're gonna see the real thing.
We've got to find shelter, come on!
Get the horses in the shed.
- Howdy, Roy.
- Where's your husband, Mrs. Larkin?
He's going to town for grub, he
ought to be back pretty soon.
Have you any water?
We have some now Mister, but the
cistern will be full of dust
after the storm.
Cistern? I thought you said the
Great Western pipeline ran
through here. Well, I had been
informed...
Of course, the water company
wouldn't misinform anybody would
- it?
- And
the pump's in the corner right
over there. Help yourselves.
Anything we got here you're welcome to.
You have dust pneumonia out here Rogers?
No, you needn't worry. We don't
even have dust storms here. They
haave them in another state.
You needn't rub it in.
I can't stand much more of this!
I thought you were the one who
wanted to see the dust storm?
Oh!
Folks, the dust storm's over.
What do we owe you, Mrs. Larkin?
Nay, sakes Mister. You don't owe
me nothing. Roy paid me yesterday.
But we weren't here yesterday.
So the whole thing was a frame up, eh?
Everything but the dust storm.
That was an added attraction.
- You mean the hold up and the water wagon were planned?
- That's
right.
I see nothing to laugh at.
Young man, I want to shake you
by the hand. Your methods are
not only unethical, they're
phenomenal. But don't you worry.
- I'll okay that water bill.
- Thanks!
- Roy, the ranchers are headed to blow up the dam!
- Rogers,
- if they blast that damn, they lose government support.
- I'll
stop them!
Find Congressman Marlowe. Head
for the dam and step on it.
All right, Richars, thanks for
the warning. We'll teach them a
lesson.
- There they are!
- Be smart and take cover!
Turn back! Get behind that hill!
- Now that stopped them.
- We better stay
- here a while and make sure.
- Yeah. Now that stopped them. - We better stay
Did you see them?
Yes, we turned them back. They've
gone over the hill. Man get back
here and get down.
They'll never get to the dam
now. Unhook that horse...
All we got to
do is turn that dynamite right
loose on that hill. Blast the dicks and
the water can't get to the dam.
Get that wagon in the road.
That's the dynamite wagon.
- We've got to get out of here.
- No, wait.
- "I'm out to win a bigger stake and you can show me how."
- If you
want a happy life, just say yes and be
the wife of Rogers, the congressman!
Hey! Halt!
www.caseway.ai is for people
who can’t afford a lawyer