Downloaded from
YTS.MX
[upbeat music]
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
OWEN DAYBRIGHT
(VOICEOVER): I got a story
to tell, yarn about cow
country and cowpunchers,
cattle and men.
I was working for the Strobie
Ranch, learning my trade.
Trade a worn leather saddle
blisters and branding irons.
Trade with some song,
some fun, some blood.
It was as good a job
as a man could ask for.
Lonely sometimes,
cold, so much distance,
you thought you'd
never get back.
But for me, a young
kid, it was a fine time.
Memories are mostly good.
You're up there on
top of the world
where the air was
clear and thin.
The only sound was
the wind in the pines.
We were in the business
of growing beef.
Always moving the cattle,
looking for new feed.
They were those new
bald-faced Herefords,
not like the longhorns.
Wild and spooky, but
friendly critters.
Gentle as a dog.
Seasons melted away peaceful,
from spring to summer,
fall, then winter.
Cows had to look out for
themselves in the snow.
The winter drift.
As soon as a man on
horseback could get around,
they'd go out and
locate the cattle,
spot them for the
spring roundup.
They'd come back from the
winter drift, cold and worn out.
Our foreman was Owen Daybright.
He knew what he was doing.
We all liked him.
And there was his foster
brother, Lee Strobie.
Their father owned the ranch.
The night they got
back, the trouble began.
Well, look who's turned up?
Hi, Cal.
People still drink whisky?
Hi, Lee.
Be down to my shoes.
That's comes from working for
someone you've known too long,
Lee.
See my wife this winter?
Jen coming down a couple
of times with your old man.
How did Arch look?
Oh, just fair, I'd say.
Cold weather always
seems to bother him.
How did Jen look?
Way to find that out is go
home and see for yourself.
Can I borrow your razor, Cal?
I don't want to scare.
her in the back.
Keeping you busy, doc?
The night--
CAL: I've been trying to get
him all day for that girl
that used to work
at the Eaton house.
LEE STROBIE: Lily?
CAL: I wouldn't know her name.
What's her trouble, doc?
Oh, small variety.
About that big.
Arrived a couple of
hours ago, they tell me.
You wouldn't go?
That's right.
I don't take calls like this
until I hear from the father.
That isn't likely.
[music playing]
There's a rifle
on you, cowboy.
Get down and walk over here
so I can see who you are.
Get down now!
Owen, is that you?
Yeah.
Put that gun down.
He's a friend.
[music playing]
What are you doing here?
Helping.
Nobody else would come.
So I heard.
How's Lee?
Wanting to see you.
I'll be home as
soon as she's asleep.
Who is he?
Her brother Dick
Fasken from out of town.
He spent the day
looking for the man.
Lily all right?
You've got company, Lily.
[soft music]
[baby crying]
Hello, Owen.
Lily.
[music playing]
Princess!
And beautiful.
Good color too.
[sighs] Yes.
The doctor wouldn't come.
Jen came instead.
Don't you even
think about it, Lily.
Not now.
I'm really pretty lucky, Owen.
I couldn't face up going back
to the restaurant to work.
Mrs. Burke offered us
work out at her place
when I'm ready for it.
We're grateful to.
Sounds queer to say it here now,
but he'll have a good life on.
I'm sure he will, Lily.
I'm sure he will.
[music playing]
JEN STROBIE: Coffee?
Thanks.
[music playing]
You've seen me before, Owen.
There's been a change.
Somebody's washed your face
and got you a new dress.
Arch.
And a tub in my own room.
I bathe every day now.
It's an improvement.
How was the winter?
Well, we stayed alive and
we kept the cattle alive.
We were snowed
in at the ranch.
Didn't see our nearest
neighbor in nearly five weeks.
We missed you, Owen.
[music playing]
I brought Lily some grub.
Owen, who was it?
Good night, Jen.
[music playing]
HUB FASKEN: Hold on a minute.
You live in these parts?
Around here.
Who's the father?
That'll be Lily's
business, wouldn't it?
I'll find out for sure.
I'll find out if it
takes me a lifetime.
Fine.
It's a nice country to live in.
[music playing]
Who was that?
Owen Daybright.
Your husband's foster
brother, ain't he?
That's right.
How much?
$500.
He brought this food too.
Why?
You're wrong.
He's good.
And there's no one else
around here like him.
[music playing]
And again.
Hey, he keeps
his aces a kicker.
And he draws to it
every time, three times.
Mr. Kicker.
It's a game of chance, boys.
We'll play again sometime.
[indistinct chatter]
I ran your errand.
Thanks, Owen.
It's paid for.
You paid for a coat.
I appreciate it.
This isn't the first
time you saved my hide.
Why don't you grow up, boy?
Oh, kid, it happens.
I sleep good.
Your wife was there.
She have any idea?
Hmm-hm!
[sighs] It happened
before I met Jen.
Even so, she wouldn't
understand it.
You know what she's like.
Why should I know
what she's like?
Oh, that's right, you don't.
She's what all the
others weren't.
She's everything I
ever wanted for myself.
It's been a long time.
Let's get back to the ranch.
Stand where you're
at, Daybright.
You, move away.
You brought Lily $500.
That's right.
Don't she need it?
Not that kind.
That wasn't grub money.
It was get out of town money.
I'll ask you one time.
Was it yours?
Point that gun to the
floor, son, and turn around.
There'll be other times.
You're a conclusion
jumper, my friend.
I don't like them.
CON ALVIS: Quit it, Owen.
I'll handle this myself, Con.
Not as long as I'm sheriff.
All right, Con.
You've scared me twice tonight.
Next time you point a
gun at me, shoot it.
[music playing]
Well, welcome home, boy.
How are you?
You look fit, son.
How are you, Owen?
- Good.
How's the leg?
Got the misery.
Same as every
winter for 20 years.
- Evening, boys.
- Hello, Mr. Willoughby.
Hello, Mr. Willoughby.
Thought you might want
some hot coffee, Arch.
Well, thank you,
Mr. Willoughby.
Same old dishwater?
You don't want any, huh?
Oh, no, I'm just kidding.
Then watch your language.
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: How's
the bad stomach?
Owen, some days, I doubt
if I'll make it till sundown.
Well, why don't you stop
eating your own cooking?
Oh, I'm stuck here.
Can't help it.
Arch, these cigars
ain't from Pittsburgh.
Kansas City.
Lee sure isn't
going downhill fast.
How'd it go?
Ask the foreman.
I just took orders.
You got a wife
waiting for you.
I haven't forgotten.
I'll look in on her.
Night.
ARCH STROBIE: Good night, son.
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: Night, Lee.
Boy looks trim.
Nobody could have
worked harder this winter.
He's got a lot to make up for.
He'll come around.
Maybe Jen has something
to do with it.
Anyway, he can
handle it alone now.
Well, it sounds like
you're giving notice, Owen.
Well, he's married now.
Jen's a fine daughter for you.
I'm just crowding the place.
Oh, if you're not
comfortable here--
I'm not forgetting, Arch.
You've done everything you
could to make me belong.
When you picked me up, I was
just a stray off, foul-mouthed,
and flea-bitten 15 years ago.
It's been a long
time, a good time.
Now, it's time for me to go.
You really mean it?
Well, I want to push
on try my own wings.
ARCH STROBIE: Owen,
how do I say this?
When I took you, it was for Lee.
I couldn't get around outside
and raise my own boys,
so I picked you to do it for me.
What I didn't know then
was that I needed you too.
I need you now.
All right, Arch.
I was just hitting you
for a raise anyhow.
Night.
ARCH STROBIE: Night.
Jen, will you hurry
up and come on out?
I don't know why
all of a sudden you
can't get dressed
in front of me.
JEN STROBIE: I'll be
two more minutes, Lee.
The top of all winter,
that's a long time.
JEN STROBIE: I know
that better than you.
You mean you've missed me?
Of course.
[music playing]
You're beautiful.
Do you think so, Lee?
Do you really mean it?
The first time I saw
you, you were wearing
a pair of split britches.
And you helped me come out of
the back country, you and Arch.
This is the second Sunday
dress I ever owned, Lee.
First, when I wore to my
mother's funeral and then
I used it to bury my father.
And I branded.
And now, you're
a lady of fashion.
Well, that's what it says
in "Godey's Lady's Book."
[music playing]
I haven't done many
smart things in my life,
but marrying you is one of them.
We'll be happy.
Nothing can stop us, honey.
[music playing]
Checking his last call.
[upbeat music]
Where have you been?
Good morning, Mr. Willoughby.
Good morning, Owen.
Nice to see a real
man back again.
Well, thanks, Mr. Willoughby.
Morning, real man.
That nasty old
noise wake you up
or were you waiting for the
sun to hit your dimpled cheeks?
[laughter]
You sandy men haven't
lost any sleep in so long.
You've forgotten what
you go to bed for.
Mr. Willoughby, it's
better than the foreman.
[laughter]
All right.
I slept late.
Why is it, though, when a man's
out on the range all by himself
and eating his own
cooking, he looks forward
to getting up for breakfast?
Well, of course,
when he's home,
he lies there and has to
figure out if it's worth
the belly getting up for.
You, uh, ain't done the
contract with the south.
Any time my cooking gets so bad
that you've got to go hungry,
I could give you your
time before you know
what gave you the miseries.
That's telling
them, Mr. Willoughby.
No offense, sir.
Mr. Willoughby, I
accept your apology.
I do.
Sure there's no hard feelings.
How about another cup of coffee?
Sure.
|- I have to move you, sheriff.
Taking the census again?
Yeah.
I like to see who
comes and who goes.
[train beeping]
Hello, Hub.
I got your letter a week ago.
You're an uncle.
How's Lily?
She's doing all right.
Who's that?
It's her brothers.
[train beeping]
Brothers, aren't you?
I'm going to kill a
man before I leave here.
Anybody special or would I do?
I don't know the
man yet, but I will.
Keep an eye on me.
The name's Fasken.
Where are the horses?
Behind the depot.
[music playing]
Fasken boys were
looking for Lily.
I heard she'd been
taken in and given
a home by a widowed
woman named Mrs.
Burke who owned a ranch nearby.
[music playing]
[door knock, music playing]
We're looking for Lily.
We're her brothers.
I didn't know Lily
had this much family.
Never said a word.
Maybe she's ashamed of us.
Not Lily.
She's not that kind.
She's in her room.
[music playing]
I'll call her.
- Never mind.
Is the room here?
[music playing]
So you sent for him?
For reasons over there.
[music playing]
I didn't ask for you to come.
I didn't ask for you
to come, do you hear?
We're this kind of family.
We don't waste any
love on each other.
We fought amongst ourselves.
We've even shot at each other.
We got one tie.
We have blood relations.
Go away, Hub.
Go away.
Do you want to marry
Owen Daybright, Lily?
I don't want him
and I don't want you.
I'll manage myself
without any help.
[baby cooing, music playing]
Daybright knows something.
If he can't talk when
I get through with him,
he'll write the
name with his feet.
[music playing, baby cooing]
[chirping, clucking]
[neighing violently]
Ride him.
Scratch him, boy.
[neighing]
Hey, Mr. Kicker,
you dropped something.
What he means now
is that fourth ace.
You know that's no
way to break a horse.
Now, get on him and ride
him like you were taught.
[clucking]
[brays]
[indistinct yelling]
MAN: Hold 'em!
[cheers]
That's it, boy!
Hang on.
Did you have to use that whip?
Oh, it's touchy.
Stop being such a farmer.
A good whipping
never hurt any filly.
Come on.
All those
authorizations come in?
All but Mrs. Burke's.
I'll ride over.
Cut me a horse, you.
And one for yourself.
Hi, Lily.
Hello, Owen.
Hello, Hewie.
Good day, ma'am.
How do you feel?
Feel good.
Why?
I just wondered.
[moos]
That's mighty good to hear.
Well, thank you.
Well, I just ask because--
because you look
real fine, Lily.
Just fine.
Had your breakfast?
Mr. Willoughby's best.
I can outcook him
with my two arms broken.
Business first, then
we'll trade recipes.
Write me a note authorizing
us to cut out your cattle
at roundup and bring them home.
Been wondering if
I was being snubbed.
The only thing could
snub you is a mountain.
I'll get paper and pen.
Thanks, Owen.
But I'm all right again.
You look fine, Lily.
Yeah, that's what Hewie says.
I wish I could find
the words to thank
you for bringing me the money.
But I can't.
Well, don't try.
I hate to see you
fronting for Lee.
Well, I'm--
I'm thinking of Arch.
I know.
You go on standing
in front of Lee,
protecting him, letting
his dirt rub off on you.
Maybe.
I'm thinking of Jen.
And all she's done for me.
That's why I can't tell.
So we'll both keep it a secret.
Lily, it ain't right.
Owen, I've been afraid of a
lot of things this past winter.
What people would say about me.
How I'd raise a baby.
How I'd keep us both alive.
Well, now it's happened.
I'm not afraid anymore.
I'm not glad it happened.
I was wrong, I know that.
I'm just not afraid
of living anymore.
[sinister music]
Daybright here?
In the house.
Start walking to
that shed over there.
Why?
You won't get hurt if you
don't break for the house.
Go on.
What is this?
You bought your ticket.
You'll see.
Sit down.
[pounds]
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: Goodbye, ladies.
See you after rondo.
HUB FASKEN: Daybright.
So you sent for big brother.
Why don't I remind
myself to pack
a gun when I visit my neighbor?
That money was
yours, Daybright.
Oh, it was, huh?
That baby's going
to need a name.
Yours.
[crashes]
You want another helping?
Well, come on.
Pull the trigger.
First you shoot me, and
then you got to shoot Hewie,
because he saw you.
Then you'll have to shoot
Mrs. Burke and your own sister
because they'll see you.
Well, come on.
Pull the trigger!
Quit it, Owen.
He'll do it!
I don't think
he's got the guts.
[clangs]
Put that down.
That gun down, big brother.
You won't use it.
And I'll break your
arm if you keep it.
[scuffle sounds]
[grunts]
[shatters]
Get up, Hub!
Dick, put that gun down.
Well go ahead.
Cut down on her.
She's only your sister.
You got to kill somebody.
Be careful who you
poke in the belly.
Hewie, that's enough.
Whatever you say, Lily.
All right, Hub.
This is still our dance.
No, Owen!
Haven't I made enough
trouble for myself?
For my baby?
You want to add murder, too?
Go on, take them to the sheriff.
If you need someone to sign
the complaint, I'll do it.
All right, Lily.
You got the right.
Come on.
Go on.
I hear the Lazy W's for sale.
How much?
They're asking
$35,000 cash for it.
That reminds me, you
owe me some money.
I generally do, Arch.
Joe Benson told me
yesterday at the bank
that you were overdrawn.
Don't worry.
The old man covered it for you.
Thanks.
Still trying to fill
those inside straights, huh?
I always forget
what you told me.
Hey.
Have you been
spending our money?
You know, that's
a joint account.
How much did he draw?
$500.
Said you drew it in gold.
[chuckles]
Makes a nice clink
in the pocket a bit.
I'll see you later.
I've got to get ready for work.
Is there some cream there?
Jam?
Excuse me.
You don't believe that
story about the $500, do you?
No, I don't.
Well, look, honey,
there's certain things
that you've got to understand.
I don't like Arch knowing
everything that's going on.
Yes.
And I can understand your
not wanting him to know.
That $500 is a lot of money.
I didn't like taking it
out of the account, either.
But well, it-- it was
for a lady's honor.
Stop it, Lee.
Stop it.
I know all about you and Lily.
Oh.
I know what you're thinking.
Oh, honey.
That $500 was to help Owen out.
I don't want Arch or anybody
else to know about it.
But now that the
fat's in the fire,
I guess I'll have to
tell you the truth.
You see, Owen got in
trouble with Lilly.
And the least I could
do to help him was--
well, you know how
much I think of Owen.
The least I could do to help
him was to give him the money.
You're a liar.
You're a mean,
contemptible liar.
[smacks]
Hey.
You're all alike.
You and Arch and Lee.
You could be a little--
You're all a pack of liars.
Well, I'm through.
I'm leaving.
Slow down to a walk.
That $500 you gave Lily.
I know where it came from.
Now, wait a minute, Jen.
Protecting him again.
Fighting with Lily's brothers.
You've known all about her
and Lee from the start.
It's just a lot of talk.
I'd pay it no mind.
Owen.
Why can't you be your own man?
These
misunderstandings happen.
All married people have a
quarrel once in a while,
I guess.
I hate him.
Jen.
You and I are kind
of in the same fix.
Arch is all the family we got.
With him, we belong
to something.
Shouldn't we give him back
a little bit in return?
Owen, what can I do?
What can I do?
Stay around.
For Arch.
All right.
But all I'll do is stay.
[clanging]
Morning, Mr. Ticker.
Hey.
Hey, Owen.
What fell on you?
A couple of hard cases.
Brothers.
Name of Fasken.
Fasken?
Two of them?
Lily's clan is gathering.
Do they know?
They're still alive.
Do you they'll find out?
Well, not for a while.
The Sheriff's got
them locked up.
How long?
Week.
He'll try again.
We'll tell them.
Well, Lily might.
She doesn't want to, but
they're kind of hard to handle.
Well, what do I do?
You wouldn't do it.
Let's see.
There's only one way.
Take Jen and get out.
Stay away from here.
Begin all over again.
Because you've worn
this place out and all
your friends are with it.
Sure.
It's either that or get shot.
With me gone,
the ranch is yours.
[smacks]
Nobody can stop
you thinking that.
But don't say it to me.
All right?
Picture?
One day, you definitely
want once too often.
Now, you boys are going
out on a big round-up.
If you ride with a short
or underfed string,
you might as well be afoot.
Now here's a horse
you can have cheap.
A real Saturday
afternoon bargain.
Sound of limb and body.
Rune, he's been
burned so often,
he looks like a brand book.
Just give me an offer.
I make out about 12 brands.
What do you say, Lee?
Oh, I'd say a
good round dozen.
That means 12
unhappy customers.
Oh, Rune.
I pass.
- All right.
Anybody else?
Take him away.
- Put him out to grass.
- Let's see him fed.
All right, all right.
I got the best tow horses
this side of K State.
I got a pedigree
comes with this one.
Name your price.
Well, this looks more like it.
Here, let me check.
Open the gate, boys.
[neighs]
[wheezing]
Good horse, Rune.
Only trouble is he's a whistler.
He leaks air!
Call that a leak?
[laughs]
Owen, you know better than
to ride a horse that way
through town on Saturday.
That team of Wilsons took
after you and almost ran away.
Well, don't blame me.
Blame the horse.
He whistles, and
everything follows.
[laughter]
Hey, hold on.
I ain't through yet!
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: You sure are.
Can't you hold
your breath a minute?
Put him away.
Oh.
[laughter]
I wonder if the Fasken
boys are comfortable.
Who cares?
Let's go look in on them.
Pick me up later
at the saloon.
Oh, Owen.
How are things?
Quiet, Con.
Getting ready for a round-up.
Tough job.
How'd you like to sign on?
30 a month in meals.
Oh, not me.
I sleep in a soft
bed every night.
Help you?
I'm bringing the
Fasken some cookies.
Better push them into
their cage with a stick.
They're a troublesome pair.
One inside?
Might be catching.
I understand the judge
gave you boys a week.
Judge?
A stinking justice of the peace.
Well maybe next time we
can arrange a real judge.
Claw, hammer, coat, and all.
Next time will be different.
Look.
Lily's doing all right
without you boys.
Why don't you leave her alone?
I don't see no Mrs.
in front of her name.
Well, that happens.
Not to a sister of ours.
All right, act like
jackasses and you'll
be treated like them.
When you get out,
the Sheriff will
put you on the train himself.
Show your faces after
that and you'll be back,
right here, for six months.
You scare me.
Just say the
word and I'll order
some curtains for this place.
By the way, I've decided
to go on a round-up with you.
Not so easy, Lee.
There's some things and some
people you can't run away from.
Well, I'll think about
that when I get back.
You ought to
think about it now.
Hold it.
There's a Cheyenne in that tree.
[gunshot]
Got him.
Hey, that thing
jumped in your hand.
How did you get it so fast?
Practice, son.
You ought to try it.
Haven't got the time.
Lee, the old Cheyenne camp.
Yeah.
Remember the night we rolled
the rocks down on them?
I remember when Arch caught
us and the licking we got.
I'd sooner been
scarred by the Cheyennes.
A couple of fool kids
playing with Indians.
We had our times, didn't we?
[gunshots]
Good morning, Arch.
Good morning, Lee.
Good morning.
Phew.
I'm getting too fat.
Well, did you buy
any horses yesterday?
Well, Obie Rune tried to push
a wind-broke gelding off on us,
but Owen caught him up.
Obie never quits trying.
All right, you know I got
the thinking last night.
Come on.
Tell me why you were walking.
Come on, walk with me.
Walk with me.
What started me thinking
was that I saw a horse
in Rune's that I'd like to own.
And I'd begun talking
about price before I
remembered that I'm strapped.
Buy him.
We always got money
for a good horse.
Oh, I don't care
about the horse.
I probably own too many.
No, Arch.
The point is that a man my age
with a wife with a father who
owns half the county
has to hold off
buying a horse because his
wages won't let him afford it.
Oh, listen, Lee.
You haven't been
able to trust me.
Now that's in the past, Arch.
You were right, but it's done.
I've been a good hand
this winter, haven't I?
Yes, you have.
You think I know
the cattle business?
Maybe not as well
as you or Owen,
but well enough to
make money at it, huh?
Of course, if you need
more money, you'll get it.
Let me tell you.
When you came home
with Jen last fall,
I thought it was another
piece of foolishness
like all the others.
It wasn't.
Jen was something else.
Something right.
That's why I put you on
the top hand's wages.
I'll raise them.
Oh, that's too easy.
Either I'm your son,
entitled to your trust
with the ranch or
anything else, or I'm not.
It's one or the other.
What do you want?
I want to be part
owner of the ranch, Arch.
I want a share in it.
I'm married and
settled down now.
Why, here is where I'll live
and raise my kids and die.
Here's where I'll help take
over from you when you've--
had enough of the business.
I'm not just camping
here for wages.
I'm here to stay, Arch.
I'm your son.
I've been thinking
about it, too.
More than you.
A lot more than you.
You're my own blood.
Man has a debt to that.
Oh, you got no
debt to me, Arch.
Yeah?
It's an old one.
Began the day your mother died.
You got it coming to you, Lee.
For doing without her.
Well, we've
managed, old timer.
Beginning to feel like one.
I'll go in town tomorrow
and draw up the papers.
From now on, half
the ranch is yours.
Oh.
My half will go
to Owen when I die.
[chuckles]
Hamilton.
Flying H.
Neely.
Dog Iron.
Sans.
Lazy S Double-O.
Frank Peter.
Box Pitchfork.
Frank Martin.
Let's see.
Box F.
Double F.
That's right, Double F.
What are you carrying
them in your head for?
Well, you got 40
different brands.
The biggest shuffle
you ever saw.
We'll have to move fast.
Talk to you a minute, Owen?
Sure.
Go ahead, Hewie.
I was back up in the
mountains yesterday
looking for the
last of the horses.
Well, we finished
the tally this morning.
They're all in.
There was a small jag
of our cattle up there.
Brands are still
haired over, but I
could tell that it was ours.
Couldn't stop because I was
trying to turn the horses in.
By the time we got them headed
downhill, I was miles away.
Do you want to
pick them up today?
Well, I aimed to this morning.
They're gone.
They've probably been rounded
up by the other crew already.
Nope, they was
drove the other way.
Did you trail 'em?
As far as I could.
Let's go try again, Hewie.
I'll come with you.
Dust up and get my gun, Hewie.
Better get Owen's, too.
Take a look at this shoe.
You see the two clocks on the
inside, how it's built up?
This rider signed
his name for us.
Two horses and four steers.
These tracks go
straight for a while.
Got dark on me here
and I turned back.
Good place to cross.
If they want to cross.
You think like
a cattle rustler.
Let's look on the other side.
[splashing]
Only one horse came
out of the water here.
I was right, this
horse is a decoy.
They either went
up or down stream.
Hewie, you look below.
Yeah.
There ain't even been
a horse down this way.
There has been here.
And they've been driving
some steers ahead of them.
Here's where they come out.
It's Herb Backett's place.
Yeah.
Let's go over and have a look.
Here he comes.
Two of them.
You looking for something?
Four steers.
Well, they ain't in
that watering trough.
Their ears would stick up.
Come here, mean.
Notice that core.
They built up
inside of that shoe.
Who owns the horse
that wears them?
Never seen it before.
There's another one.
It's fresh.
[creaks]
What about it, Herb?
What about what?
Whoever rode that horse drove
four of our steers in here.
Look, if you see your
steers here, you can talk.
If not, I ain't accountable.
Get on your horse
and get out of here.
Everybody figure you
butchered their beef
and buried the hides,
but I can't prove it.
So I'm going to do
the next best thing.
I'm going to show you what
you buy into every time I
track our cattle here.
[gunshot]
[heavy breathing]
I always heard you were a pretty
good saloon fighter, Herb.
How are you without
a bottle or a knife?
[fight sounds]
[crashes]
Now we're going to take
four of your steers.
You licked him.
Why go to jail for
stealing his cattle?
You talking as
the new half owner?
You got a round-up to go to.
So have I. How are we going
to make it if we're in jail?
You coming, Hewie?
You're still foreman.
You're going to keep me
from going to the Sheriff?
Think back aways, Herb.
Did I put a gun on you?
Did I shoot the knife
out of your hand?
Am I driving off your steers?
I got no part of this.
He's your foreman.
Sad, but true.
Put a good price
on your beef, Herb.
You can't buy me off.
Don't try.
It wasn't a $250
beating, was it?
All right.
It's a deal.
But I ain't done with him yet.
Long as I can look down a gun
barrel, I ain't done with him.
Come on into town with me.
I'll get you the money.
I can't sit a horse
till I get this hand fixed
and get a drink.
[cheerful music]
Ain't you dancing
tonight, son?
I'm drinking tonight,
Mr. Willoughby.
Careful that applejack
don't put your lights out.
Seen Owen?
Start bleeding again.
Jen took him to the house.
Too tight?
The tighter, the better.
You seem to be getting
a lot of trouble lately.
Trouble?
You don't have to, you know.
You can stop them from
saying those things
about you and Lily.
Oh, I don't mind.
I happen to like Lily.
There.
Here, let me help you.
Thanks, Jen.
Owen.
You can't make it up
to Lily by yourself.
If Lee was half a man and--
I want to see Jen alone.
Wait, Owen.
Stay.
What do you want?
I'm leaving in
the morning, honey.
Big round-up.
I'll be gone a long time.
I know that.
Well, I've got to
say goodbye, don't I?
Well, goodbye, then.
Oh, no.
Not like that.
Not anymore.
Leave me alone.
Oh.
It's easy enough to lock one man
out as long as there's somebody
else to take his place, huh?
You're drunk, Lee.
Drunk enough to see double.
To see you here with Jen!
JEN STROBIE: I'm sorry
you had to see that.
I wish I could help you.
Just knowing
you're around helps.
There are things
I'd like to say.
What would you say, Owen?
I'd say I haven't
got the right to help.
I'd say it's too bad.
[thrilling music]
[knocks]
What do you want?
I want to talk to you.
How's the hand?
Still sore.
Sit down.
Still sore, huh?
I guess you don't have
much love for Daybright.
Man's time will come.
I hear the Fasken boys are
getting out of jail soon.
So I hear.
And they'll still
be looking for Papa.
I got them figured.
Daybright will be dead
in another few days.
No.
He'll be gone.
The round-up?
That ain't going to be
hard for him to find.
Oh, a couple of saddle tramps
like them would be picked
up in no time at round-up.
In order for them
to join, they'll
have to have a letter
of authorization
from some well-known brand.
Like yours, say.
Daybright'll try
to keep them out.
Sure he will, if they try
to join the Western Division.
But if they ride to the Eastern
Division, present your letter,
they can get in.
I'll be with the Eastern.
Likely his wagon captain.
East and West Divisions
meet, don't they,
to finish up the roundup?
Yeah.
To finish up.
You know, Herb, I should have
made that check much bigger.
That was a bad beating you took.
Yeah.
An awful beating.
Jones, Western.
Hewie, you're with me.
Stu Miller, Western.
Orv, you're Eastern.
Hung over?
LEE STROBIE: I feel fine.
How'd you make out
with Backett yesterday?
I bought the steers.
Good price?
$250.
Just for cattle?
Yeah.
I've decided to take
your advice, Owen.
I'm getting out of the
country after this round-up.
You, starting all over again?
Working for a living?
Yeah, just like that.
What about Jen?
I'll send for
her when I'm ready.
She'll join me.
NARRATOR: Was a nice
morning the day we left.
The sun warm on your shoulders.
But we didn't feel good.
This time, there was
something under your wishbone
that said we were in for grief.
Seems like they
were just coming
home from the winter drift.
We turn around,
they're off again.
How do you feel about
another month with me?
Scare you?
You'll wait for
him alone this time.
What's wrong, Jen?
Something to do with Lee?
I can't talk about it, Arch.
Sounds final.
It is final.
I was going to leave
without telling you.
Where are you, Jen?
Can't I help you?
You can't always
make it up for him.
I always have, till now.
That's part of the trouble.
Look, maybe it's my fault. Maybe
it never could have worked.
I'm restless here.
I've been alone so
long, I'm used to it.
We've never lied
to each other.
We don't have to start now.
Are you running away from
Owen because he loves you?
You're a good woman, Jen.
Your life should be
rich and peaceful.
But if you run away
from it now, you
will spend what's left with
bitter memories of the house.
Wait till they get back.
That's something
like what Owen said.
It's good advice, Jen.
NARRATOR: The spring
round-up is a cow hunt.
In the winter, they drift.
The aim is to get them
back to the home range.
Besides that,
there's the calves.
Make a tally, brand,
crop, and dehorn.
I was with Owen in
the Western Division.
We worked hard, and
the hours were long.
You didn't measure
time by the day,
but by the greening
of the grass.
It was all planned well and
the work went even smooth.
[ringing]
Get on.
- What about our guns?
- Get inside.
I'll throw them
in the back platform
after the train starts.
You were going to
kill a man, remember?
I ain't through yet.
- Next visit?
- That's right.
Now I'm worried.
[honks]
[horn blows]
Sheriff tell you to stay out?
What do you want?
Being neighborly.
Help you find the man you're
looking for, Daybright.
Why do you care?
I run a business.
It's the business
of moving cattle
fast over long distances.
Mostly in rainy
weather and at night.
Daybright bothers me.
Well, why don't you
level on him, then?
That shouldn't bother
a man like you.
And hang?
No.
I'm looking for someone to
shoot him who's got a right to.
You found him.
Here's the setup.
Daybright's on round-up.
I can get you into it legally.
Once you're there, you'll
have no trouble finding him.
Go on.
When this train hits
the top of Bench Grade,
it'll be slowed to a walk.
We get off there.
I got three horses waiting.
Daybright would sure
be surprised to see us.
Yeah.
Come on, here we are.
[sinister music]
NARRATOR: On the other
side of the mountain,
Lee was with the
Eastern Division.
Orv.
Cut out all of our brand.
It's local.
Turn them over to
Mr. Jenkins here.
Right.
Get out too far.
[cattle mooing]
[mooing]
Lee!
Referee that brand.
- I read O bar.
- I take it back.
It looked like mine.
- Satisfied?
Satisfied.
He's yours, Jenkins.
What brand?
O bar.
See that pair with a
pack horse behind Hardison?
They brought this.
Claim to represent
an outfit near you.
Yeah.
They're from our part.
Know these two riders?
Yeah I've seen them.
All right, I'll
assign to your wagon.
No, no.
Some of the boys
having a very friendly
feeling for that brand.
Well, if they're wrong ones,
I'll send them whistling.
Well, you can't do that.
They got a right to their stock.
We'll keep a close look out
of the stuff they cut out.
Meanwhile, assign
them to another wagon.
Somebody who doesn't know 'em.
I don't want them around me.
Well, that's fair enough.
NARRATOR: In Lee's division,
work was the same as ours.
They'd make the combings,
snake them out of the draws,
gather them, push them
toward the middle.
Hey.
First of our stock we've seen.
Yeah, they really wintered.
Heavier than anything
on the home range.
Yeah.
Looks like a bonus
for all hands.
Arch, you'll be a rich man.
So will you.
You're a partner now, ain't you?
That's right.
I was forgetting.
Well, I got a half of
summer's work laid out.
I'm heading for
Texas to restock.
How are you going to
get your beef from Texas
all the way home to Montana?
Yeah, by the time
you buy your herd,
Kansas will come up with
some new kind of fever
and quarantine you out.
If you move to New Mexico,
the same thing will happen.
I reckon you'll just have
to stay put in Texas,
and that's no life.
Now, son, you must
have heard of railroads.
I'm just going to lock my
herd up in airtight boxcars,
put a bag of that clean
Texas air in each car,
and unload in Montana.
[laughs]
Sir, my name is Strobie.
I don't think I got your name.
Oh, Dave Allard.
I gathered you're
sending your crew back
to Montana with your
strays while you
head for Texas to restock.
That's right.
Well, I can save
you the trouble.
I'll have 3,000 double
wintered steers for sale
at the end of round-up.
[whistles]
In good shape?
You're picking
them up every day.
Look at them.
They've got our brand.
What price?
14.
Laid down at Wet
Mountain Meadow.
14.
You just made a deal.
I'll have to find the
nearest telegraph station.
And it'll take a few days till
I can cover a check for $42,000.
That's all right.
[sweeping music]
Here's some hot coffee.
Well, thanks, Mr. Willoughby.
Why don't I save
my money and buy
a nice warm store I can sit in?
I've seen them stores.
They're drafty.
Beats washing away.
Sure does.
Come on in out of
the weather, friend.
What are you, East
or West Division?
West.
Name's Allard.
Daybright.
Thanks.
I needed this.
I need a horse, too.
I wanted to ride
on through tonight.
Mine's beat.
Hewie, get the man a horse.
Where are you headed for?
I left the East
Division for a few days.
I'm looking for a telegraph.
Missed it in the rain, huh?
Man can miss anything in this.
I don't know whether
I'm drowned or not.
[chuckles]
Well, there's a
telegraph at our meeting
place, the Wet Mountain Meadow.
Hewie, change the man's saddle
while he finishes his coffee.
Say, is that your brand?
That's right.
I just bought your herd.
That's why I was
looking for a telegraph,
to get my credit
and shape by wire.
Bought?
You must be mistaken, Mister.
Strobie own the brand?
Yeah.
That's it.
3,000 double winter steers
delivered at the meeting place.
Strobie's the owner, ain't he?
He can sell them?
There anything wrong?
Not a thing, friend.
Not a thing.
Well, thanks for everything.
I didn't think he could
plan that far ahead.
You reckon that's why Lee
made his bid to be partner?
That's why.
Sell the beef and get
the money to clear out.
What's he running from?
There's people he
has to answer to.
You always stand up
for him, don't you, Owen?
When you're loyal
to a man, Hewie,
you're loyal to
everything about him.
Even his faults.
Even his son.
It's funny what you
just said about Arch.
I've been feeling that way a
long time about somebody else.
About Lily.
[music playing]
[mooing]
NARRATOR: Day by day
and hour by hour,
the two divisions
pushed closer together.
So did Owen and Lee
for the showdown.
Only an hour away, Owen.
Eastern Division's
over the next hill.
Hiya, big fella.
Howdy, Orv.
How are you feeling?
Making too many
days in the saddle.
I'll take it.
Lee around?
Yeah.
Lee!
- Owen!
How'd it go?
How are you?
Oh, smooth as silk.
- What's your count?
- 2,000.
Yours?
Good.
A little over 1,000.
Well, that gives you Allard's
3,000 and some to spare.
Who's Allard?
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: Man you're
going to sell the herd to.
That's right, so it is.
It'd be news to Arch.
Especially since he's planning
to get down to the panhandle
and buy more stock.
The deal's going through.
How much does foreman make?
And I'm a partner.
I pay half your wages, remember.
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: You
give me half my orders?
Your orders are to keep
your nose out of my business.
And let you steal
Arch's cattle?
I'm a little hard
of hearing, Lee.
Day after tomorrow,
we start for home.
It's a big herd.
A man in the way
could get run over.
You better tell
it was a mistake.
To forget about it.
Your orders are still to keep
your nose out of my business.
Wait a minute, Lee.
I don't get it.
You don't think you can pull
this off with me around,
do you?
[mooing]
Let's get on with the cutting.
Owen.
Figure this one out.
I was working down by the river
past the last of the wagons.
Don't make sense.
- What?
Well, passing
one of the wagons,
I saw those two Faskens.
You're sure?
No mistake.
They've been on round-up.
Stood there talking with
the rest of the crew.
Needed a shave.
They've slept in
wet clothes like us.
Lee knew it and
didn't say anything.
And he isn't worried
like he should be.
Owen.
You know, I've been
thinking about that deal
I made with Dave Allard.
Yeah?
I admit, I made a mistake.
Like I always do when I haven't
got you around to steer me.
Well, I'm glad you
see the light, Lee.
Yeah.
Well, I better get
down to the depot
and stop Allard before he gets
too involved in that deal.
Fine, you go ahead.
Will you come with me?
I'm pretty busy here.
Well, it'll be much more
convincing with you around.
All right, I'll
tell Mead we're going.
Lee and I are going
over to the telegraph.
We won't be long.
All right.
[music playing]
Remember now, we don't
blast till Daybright
gets to that boulder.
Yeah, I'll remember.
Looks like this is our
last round-up together, Owen.
Oh, I tried to pull a fast
one on you by grabbing that
Allard deal, but I couldn't.
So I'm going anyway.
Just like I told you I would.
Fine.
I'm leaving you to win
right down the line, Owen.
I'm leaving everything.
Arch.
The ranch.
Jen.
You.
It's yours.
The works.
You sure you
thought this out good?
You've been trying
to tell me for years
how to do the right thing.
You gave me the straight line
about getting away from here
and beginning all over again.
I just kind of hate
to do it, that's all.
Maybe it's because, well, we've
had a lot of fun together.
We have at that.
Remember that time in
Kansas City when Arch took
us to the cattlers' convention?
Yeah.
I played cards
with the big Texan.
Yeah, man.
You beat him in five
cold poker draws.
Right.
That's when I found out
what good a kicker was.
Yeah, we sure had a
lot of good times, Lee.
That's what I'll miss.
I'll miss 'em, too.
No matter how old you
get, there's that part
of growing up you never forget.
I'm glad you said that, Owenn.
I'll remember that
when I'm gone from you.
Now.
[gunshot]
[gunfire]
[distant gunshot]
Where's Owen?
Went with Lee over
to the telegraph.
You hear that?
Somebody's in trouble.
Take some men and go see.
[gunfire]
Go around the other side.
Try to sneak up behind him.
I'll cover you.
[gunshot]
[splashes]
OWEN DAYBRIGHT: Lee!
I'm taking you in, Lee.
We're going to settle up.
Not a chance.
We're going to face Arch
and tell him the whole truth.
For once.
Come on out.
You're forgetting.
I still got my kicker.
I always could
outdraw you, Owen.
I'll spot you that, but
it won't change anything.
Come on out.
Or do I have to
come in and get you?
[gunshot]
[splashes]
That's the whole story, Arch.
All of it.
It was in front of
me for years, Owen.
I refused to see it.
I lied to myself.
You lied to make
it easier for me.
You didn't kill him, I did.
A long time ago.
The day I looked away
and hoped he'd change.
Hoped he'd work out.
I'll have to tell Jen.
I'd like to tell her myself.
[heroic music]