[Music]
[Applause]
in the jungles of New Guinea on the
barren shores of the aleutian in the
tropic heat of the Pacific island
in the sub-zero cold of the skies over
Germany
in Burma and Iceland the Philippines and
Iran France
in China and Italy American fighting
fighting over an area extending 7/8 of
the way around the world men from the
green hills of New England the sun-baked
claims of the Middle West the cotton
fields of the South the close-packed
streets of Manhattan Chicago the teeming
factories of Detroit Los Angeles the
endless stretching distances of the
Southwest men from the hills and from
the plain from the villages and from the
city bookkeeper soda jerks mechanics
college students rich man poor man
beggar man thief doctor
lawyer Richard chica
mal veteran fighting yet two years ago
many had never fired a gun or seen the
ocean or been off the ground fighting
for their country while half a world
away from it fighting for their country
and for more than their country fighting
for an idea the idea bigger than the
country without the idea the country
might have remained only a wilderness
without the country the idea might have
remained only a dream
[Music]
over the social 1607 Jamestown
1620 Plymouth Rock here was America the
sea the sky the Virgin continent
we came in search of freedom facing
unknown dangers rather than bend the
knee or bow to tyranny
[Music]
out of the native oak and pine we built
a house a church a watchtower we cleared
a field and there grew up a colony of
free citizens we carved new states out
of the green wilderness Virginia's
Massachusetts Rhode Island Carolina then
came the first test in the defense of
that Liberty 1775 Lexington our leaders
spoke our deepest needs colonists are by
the law of nature Freeborn
has indeed all men are it is the right
of the people to alter or abolish it and
to institute new government these are
the times that try men's souls but as
for me give me liberty or give me death
in the midst of battle it happened the
idea grew the idea took form something
new was expressed by men a new and
revolutionary doctrine the greatest
creative force in human relations all
men are created equal all men are
entitled to the blessings of life
liberty and the pursuit of happiness
that's the goal we set for ourselves
defeat meant hanging victory met a world
in which Americans rule themselves 1777
Valley Forge
we fought and froze suffered and died or
blocked for the future freedom of all
American a few of us doubted and despair
most of us pray and in do-it-all 1781
Yorktown now we were a free independent
nation the new idea had won its first
test now to pass it on to future America
the Constitution the sacred charter of
We the People the blood and sweat of We
the People the life liberty and
happiness of We the People the people
were to rule not some of the people not
the best people or the worst not the
rich people or the tour but we the
people all
[Applause]
[Music]
in this Brotherhood America was born one
nation indivisible with liberty and
justice for all
we began as 13 States along the Atlantic
seaboard we pushed across the
Alleghenies the Ohio River the
Mississippi the last power range of the
distant Rockies we carried freedom with
us
no aristocratic classes here no King no
Nobles or princes no state church no
courts no parasites no Divine Right of
man to rule man here humanity was making
a clean fresh start from scratch behind
us we left new States chips off the old
blocks welded together by freedom
[Music]
until finally we were one nation a land
of hope and opportunity that had arisen
out of a skeptical world a light was
shining freedom's light from every
country and every clime men saw that
light and turned their faces toward it
give me your tired your poor your
huddled masses yearning to breathe free
the wretched refuse of your teeming
Shore send these the homeless
tempest-tossed to me I lift my lamp
beside the Golden Door I strangers to
one another we came and built a country
and the country built us into Americans
the sweat of the men of old nations was
poured out to build anew the sweat of
our first settler to each the Scotch the
Dutch building the workshop of New
England of the Italian in the sulfur
mines of Louisiana of the Frenchmen and
the Swit in the vineyards of California
and New York State of the Dane the
Norwegian the Swede seeding the good
earth to make the Midwest bloom with
of the poll and the Welsh at the Negro
harvest in cotton in the hot southern
Sun
of the spaniard the first to roam the
great southwest of the Mexican in the
oil fields of Texas and on the ranches
of New Mexico of the Greek and the
Portuguese harvesting the crop the ocean
here of the German with his technical
skill of the Hungarian and the Russian
of the Irish the Slav and the Chinese
working side by side the spread of
Americans and a great nation was period
[Music]
[Applause]
yes the sweat of the men of All Nations
built America and the blood for the
blood of Americans has been freely
shared five times in our history have we
withstood the challenge to the idea that
made our nation the idea of equality for
all men life liberty and the pursuit of
happiness the idea that made us the
people we are let's take a look at
ourselves before we went into this war
well first of all we're are working
people on the land at the workbench at a
desk and we're an inventive people the
lightning-rod cotton gin
The Telegraph the Blessed anesthesia of
Ethan the rotary printing press the
telephone electric welding incandescent
lamp submarines steam turbine the motor
driven airplane the x-ray tube the
gyroscope compass the sewing machine
television all these and countless more
bear witness to our own benefits
[Music]
and this inventiveness and enterprise
plus our hard-won democratic ideal of a
greatest good for the greatest number
created for the average man the highest
standard of living in the world thirty
two and a half million registered
automobiles two-thirds of all the
automobiles there are in the entire
world we demand the highest standards
and sanitation purity of food medical
care our hospitals our models for the
world a copy we want the best for the
average man woman or child particularly
child we have reduced the hazard of
being born from men on we protect foster
and generally spoil the majority of our
children but it doesn't seem to hurt
them much they go to school all kinds of
schools the kindergarten public schools
private schools trade schools high
schools the twenty-five thousand high
school and to college in the last war
twenty percent of all the men on the
Armed Forces had been to high school or
college in this war sixty-three percent
there a great two weeks vacation people
[Music]
we hunt and we fish up north down south
back east out west when the season opens
we hunt and fish and we're a sports
loving people
[Applause]
[Music]
and we're probably the traveling is
nation in all history if we love to go
places we have the cards we have the
roads we have the scenery we don't need
passports but sometimes we need alibis
we sleep by the road we eat by the road
the fauna is enchanted and amazed by
what we like to put on our stomachs
[Music]
and we're a great joining people we join
clubs fraternities unions Federation
shove a blanket US will sign up radios
we have one in the living room the
bedroom like the bathroom in our cars in
our hands and up our sleeve does your
cigarette pace different lately
music we couldn't be without it
[Music]
the press yes it's the biggest but most
important it's the freest on earth over
12,000 newspapers of all shades of
opinion books on every conceivable
subject and more than 6,000 different
magazines not counting the commerce
churches we have every denomination
owner sixty million of us regularly
attempt and no one dares tell us which
one to go to we elect our own neighbors
to governess we believe in individual
enterprise and opportunity for men and
women alike we make mistakes we see the
results
we correct the mistakes we skyrocket
into false prosperities and then plummet
down into false needless depressions but
in spite of everything we never lose our
faith in the future we believe in the
future we build for the future yes we
build for the future and the future
always catches up with us before we're
done building we've developed something
new and have to start rebuilding that's
roughly the kind of people we are both
easygoing sentimental but underneath
passionately dedicated to the ideal our
forefathers passed on to us the liberty
and dignity of man we've made great
material profits but spiritually we're
still in the frontier days yet deep down
within us there is a great yearning for
peace and goodwill toward men somehow we
feel that if men turned their minds
toward the fields of peace as they have
toward the fields of Transportation
communication or aviation wars would
soon be as old fashioned as the horse
and buggy days we hate war we know that
in war it's the common man who does the
pain the suffering the dying we bend
over backwards to avoid it but there are
freedoms be endangered and will pay and
suffer and fight to the last man that is
the America that is the way of living
for which we fight today why
is that fight necessary did we want war
[Music]
in 1917 before most of you fighting men
were born our fathers fought the First
World War to make the world safe for
democracy for the common man they fought
a good fight and won it
there was to be no more war in their
time or their children's time faithful
to our treaty obligations we destroyed
much of our naval tonnage our army went
on a reducing diet until it became
little more than a skeleton for us war
was to be outlawed for us Europe was far
away and as for Asia well that was
really out of this world where
everything looked like it was torn from
the National Geographic yet in this
remote spot in Asia in 1931 while most
of you were playing ball in the sandlots
this war started without warning Japan
invaded Manchuria
[Music]
once again men who were peaceful became
the slaves of men who were violent in
Washington DC our Secretary of State
made a most vigorous protest the
American government does not intend to
recognize any situation treaty or
agreement which may be brought about by
means of aggression but we the people
haven't much time to think about
Manchuria we were wrestling with the
worst depression in our history some of
us were out of jobs some of us stood in
bread lines some of us suffered homemade
aggression some of us were choked to
death some of us had no place to go two
years later in 1933 while most of you
were graduating from high school we read
that a funny little man called Hitler
had come into power in Germany
[Music]
we heard that a thing called the Nazi
Party had taken over today we rule
Germany tomorrow the world what kind of
talk was there it must be only hot air
in 1935 about the time you had your
first date we read that strutting
Mussolini had attacked far-off ethiop
[Music]
the disease seem to be spreading so
Congress assembled to insulate us
against the growing friction of war we
want no war
we'll have no war save in defense of our
own people for our own honor toward this
end our chosen representatives passed
the Neutrality Act
no nation at war could buy manufactured
arms or munitions from the United States
1936 when you were running around in
jalopies we were disturbed by news from
Spain
in our newsreels we saw German and
Italian air forces and armies fighting
in Spain and wondered what they were
doing
[Music]
for the first time we saw great cities
squashed flat civilians bombed and
killed
in November 1936 the American Institute
of public opinion known as the Gallup
poll asked a representative
cross-section of American people if
another war develops in Europe should
America take part again No
ninety-five percent we the people had
spoken 19 out of 20 of us said include
us out to further insulate ourselves we
added a cash-and-carry amendment to the
Neutrality Act
not only wouldn't we sell munitions but
we wouldn't sell anything at all not
even a spool of thread
unless warring powers sent their own
ships and paid cash on the line
in 1937 the press services received a
flash from Asia
[Music]
yes the Jets were turning Asia into a
slaughterhouse but for us
Asia was still far away in September
1937 the Gallup poll asked us in the
present fight between Japan and China
are your sympathies with either side we
answered with China
43% with Japan 2 percent undecided 55
percent we hadn't made up our minds
about China our Neutrality Act barred
sales of armaments only to nations at
war Japanese had not declared war so we
went right on selling scrap iron and
aviation gasoline to Japan in March 1938
Hitler had not declared war either but
his goose-stepping army suddenly smashed
in and occupied all the soil of Austria
[Music]
six months later Hitler and his stooge
met the anxious democracies at Munich
Hitler promised peace in our time if
Britain and France would give him that
part of Czechoslovakia known as the
Sudetenland Britain and France gave him
that product Czechoslovakia hoping to
avert war
[Music]
and all we had his word peace in our
time
at home we began to hear strange
headlines we sat in our theatres
unbelieving as motion pictures exposed
Nazi espionage in America we must
destroy the change that ties the whole
misery of American politics together and
that chain is the United States
Constitution could these things really
be yes these subversive acts were
happening in real life everything German
American Bund organized for the purpose
of destroying us marched under our very
noses
[Music]
in our press we read the news from
abroad matches were spending millions on
in Germany to the teeth
[Music]
we read that the Tokyo diet was
appropriating tremendous sum converting
Japan into one vast emissions plan
we watched the supposedly poor have-nots
nations spend huge sums for armament and
we wondered why apparently they told us
why they had declared war on us long
before the shooting started
[Music]
Germans are no have unique great wound
was given by the grace of God
[Music]
when the people of these three nations
elected to follow their leaders death
incorporated they organized to smash
personal freedom equality of man
[Music]
freedom of speech
freedom of religion
organized to smash the very principles
which made us the people we are so in
December 1938 when the Gallup poll asked
us should the United States increase the
strength of its Army Navy and Air Force
we answered yes 85 percent it was time
to look to our defense
gentlemen this is the Military Affairs
Committee of the United States House of
Representatives meetings for the purpose
of considering national defense the Navy
is asking for an increase of 25 percent
an authorized naval tonnage in view of
the grave international situation
Congress reflecting the voice of the
people
appropriated the largest sum for
military use ever voted during peace in
American history we didn't dream that a
few years later it would look like
peanuts
on March 14 1939 Adolf Hitler broke the
pledge he made it Munich he took over
all the rest of Czechoslovakia there
would be no more peace in our time April
7 1939 as we here in America observed
good fighting
the picture was becoming clear the
conquering forces of violence were being
set loose in the world
well would they stop in a last desperate
effort to avert of world war President
Roosevelt has a neutral sent messages to
Hitler and Mussolini asking their
promise to respect the independence of
33 countries
Roosevelt's to add off hypnotists
message was a huge joke as he repeated
the names for jeering rack study Sweden
Tama needle of the Belgian Hospital Elam
protocol spawning despise least and Duke
support Romanian Jews loving Ruslan who
Guardian UK Iraq Arabians Union
Palestina
this was the only answer the president
Racine
on September the 1st 1939 the Nazi army
smashed into polar
[Music]
England and France had a treaty with
Poland would they act now at home we
listened in suspense
Prime Minister Chamberlain of Great
Britain gave the Nazi dictator a zero
hour for withdrawing his troops from
Poland that zero hour ends now at this
time we transfer you to London for an
important announcement by the British
prime minister up to the very last it
would have been quite possible to have
arranged a peaceful an honorable
settlement between Germany and Poland
that Hitler would not have it the
situation in which no word given by
Germany's ruler could be trusted and no
people or country could feel itself safe
to become intolerable now may God bless
you all and may he defend the right but
it is evil things that we should be
fighting against and against them I am
certain the rightful prevailing six
hours after Great Britain declared war
on Nazi Germany the Republic of France
followed all Frances in a mail storm of
activity the Maginot Line had already
opened fire on the German the sparring
is in world war has begun
at home we were asked what country do
you consider responsible for causing
this war Germany 82% we Americans had no
doubt who started it all so we began to
fear that this war was going to concern
us President Roosevelt called a special
session of Congress to reconsider the
embargo against selling the missions I
have asked the Congress to reassemble an
extraordinary session in order that it
may consider and act on changes in our
neutrality law the men of Congress
wrestled with their beliefs and our
futures they debated and they argued the
arms embargo is far too great a security
to American peace to permit its
surrender without a last ditch fight the
Embargo Act because it now stands is
one-sided and works entirely to the
advantage of one side therefore the
Embargo Act should be modified we the
people also debated and argued whether
we should sell arms and munitions when
the question was put to us as we had an
answer should we change the Neutrality
Act so we can sell war supplies yes 57%
shortly after our representatives
changed the Neutrality Act
we lifted the embargo on arms and
emissions now we would sell if purchases
would pay and take the stuff away in
their own ships American ships were
still barred from combat zones meanwhile
on the other side of the globe Japan was
busy trying to bomb shoot and terrorize
the Chinese into submission we began to
realize that if Japan conquered 400
million Chinese she might become so
strong as to run us right out of the
city
[Music]
you will remember that two years earlier
in September 1937 when we were asked in
the present fight between Japan and
China are your sympathies with either
side only 43% were with China most of us
were undecided in June 1939 when we were
asked the same question 74% said we were
with China now our minds were made up
when we loaded our scrap iron on
Japanese ships our citizens protested
let mister Atchison assist his Secretary
of State chemists the inside of the
story so until the middle of 1940 the
restriction of exports to Japan took the
form of moral embargoes of aeroplanes
and direct munitions then Congress
passed the Export Control Act and
increasing cut-offs of scrap iron
aviation gasoline and other strategic
items follow exports were curtailed to
the limit which those responsible for
our defense were willing to risk it was
a fearful responsibility on one side was
the possibility in fact the probability
that one day these materials might be
used against us on the other side was
the possibility in fact the probability
but to cut them off would provoke an
attack which we were not then prepared
to resist finally in the summer of 1941
as it became clear that Japan was
turning her back upon every possibility
of reconciliation and adjustment and was
determined upon her great gamble of
conquest all exports ceased on April 9th
1940 the leaders of Nazi Germany shifted
their war machine into high gear
they over ran into Denmark
they smashed into Norway on May the 10th
1940 they blitzed into Holland and
Belgium the Nazis are marching ahead at
the fastest speed a conquering army has
moved in all history all roads and
France had choked with slow-moving
masses of refugees Nazis took the dive
bombers are scraping and bombing
thousands of helpless women and children
mr. Kelton gone good evening everybody
tonight it seems clearly apparent that
the first great phase of the war in the
West has been won by Germany
the army of French and British has made
a valiant battle in its effort to
retreat to Dunkirk rather is summits
like Jack's at some part of it will be
about you it all fit lers mechanized
forces are racing toward Paris as French
resistance collapses on this 10th day of
June 1940 the hand held the dagger as
crooked into the back of its neighbor
this is William L Shire speaking from
the forest of pompeia we're at off
Hitler today is pending his armistice
terms to friends it is 3:15 p.m.
Adolphe Hitler's strides slowly toward
the little clearing I can see his face
this grave solemn yet brimming with
revenge off to one side is a large
statue of marshal foes Hitler does not
appear to see it now we see the French
walking down the Avenue led by General
huntzinger Hitler and the other German
leaders rise as the French enter general
title reads the preamble to the German
armistice terms this whole ceremony is
over in a quarter of an hour
[Music]
and lovers walk to be neat and I dodge
the same
the chorus
[Music]
no matter
conquering armies now stood on the
shores of the Atlantic the danger was
suddenly closed countries conquered by
the Nazis had possessions outside of
Europe some of these possessions are in
America with the Nazis demand the French
naval units at Martinique with the Nazis
move into the Dutch oil fields at
Curacao with the Nazi seized the French
naval base at the Carrefour invasion of
South America already in Brazil there
were over 1 million Germans who lived
exactly as they did in Germany 1,200
German schools with Nazi textbooks and
Nazi teachers that's in newspapers
Herman Goering glider clubs had been
established also in Brazil there were
two hundred and sixty thousand Japanese
taking orders from Japan in Ecuador with
an easy bombing range of the Panama
Canal German airlines had been
established German pilots were reserve
officers of the Luftwaffe
the German transport planes had bomb
racks already built in in Argentines
German athletic clubs similar to the
Hitler Youth movement had been organized
exclusively for Germany's here was a
fifth column ready to take over
in Havana we met with 20 other American
republics the shadow of anyway as to the
determination of the American nations
not to permit the invasion of their
hemisphere by the armed forces of any
power or any possible combination of
power 20 American nations stood firm the
Americas would not allow any European
colony in this hemisphere to be
transferred to a non-american power we
said keep out we meant it we must
increase production facilities for
everything needed for the Army and Navy
for national defense I believe that this
nation should plan at this time a
program that will provide us with 50,000
military and naval planes to protect our
shores we authorized construction of a
two ocean Navy the greatest of world has
ever known at least it would be the
greatest Navy when completed in 1944 but
then in 1940 it was only a paper Navy
our fighting forces at that time
consisted of an army of a hundred and
eighty seven thousand men a navy of a
hundred and twenty thousand and this dot
was the Air Corps twenty two thousand
and three hundred and eighty seven
strong all told three hundred and thirty
thousand men we had makeshift supplies
makeshift equipment stove pipes for
Canada
bags of flour for bombers and trucks
were labeled tanks our infantry had
exactly 488 machine gunners we possess
235 pieces of field artillery 10 light
and 18 medium tanks that was the army of
the United States in May 1940 the month
in which the matches over and France
so we called our Minutemen at the
National Guard to the 48 states and
placed them into Federal service
and most important Congress passed the
Selective Service Act for the first time
in our history we began mobilizing an
army while still at peace
the first number is serial number 158
[Music]
the second number which has just been
drawn is 192
[Music]
anymore
it wasn't too soon time was running out
the matches had begun their shattering
blitz on brick
hello America this is Edward Murrow
speaking from London there were more
German planes over the coast of Britain
today than at any time since the war
began and the aircraft guns were in
action along the southeast coast today
back on Main Street USA daily we
followed brick whose life struggle for a
Briton died we would be in grave peril
our first line of defense in the
Atlantic the British fleet might go to
Nazi Germany we would be unprotected our
shores our people our homes endangered
Britain must not fall in our harbors
idle and rotting lay ancient destroyers
they had been built for World War one
but this was World War two and this gave
us an idea fifty tired overage
destroyers will revitalize transferred
to Great Britain in return be acquired
for the protection of our shores
we received a chain of bases stretching
from Newfoundland to British Guiana
these bases through a steel wall around
the Caribbean these bases gave new
safety to the Panama Canal it was now
clear to the aggressors that we were
conscious of the threat they represented
to our country mr. Burley Assistant
Secretary of State will tell us how they
got together and tried to scare us off
from 1936 on it became increasingly
clear to the world that Germany Italy
and Japan were pursuing a common pattern
of aggression both in Europe and in the
Far East on September 27 1940
he powers psy.d so-called pact of Berlin
or tripartite pact the Treaty of
far-reaching
alliance by that treaty it was provided
that the three countries would assist
one another with all political economic
and military means when one of the pars
was attacked though particularly the use
of the word attacked by a power not then
involved in the European war or in the
chinese-japanese
conflict the last of these provisions
was aimed directly at the United States
Tokyo celebrated
[Music]
wrong chair Berlin hired itself for us
was clear now that the three axis
countries definitely stood against us
more anxious than ever
we watched the life-and-death struggle
for the position of the skies over
Britain
[Music]
despite the propaganda and confusion of
recent months it is now obvious that
England is losing more England will now
only survive England will win
[Music]
so should we keep out of war or a
Britain even at the risk of war aid but
even at the risk of war 68% thus the
march of conquest of the self term
master races changed our national
attitude from 1936 when only 1 out of 20
Americans thought we would be involved
in war to 1941 when 14 out of 20
Americans were willing to risk war if
war was necessary to ensure access
defeat I asked this Congress for
authority and the funds sufficient to
manufacture additional munitions and war
supplies of many kinds to be turned over
to those nations which are now in actual
war with aggressor nations our most
useful and immediate role is to act as
an Arsenal for them as well as for
ourselves we shall send in
ever-increasing numbers ships planes
tanks good that is our purpose and our
pledge by an overwhelming majority
Congress passed lend-lease bill number
1776 another declaration of independence
independence and tyranny 1941 style
on April 6 1941 the Nazi juggernaut over
ran into Yugoslavia and Greece on June
the 22nd 1941 the success crazy Nazis
took their longest step toward world
countries without any declaration of war
they blitzed into Russia we were
determined not to let down any nations
defending themselves against unprovoked
attack so we extended lend-lease to
these new victims
now the lend-lease products of our
factories were being unloaded in the
bombed ports of Great Britain at the Red
Sea ports for the British in Africa
lend-lease was being hauled over the
Burma Road to China lend-lease was
piling up in Murmansk and Iran for
Russia
why did we supply war materials to the
countries defending themselves against
axis aggression was it our natural
sympathies for people unwilling to lose
their freedom was at our ancient
antagonism to conquerors imposing their
rule on others by force yes partly but
principally it was because the American
people had become certain that they were
on the list of free nations to be
conquered who will sign conflict true
velocity supplier one of these
must break asunder and we were the
leading example of that free world that
Hitler was committed to breaking asunder
what would have been our defensive
position if the aggressors had succeeded
in conquering Britain Russia and China
German conquest of Europe and Africa
would bring all their raw materials plus
their entire industrial development
under one control of the two billion
people in the world the Nazis would rule
roughly one-quarter the 500 million
people of Europe and Africa forced into
slavery to labor for Germany German
conquest of Russia would add the vast
raw materials and the production
facilities of another of the world's
industrial areas and of the world's
people another 200 million would be
added to the Nazi labor pile Japanese
conquest of the Ori
would pour into their Factory the almost
unlimited resources of that area and of
the peoples of the earth a thousand
million would come under their rule
slaves for their industrial machines we
in north and south america would be left
with the raw materials of 3/10 of the
earth's surface against the axis with
the resources of 7/10 we would have one
industrial region against their three
industrial regions we would have won
eight of the world's population against
their seven aids if we together with the
other nations of North and South America
but mobilize 30 million fully equipped
men the axis could mobilize 200 million
thus an axis victory in Europe and Asia
would leave us alone and virtually
surround facing enemies 10 times
stronger than ourselves
these are the reasons that led us the
American people to change the neutrality
to send aid to Britain to Russia to
China to make ourselves the arsenal of
democracy these are the reasons why now
the first American troops set forth into
the Atlantic to occupy new bases in
Greenland and Iceland with the consent
of their local governments in our hands
bases of defense in Nazi hands bases of
offense
[Music]
the Germans open unrestricted submarine
warfare
[Music]
if today maybe should make secure the
C's for the delivery of our munitions to
Great Britain it will render as great a
service to our country and to the
preservation of American freedom as it
has ever rendered in all its glorious
history we want those cargos protected
the laws Congress repealed the entire
neutrality
[Music]
we armed our merchants and for the first
time they steamed the combat zones to
deliver lend-lease while this was going
on in the Atlantic the Japs by so-called
agreement with the puppet government of
defeated France moved in on Indochina
[Music]
there were now only two threats to their
plan for conquest of Greater East Asia
first was their northern neighbor Russia
the only military power within striking
distance of Japan the Nazis were taking
care of Russia the second threat to
Japanese conquest was us Japanese
southward expansion was too dangerous to
attempt with our bases still standing in
the Philippines and our supply lines
opened awake to Midway and in our life
we were in their way we had to be
removed the Japanese way off to
Washington went special ambassador Kira
stone on what the Japs said was the
mission of peace but carefully
synchronized with this departure from
Tokyo was the departure of a [__] task
force under sealed orders not on a
mission of peace on November 14th mr.
kurosu arrived in San Francisco smiling
his toothy smile as he sang the old song
of Japanese friendship the Japanese were
a peace-loving people their whole policy
was devoted to the establishment of
permanent peace in Asia our aid to China
was delaying the establishment of that
peace our refusal to sell them oil and
scrap was interfering with the
establishment of that peace our
objections to they're taking over the
East Indies Greater East Asia was an
interruption in the establishment of
that peace all they wanted was peace
on November 17 mr. caruso and Japanese
ambassador Nomura were received by the
president in the presence of the
Secretary of State Cordell Hull it very
quickly became clear that the Japanese
had brought no new proposals and that
the Japanese intended to continue their
campaign to conquer China and all East
Asia on November 26th our Secretary of
State presented the Japanese with the
basis for peaceful agreement between the
two nations the proposal was forwarded
to Tokyo
the Japs had to stall for time but only
a short time the task force was nearing
its goal Sunday December 7 1941
[Music]
1:00 p.m. Eastern Standard Time
the Japanese emissaries are expected at
the State Department to keep a 1 o'clock
appointment they had requested in order
to present their answers to our
proposals 1 5 p.m. the Japanese planes
are approaching Hawaii 1:10 p.m. the
Japanese emissaries telephoned to
postpone their appointment until 1:45
1:20 p.m.
[Music]
- p.m. the Japanese n boys smiling and
correct arrived at the State Department
2:20 p.m.
japanese planes have been sowing death
and destruction for an hour on American
outposts in the Pacific
when the Japanese end boys presented a
memorandum to mr. Hall here is the
memorandum who sent it to me as you can
see it is quite a lengthy document I
read it hurriedly
discovering that it contained the
recital of monstrous accusations against
the United States charging it among
other things with court scheming for the
extension of the war we planned to
attack Germany and Italy to power
striving to establish a new order in
fury and ignoring Japan's sacrifices in
the four years of the China effect
menacing the Empire's existence itself
and discouraging its honor and prestige
after reading the note I said to the
Japanese emissaries I have never seen a
document that was more crowded with
infamous falsehoods and distortions on a
scale so huge and I never imagined that
any government on this planet was
capable of uttering them
[Music]
I ask that the Congress declare that
since the unprovoked and dastardly
attack by Japan on Sunday December 7
1941 a state of war has existed between
the United States and the Japanese
Empire
[Music]