National Socialism Will reshape the
World Adolf Hitler
the symbols and the leaders change,
but Germany's Will on others...
.. continue from generation to
generation.
In the last 75 years, this magnum
has cost the World...
.. more than 20 million killed,
more than 60 million Wounded...
.. more than 200 million
made homeless.
this does not include the untold
millions that died of disease...
.. resulting from War.
Or the billions upon billions of
dollars Worth of property destroyed.
Nor does this include the grief...
.. the anguish...
.. the misery... the terror
that the World has sufered.
Due to the German's insane passion to
enforce their rule upon their neighbors.
this passion for conquest,
reached its histerical climax...
.. When Adolf Hitler enthroned himself
as God and the German Führer
What fantastic dreams Was this
humorless man dreaming
..as he stood at Nürnberg and looked
doWn on his fanatic folloWers.
In the MiddleAges, a plague of
slavery descended on the World.
Out of the Wilds of Mongolia, came
a mighty army of fierce horsemen...
.. led by Djengis Khan.
Burning, looting, pillaging.
the Barbarian horde sWept across
Asia and Eastern Europe.
Djengis Khan conquered most of
the World of the 13th century
Adolf Hitler Was determined
to outdo him...
.. and conquer all of the World
of the 20th.
Set up at Munich Was an institute
devoted to the little knoWn...
..science of geo politics.
Vaguely defined as the military
control of space.
Germany's leading geo-politician
a former General...
.. Karl Haushofer, Was head man.
Here Was gathered together more
information about your home toWn...
.. than you yourself know
to the German geo-politician
the World is not made up of...
..men, and Women and children Who live
and love and dream of better things.
It is made up of only two elements
labor and raW materials.
the geo-politicians job Was to
transform Hitler's ambition to control...
.. these elements into cold
hard reality.
On their map, our planet is neatly
divided into land and Water.
Water forms 3/4 of the earth's
surface, land only 1/4.
And in that 1/4 of the earth's
surface, lies the World's Wealth.
All its natural resources.
And the World's manpoWer.
Control the land and you
control the World.
that Was Hitler's theory.
this all important land, the geo-
politicians noW break up into two areas.
One the Western hemisphere, Which
together With Australia and all the...
.. islands of the World including Japan,
comprises 1/3 of the land area.
the other area, Which consists of
Europe, Asia and Africa...
.. makes up the other 2/3.
this Super Continent Which
they call the World lsland...
..is not only twice as large as
the rest of the World...
.. but also includes 7/8 of
the World's population.
the heart of his World lsland, comprises
eastern Europe and most ofAsia.
this they call the Heart Land.
Which just about coincides With
the old Empire of Djengis Khan.
Hitler's step by step plan for World
conquest can be summarized this Way
Conquer eastern Europe...
.. and you dominate the Heart Land.
Conquer the Heart Land...
.. and you dominate the World lsland.
Conquer the World lsland...
.. and you dominate the World.
that Was the dream in Hitler's mind,
as he stood at Nürnberg.
With page and pageantry the district
leaders from all over Germany...
.. sWore personal allegiance to him,
hypnotized by the belief...
.. that they Were members of
a master race.
this film Will deal With act one
of the Nazi bid for World poWer.
the most fantastic play
in all recorded history.
Hitler had seen Hirohito grab off
Manchuria and other...
.. territories from the Chinese.
He had Watched Mussolini get aWay
With the rape of Ethiopians.
He had seen the democratic World
look the other Way, While...
.. these illegal aggressions
Were going on.
And he smiled.
For collective acts of peace,
the only Weapon he had to fear...
.. had broken doWn.
It Was time noW for the Nazis
to start crossing borders.
It Was time for Hitler to put
his plan into action.
And What Was he Waiting for?
He Was Waiting to soften up his
victims, keep them from uniting.
Demoralize the enemy from Within
by surprise, terror, sabotage...
.. assassination. That is the War
of the future. —Hitler
For his softening up process, he
sent his agents all over the World...
.. disguised as tourists, students
and commercial travelers.
Pay-off men like Ribbentrop came too.
to buy, threaten and form
local fascist parties.
Such as Degrelle and his
Rexist Party in Belgium.
Hagelin in Czechoslovakia.
Seyss-lnquart for the National
Socialists in Austria.
In Britain, Sir OsWald Mosley offered
himself to the people as a Hitler...
.. With a mocks of accents.
In other Words, I'm told that
Hitler is mad.
Well, I've got another theory myself.
Until the day When they Would make
easy, Hitler's actual invasion...
.. these subversive fascist
organizations provoked riots...
. and rebellions creating scenes
like these in France.
Scenes like these in Belgium.
And Where do you think this is?
Right in Madison Square Garden,
U.S.A.
And this is Fritz Kuhn.
Leader of a German/American Bund...
.. hiding behind the American flag
but taking his orders from Berlin...
.. and copying the methods of Berlin.
that Was the softening up
process outside Germany.
But, inside Germany it Was
a different story.
Here, in up-most secrecy,
the hardening up process.
Building up Hitler'sArmy
and his industry
tell the World We have no raW
materials...
.. and never let them see What goes on.
Day after day, night after night,
month after month, year after year.
We must have the World's most
poWerful club.
Forget hours, forget hoW to think.
Forge the club of blood and iron.
And let the Democracies talk about
freedom. No freedom here.
No labor unions. No overtime.
the Führer tells you Where to Work.
When to Work. HoW long to Work.
HoW much your Work is Worth.
Forge the club of blood and iron.
We have a sacred mission.
today We rule Germany...
.. tomorroW the World.
For those Who don't like it
you don't eat.
Or you disappear into a
concentration camp.
Or you get this.
And this is the man
Who gives it to you.
And What of the Army?
Before Hitler came into poWer,
the German Army, by treaty...
.. Was limited to 100 thousand men.
But treaties to the Germans, have
alWays been something to ignore.
these 100 thousand men Were, in
reality, 100 thousand...
.. highly trained officers.
the men Who lead the
Nazi regiments today.
But Hitler didn't merely ignore
the treaty, he tore it up.
And in 1935, ordered National
Conscription.
Simultaneously, he ordered German
youth to become air-minded.
toy gliders filled the air.
As the youth greW bigger,
so did the gliders.
Soon these same youths Were trained
pilots, flying neW planes...
.. the factories Were producing.
the Luftwaffe Was being assembled.
the only thing old about this
neW army Was the goosestep.
And even Hitler couldn't improve on
that ancient form of German torture...
.. designed to make man stop
thinking and blindly obey
Goosestep them until they become
an insensible as Weapons.
Everything else Was neW.
tanks, motorized equipment
and one of our oWn inventions.
the dive bomber.
All this rearmament Was strictly
illegal to the Versailles treaty.
And the next illegal step Hitler took...
.. Was to march his troops
into the Rhineland.
A strip of land between Germany
and France, demilitarized...
.. after the last War as a precaution
against future German aggression.
But Hitler's plan of eastern conquest,
demanded a barrier against...
.. democratic action in the West.
So Hitler demilitarized the Rhineland
and began building the...
.. formidable Siegfried Line.
A chain of forts and defenses
450 miles long and in some places...
..30 miles Wide.
Germany had fought one, two-front
War and didn't Want another
As many as 1/2 a million men
Worked at least 20 hours a day...
..to build 22 thousand fortified
positions on land...
.. Where, by treaty, no German
soldier Was suppose to set foot.
Hitler had his Siegfried Line,
he had his equipment...
.. he had his army.
NoW to unveil the German might,
and terrorize his intended victims...
.. into submission.
General staffs all over the World,
anxiously aWaited the report...
.. of their military attaches.
A Would-be peaceful World learned
that a vast military poWer had...
.. materialized out of noWhere.
A poWer controlled by one man,
Who tore up treaties...
..as We tear up tickertape.
I am Willing to sign anything.
I Will do anything to facilitate...
.. the success of my policy.
Hitler lntervieW October, 1933
Satisfied that they had created
the right sense of fear in the World...
.. the Nazis got ready to strike,
the hour had come.
It Was time to start conquering
eastern Europe...
.. according to the plan of
Hitler's geo-politicians.
It Was time to Win the domination
of the Heart Land.
Who Was the first victim to be?
Naturally, the softest, Austria.
Bite off just enough...
.. not to set the World against you.
On March the 12th, 1938,
Without Warning,
.. the German armies marched over
the Austrian border.
It Was merely only a full-scale invasion
test and Hitler rode in triumph...
.. into Vienna.
Even the very name of Austria
disappeared from the map...
.. though Hitler had promised
earlier to the World:
the assertion that it is the intention
of the German Reich to coerce...
.. theAustrian State is absurd
Adolph Hitler, January 30, 1934
Why Was Austria important to Hitler?
It put him on the southern flank of
Czechoslovakia...
.. and Czechoslovakia Was the key
to the control of eastern Europe.
the German Chancellor Bismarck
explained that years ago When he said...
.. He Who Would conquer Europe, must
first toll the bastions of Bohemia.
And Bohemia Was noW part of
Czechoslovakia.
But Czechoslovakia Was tough.
It had a good army.
It had good equipment.
It had one of the finest
ammunition plants in the World...
.. the Skoda Works, Which Hitler
Wanted very badly.
It had incorrupt able President Benes.
It had a military alliance With France
and France had a military...
.. alliance With Britain.
Find excuses to take Czechoslovakia
one piece at a time.
He found his excuse in the
Sudetenland.
the portion of Czechoslovakia
bordering Germany.
Here lived some people of German
origin, although they had never been...
..a part of Germany itself.
that Was Hitler's cue.
Completely ignoring the fact
that most people Who left Germany..
.. had done so to get aWay
from things like Hitler.
He sprang his pet theory, that
every person of German blood...
..no matter Where he lives,
belongs to the Nazi Reich.
Germans or descendants of Germans.
Often With no more than a drop...
.. of German blood in their veins,
suddenly learned they Were God-like.
Not subject to the land in
Which they live or...
..to Which they oWe their
allegiance...
.. Whether it be Czechoslovakia...
Norway.
SWeden.
China.
the United States ortimbuktu.
According to the Nazis the German Was
a special creature Who Would remain...
.. forever German of the 6th and 7th
generation and must take his...
.. orders from Berlin.
Some people We knoW of German
decent think this is a lot of hogWash.
Lieutenant General Walter Krueger
Senator Robert Wagner
Wendell Willkie
Henry J. Kaiser
Including 15%% of any group like this.
But in the Sudetenland he found
some stooges Who fell for this bunk.
Conrad Hemline Was their
bush-league Führer
the people of the Sudetenland Were
told they should be liberated.
they Were told Hitler Was their
liberator.
the Nazi smuggled over their standard
softening-up equipment, blackjacks.
And When the Czechs Were beaten up
trying to combat his 5th Columnists...
.. Hitler screamed the Germans Were
being persecuted and threatened...
.. War, unless he got the Sudetenland.
It is the last territorial claim
I have to make in Europe.
I have assured Mr. Chamberlain,
and I repeat it here...
.. that When this problem is solved,
there is for Germany no further...
.. territorial problem in Europe.
We Want no Czechs.
to the League of Nations,
Foreign Minister Maxim Litvinov...
.. announced that Russia Was ready
to back...
.. considered action against Germany.
But once again, there Was no
considered action.
the Czechs mobilized and closed
their borders.
the leaders of France and Britain
desperately stride to avoid War...
.. fleW to meet the jubilant
Axis leaders at Munich.
On September 29, in return for
Hitler's guarantee of World peace...
.. Chamberlain and Daladier prevailed
upon Czechoslovakia to give up...
.. the Sudetenland Without a fight.
In Czechoslovakia the Munich Pact
Was greeted by riots of protest.
But Daladier returned to France
to be greeted by cheers...
.. from a relieved French people.
And in Britain, a happy Chamberlain
came back declaring he had...
.. achieved peace, peace in our time.
One of the most tragic and
ironic scenes in all history.
this morning, I had another talk...
.. With the German Chancellor Herr
Hitler, and here is the paper...
.. Which bears his name upon it
as Well as mine.
the agreement Was signed last night...
.. and theAnglo-German Naval
Agreement as symbolic...
.. of the desire of our two peoples never
to go to War With one another again.
PEACE IN OUR tlME
- Chamberlain
Peace... it Wasn't peace.
the Nazis hadn't nearly dropped
3 million more souls...
.. under the German flag.
By taking the Sudetenland, they had
made Czechoslovakia defenseless.
For in this territory lay
the natural defenses.
the mountain ranges and a
defensive line of forts...
.. considered even stronger
than the Maginot Line.
Without these fortified cautions,
Czechoslovakia Was disarmed.
A ripe plum ready to fall
into Hitler's lap.
Within 6 months of declaring that he
Wanted no more territory anyWhere.
Hitler violated the Munich agreement,
marched in...
.. and took the Whole
of the Czech State.
though he had specifically promised:
I have no further interest in the
Czechoslovakian State, that is...
.. guaranteed. We Want no Czechs
Adolph Hitler September 26, 1938
Austria and Czechoslovakia
Were gone Without a fight.
And Hitler Was getting his control
of eastern Europe.
Poland Was next on the map.
the tired old men of Munich, noW
kneW, that there could be no peace...
..in our time.
If an attack Were made...
..to change the situation by force...
in such a Way dares to
threaten Polish independence...
.. Why then, that Would inevitably
start a general congregation...
..in Which this country Would be
involved."
But after his success in Munich,
Hitler Was sure...
.. that France and Britain Would not fight.
Here is What one of his spokesman
Democracy has no convictions for
Which people Would be Willing...
to stake their lives."
Dr. Ernst Hanftstaengl
But What about the Russians?
the lights began to burn
all night in MoscoW.
British and French military
missions arrived to confer...
.. With the Soviet government.
So did a German representative.
And on August 21, 1939, the World Was
set on its heels by the announcement...
.. of a treaty between the Russians
and the Germans in Which they..
.. agreed not to fight each other
Here Were the admitted arch-enemies
in a state of apparent friendship.
It Was too fantastic to make any
sense... it didn't.
the Germans hoped they could lull
Russia into a false sense of security.
And the Russians needed to prepare
for the fight they kneW Was coming.
they'd read Hitler's book
"Mein Kampf" too...
.. and kneW he had his eyes on
the rich Russian land.
the acquisition of neW soil Was to be
obtained only in the East." Mein Kampf
Confident that Russia Was safely
pigeon-holed, and that the...
.. democracies Would not fight.
the Nazis started singing their...
.. favorite theme song, that all people
of German blood belong to them.
And picked Danzig as their excuse
for the gobbling up of Poland.
Danzig a free city, self-governing
under the League of Nations...
.. Was an important seaport at
the head of the Polish corridor.
Poland's access to the sea.
the same old softening process
had gone on here.
Local stooges, armed by Germany,
began to terrorize the city.
Hitler demanded Danzig in
the Polish corridor or else...
.. Poles Will Fight for Danzig
the people of Poland prepared
for the inevitable.
Although they kneW that Britain and
France had guaranteed their borders...
.. they also kneW those countries
Were a long Way off.
Germany's theft of Czechoslovakia had
make Poland's strategic position...
.. even Worse.
Carpathian Mountains, Poland is
relatively flat and loW-lying.
the Vistula is the Mississippi of
Poland.
It is broad, muddy and unafordable
for most of its length.
It tributaries are formidable
streams during certain seasons.
But there Was a drought, and the
streams Were so loW during the...
.. campaign that they could be
forded at almost any point, by men...
.. trucks and tanks.
Militarily the Vistula offered
the best line of defense.
HoWever making a stand here
Would have meant surrendering...
.. WarsaW, the richest part
of the country.
the alternative Was to accept
battle on the border.
that Was the Polish decision.
the Nazi plan Was an enormous
pincher movement...
.. aimed at encircling the mass
of the Polish army.
Secondary pincher movement Were
to encircle any Polish groups...
.. Which escaped the main trap.
the last two Weeks in August,
the German armies moved...
toWard the Polish border, Where
they assembled 70 Divisions...
.. many of them armor.
From a military standpoint, the
Poles Were hopelessly outclassed...
..by their predatory neighbor
they managed to mobilize barely
30 Divisions, made up of...
.. infantry or horse cavalry.
In two important respects, the
difference Was staggering.
the Nazis 5000 modern tanks,
Poland 600 non descript tanks.
the German Luftwaffe, 6000 modern
planes...
.. the PolishAir Force, less than
1000 of inferior types.
the German Army secretly made ready.
the Way of living for the next
thousand years Was to be decided.
the fire that had begun in Manchuria...
.. and spread through China and
Ethiopia...
.. and Spain Would noW blaze
around the World.
this man made that decision.
War!
Precisely at daWn on
September 1, Without Warning...
.. the German Wehrmacht rolled
over the Polish borders.
Before the invasion Was 30 minutes
old, the planes of the Luftwafe...
.. Were over Poland, Wiping out
the Polish Air Force...
.. most of it caught flat-footed
on the ground.
Most planes that did not get of,
faced overwhelming odds...
.. and Were shot out of the sky
Fire-flying Nazi squadrons ranged
deep into Poland...
.. destroying communications,
radio stations, poWer plants...
highWays, bridges, railroads.
the Polish Army Was disorganized
by the loss of itsAir Force...
.. and the destruction of
communications.
the mass ground unties of the Nazi
Army continued their advance.
Occasionally they unveiled a neW
technique on the arrival of equipment.
For example, advanced units of the
German 4th Army crossed the...
.. Vistula in a neW type of storm boat.
the Polish retreat developed
alarming tendencies...
.. the poWerful German 10thArmy,
Which Was to form the southern claw..
.. of the great Nazi pinchers, Was
advancing With its five armored...
.. divisions on either flank.
On September 6th, the opposing Poles
began splitting into two groups...
.. the southern one falling back
toWard the Vistula...
the armored Divisions on the
German right raced ahead...
.. circling Radome and cutting of this
group, Which finally surrendered.
MeanWhile further north,
the main Polish mass...
.. began drifting toWard Lodz.
the German Command, receiving that
this opened a gate toWard WarsaW...
sent the northern Nazi armored
units racing through the gap...
..to the Polish capital.
the infantry advanced in forced
marches of 35 miles a day...
.. and two days later relieved
the Panzers above WarsaW.
the city Was noW cut off.
West of WarsaW, the main Polish
Armies Were encircled.
Under terrific pressure on the ground,
and pounded coarsely from the air..
.. they began to disintegrate.
they fought on With high personal
courage...
.. but Without airplanes, Without
communications, cut off from...
.. their general staff, the isolated
Polish groups Were forced to surrender...
..one by one.
But WarsaW still resisted.
the heroic strains of the Polonaise,
told an incredulous World...
.. that the people of WarsaW, led by
Mayor Kaczynski, had erected...
..a Wall of courage around their
city defying Hitler's dam nest.
Stopped cold by the city's
desperate resistance...
.. the Nazis Were forced to send
for heavier artillery.
the only source of such artillery
Was Germany's Western front.
With great secrecy, the giant 240 mm
haubitzers...
.. Were toWed at high speed across the
highWays, Which Hitler had built...
.. for just such purposes and set
into position around WarsaW.
the huge guns subjected the city to
a bombardment of incredible fury
their fire concentrated on the
densely populated residential areas.
For 20 days of death and horror...
.. every man, Woman and child
fought to save his city.
But Without food or Water,
human endurance fails.
On September the 27th, the strange but
colonialism died on the WarsaW radio...
.. and the Polish capital
Was forced to capitulate.
NoW all Polish resistance Was
at an end, except here...
the Westerplatte port, opposite
Danzig.
this small island of stubborn defiance,
had stood up under the fire of...
.. German Warships from the first day
Its guns silenced, its ports shattered,
it still refused to surrender
Even under point blank fire at 800
yards range.
It Was an exhibition of Polish valor
that Will go doWn in history
But militarily it could not avail.
On October 1, the garrison
at last surrendered.
Surrendered to face the fate of these
men.
Polish prisoners being marched of
to massive prison camps.
And eventual extermination.
For the Nazi master race theory calls
for the complete Wiping out of the...
..so-called inferior races.
And in village after village, local
Judas's point out loyal Polish neighbors
Himmler.
these things the Poles can never forget.
Including another one of Hitler's
famous promises:
Germany has concluded a Non-
aggression Pact With Poland.
We shall adhere to it unconditionally"
- Adolph Hitler, May 21, 1935
the World noW kneW, that a non-
aggression pact With Hitler...
.. Was the kiss of death.
Poland Was completely destroyed.
Completely?
Not quite. During the last days of the
campaign, the RussianArmy entered...
.. eastern Poland and took up
positions along the Bug River.
the two strongest armies in Europe
meet and Hitler could decide now..
.. Whether to keep on heading east
or call it quits.
He called it quits. Why did Hitler
quit here?
He had to!
to continue a drive to the east, Would
leave Germany facing the threat...
.. he'd alWays sWorn to avoid.
A two-front War.
HoW he met that threat, you Will
see in the next film...
.. for Hitler thought impossible,
Was anything but.
the day after Hitler crossed
the Polish border...
France called up her reserves.
Within 24 hours, British planes had
bombed German Warships...
..in the Kiel Canal.
Britain, not merely the British
government...
.. but the British people had declared War
War on Hitler and everything
he stood for.
the Democracies did have convictions
for Which people Were Willing...
..to stake their lives.
Unprepared? Yes.
But that didn't matter
For they finally realized that
What Was being threatened...
Wasn't just the integrity of Poland,
but the integrity of free men...
.. everyWhere in the World.
What tragedies, What horror,
What crime...
.. has Hitler and all that
Hitler stands for...
.. brought to Europe and the World?"
He did upon this foundation...
.. that Hitler pretends to build
out of hatred...
..a neW order for Europe."
But nothing is more certain...
.. than that every trace of Hitler's
footsteps...
.. every stain of his infected
and corroding fingers...
.. Will be sponged and purged
and if need be blasted...
.. from the surface of the earth."
Lift up your hearts.
All Will come right."
Out of the depths of sorroW and
sacrifice...
.. Will befall again the glory of mankind."
No compromise is possible and the
victory of the democracies can only...
..be complete With the utter defeat of the
War machines of Germany and Japan."
G.C. Marshall
Chief of Staff