- Six years of hard training and actual battle experience
- in Spain and Poland had made the German Army look invincible.
- But what about the British and French?
- First, let's take up the British.
- They started from scratch,
- but both at home and abroad,
- an army was growing.
- For not only Britain had declared war,
- Canada, Australia, New Zealand, South Africa,
- the whole British Commonwealth of Nations
- was also determined on victory over Hitlerism
- and all it stands for.
- And Britain had one weapon that was ready, the Royal Navy.
- Shortly after war was declared at its swept German shipping from the high seas.
- And units of the British fleet were deployed at Suez, Malta, Gibraltar,
- in the Channel, and in the North Sea, blockading Germany.
- World conquest was impossible without running smack up against the rock called Britain.
- How to strike at that little island?
- That was the question.
- Between Britain and Germany stood not only France, but the little countries of Luxembourg,
- Belgium, Holland, Denmark, Norway, and Sweden.
- The people of these small, neutral countries were peaceful, hard-working, and free.
- They knew they were in the middle and feared violation of their neutrality. Hitler knew this.
- He also knew that if they united with the Allies, they would form a solid
- democratic wall against Nazi aggression, and their conquest would be far more difficult.
- So before striking with his armies, he used another weapon, the propaganda barrage, to
- confuse, to make them lose faith, to divide and conquer. To lull the fears of the little neutrals propaganda minister
- Gurbels told them Germany didn't want to war at all.
- It was Britain and France that caused all the trouble.
- Then it was Hitler's turn.
- In the speech on October 6, 1939, he made the more kinds of specific promises. To the day he said, "We have concluded a non-aggression pact with Denmark."
- To the Norwegians he said, "Germany never had any conflict with the Northern States
- and has none today."
- To the Dutch he said, "The new Reich is endeavor to continue the traditional friendship
- with Holland.
- And to the Belgians he announced, the Reich has put forth no claim which might in any way be regarded as a threat to Belgium.
- And while Hitler was making these promises, his generals were cold bloodedly picking out the first victim, Norway.
- And why did they pick Norway?
- It's many steep inlets or fjords would make excellent U-boat
- bases, from which raiders could prey on British supply
- lines.
- Also, it would give the Nazis vital air bases.
- This is a scape-flow British naval base,
- and this the blockade fleet.
- At this time, the German-based bombers couldn't reach them.
- Possession of bases on Norway's western shore would bring these vital British defenses under easy bomber attack.
- But he couldn't take Norway without also taking tiny Denmark, the springboard for his attack.
- So a dawn on April 9, 1940.
- The German Army rolled across the neutral borders of little Denmark,
- and in a matter of hours it occupied the entire country.
- By nightfall, Denmark is erased as a nation,
- and the Danes go into slavery.
- Although only six months before Hitler had announced, we have concluded an unaggression
- pact with Denmark.
- The Danes will not forget.
- Meanwhile in Norway, peaceful looking German merchant ships like these had sneaked inside Norway's neutral waterway and tied up at all principal ports.
- That is, they looked like merchant ships.
- But if the Norwegians had had X-ray eyes, this is what they would have seen.
- The Trojan horse of ancient Greece brought up to date with new and deadlier weapons.
- At the precise moment that the Nazis overran Denmark,
- these quiet-looking ships sprang to life.
- At the same time, Nazi warships discovered
- along the entire coastline, started steaming up the Norwegian fjords.
- Ships, transports, tanks, men, planes, all flung themselves simultaneously upon a defenseless country.
- Airborne infantry seized every strategic Norwegian airport.
- The whole job was made easier by treacherous fifth columnists,
- led by Major Quisling, who seized power and issued orders to suppress resistances.
- Maxi warships steamed past silent guns that could have blasted them out of the war.
- This was one of the most amazing acts of treachery the world has ever known.
- It brought Major Quisling international fame, making his very name synonymous with the word traitor.
- By the afternoon of April 9th, the Germans were in complete control of all seven ports where they had landed in the morning.
- For the first time in more than 200 years, the people of Norway saw an invading army parading through their cities.
- Many of these Nazi soldiers strutting his conquerors in 1940, at last seen Norway some 20 years earlier.
- When this refugee German children they had been raised and cared for
- by kind Norwegians.
- Now these same Germans were back to repay that kindness with terror
- and destruction.
- Once they had occupied the capital, the Nazis quickly found out in all directions.
- But loyal Norwegian troops stopped one German column between Hamar and El Veron.
- So the Germans brought up their bombers? The Norwegians were forced to flee to the north,
- under constant and none-aposed air attack.
- It was here that Captain Robert Lose, an American military
- attire was killed.
- The first American soldier to lose his life in this war.
- Meanwhile, the Nazis had spread all over the country.
- Small patrols occupied every strategic village.
- Parachute troops landed high in the mountains.
- Unaposed bombing raids sent defenseless civilians fleeing in stark terror. They hadn't wandered more.
- They had done everything to avoid it.
- Hoping they could escape the Nazi scourge, they had compromised,
- and tragically failed to unite with the other democracies.
- And now they faced the scourge defenseless and alone.
- Or before the Allies could come to their aid, the Germans were in control of all principal forts.
- Regardless of this, British, French, and Polish contingents
- plunged in and made several landings
- along the Norwegian coast.
- They landed forces north and south of
- Trondheim and attempted an
- uncertain movement on the city,
- under constant heavy and almost
- entirely on the whole dare attack.
- and almost entirely on the pole's dare attack.
- Well, the scene of action was out of range of British fighter planes.
- So they brought up aircraft carriers.
- But these are out of disadvantage when a pole's by land-based planes.
- The Allies therefore were badly battered from the air.
- Finally, suffering heavy losses, they withdrew from a hopeless situation. Further to the North, at Narvik, they met with better success,
- inflicting heavy naval losses on the Nazis.
- They made landings and held the town for nearly two months.
- Incidentally, they also took their first prisoners at the present war.
- While our regions were left with their chrisbings, their ruins, their debt, even though six months before Hitler had said
- Germany never had any conflict with the northern states and has none today
- The Norwegians will not forget and Hitler
- Hitler had another victory. it hijacked two more countries the world wondered and sometimes marvel at this man's efficiency
- gangsta dillinger was efficient too
- when a man ordination throws away all regard for the laws of God and man, he is bound
- at first to be more efficient than his victims.
- Society had a police force to deal with a gangster delinger, but it had no police force
- to deal with gangster Hitler.
- So he clubbed Norway into submission and got what he wanted, bases for use against Britain.
- Now he had the Northern Claw of an enormous pinter movement.
- A drive through France would give him the southern claw.
- Blockade by you boats, coupled with masked bombing attacks,
- would weaken the British for final invasion.
- Then, with Britain gone, Germany could reach out in all directions for world conquest.
- His next move must obviously be through France,
- to get his southern claw.
- Through France,
- how was she to face the arms slot?
- These scenes are ancient history.
- They occurred in 1914.
- The German armies without warning had smashed across neutral Belgium.
- Invaded France, reached the River Marne only a few miles from Paris.
- Out of the French capital poured the French reserves,
- riding out to battle the enemy in every vehicle that could move.
- Famous taxicab army.
- Note well, it was riding out too fast.
- In the center of the French lines to the ninth French army,
- commanded by a then comparatively unknown general.
- On September 5th, 1914, he is reputed to have said,
- "My right is driven in.
- My center is giving way.
- The situation is excellent. I attack. The German armstop was checked, and Parris was saved. That comparatively unknown
- general later became Commander-in-Chief,, all the Allied armies, and presided for signing of the Honestess
- with the defeated Germans on November 11, 1918.
- To this general, the French people erected the monument.
- The Marshall Ferdinand Folche, whose model was "a type, always a type."
- Still later, the war weary French people erected another monument.
- This one to a minister of war, Andre Maginot.
- Between the ideas symbolized by these two statues,
- they well lie the military story of the fall of a great nation.
- In posthus time, the proud spirit of France demanded nothing less than victory
- and placed its faith in the attack.
- In Maginot's time, the spirit no longer proud,
- asked only to avoid defeat and placed its faith in concrete.
- So the French built the mighty chain of fortresses
- called the Maginot Line.
- These tremendous bastions were built deep into the French land.
- They were connected by underground passages and railways,
- guarding France's eastern borders facing Germany.
- And when France was finally forced to declare war against the rising Nazi menace,
- the French troops, instead of attacking, were marched into their modern caves to wait for the Nazi blitz to smash itself against the Maginoline. Their generals headed by Marshall Payter,
- proudly announced, whoever makes the first move
- in this war will be hurt.
- But Hitler didn't go near the Maginoline.
- That was France's strong point.
- Instead he attacked the weak point.
- Hitler knew that the French had tried to avoid war instead of preparing for it.
- That knowledge was one of his greatest weapons.
- He knew they had planes, but he knew they were antiquated.
- He knew they had tanks, but he knew they were few in number and lightly armored.
- But most important of all, he knew that France had become a cynical and disillusioned nation.
- What made this change in the French spirit?
- In the first place between 1914 and 1918, the French suffered more than six million casualties,
- in the heroic defense of their land against German invasion.
- The flower of an entire generation was lost,
- with its stimulus of new blood, new determination,
- new ideals.
- Secondly, the failure of the League of Nations,
- to which the French had pinned their hopes of peace,
- the corruption of many in high places,
- the greed of special interests, all had
- combined to shake the faith of the French people in their democratic ideals,
- and one of people loses its faith in its own ideals.
- It is right for the insidious words of the devil.
- France still looked like an imposing castle, but Hitler's political termites have so nought away the binding of national unity,
- that the castle was ready to crumble.
- And during those months of military and activity that we call the "Pony War," a ceaseless barrage of German propaganda crossed the still waters of the Rhine
- to affect the soldiers in the Maginoline.
- Why do you fight as the banners? Palms and friendly notes were sent over by balloons.
- French tunes were played by German bands.
- And German cooling was broadcast in French.
- The British will fight to the last drop of French blood.
- You have been deceived.
- This is an imperialistic war of the Britain.
- We Germans want nothing of France.
- What is happening to your wives back home soldiers?
- The British are stationed in your villages.
- Yes, France was ready to be plucked.
- The whole force of the Nazi Mike was turned toward the west. How would they strike this time?
- Through Alsace, Lorraine is in 1870.
- Through the Hmong countries, as in 1914.
- What was the 1940 model conquest?
- The French considered the Maginoline utterly impregnable.
- And therefore, I believe the Germans would again
- try to swing through the low countries as in 1914.
- But even after Hitler's rape of Scandinavia, Holland and Belgium
- hoping against hope still plung to their neutrality.
- So the French mass 78 divisions here
- along the border to Belgium.
- 17 were in the Maginot Line.
- 10 divisions here in Case Mussolini got bold.
- Three and a half was a safeguard against Spain.
- The British had 10 divisions here.
- The Allied strategy and the event of an attack
- against the low countries was to swing their
- armies like a gate into Belgium, the hinge being the north end of the Maginot Line.
- This all-important hinge was protected by the forest of the Ardenne, a hilly and thickly
- wooded area, honeycombed with streams, its roads narrow trails, it's bridges too weak for military vehicles.
- French strategists estimated the forest of the Ardandy Passible for armored forces.
- As you will see, this was one of the costly assessments in all military history.
- That was the situation on May 9, 1940. The hour of the democracy is prayed for strength to meet the coming hurricane of terror.
- Well across the Rhine....and the war against the people of the world.
- A glorious man possesses the germination. We, as your command, are for us, our greatest.
- We, the influence, the enemies, are never defeated again.
- And that you, the truth about the country, will be destroyed. The government has always been able to destroy the war against Germany.
- The war has always been over.
- The war has always been over. The war has always is over. The war is over. Deep down! Deep down! Deep down!
- Deep down!
- Their time can come!
- Without even bothering to declare war, the German armies launched a coordinated attack
- across the neutral borders of Luxembourg, Belgium and Holland from the
- maginoline north to the sea. The action along the entire front was simultaneous
- so for purposes of clarity let's take up one country at a time. First let's see
- what happened in Holland.
- Maxi ground forces smashed through, the improvised and hastily erected border defenses.
- But the main attack was to come from the air,
- far behind the defense lines.
- Over 10,000 troops were landed in this manner.
- Before the stunned citizens of Rotterdam even knew they were at war,
- these troops, aided by well-trained Fifth columnists,
- quickly captured the airport and outlying sections of the city.
- Mean time, Nazi armored columns were racing across the country.
- Their progress was speeded by other 5th columnists.
- They prevented the destruction of vital dynasties and bridges.
- These forces affected a meeting with the parachutists landed in Rotterdam.
- The Dutch were doomed to defeat.
- On the 4th day of the invasion, the Nazis gave the Dutch General an ultimatum. All Dutch resistance mcease or Rotterdam will be bombed flat.
- The Dutch General had little choice. To save the lives of innocent civilians he accepted the German Terps. But after the unconditional surrender, the Nazis bombed the city anyway.
- Lights have unimposed German bombers blue- low over the center of Rotterdam,
- and methodically bomb did into a heap of rubble.
- One of the most ruthless exhibitions of savagery the world has ever seen. Over 30,000 men, women and children were killed in the space of 90 minutes.
- The only six months before Hitler had said,
- "The new Reich has endeavored to continue the traditional friendship with Holland.
- The Dutch will not forget."
- The main German attack was directed at the Albert Canal Murs River Line, the anchor of which was Fort Ebena-Mail, a modern and seemingly impregnable fortress. The Germans had secretly built a replica of the mighty
- fortress in Czechoslovakia and had
- rehearsed the attack until I knew every detail of the
- fort's construction, and it's every weakness.
- When the real attack came, it was foolproof.
- Parachute troops, dive bombers, plane forwards,
- specially trained engineer battalions,
- all working together as a well trained team.
- They knew exactly where to cross the river.
- You will notice that this assault engineer knows exactly where to put his high explosives charge in order to destroy the block house.
- Fort Ebena male withstood the Nazi attack exactly two days, and the German armies rolled on.
- Meantime, a mile and a half after the German invasion began, allied troops crossed the French Belgium border to meet the advancing Germans.
- As they raced across Belgium to take up their defense positions, they met an obstacle they hadn't counted on.
- Refugees.
- And the refugee choke droids didn't get that way by accident. The Nazis methodically bombed little towns in villages,
- otherwise devoid of any military value,
- not so much to kill as to drive the inhabitants out onto the highways.
- Then by expert machine gun, the Nazis would herd them along in terrorist-stricken flight,
- and hopelessly in pangol with fancy-aligned armies. The spirit machine gun, the Nazis would heard them along in terror-stricken flight,
- and hopelessly in pangol with a fancy-gallied armies.
- Refugees used as a weapon of war, a new law in Inhumane.
- No school today, the sign says. The children are otherwise occupied.
- says the children are otherwise occupied.
- No, no school today. Although only six months before, Hitler had announced, the like has put forth no claim which might in any way
- be regarded as a threat to Belgium.
- The Belgians will not forget.
- And what about the Allies?
- They were convinced that the German attack on Belgium
- and Holland was the main thrust, and according to plan,
- it swung their armies like a gate in the Belgium.
- But the attack on Belgium and Holland was only a faint.
- The main German attack was to be
- centered where the Allies least expected it,
- through the Ardenne Forest.
- For this decisive blow, they had secretly assembled
- the mightiest striking force the world had ever seen,
- including 45,000 armored vehicles.
- At the same time that the Nazi armies were plunging into Holland and Belgium,
- this column started to move.
- Well-trained engineer battalions went first. They were posed only by scattered-aligned patrols.
- They cleared pathways for the tends to follow.
- In three days, the Germans armored force reached the Murs River. Two days faster than the French Thor and Eight troops could get through.
- By all rules, the Germans should have paused here to bring up heavy artillery
- before attempting to force the river.
- But the Nazis had a new type of artillery.
- Now it's parmines.
- And they blasted the French positions across the Murs.
- With feverish haste, the Germans later barrage across the river
- with anything and everything that would shoot. This tremendous concentration of firepower continued all through the night.
- By the following day,
- shoprooms were able to get across the river. These shot troops held the bridge in until the engineers brought up Pothons and built bridges. Then, without wasting a moment, across these bridges, the main armored force of the German
- military machine rolled through to Sudan, for the all-important breakthrough into a dismayed
- and flat-footed France. There went the old ballgame for the Allies.
- From here on it was only a matter of how long.
- Watch the math as one of our intelligence officers explains
- the details of the German breakthrough.
- We speak of the breakthrough at Sadan.
- But actually the break was along a wide front,
- extending for 50 miles from Namur in Belgium to Sedan.
- Further north the Allied armies had swung like a gate into these positions.
- The German armies had swept over Holland, broken the line of the Albert Canal,
- and for all anyone new, were preparing to smash against the Allied front with all that power.
- That was the situation dangerous but obscure on the evening of May 13th.
- On the 14th and 15th it became clear that the German breakthrough south of
- Namor was in the greatest strength and that the French 9th Army attacked while moving
- into position had been shattered.
- Without doubt this was the point of mortal danger and the French high command ordered the
- abandonment of these positions, although they had not yet been attacked.
- Those positions were abandoned solely because of the situation developing along the Murs
- near Sadam. In the meantime, the French Seventh Army had been ordered to make its historic
- forced march far to the south into the area threatened by the rapidly advancing German
- spearheads. This army was not used to attack the German flank, but rather was used as a plug to restore the broken front.
- Throughout the Allies had placed their faith not in offense, but in defense, and the
- defense was doomed to failure. Because it was confronted with an entirely new technique
- in warfare, the playing tank infantry team in action. The world was staggered by the speed with which the German armoured columns moved.
- What was the secret that enabled armies to move so far so rapidly?
- The secret lay in the organization of the striking spearhead.
- Armoured forces came first, closely followed by motorized divisions, which peeled off
- forming solid walls.
- And through the corridor, thus formed,
- raced the supply trucks to feed the ever-lengthening column.
- It was obvious that if the Allied situation was to be restored, the German column would have to be cut.
- On May 17th, General De Gaulle attacked the German flank
- and captured a few prisoners.
- But his like mechanized forces were like a pin
- breaking the side of a rhinoceros.
- A subsequent attack met with even less success.
- The means for a really successful counter-attack the German carder simply did not exist,
- where numbers of divisions were required, only handfuls of companies and battalions were
- available.
- A valiant attempt to cut the German carder was made by a group of slow-moving British tanks,
- just south of Arah.
- But lack of sustained striking power,
- doomed this valiant unit to destruction.
- On May 21st, the German spearhead
- reached the channel port of Abbeyville.
- Protecting their flank along the psalm,
- the Germans found out to the north and east.
- This was to be the perfect battle of annihilation.
- On May 28th, the Belgian army compressed into a small space
- and weary of battle lay down its arms.
- That left the desperate French and British defenders
- with their backs to the sea at the small Channel Port
- of Dunkirk.
- One of the greatest disasters in history
- seemed in the making.
- An entire British army faced annihilation.
- But out of the fog and the mist,
- robbing the channel came a strange armada. Of Navy craft, fishing boats,
- pleasure yards, anything that would float.
- The sea-going people of Britain had come to rescue their army.
- High overhead British fighter planes fought the Luke Walker to a stanzed him.
- While below, small Allied suicide units, held a German pack long enough
- with a miracle of gun-curred to take place.
- 211,500 British troops, plus 112,500 French and Belgian were rescued.
- Over 300,000 battle-tested men, grimly determined to go back again with new tools,
- new weapons with which to blast the heated Nazis out of this world.
- For three men, like rubber balls, the harder they fall,
- the higher they bounce.
- Leading the British by this time was a man who had been bouncing all his life,
- Winston Churchill, who had tried for years to warn the world about Germany.
- Mean time the situation that faced France was as nearly hopeless as a military situation
- can be.
- Two-fifths of the French army was lost.
- There were fewer than 50 divisions left to defend the front almost 200 miles long, running
- from the northern end of the Magoon or line to the sea.
- And behind that thin front line, there were no reserves.
- Despairing people of Paris sent their children south,
- praying that some miracle would keep them from harm.
- The hopeless men of the French army without adequate arms or equipment
- braced themselves for the coming blow.
- The first blow fell on June 5th.
- The French resistance was determined,
- but by June 8th, the left flank army had been shattered and a general withdrawal was ordered to the line of the man and the same.
- On June 9th, the German main attack came.
- Within two days, the German, armoured and motorized divisions roared out into the open terrain.
- With this breakthrough, the issue of the Battle of France was decided. And from
- that time on, there was official talk of anomesthes.
- Now, what about the famous Marginal Line? Let's go back and take a look. On June 14th, the Germans
- launched two attacks against the Marginal Line. In both cases, penetrations were affected.
- But we must remember that this was against fortifications
- defended by men devoid of hope.
- In the meantime, Mussolini is now thinking it's safe
- sent his division, racing across the border.
- The hand that held the dagger has struck it into the back of its neighbor.
- Organized resistance in France was no longer possible.
- The government faced two alternatives,
- retired to North Africa and carry on from there,
- or give up the struggle.
- France's leaders were old and tired,
- and the oldest and most tired was Marshall Paytown,
- egg-donned by men like Laval,
- who saw in a German victory his chance for personal power on June 16th,
- pay-tie asked for an armistice.
- The news is carried to Hitler, who received this word of a great nation's fall in a characteristic
- manner.
- Also characteristic were his terms for the armistice. It must be signed in the coach where Marshal Fosch met
- the defeated Germans in the last war.
- The French delegation arrives to pay the final price of French disunity and the treachery of some of its leaders.
- The final price, a price that for centuries to come, the French won't forget.
- More than three-fifths of their country was to be blacked out by a military occupation.
- The remainder was to be controlled by a French government acceptable to Hitler.
- Attacks of 400 million francs a day was to be imposed on the French people to support
- the German army of occupation.
- Nearly two million French prisoners of war were to be taken into Germany and kept there
- as hostages to work as slaves or rot of hunger tuberculosis or other diseases in concentration
- caps. tuberculosis or other diseases in concentration camps.
- Men deliberately and permanently separated from their families
- in order to decrease the French birth rate
- and thus eliminate France as a world-powered and future generation.
- French civilians, men, women and children,
- must slave on farmer-enf factory for the Nazi master race,
- or starve.
- There will be a class of subject alien races.
- We need not hesitate to call them slaves.
- French children were to grow up on such inadequate food
- that many would reach the age of 12
- before they grew new teeth.
- And for any attempts to protest against these restrictions, thousands of innocent French
- civilians would be executed.
- This was the price the French were to pay as they signed the armistice.
- And the master of the master, Race Musgot de Paris,
- to tour the streets of what was once the city of light.
- You notice no cheering crowds here to welcome in the new order.
- When the people of Paris come to the streets again, it is to hear the voice of dictators,
- telling them what they must do, how they must live, what they must say, what they must think, telling them how to be slaves,
- gone is through a public of France,
- gone is free speech in a free representative government,
- gone is liberty, equality, fraternity.
- These are the French.
- With their ears they listen.
- But their minds and their hearts,
- these are down on the Mediterranean,
- where the battle colors of the regiments
- are being taken to Africa, out of the Nazi grasp.
- The people weep as their glory departs,
- but they don't as yet know that France has hope,
- a rallying point.
- Charles de Gaulle, a soldier in the great tradition of Bosch is not surrendering. He will continue to go, a soldier in the great tradition of
- Bosch is not surrendering. He will continue to fight, gathering
- about him loyal Frenchmen from all over the world to become
- the free French army, the fighting French. Yes, the people
- weak as they watch their colors go. Not knowing the two
- years later, those same flags would again be unfurled in North Africa.
- Alongside the stars and stripes.
- Alongside the Union J.
- Once more their leaders general to Gaul and the famous General Zero stand united in the
- common cause with the leaders of their allies.
- Once more the red white and blue of France
- is raised on high. For out of the ashes of the defeat and the humiliation of France,
- her soul has been born again.