this is the Battle of China
this the great city of Shanghai on a
September day in 1937
this the fearful beginning of a new kind
of war
this first mass bombing from the air of
a helpless civilian population
why hire these innocent Chinese men
women children to die beneath the hail
of Japanese bombs to find the answer to
this question we must first understand
something about China and Japan and to
understand China three facts must never
be forgotten
China is history China is land China is
people Chinese history goes back for
more than 4,000 years that's a long time
it was only a hundred and sixty-eight
years ago that Washington crossed the
Delaware
only 452 years of passed since Columbus
discovered America
it's 1,500 years since the world saw the
fall of the ancient Roman Empire 3400
years have gone by since Moses received
the Ten Commandments 3,700 years have
passed since the pyramids were built but
more than four thousand years ago the
Chinese Empire was already in existence
and more important so was the Chinese
civilization a civilization of art and
learning and peace yes China is history
and China is also land more land than
the entire continent of Europe a third
larger than the United States and rich
in raw materials
this vast area consists of China proper
and for outer provinces to the north is
Manchuria huge and desolate but
abounding in raw materials next to
Manchuria our Mongolia and Sinkiang
here lies the Gobi Desert a vast plateau
twice the size of Texas inhabited by
nomads tribes who lead their camel
caravans back and forth over ancient
trade routes to the West is Tibet the
icy roof of the world its borders
encompassing the eastern end of the
Himalayan mountains the mystery land
that few have entered and from these
vast mountains of the West rise the
three Great Rivers the northernmost of
these is the playing ho the Yellow River
far to the south flows sea Kiang the
Pearl River which enters the sea past
the great ports of Canton and Hong Kong
but the greatest river of all is the one
that flows between the Yangtze winding
for 3,000 miles through the heart of
China bringing fertility to the good
earth and bearing upon its broad waters
half the Commerce of China yes China is
land next to Russia the largest country
in the world but most important China is
people 450 million of
if the whole population of China would
walk past you for a breast there would
never be an end to the procession for
new Chinese would be born and would grow
up before the last man could pass by of
every five persons on the face of the
earth one is a Chinese and since
one-fifth of all the human beings in the
world are Chinese we should know what
sort of people they are well in all
their 4000 years of continuous history
they have never waged a war of conquest
they're that sort of people they
developed the art of printing from
movable type they invented the Mariners
compass without which no ocean could be
cross they were among the first
astronomers and their observations of
the stars and planets made possible the
accurate measuring and recording of time
they are that sort of people and why do
we call our dishes China because the
Chinese invented the art of making
porcelain and as we all know they
invented gunpowder not as a weapon of
war
but to celebrate their holidays and
religious festivals and it was one of
China's great philosophers who 500 years
before the birth of Christ gave mankind
these words what you do not want done to
yourself do not do to others they are
that sort of people enriching the world
in which we live yes China is incredibly
old incredibly big incredibly pop just
yet it was until recently a land with
which few of us concerned ourselves but
now a great change has taken place China
is now our fighting hour or more
accurately we are China's for China has
been fighting our enemy Japan for seven
long years
why is this why if the Chinese when all
their 4000 years of history have never
waged an aggressive war then forced to
fight the fight who died by the millions
because China is land 4 million square
miles and because China is people 450
million of them and because Japan had a
plan to use them both that plan was
finally stated in the Tanaka memorial a
blueprint for world conquest formulated
in 1927 by Baron de Shi Tanaka the
Japanese Foreign Minister in order to
conquer the world we must first conquer
China here was their mad dream phase 1
the conquest of Manchuria for raw
materials phase 2 the absorption of
China for manpower piece by piece so as
not to arouse the rest of the world
phase 3 a triumphant sweep to the south
to seize the riches of the Indies Bay is
for the eastward move to crush the
United States one fact was obvious China
was to be the giant back on which Japan
would ride to world conquest just as
Russia was to be enslaved for German use
but how was it possible for Japan only
one twentieth the size of China and with
only one-sixth its population to think
of conquering China much less the world
there were two main reasons for this in
the first place modern China in spite of
its age-old history was like the broken
pieces of a jigsaw puzzle each piece
controlled by a different ruler each
with his own private army in modern
terms China was a country but not yet a
nation
while Japan was a united well nip highly
regimented military dictatorship second
reason lies in the uses each country
made of our Western civilization let's
see what China took you will notice that
this is a very old piece of film
actually it is more than 30 years old
and it shows a very great man by the
name of soon yat-sen in 1911 this man
fathered a People's Revolution which
brought to an end China's ancient
Imperial government and began its new
era as a modern Republic winning for
himself in Chinese history as secure of
place as George Washington has in ours
and he and his followers chose for the
cornerstone of their new republic
Chinese words that echoed those of
another believer in democracy government
of the people by the people for the
people and to make these principles
become reality they built more schools
and colleges they establish scholarships
so that their young men and women could
go forth to the universities of America
and Europe and bring back to their own
country other Western ideas and this new
generation returned to China with new
techniques of Industry architecture
science medicine they built more
hospitals to free their people from the
blight of disease they introduced
compulsory education they laid down as
essential two of the four freedoms for
which we fight today freedom of
expression and freedom of religion
in 1925 Sun yat-sen died but his
disciples led by Chiang kai-shek carried
on his monumental work their aim the
unification and modernization of China
Chinese industry was old-fashioned and
inefficient transportation was slow and
inadequate but now railroads began to
link the great seaports and river
harbors with the inland cities a network
of Highways began to stretch beyond the
railroad lines into the deep interior
after leaving them untouched for
centuries China was beginning to use her
vast store of raw materials
and soon the tools and machines of the
new factories were delivering the goods
and products for China's new economy for
the Chinese believed in using the best
of Western civilization so the progress
of their country and while they were
building this new nation just a day and
a half by steamer across the Yellow Sea
lay Japan
here the god Emperor and his fanatic
warlords were using this same Western
civilization for one purpose and only
one to create one of the world's most
powerful war machines their aim the
absorption of China and the fulfillment
of the Tanaka memorial
for years Japan had deliberately copied
military weapons and industrial
techniques discovered in other countries
for years Japan under the pretext of
lacking raw materials for industry had
been buying in every corner of the world
materials not only to build this war
machine but materials which could be
stored to feed it in the war of conquest
they were planning for years while other
nations were trying to outlaw war by
reducing armaments Japan was feverishly
and secretly building a modern army a
modern Navy a modern Air Force to strike
its infamous blow at the civilized world
and we all now know about the islands in
the Pacific that Japan fortified in
violation of all international treaties
these were the reasons why F was
possible for Japan only one twentieth
the size of China and only one-sixth the
population of China to think of
conquering China as the first step to
world conquest and as you have seen in
1931 they embarked on phase one the
occupation of Manchuria
the small bonfire that the Japanese live
in Manchuria was to grow and spread with
uncontrollable fury until the entire
world was aflame
phase 1 if the Tanaka plan was completed
and exactly as planned
the Japs have been confident that this
first and sudden land grab could be
accomplished without their becoming
involved in a major war and they were
right the unification of China was still
too remote for the Chinese of the south
to care what happened to their kinsmen
in the north
using the step-by-step technique a few
months later the Japs took a crack at
Shanghai
but Chinese resistance was so great they
hastily called that deal off waited
another year and then struck in the
north again carving the province of gay
whole' out of China proper this too they
got away with the world criticized the
Chinese protested but still the Japs got
what they wanted another piece of China
and without a war on their heads and to
rule over Manchuria and yaho
the Japs then set up a puppet government
under their stooge
Henri puyi the Chinese Quisling Prince
but the leaders of new China remembered
that in other centuries other barbarians
had invaded their country the evidence
still stood in the great wall built by
their ancestors more than two thousand
years earlier and stretching for 1,400
miles across mountain and desert to
protect themselves from the barbarians
of the north
of the Great Wall it has been said that
it is the only work of man which would
be visible from the moon but the Chinese
knew that modern barbarians can't be
stopped by a wall however strong are
high they can't even be stopped by
people unless the people are united
and by 1937 the unification of China was
making such progress the Japs got
worried the one weapon they could not
permit China was unity they would strike
again before China cat become a nation
this time it would be a big bite five
more northern provinces out of a heart
of China at the United States Embassy in
China as military attache for a number
of years was Colonel William mayor let
him tell you what happened the first
thing the Japs did was to prepare their
usual fake alibi this time it wasn't a
damaged railway track as it had been in
Manchuria in 1931 a [ __ ] soldier had
disappeared obviously he'd been
kidnapped by the insolent Chinese once
more Japan's honor had been insulted
once more the insult must be avenged so
on the night of July 7th 1937 at the
Marco Polo Bridge near Peking the jack
war machine struck
within the space of a few weeks the
invaders were in control of Tinson and
Bay pain it looked as if the Japs are
going to have another walkover now the
Japs sat back to digest and organized
this new conquest the peace-loving
Japanese didn't want a war if they could
get their land grabs without one but
this time they were in for a rude
surprise this time instead of protesting
and negotiating the Chinese struck back
and not in the north but at shanghai
where the Japs least expected
to understand the fighting that followed
we must know something about the city of
Shanghai itself situated near the mouth
of the Yangtze River it is the biggest
city in China as the largest seaport in
the Far East it dominated the commerce
and foreign trade of China and through
its great docks and channels passed most
of the wealth of the Orient inshallah I
truly the East met the West
and within this city of three and a half
million Chinese was another city the
foreign settlement made up of the French
Concession
and the well-known international
settlement there the various powers
including Great Britain the United
States and Japan at station 2 catchments
of troops Japanese British French and
our own United States Marines to assist
the police of the Shanghai Municipal
Council in the preservation of peace and
order and to protect the boundaries of
the International Settlement these
detachments were limited in size but the
Japs secretly and in violation of all
treaty agreements that increased their
Garrison's so that when fighting started
on the border of their concession in
August of 1937 they thought they were
fully prepared for any eventuality
the force of the Chinese counter-attack
almost drove the Japs into the Wankel
River backed up by the heavy guns of
their warships however the Japs managed
to hold out until reinforcements arrived
[ __ ] landings were then made in the
vicinity of the Woosung forts and in
lieu ho and lo tian on the Yangtze River
north of Shanghai the Chinese drew back
to positions five or ten miles inland
where they could secure some protection
from the heavy [ __ ] naval gunfire
at the same time the invaders succeeded
in making a surprise landing some 20
miles to the south of Shanghai put two
divisions short and pushed rapidly north
to our flank the city
the Chinese position was thus made
untenable
under withdrawal was ordered to the west
and to the south toward Nanking and
Hangchow but only about half of the
Chinese army that had fought at Shanghai
was left to withdraw
meanwhile enraged at the very idea of
anyone resisting the Imperial Japanese
might the Japs took their vengeance upon
the civilian population of the city a
city without guns or planes to defend
itself and deliberately slaughtered
thousands from the air
the some there was refuge inside the
International Settlement where Japan was
afraid to bomb the property and people
of the foreign powers just yet
there was not room for all for each who
found safety inside there were thousands
huddled beyond the gates standing
helpless and undefended against the
Chaput acts
there was no escape for these surging
and panic-stricken people
they could only scurry through the
narrow streets pushing and packing
themselves into the center of the city
to be exact
buried alive in the collapse of bombed
and burning buildings
thus for Japanese introduced the world
to a new kind of war
a war of deliberate terrorization of
deliberate mass murder of deliberate
frightfulness
when the campaign was over the Japs
occupied the entire peninsula east of
Shanghai reorganizing rapidly they then
launched a coordinated drive on Nanking
one column pushed along the railroad
while another swung further to the south
this column then split and continued its
drive
hoping to cut off any possible to
retreat of the Chinese armies defending
Nanking it was here in the Yangtze that
the blood-crazed Japs attacked an
American gunboat the USS Panay
despite its distinctive markings
the ship was bombed and sunk with the
loss of American lives the first
American warship to go to the bottom in
this war but officially at least this
was a mistake and the Japanese
government apologized meantime at
Nanking Chinese armies valiantly
defended their city which was the
capital of the Chinese Republic
but again Japanese power was too great
and after a battle lasting but a few
days the city fell to the invaders
their occupation of Nanking the chaps
again outdid themselves in barbers the
helpless populace was tapped by the city
walls he did not flee Japanese soldiers
went for certain they raped and tortured
they killed and butchered
in one of the bloodiest massacres of
recorded history they murdered 40,000
men women children
but those who live might better have
died for the horror of their twisted and
porn bodies was worse than death these
scenes were photographed by an American
missionary and smuggled out of China
after the rape of Nanking
this nightmare of cruelty was all the
more horrible because it was
deliberately planned by the Japanese
High Command to tear the heart out of
the Chinese people once and forever
and then it happened that which soon
yat-sen had dreamed of that which Chiang
kai-shek at toiled for that which is
stronger than stone walls had at last
been born in China the will to resist
ten Yemen
in their last bloody blow the Japanese
that accomplished what 4,000 years had
failed to bring into being a united
China
but the Chinese knew that the will to
resist was not by itself enough they
knew that China must develop the power
to resist also and this cannot be
created in an instant so they too made a
plan and it was this they would slowly
yield territory piece by piece
while they developed the power and built
the weapons to rid the land of its
invaders the industrial strength of
China must be moved to the west beyond
the mountains beyond the railroad lines
beyond the lines of communication they
are safe from enemy attacks they might
produce the rifles and guns that China
so tragically needed
thus China would trade space for time
space for time blow up the roads
space for time sports the earth
space for time blow up the factory
building
leave nothing to the invaders
and then the people rose and moved
riding walking crawling
thirty million of them spontaneously
driven by an epic impulse rose and made
their way west the earth teeming with
them moving westward on a trek that
stretched through two thousand miles of
road less wilderness thus the world
witnessed one of the most amazing
spectacles in human history the greatest
mass migration ever recorded whatever
could be abuse and could be moved the
Chinese took with them on a Homeric
journey their libraries their schools
their hospitals all dismantled and
carted away the machinery from over a
thousand factories weighing over 300
million pounds was moved away in trucks
and ox carts and on their banks
2,000 miles away 2,000 miles west
wherever they could they gathered along
the few remaining railroads waiting
hoping for some chance to ride part of
the way toward their westward goal and
when they attacked the last train with
the last ounce of humanity and machinery
the tracks themselves were taken up rail
by rail tie by tide to be transported
westward to leave nothing for the enemy
every river pointing westward was heavy
late every sampan every bar was pressed
into service weighted down to the
water's edge with the precious tools for
new China
nothing could stop not even the rivers
that narrowed in the mountain gorges
westward with their loads of machinery
more precious than gold
progress was measured by the mile by
feet by inches the trail had broke this
noise and every step of the way by their
sweat where there were no trains no
boats no ox carts there were still
willing hands and willing feet straining
backs 30 million people moving west
westward from the invader westward from
slavery and death westward to freedom
now in the free mountain lands of the
West
ancient cities sprang in fresh and
modern life chief of them all was the
new capital of free China Chongqing here
on the cliffs high above the Yangtze
River the Chinese had reestablished
their government they knew however that
the people of the city would not be safe
from [ __ ] air raids the memories of
Shanghai were fresh in their minds and
in the sandstone cliff on which the city
is built thousands of workmen rushed the
construction of enormous caves as
shelters for the people and for the
pitifully few machines more important
than life to the Japs Chongqing became
the heart of the Chinese nation they
were determined to conquer destroyed
Chongqing and they would break the
spirit of new China
as they could reach the city by land
they would send their bombers to blast
it from the face of the earth
against these Japanese are modest slow
and obsolete Chinese planes made a
suicidal attempt to defend Chongqing
but neither Japanese planes nor Japanese
mugs can destroy the life of the city
but not only the people but the
factories have gone underground where
the vital machines could operate by day
and by night safe from bombs and
strapped
this time the Chinese had anticipated
their enemy in spite of bombs and fire
and destruction this time the Chinese
stood fast
blaming chongqing became the symbol of
their indestructible spirit
and now the cold ones sounded throughout
new China and from the past interior
China's millions answered the call
they came from the south and from the
north from the east from the West the
form of People's Army with a new faith
in their hearts
men and women left their homes and farms
to fight for something bigger now than
each man's home and each man's farm in
each man's life they were fighting for
new China
new soldiers awkward and unskilled like
all new soldiers but I toughened and
trained
they learned the discipline and order of
drill they knew they must strike and
strike hard they learned to kill
the youth of trying also came forward
training to care for the sick and the
wounded girls joined their husbands
brothers and sweethearts in uniform and
to the aid of China came volunteers from
other lands men who pledged themselves
to fight against tyranny and oppression
no matter where Americans like the
legendary Colonel Charlotte and his
Flying Tigers who were there few
American planes were knocking down enemy
planes of the fantastic ratio of 20 nips
to one of their own had hoped to ride
the world conquest on the back of the
giant Chinese workhorse Phase two of the
Tanaka plan called for breaking the
horse to their will but the great
patient horse refused to be broken the
enraged [ __ ] saw their whole plan of
conquest bogging down so they set out to
drain the Giants strength by cutting the
arteries through which flowed China's
lifeblood of supplies they penetrated
along the rivers railroads destroyed by
the Chinese were rebuilt with slave
labor as the Japanese moved inland
secured control of key rail lines and
important communications
and China's supply lines from the
outside world were cut off by [ __ ]
warships blockading the coast the
Japanese strategy was the isolation of
China port after port was occupied this
meant China was being cut off from
supplies she couldn't manufacture for
herself supply as she was getting from
her Western friends without oil gas guns
and planes china was doomed with the
whole of the chinese coast in the hands
of the chance there would only be two
roofs over which to bring the vitally
necessary materials from Indochina a
narrow gauge railway ran inland from the
sea to kun Ming connecting with a truck
road that went to Chongqing but its
capacity was limited and then there was
the old trail of the camel caravans from
Russia across the Gobi Desert which
could bring in even less not only did
these routes provide too little for
China's needs but they were too near [ __ ]
territory to be safe there was only one
other possibility in Burma was a
railroad that ran from the port of
Rangoon to Lazio separating it from the
truck road at Kunming were hundreds of
miles of high mountains and deep river
gorges
if this stretch of tortuous mountain
trails could be replaced by a modern
highway where now only pack trains could
pick their plodding way China would have
a practical supply route to Burma and
the sea several internationally known
firms of Engineers were called in to do
the job they said the work might be
completed in six or seven years if China
could supply them with the most modern
machinery but China didn't have the
modern machinery nor did she have the
six or seven years so she began building
the road with her bare hands
by thousands by tens of thousands by
hundreds of thousands they toiled at the
back-breaking pass of carving this
desperately needed supply line out of
the reluctant madness
and out of their toil and their sweat
they created the Burma Road not in six
or seven years but in less than twelve
months a monument for the new spirit to
the new China as soon as it was
completed the road went into immediate
service
by thousands the truck shuttled back and
forth between its terminals climbing to
nearly 10,000 feet around hairpin curves
along the edges of sheer precipices
we're passing trucks had barely 1 foot
of clearance
the blood plasma of new supplies flowed
steadily over China's lifeline to the
sea protected by Colonel Chennault
incredible Flying Tigers the Chinese
sacrifice cannot be measured only in
miracles of construction that must be
counted too in the tragedy of
destruction for while still the Burma
Road was being built the invading
Japanese had fanned out and straddled
fully two-thirds of the railroad lines
of the country in the summer of 1938
they set out to capture the remaining
one-third starting with the vital
railroad junction at Chang Chau change
how is situated on the banks of the
Yellow River
China's sorrow originally the river
flowed from Chang Chau southeast way to
the Yellow Sea but nearly a century ago
a great flood abruptly changed its
course
swinging it far to the north for
generation upon generation as the spring
floods rushed down to the sea thousands
of Chinese worked on the dikes to hold
the river in its new course protecting
their homes and their crops
now as the Japs advanced on Cheng Chao
the Chinese blew up the southern dike of
the Yellow River
thus loosing a flood between themselves
in the jacks
once more the river flowed in it's old
course forming a barrier which to this
day was prevented the [ __ ] from
entrenching himself in this area
thus once more with no thought of the
human sacrifice of the material cost the
Chinese traded space for time and the
Chinese had still other tricks to pull
from their patched and faded sleeves you
will notice that this map of [ __ ]
conquests doesn't look like the military
Maps you have seen in the previous films
by all military standards it should have
looked like this which is the way the
Japs wanted it to look but the Japanese
were learning that the occupation of
Chinese cities and control of Chinese
rivers and railroads still was far from
meaning the subjugation of China
but the Chinese have formed themselves
into guerrilla bands trained to Harris
the [ __ ] forces these guerrillas were
mostly farmers who had stayed behind on
the land when the great migration to the
west took place peaceful farmers one day
deadly fighters the next they made an
unpredictable and uncontrollable enemy
the chaps sell the lines of
communications but in the pockets thus
formed these uncomfortable guerrillas
constantly sniped at the [ __ ] invaders
when the Japs tried to annihilate them
they disappeared only to reappear in
another pocket
tender
attacking with speed and surprise they
ambushed enemy patrols
the Japanese were fighting more than the
Chinese people they were fighting the
Chinese land the great distances the
rivers the floods the swamps and marshes
these two were enemies that defied the
[ __ ] war machine the giant back Japan
intended to ride to world conquest was
proving to be a bucking bronco
phase two of the Tanaka plan had fogged
down in what the Japs still referred to
as the China incident this left them in
a fateful quandary phase two of the
Tanaka plan was still incomplete but
phase 3 in phase 4 could no longer be
delayed in Russia the overwhelming
German offensive was taxing Russia's
military capacity to the limit removing
any Japanese fear of Russian
interference Britain after the
sledgehammer blows of Dunkirk in the
Battle of Britain was left groggy and
militarily almost exhausted her Navy
scattered across the seas guarding her
lifeline of supplies but here in America
we were finally awakening to our danger
and taking steps to protect ourselves we
had appropriated funds for the
construction of a two ocean Navy and our
army was rapidly expanding
if the ultimate objectives of the Tanaka
plan were to be achieved now was the
moment to strike
now when Russia was otherwise occupied
now before Britain could recuperate now
before we could gather too much strength
so the Japs made a fateful decision they
would embark on phase 3 and phase 4 the
conquest of the Indies in the United
States without waiting to complete phase
2 the conquest of China
thus the paralyzed American power in the
Pacific without warning as they have
always struck they struck again
according to all the rules China's
position should now be greatly improved
for inner war with Japan China now had
fighting allies ourselves the British
the Dutch but it didn't work that way
for China for in those tragic early
months of 1942 when we sustained defeat
after defeat at the hands of our common
enemy
China endured the worst setback of all
out of our defeat China lost the Burma
Road
but still china's courage never faltered
her determination never weakened and in
the history of those long and tragic
months of black defeat in 1942
one bright page stands forth the page
written by our Chinese Eliza here is the
city of Changsha the Japs wanted it for
two reasons it was in the center of the
Chinese rice bowl and it was also an
important railway Junction place before
they have tried to take it and twice
before they have been thrown back
massing a large striking force near yo
choke on Christmas Eve 1941 the Japs
started southward toward Shanghai and
three columns of three points during the
drive south the Chinese forces put up
token resistance but instead of
withdrawing toward Changsha they
withdrew east into the mountainous flank
by New Year's Eve the Japs had
surrounded the city they quickly pierced
the outer defences and attacked the
inner defenses from four directions in
spite of fierce resistance the Japs were
certain of the fall of Changsha was only
a matter of hours what they didn't know
was that they had walked into a well
baited trap for the Chinese forces which
had withdrawn into the hills
now swept down on the [ __ ] supply light
he cut them to ribbons
the [ __ ] forces attacking the city soon
ran out of food and ammunition and began
a withdrawal
whereupon the Chinese launched a
counter-offensive and pushed the
Japanese back where they had come from
the [ __ ] column was forced to run the
gauntlet continuous attack by the
pursuing Chinese forces
the Battle of Changsha was a magnificent
victory for the people of China the
people who wouldn't surrender the people
determined to fight for their freedom
their good earth the people who can't be
beaten and US 1944 Dawn's there is
another and greater story being written
from the Aleutians to the South Pacific
we are on the offensive in the jungles
of New Guinea in the Gilbert and
Marshall Islands on the shores of New
Britain on the broad Pacific waters
Japan faces the daily expanding
power the nation's she attacked
and in India American British and
Chinese forces are gathering strength
under Lord mount back for the liberation
of China for China's war is our war and
now her millions belong not only to
United China but also to the United
Nations leader of our American forces is
general Stillwell who has the unique
honour of being the chief of staff of
all the Chinese expeditionary armies
division after division of picked
Chinese troops are being flown in our
planes from China to India where they
arrived and equipped with the most
modern American weapons trained and
hardened the spearhead the coming drive
against Japan through enemy-held
territory in northern Burma the new Ledo
Road is being pushed
over mountains through jungle and swamp
from India to China to connect with the
old Burma Road in the jungle on either
side American and Chinese patrols
protect the road and strike up the Japs
their supplies and ammunition brought in
by playing in parachute
from fields in India an Air Transport
Command plane takes off every six
minutes loaded with artillery jeeps
ammunition men and supplies for the
armies of China over this Burma Skyway
over this hump of mountains 16,000 feet
high more tonnage is being flown into
China than was ever trucked in over the
old Burma Road and in the skies over
China Japan faces new opposition
young Chinese many of them trained in
the fields of Arizona New Mexico
California fly and fight beside their
American comrades the fighters and
bombers of the Chinese air force and
those of general Chennault
14th Air Force today fly far and wide
over China
hitting enemy concentrations smashing
their sea lanes along the china coast
the same people that moved in nation
2,000 miles to built the Burma Road are
building airfields out of stones mud and
patient tireless hands
today they'll still call by land and sea
from the rest of the world Chinese
armies and Chinese guerrillas still
stand firm against the [ __ ]
the oldest and the youngest of the
world's great nations together with the
British Commonwealth bikes side-by-side
in the struggle that is as old as China
herself the struggle of freedom against
slavery civilization against barbarism
good against evil upon their victory
depends the future of mankind we in
China like you what a better world not
for ourselves alone but for all mankind
and we must have it