♪ Grab your partner ♪
♪ Grab your gal ♪
♪ And rock ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Ya rollin' and ya rollin'
and ya rollin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪
♪ Hop, hop, hop, hop everybody ♪
♪ Hop, hop, hop, hop, everybody ♪
♪ Ya hoppin' and ya hoppin'
and ya hoppin' around ♪
♪ Clap, clap, clap, clap everybody ♪
♪ Ya clappin' and ya clappin'
and ya clappin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Jump, jump, jump, jump everybody ♪
♪ Ya jumpin' and ya jumpin'
and ya jumpin' around ♪
♪ Bump, bump, bump, bump everybody ♪
♪ Ya bumpin' and ya bumpin'
and ya bumpin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Clap, clap, clap everybody ♪
♪ Jump, jump, jump everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ You rockin' and you rockin'
and you rockin' around ♪
♪ They used to try to
put jazz on the trumpet ♪
♪ A fine brunette would sing them songs ♪
♪ Now they shout for the tenor sax ♪
♪ They all give up with a go man go ♪
♪ Everybody shout for the big beat ♪
♪ All across the nation
from coast to coast ♪
♪ In true syncopation
and here's how it goes ♪
♪ Rock, roll, go ♪
♪ Everybody shoutin', everybody singin' ♪
♪ Everybody dancin' ♪
♪ To the big, big, big beat ♪
Is Tommy taking you to the school prom?
He hasn't asked me yet.
He will.
I sure hope I found
someone as nice as Tommy.
Oh, you'll meet him someday.
Well, I hope it's before the prom.
Are you in love with Tommy?
Well...
♪ I ♪
♪ Never had a sweetheart ♪
♪ No lover's ♪
♪ Lane ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ No moonlight rides ♪
♪ No firesides ♪
♪ No romance ♪
♪ By the sea ♪
♪ Oh, no ♪
♪ That's never happened ♪
♪ To me ♪
♪ I ♪
♪ Never had a sweetheart ♪
♪ Like lovers ♪
♪ I would see ♪
♪ When they passed by ♪
♪ I'd sit and sigh ♪
♪ Unhappy ♪
♪ As can be ♪
♪ To know ♪
♪ It's never happened ♪
♪ To me ♪
♪ Then one day ♪
♪ All of a sudden ♪
♪ My true love ♪
♪ Came my way ♪
♪ And I knew that our love ♪
♪ Was here to stay ♪
♪ Now lonely days are over ♪
♪ I'm happy ♪
♪ As can be ♪
♪ He came along ♪
♪ My life's a song ♪
♪ Because I know ♪
♪ That he's ♪
♪ The one ♪
♪ Wonderful, sweetheart ♪
♪ For ♪
♪ Me ♪
Well, that's how I feel.
Oh, I wish I was in love.
I mean, I wish someone
was in love with me.
Anyway, you better keep an eye on Tommy.
That new girl, Gloria, asked me who he was
when he said hello to me in
the school corridor today,
and she's a girl who when
she makes up here mind
to get something--
- Hello.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
- Hi, Tommy.
Well, I have to go.
I have to take care of my kid sister.
Remember what I told
you about you know who.
The school paper's got
these announcements today.
Have you seen them?
Are you going to enter it?
Why don't you enter, too?
Oh, I'd never win.
I think you would.
Hello, Dori.
Hello, Gloria.
Oh, Gloria, this is Tommy.
Tommy, Gloria.
Hi, Gloria.
Hello, Tommy.
Ah, see you later.
Who's she?
Her name's Gloria Barker.
She's new in town.
Well, I have to go now.
Aren't you going to walk me home?
Oh, sure.
Say, I almost forget to tell ya.
Be sure and watch Alan
Freed's television program
tomorrow night.
I never miss it.
What's going to be on tomorrow night?
A surprise.
What kind of a surprise?
Just watch it and see.
I'll ask Arabella to come over my house.
We'll see it together.
Hello, Gloria.
God, what a day I've had.
I went to the dress shop this morning
to order a new evening
dress for the dance.
You're going to wear an
evening dress to the dance?
Strapless, blue, strapless, blue.
A friend of yours told
me it his favorite color.
Well, so long.
Gosh, if she's going to get one,
I'm going to get one, too.
I think you oughta have one.
I think you oughta have all
the things your heart needs,
and I wish I could give them to ya.
♪ I can't give ya diamonds ♪
♪ And I can't give ya pearls ♪
♪ I can't give ya palaces ♪
♪ With princes, dukes and earls ♪
♪ But when it comes to love ♪
♪ You'll have the things
your heart needs ♪
♪ You'll lips who kiss you sweetly ♪
♪ And arms to hold you tight ♪
♪ All my thoughts will be of you ♪
♪ Each morning, noon and night ♪
♪ For when it comes to love ♪
♪ You'll have the things you heart needs ♪
♪ Ooh, I can't give you ♪
♪ Satins or sables ♪
♪ Or things that you may
have been dreaming of ♪
♪ But baby what good are those satins ♪
♪ And those sables ♪
♪ Unless ♪
♪ You've heart full of love ♪
♪ You'll have deep devotion ♪
♪ A love that's just for you ♪
♪ Tenderness and kindness ♪
♪ And the heart that's always true ♪
♪ For when it comes to love ♪
♪ You'll have the things ♪
♪ Your heart needs ♪
Hello?
It's for me.
Hello, Arabella.
What are you doing this
beautiful Saturday afternoon?
My mother's going shopping,
and I have to take care
of my little sister,
so I'm taking her to the movies.
You wanna go?
Gosh, I'd like to, but
I haven't got any M-O-N-E-Y.
What?
I used up my allowance for this week.
Oh, and I only have enough
for me and the B-R-A-T.
Mm, ow.
I tell ya what,
I'll meet you on the terrace
at the country club in half an hour.
I have a plan, goodbye.
Father, give me a dollar, quick.
I have to go somewhere.
Okay, where do you have to go?
- To the movies.
- Oh.
Just a minute, young lady.
Stay right there.
You mean to say you haven't
any money left from your allowance?
I didn't mean to tell you.
I just found out anyway.
I thought you were gonna keep a budget?
I did, but it didn't stay kept.
May I see it?
Uh-huh, ice cream, candy,
magazines, jukebox, forty cents,
E.P., sixty cents.
E.P., what's that?
Elvis Presley.
I still say, what's that?
Father, you're sweet
but so square.
I played Elvis Presley
records on the jukebox.
You already have an item down here
for playing the jukebox.
Why don't you put 'em both together?
Oh, it would look like
I spent too much money
for just one thing.
That is dishonest.
Why, why in business, that's
like keeping two sets of books.
Is that bad?
Bad, it's illegal.
They put men in jail for that.
Oh, well, I have to
go meet Arabella now.
Thanks for the movie money.
Ah, you're welcome.
Now wait a minute.
Wait a minute, I didn't give...
Louise?
What's the matter?
It's that daughter of yours.
Louise, there hasn't been one week
that she hasn't run out of her allowance.
She has no idea of the value of money.
Look at this, look, wait.
Look, bills, bills, nothing but bills.
Bills for clothes, bills for hats,
bills for all sorts of things.
Louise, we've gotta teach that girl
that money doesn't grow on fathers.
Now, first thing Monday morning,
I'm gonna go right down,
and cancel everyone of
our charge accounts.
But supposing she
needs some new clothes?
Nope, Dori's not
gonna get one new thing.
- Hi.
- Hi, Dori.
Hi, baby.
Hello.
Where you waiting long?
Just a few minutes.
Ready to go?
I am, but this one...
Don't you wanna go to the movies?
No.
You wanna a little doll?
- No.
- Don't you want
a storybook?
No.
- Do you want blocks?
- No.
Well then, what do you want?
I know what she wants, come on.
♪ Don't want a dolly ♪
♪ A storybook or blocks ♪
♪ Baby's only happy ♪
♪ Oh, when she rocks ♪
♪ Baby wants to rock ♪
♪ Rock ♪
♪ Baby wants to roll ♪
♪ Roll ♪
♪ Baby wants to tap ♪
♪ Well bless my soul ♪
♪ Baby wants to dance ♪
♪ Dance ♪
♪ Dance from head to toe ♪
♪ Go ♪
♪ Baby wants to rock ♪
♪ And go, go, go ♪
♪ Rock pretty baby ♪
♪ Roll pretty baby ♪
♪ Don't mean maybe ♪
♪ Dance pretty baby ♪
♪ Jump pretty baby ♪
♪ Dance to the rock'n roll beat ♪
♪ I don't want a lollipop ♪
♪ In my hand ♪
♪ I just wanna dance to a rockin' band ♪
♪ Then rock pretty baby ♪
♪ Roll pretty baby ♪
♪ Rock pretty baby ♪
♪ Don't mean maybe ♪
♪ Dance pretty baby ♪
♪ Jump pretty baby ♪
♪ Baby, you're doin' alright ♪
♪ So keep on rockin' ♪
♪ Day and night ♪
♪ I don't want a lollipop in my hand ♪
♪ I just wanna dance to a rockin' band ♪
♪ Then rock pretty baby ♪
♪ Roll pretty baby ♪
♪ Rock pretty baby ♪
♪ Don't mean maybe ♪
♪ Dance pretty baby ♪
♪ Jump pretty baby ♪
♪ Baby, you're doin' alright ♪
♪ I'm hip to the light ♪
♪ And manners for days ♪
♪ Rock ♪
♪ Anytime ♪
And here it is,
Alan Freed's Rock'n Roll Party.
And here he is in person, Alan Freed.
Hello, everybody, how y'all?
Welcome to our Rock'n
Roll Jubilee Of Stars,
and here we go to rockin'
with Wayland Tenneman and Freddy Mitchell
and the Rock'n Roll Boogie, here we go.
♪ Rock'n roll boogie ♪
♪ Yes, the rock'n roll boogie ♪
♪ It's the blue star boogie ♪
♪ We want rock'n roll ♪
♪ All night long ♪
♪ Go, move ♪
♪ Blow, Freddie, blow ♪
♪ Yes, yes, blow ♪
♪ It's the rock'n roll boogie ♪
♪ Yes, the rock'n roll boogie ♪
How about that?
And now, one of America's
top rock'n roll vocal groups.
Here The Moonglows and
I Knew From The Start.
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Oooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I knew from the start ♪
♪ That you were the only girl for me ♪
♪ And I knew ♪
♪ From the start ♪
♪ That ours was a love
that was destined to be ♪
♪ And I knew ♪
♪ From the start ♪
♪ You were the one for me ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Yes I knew ♪
♪ At a glance ♪
♪ That you were the
only one for my heart ♪
♪ And I knew ♪
♪ At a glance ♪
♪ That cupid had has flown ♪
♪ And then loosened his dart ♪
♪ And I knew ♪
♪ At a glance ♪
♪ That you are the one for me ♪
♪ Ah, ah ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ I waited ♪
♪ It seems like forever ♪
♪ For true love to come my way ♪
♪ I'm so glad that I ♪
♪ Was so clever ♪
♪ To know that I'd meet you someday ♪
♪ Whoa, whoa, I knew from the start ♪
♪ That you were an angel
and you were divine ♪
♪ And I knew from the start ♪
♪ From here to eternity
you would be mine ♪
♪ And I knew from the start ♪
♪ You were the one ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Oooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, ba ♪
♪ Bah ♪
Yo gang, you all remember Maybellene.
About the young man with the guitar
who couldn't catch her with his car?
Well, here is to tell us all about it
with a brand new automobile,
Chuck Berry and You Can't Catch Me.
♪ I bought a brand new air-mobile ♪
♪ It's custom made,
was a Flight De Ville ♪
♪ With a powerful motor
and some hideaway wings ♪
♪ Push in on the button
and you can hear her sing ♪
♪ Now you can't catch me ♪
♪ Baby, you can't catch me ♪
♪ 'Cause if you get too close ♪
♪ You know I'm gone like a cool breeze ♪
♪ New Jersey Turnpike
in the wee, wee hours ♪
♪ I was rollin' slowly
'cause of drizzlin' showers ♪
♪ Here come a flat-top,
he was movin' up with me ♪
♪ Then come wavin' goodbye ♪
♪ In a little ole souped-up jitney ♪
♪ I put my foot in my
tank and I began to roll ♪
♪ Moanin' siren, twas the state patrol ♪
♪ So I let out my wings
and then I blew my horn ♪
♪ Bye, bye New Jersey,
I've become airborne ♪
♪ Now you can't catch me ♪
♪ Baby, you can't catch me ♪
♪ 'Cause if you get too close ♪
♪ You know I'm gone like a cool breeze ♪
♪ Flyin' with my baby
last Saturday night ♪
♪ Wasn't a gray cloud floatin' in sight ♪
♪ Big full moon shinin' up above ♪
♪ Cuddle up honey, be my love ♪
♪ Sweetest little thing I've ever seen ♪
♪ I'm gonna name you Maybellene ♪
♪ Flyin' on the beam,
set on flight control ♪
♪ Radio tuned to rock'n roll ♪
♪ Two, three hours done passed us by ♪
♪ Five to two dropped to 5:05 ♪
♪ Fuel consumption way too fast ♪
♪ Let's get on home
before we run out of gas ♪
♪ Now you can't catch me ♪
♪ No baby, you can't catch me ♪
♪ 'Cause if you get too close ♪
♪ You know I'm gone like a cool breeze ♪
Now gang, here's America's
original rock'n roll vocal group.
From Chicago, Illinois,
here are the Fabulous Flamingos
to sing Would I be Crying?
♪ I ♪
♪ Can't be lying ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Can't you see that I'm crying ♪
♪ Would I be ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Crying ♪
♪ If I were lying to you ♪
♪ My heart's ♪
♪ About to break ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ I regret making ♪
♪ My mistake ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ My love ♪
♪ For you burns the same ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ And my tears can't ♪
♪ Put off, off the blame ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Would you forgive me ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Oh, darling ♪
♪ Forgive me ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ You must believe me ♪
♪ I will always be true ♪
♪ Would I ♪
♪ Be crying ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ My heart out for you ♪
♪ And hurting the way I do ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Would I be crying ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ If I were lying ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Won't you ♪
♪ Forgive me ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, darling ♪
♪ Forgive me ♪
♪ You must believe me ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ I will always be true ♪
♪ Would I be crying ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ My heart out for you ♪
♪ And hurting the way I do ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Would I ♪
♪ Be crying ♪
♪ If I were lying ♪
♪ To ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
Now, nail down the roof, gang
because here's a new act
that can blow it right off.
The sensational Jimmy
Cavallo and his House Rockers
and The Big Beat.
♪ They used to dance to
the two-step and tango ♪
♪ And hopty-hopped to the Dixieland ♪
♪ Now they dance to rock'n roll ♪
♪ To big, big beat of a rockin' band ♪
♪ Everybody dancin' to the big beat ♪
♪ All across the nation
from coast to coast ♪
♪ In true syncopation
and here's how it goes ♪
♪ Rock, roll, go ♪
♪ Everybody dance to the big beat ♪
♪ They used to sing to wide open spaces ♪
♪ They used to groove so soft and sweet ♪
♪ But now to be real up to date ♪
♪ You shout it out with a big, big, beat ♪
♪ Everybody's singin' to the big beat ♪
♪ Everybody's singing' to the big beat ♪
♪ All across the nation
from coast to coast ♪
♪ In true syncopation
and here's how it goes ♪
♪ Rock, roll, go, blow ♪
♪ They use to try to put
jazz on the trumpet ♪
♪ A fine brunette would sing them songs ♪
♪ Now they shout for the tenor sax ♪
♪ They all give up with go man go ♪
♪ Everybody's shoutin' for the big beat ♪
♪ All across the nation
from coast to coast ♪
♪ In true syncopation
and here's how it goes ♪
♪ Rock, roll, go ♪
♪ Everybody's shoutin',
Everybody's singin' ♪
♪ Everybody's dancin' ♪
♪ To the big, big, big, beat ♪
And now, here's that crucial moment
that we wait for every week.
The winner of our Rock'n Roll
Talent Contest for this week.
A wonderful young man
who sings a great song,
and you'll be hearing plenty about him.
Tommy Rogers and Thanks To You.
♪ Thanks ♪
♪ To you ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪
♪ I've begun to live ♪
♪ Thanks to you ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪
♪ Now it's fun to live ♪
♪ I never knew that life ♪
♪ Could be such a glorious story ♪
♪ Until you came my way ♪
♪ And put the glow ♪
♪ In glory ♪
♪ What a thrill ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪
♪ Sharing love with you ♪
♪ Now I know ♪
♪ Doo, doo, doo ♪
♪ What true love can do ♪
♪ My life was once a wilderness ♪
♪ The way I was lonely and blue ♪
♪ Now I found true happiness ♪
♪ Thanks to you ♪
♪ My life was once a wilderness ♪
♪ The way I was lonely and blue ♪
♪ But I found true happiness ♪
♪ Thanks to you ♪
I bet I know what you're thinking.
Hmm, now that he's won the contest...
That Gloria will want
him more than ever.
And she's going to wear an
evening dress to the dance.
A blue evening dress.
And strapless.
There's just one thing to do.
I'll go down to the dress
shop tomorrow and get one, too.
But please, Miss Silky.
Now girls, you'll just have to wait,
and I'll take care of you one at a time.
I have a customer in the
fitting room right now,
and I'll be out as soon
as I'm finished with her.
Come along.
You're next, aren't you?
Uh-huh.
It seems like everybody
wants an evening dress
since they know that Gloria
was going to get one.
Ah, I wish I had someone to
wear an evening dress for.
Oh, you'll meet him someday.
Just like that, you'll see.
I don't know.
Sometimes I think I'll never meet him.
Pardon me, could you tell
me where the proprietress is?
Miss Silky's in the back.
That's him.
I know that's him.
Who?
My dream man.
His name is Melville.
Melville.
He's in my French class.
- He is?
- Uh-huh.
And I had to take Spanish.
Oh, Melville, I'd like
you to meet Arabella.
Arabella, Melville.
Pleased to meet you.
Why didn't you say something?
He's beautiful.
Now Dori, what can I do for you?
I'd like to get an evening dress.
There's a nice one in
the window for $30.00.
The blue one.
And are you going to pay for it now?
Why, no, I'm going to
charge it like I always do.
And haven't you heard?
What?
Your father closed your
charge account this morning.
He did?
I'm sorry.
Gosh.
Are the dishes done already?
- Mm-hmm.
Dori helped me.
Dori did?
That's strange.
I thought so, too.
She's taking an awfully long time.
I hope she's doing them right.
Dori doing the dishes?
Comfy?
Oh, sure.
Dori?
Yes, Father?
Is there something on your mind?
As a matter of fact, there is.
You see, Father, I went
to the dress shop today,
and Miss Silky told me that we didn't have
a charge account there anymore and,
well I've just have to get an
evening dress for the prom.
An evening dress, huh?
I saw a beautiful one
there for only $30.00.
Only $30.00?
Do you realize, young lady,
how difficult it is to earn $30.00?
I know, but I need this dress so badly.
Well, when is this dance of yours?
Two weeks from Saturday.
When's the latest you
can order the dress?
Oh, about three days
before the dance, why?
Well, I'll tell ya what
I'm gonna do with ya.
Now the dress is $30.00, huh?
Alright, I'll give $15.00,
if you earn the other 15.
Oh.
Maybe when you find out how
difficult it is to earn money,
then you'll spend it a little less freely.
Where am I going to get $15.00?
Well, Dori Graham, how are you?
Very well, thank you, Mr. Bimble.
Ah, sit down.
Well now Dori, how can I help you?
I'd like to borrow some money.
What?
Well, isn't that what banks are for?
Well, yes, true, but we don't lend money
without business references, collateral.
What's collateral?
Collateral, well that's
something that people pledge
that's worth as much as the
amount of money we lend them.
When someone puts money in your bank,
what do you do with it?
Well, I don't really know.
You mean to tell me, Mr. Bimble,
that you take people's money
and don't know what you do with it?
Well, of course I
know what we do with it.
What I mean there is that I don't know
where any particular deposit goes.
You mean, the deposits are all mixed up?
No, no, no.
They're kept in order by bookkeeping.
Double-entry bookkeeping.
You keep two sets of books?
I do not keep two sets, I...
Oh, Dori Graham, let--
When depositors put money in your bank,
where do you get the
money to pay in interest?
Well, ah, the bank makes its money
by giving loans to responsible
people who have collateral,
and charging interest on the loans.
How much interest do you charge?
6%.
That's awfully high, isn't it?
6% interest is standard.
- It is?
- Yes.
Seems awfully high to me.
Suppose some person came along,
and charged less interest than you do.
Well, I'd bet pretty soon,
they'd take all your business
away from you, wouldn't he?
Mr. Bimble, you've given me something
more valuable than money.
You've given me knowledge.
Thank you, Mr. Bimble.
Arabella, how would you
like to be wallowing...
Arabella, how would you like
to be wallowing in money?
Huh?
I just thought of the most wonderful way
to make money to pay for my evening dress.
I'm going to be a banker.
You?
Sure, I'm going to lend
money and get interest on it.
Where will you get the money?
That's where you can help me.
All I've got in the world is $15.00,
and that's in Mr. Bimble's bank.
Oh, but that's terrible.
You'll have to get it out right away.
They're dishonest.
How do ya know?
They keep two sets of books
and that's a government offense.
My father told me so.
Why they can close the bank any minute,
and take them all off to jail.
Gosh, I'd better get my money out.
Then you can put it in my bank.
Oh, it will earn scads of interest.
Now, you go down and get your money
out of Mr. Bimble's bank right away.
But I have to go to class.
Which would you rather
be, ignorant or bankrupt?
That's a good question.
C'mon.
What's the matter?
Oh, it's nothing.
I saw Melville again.
He spoke to me.
And?
I couldn't think of
anything to say back.
Well if he spoke to you,
he must be interested.
Maybe next time you'll
think of something to say.
I sure hope so.
Hey, kids, listen to me.
Knock it off.
Phil, go get the jukebox.
I got great news for ya.
After the television show,
I asked Alan Freed if he'd
come down to our prom.
I just talked to Alan on the phone,
he's comin' and he's bring a whole show.
So, we're gonna rock tonight.
♪ Gonna rock ♪
♪ Gonna rock, rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ Gonna call for my baby
about a quarter to eight ♪
♪ And be there on time
'cause it never starts late ♪
♪ Oh, me and my baby say
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna rock with my doll
about a quarter to nine ♪
♪ 'Cause nobody else
but the baby of mine ♪
♪ Oh, me and my baby say
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna rock ♪
♪ Gonna rock, rock,
rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ Gonna keep on rockin'
'til a quarter to 10 ♪
♪ Come up for air and go rockin' again ♪
♪ Oh, me and my baby say
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna keep on rockin'
'til a quarter to 11 ♪
♪ And rock along up half ways to heaven ♪
♪ 'Cause me and my baby say
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna rock ♪
♪ Gonna rock, rock,
rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ Gonna go on rockin'
'til a quarter to 12 ♪
♪ Havin' a ball enjoying ourselves ♪
♪ 'Cause me and my baby,
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna get to the door
about a quarter to one ♪
♪ Kiss for awhile, what a barrel of fun ♪
♪ 'Cause me and my baby say
we're gonna rock tonight ♪
♪ Gonna rock ♪
♪ Gonna rock, rock,
rock, rock, rock, rock ♪
♪ Gonna kiss goodnight
with a quarter to two ♪
♪ With a heart full of love
and a hole in my shoe ♪
♪ 'Cause me and my baby ♪
♪ We're gonna rock tonight ♪
Hello, Dori.
Oh, hello, Gloria.
I've just picked up
my new evening dress.
Oh.
Have you gotten yours yet?
Well, I haven't had time yet but I will.
By the way, Gloria, do you need money?
I always need money.
Then I'm the one who can lend it to you.
I've just gone into the banking business.
What?
I'm lending money.
$1.00 until next allowance
day to anyone who needs it.
What's your rate of interest?
Well, the bank charges as high as 6%,
but I'm only charging one.
Just 1%?
If I lend you a dollar,
you pay it back to me plus
another dollar interest.
Another dollar interest?
It's a bargain when you think
the banks are charging as much as 6%.
Are you sure you're charging
$1.00 interest on the dollar?
1% of a dollar is a dollar, isn't it?
Oh, sure, sure.
Tell me, Dori, have you
lent much money yet?
You're the first person I've asked.
Mm-hmm, where'd you
get the money to lend?
From Arabella.
She's my depositor.
How much did she deposit?
$15.00.
Dori, instead of trying to find a lot
of little $1.00 customers,
how would you like to lend the
whole 15 to just one person?
Who?
Me, with $15.00 more,
I could take this tacky ole evening dress
back to the dress shop.
I saw a much smarter one there for $45.00.
It just came in.
If you lend me the 15 to
buy it, I'll pay ya back
plus another 15 for interest.
You'll make $15.00 fast.
When will you pay it back?
My birthday's next week.
I'm expecting a couple of checks.
I'll pay ya back then.
Will you give me collateral?
What kind of collateral?
Oh, I don't know.
It has to be something
worth at least $30.00.
Tell you what, I'll pledge my new dress.
The one I'm going to get.
Alright, you write me a note saying,
that if you don't pay me
back, I can have the dress.
Then I'll lend you the $15.00.
It's a deal.
Tommy, can I ask you something?
- Sure.
- Come here.
Tommy, what do you think the school
would think of a girl who took advantage
of one of her own classmates?
Well, I guess they
wouldn't like here very much.
Suppose this girl learned
that one of her classmates
needed money very badly,
and she lent it to her?
Well that's not taking advantage.
That's pretty nice.
But what if she lent it to her
on condition that she pay it back double?
Double?
Who'd do a thing like that?
Dori.
Dori?
I don't believe it.
You can ask her.
But why?
She was just trying to
make some money for herself.
Who told you all this?
I'm the one she lent the money to.
That's terrible.
Would be even more terrible
if the whole school found out about it.
Of course, I might be persuaded
not to tell anyone about it.
What do you mean?
Well, if you took me to
the prom instead of Dori,
I might just possibly
forget the whole thing.
But I already asked Dori.
You can always say you
forget you'd asked me first.
I can't do that.
Would you rather the whole school
knew about what Dori tried to do to me?
Nobody would talk to her for months.
Dori, wait a minute.
Dori, I got wonderful news.
- What is it?
- It's Melville.
He's taking me to the prom.
He asked me just five minutes ago.
Oh, that's wonderful.
This is my big chance.
That's why I need the $15.00 I gave you.
Oh, no.
I've got to get a permed, a manicure,
and maybe even a facial,
so give me back the money.
I've already loaned it out.
Then get it back.
A depositor has the right
to get her money back
when she wants it, doesn't she?
Well, yes, but--
Well this is an emergency.
Arabella, I just can't.
Dori Graham, if you
don't give me back my money
by tomorrow, I'll, I'll
never speak to you again.
Arabella?
Gloria, come here.
Gloria, I wanna talk to you.
Well?
It's about that money you borrowed.
Your birthday was last week,
and you still haven't paid it back to me.
Oh, that, you really didn't think
I was going to pay it back, did you?
Besides, my birthday isn't
until five months from now.
But you told me that--
And you told me you
wanted $1.00 interest
on every dollar you lent me.
For your information, that's
not 1% interest, that's 100%.
It is?
If you knew any arithmetic,
you'd know that 1% of a
dollar is .01 not $1.00.
Why I could send you
to jail for extortion.
Well, what about the $15.00?
You'll return that to me, won't you?
In my own good time.
Maybe a dollar a week.
But I need the money now.
Oh, isn't that too bad.
Well, I've gotta study for my next class,
and, uh, you'd better brush
up on your arithmetic.
Dori?
Oh.
Hello, Tommy.
What's the matter?
Oh, nothing.
Have you been talking to Gloria?
Did she tell you?
Tell me what?
That's she going to the prom with me.
What?
I asked her weeks ago,
and I'd thought she'd forgotten about it.
Gloria
and you?
Oh, Tommy.
Poor little bird.
I know just how you feel.
♪ Little blue wren ♪
♪ I know why ♪
♪ Why you cry ♪
♪ Nobody knows ♪
♪ Nobody cares ♪
♪ That your love has flown away ♪
♪ Little blue wren ♪
♪ In the sky ♪
♪ Way up high ♪
♪ Love didn't stay ♪
♪ It flew away ♪
♪ Now your heart's ♪
♪ No longer gay ♪
♪ With your head ♪
♪ Upon your shoulder ♪
♪ You just cry ♪
♪ And hope that he ♪
♪ Will return ♪
♪ Before you're older ♪
♪ And I know 'cause it happened to me ♪
♪ So little blue wren ♪
♪ In a tree ♪
♪ Little blue wren ♪
♪ Wait and see ♪
♪ Some day he'll know ♪
♪ You love him so ♪
♪ And then he'll ♪
♪ Come back again ♪
♪ And you'll ♪
♪ No more be ♪
♪ A little ♪
♪ Blue ♪
♪ Wren ♪
Well, what's the matter now?
Oh, nothing.
Father, if a person lends
another person money,
and the other person refuses to pay,
can that person do anything
to the other person?
Well, that depends.
Did the other person give the person
any collateral for the loan?
Yeah, she did.
Well, then the person can foreclose.
Foreclose?
Uh-huh, assume ownership
of the collateral
in lieu of the unpaid loan.
Assume ownership, really?
It's the law.
Hey, where are you going,
it's almost dinner time?
Tell Mother not to
wait, I'll be back later.
But it's very simple, Miss Silky.
I just wanna foreclose
on a collateral dress.
But I don't understand?
Is this some kind of joke?
It's absolutely serious.
Would you mind waiting just a minute?
Miss Silky, is my dress almost ready?
Just a minute.
Here it is.
Oh.
It's so beautiful.
I can't wait to see what
it looks like on me.
Dori?
Thank you for calling me, Miss Silky.
Father, what are you doing here?
This is a ladies shop.
Miss Silky called me,
and told me she'd keep you here
until I could get here.
Now what's this all about?
Yeah, that's what I wanna know.
I tried to tell you on
the phone, Mr. Barker.
Dori says your daughter
borrowed some money from her
and refused to pay it back,
and now she's claiming this dress.
I'm just foreclosing on the collateral.
You mean, Gloria gave you this dress
as collateral for a loan?
Why did you have to borrow money?
Well, I didn't really like
the $30.00 dress you bought me,
and I happened to see this
beautiful dress for $45.00,
and I knew you wouldn't
give me anymore money, so--
So you borrowed it from my daughter,
but where did Dori get it to lend?
She borrowed it form Arabella.
No, I didn't.
Arabella was my depositor.
But I don't have to pay the money back
because Dori charged me 100% interest
when she gave me the money,
and that's against the law.
100% interest?
Dori.
I made a mistake, Father.
I thought I was charging 1%.
Never was very good at arithmetic
but she knew it, and she didn't tell me.
Besides, you said the dress
belonged to me as collateral.
Well, yes, it does legally.
Now wait just a minute.
I paid $30.00 for that dress.
And I paid another $15.00.
I'm not going to let you take
a $45.00 dress for a $15.00 loan.
Well, there's only
one other thing to do.
Pay Dori the money that
Gloria borrowed from her,
and forget the whole the thing.
I'm not going to pay Gloria's debt.
Well, I admit, you got me stumped.
Do you have any other suggestions?
- No.
- Do you?
No.
I have a suggestion.
Mr. Barker just wants his $30.00.
Right.
Father, here's a chance for
you to make a real bargain.
All you have to do is give
Mr. Barker his $30.00,
and you get a $45.00 dollar
dress for only $30.00.
Yeah, sounds good.
Now, wait a minute, young lady.
Our agreement was that I pay $15.00,
and you earn the other 15.
Yes, but I'm saving you $15.00
at the price of the dress.
Now that's the same as if
I earned $15.00, isn't it?
Now, just do as I say.
First, give Gloria's
father his money back.
Now, the dress is mine.
But you still have to
give Arabella her $15.00.
How do you think you'll get around that?
Oh, that's simple.
Here, Miss Silky, I'd like
to turn this $45.00 dress in
for the $30.00 dress and a $15.00 refund.
Now you can get the dress for me.
It's only $15.00 more.
After all the trouble you've caused?
Trying to take advantage of Dori?
Sneaking behind my back to
buy a dress that costs more?
Nothing doing, Gloria.
I don't buy any dress for you.
Not even a $30.00 one?
Sorry, this is the last one left.
A blue strapless dress.
Tommy's favorite color.
She's taking my dress.
Come on, we're going home.
Oh.
Now let me see.
Dori saved me $15.00,
so that's the same as earning $15.00.
Then she took the dress,
she exchanged the $45.00
dress for the $30.00 dress--
Here's your refund, Dori.
Come in in the morning,
and we'll fit the dress.
Thank you, Miss Silky.
We'd better go home, Father.
Dinner's probably still waiting.
Father, are you alright?
Oh, yeah, yeah, sure.
Oh, goodnight, Miss Silky.
Everybody quiet.
Alright, let's get this prom rocking
with Jimmy Cavallo and the House Rockers
and Rock, Rock, Rock.
♪ Grab your partner ♪
♪ Grab your gal ♪
♪ And rock ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Ya rollin' and ya rollin'
and ya rollin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪
♪ Hop, hop, hop, hop everybody ♪
♪ Ya hoppin' and ya hoppin'
and ya hoppin' around ♪
♪ Clap, clap, clap, clap everybody ♪
♪ Ya clappin' and ya clappin'
and ya clappin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Jump, jump, jump, jump everybody ♪
♪ Jump, jump, jump, jump, jump everybody ♪
♪ Ya jumpin' and ya jumpin'
and ya jumpin' around ♪
♪ Bump, bump, bump, bump everybody ♪
♪ Ya bumpin' and ya bumpin'
and ya bumpin' around ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Clap, clap, clap everybody ♪
♪ Jump, jump, jump everybody ♪
♪ Roll, roll, roll everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪
Rock'n roll is a river of music
which has absorbed many streams.
Rhythm and blues, jazz, ragtime,
cowboy songs, country songs, folk songs,
all have contributed
greatly to the big beat,
and here's a young man who's come out
of the country field to
join us rock'n rollers.
Johnny Burnette singing Lonesome Train.
♪ Lonesome train on a lonesome track ♪
♪ I'm going away, ain't coming back ♪
♪ I'm going somewhere far from my baby ♪
♪ On a lonesome train,
on a lonesome track ♪
♪ A Lonesome train, on a lonesome track ♪
♪ Got all my troubles in one big pack ♪
♪ My baby left me so sad and lonely ♪
♪ On a lonesome train,
on a lonesome track ♪
♪ Lonesome train, on a lonesome track ♪
♪ My girl don't love
me and that's a fact ♪
♪ No use in living, no use in dying ♪
♪ On a lonesome train,
on a lonesome track ♪
♪ Oh, a lonesome train,
♪ I want my baby, I want her back ♪
♪ Don't want to go on forever traveling ♪
♪ On a lonesome train,
on a lonesome track ♪
And now, here's one of
your favorite vocal groups.
The Moonglows, the sincerely kids,
singing Over and Over Again.
♪ Doo ♪
♪ Ooh, wee, doo ♪
♪ Doo, doo ♪
♪ Doo ♪
♪ Ooh, wee, doo ♪
♪ You hurt me over and over again ♪
♪ And I cried over and over again ♪
♪ Why do I listen to all of your lies ♪
♪ I love you, that's why ♪
♪ Love you, that's why ♪
♪ I beg you over and over again ♪
♪ I pleaded over and over again ♪
♪ Why don't I pack up
and tell you goodbye ♪
♪ I love you, that's why ♪
♪ Love you, that's why ♪
♪ My heart refuses to learn ♪
♪ It speaks your name all the time ♪
♪ My heart says you will return ♪
♪ And fill these empty heart of mine ♪
♪ I give in over and over again ♪
♪ And you win over and over again ♪
♪ And if you ask me the reason why ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ That's ♪
♪ Why ♪
♪ Love you, that's why ♪
And now, let's get
into a real happy mood
with a tweedly-dee girl, La
Verne Baker and Tra La La.
♪ Tra la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ You're as sweet as a candy bar ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, ly ♪
♪ I'm so happy that I could cry ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ You're as cute as a movie star ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, lo ♪
♪ I'd be crazy to let you go ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, loo ♪
♪ All my lovin' is just for you ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ A wolf whistle goes, I don't know how ♪
♪ So I'm singin' ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ I love you just the way you are ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, lee ♪
♪ I'm as happy as I can be ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, loo ♪
♪ All my lovin' is just for you ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ A wolf whistle goes, I don't know how ♪
♪ So I'm singin' ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, la ♪
♪ I love you just the way you are ♪
♪ Tra, la, la, tra, la, lee ♪
♪ I'm as happy ♪
♪ As I ♪
♪ Can be ♪
And now, here's a
wonderful singing group
with a great song.
Cirino and the Bowties
from Brooklyn, New York
and Ever Since I can Remember.
Where's Cirino and the Bowties?
They must be cruisin' again.
Oh, there they are.
♪ When the kids were
playin' cops and robbers ♪
♪ I was buying lollipops for two ♪
♪ Ever since I can remember ♪
♪ I've been in love with you ♪
♪ When the guys were
choosin' sides for baseball ♪
♪ I was dreamin' of two eyes of blue ♪
♪ Every since I can remember ♪
♪ I've been in love with you ♪
♪ Then to junior high ♪
♪ The time flew by ♪
♪ Until the senior dance ♪
♪ From the first we kissed ♪
♪ I knew that this was not
just a childhood romance ♪
♪ Now the dreams we spun
for fun as roommates ♪
♪ Every day another one comes true ♪
♪ Ever since I can remember ♪
♪ Somehow I always knew ♪
♪ I'd never loved ♪
♪ Anyone ♪
♪ But ♪
♪ You ♪
I don't know what I can
say about this next act.
What can you say but sensational?
All over the world, Frankie Lymon.
A 13 year old youngster with
a great way with a song,
and the Teenagers.
♪ Baby, baby, da-da-da-da ♪
♪ Da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da ♪
♪ Da-da-da-da-da-da, whop,
whop, boom, boom, whop, whop ♪
♪ Baby, baby, how I want you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, how I need you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, your the only ♪
♪ One, two, three, four ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ Baby, baby, how I miss you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, long to kiss you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, say you want me ♪
♪ Two, three, four, five ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ You're my favorite number,
all that counts is you ♪
♪ I'm so glad it's you I want ♪
♪ I'm so glad you want me too ♪
♪ Baby, baby, want to bring you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, a wedding ring too ♪
♪ Baby, baby, soon we'll be ♪
♪ Three, four, five, six, stop ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ Baby, baby, when I'm near you ♪
♪ Baby, baby, I go right to ♪
♪ Baby, baby, heaven number ♪
♪ Seven, eight, nine, 10 ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ Baby, baby, in your arms dear ♪
♪ Baby, baby, all your charms dear ♪
♪ Baby, baby, I appreciate ♪
♪ Nine, 10, 11 ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ You're my favorite number,
all that counts is you ♪
♪ I'm so glad it's you I want ♪
♪ I'm so glad you want me too ♪
♪ Baby, baby, hug me tight dear ♪
♪ Baby, baby, with all your might dear ♪
♪ Baby, baby 'til the clock strikes ♪
♪ Nine, 10, 11, 12 ♪
♪ Boom, boom ♪
♪ Go home ♪
♪ That's all, bye-bye ♪
♪ I'm not a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no ♪
♪ No, no, no, I'm not
a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ Do the thing that's right ♪
♪ And you'll do nothing wrong ♪
♪ And life will be so nice,
you'll be in paradise ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Because I'm not a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ But listen boys and girls ♪
♪ You need not be blue ♪
♪ And life is what you make of it ♪
♪ It all depends on you ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Because I'm not a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ It's easy to be good,
it's hard to be bad ♪
♪ Stay out of trouble,
and you'll be glad ♪
♪ Take this tip from
me, and you will see ♪
♪ How happy you will be ♪
♪ Oh, oh, boys and girls ♪
♪ This is my story ♪
♪ And I add ♪
♪ All of my glory ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Because I'm not a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ It's easy to be good,
it's hard to be bad ♪
♪ Stay out of trouble,
and you'll be glad ♪
♪ Take this tip from
me, and you will see ♪
♪ How happy you will be ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, boys and girls ♪
♪ This is my story ♪
♪ And I add ♪
♪ All of my glory ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Because I'm not a juvenile delinquent ♪
♪ No, no, no ♪
♪ I'm not a juvenile ♪
Want some more?
Dori, I've gotta talk to you.
I told you on the phone,
I have nothing more to say to you.
Gloria made me take her to the prom.
How could she make you take her?
She said she'd tell everyone in school
about you trying to cheat
her out of some money
unless I took her.
And you believed her?
I didn't believe you'd do anything bad,
but I believed she'd tell everybody.
And now, here is your own singing star,
Tommy Rogers.
Go on.
This song is for someone very special
who knows who she is.
♪ I was wrong to make you cry ♪
♪ I will love you 'til I die ♪
♪ Give one more chance ♪
♪ Won't you give me a chance ♪
♪ To give ♪
♪ My heart to you ♪
♪ Won't give me a chance ♪
♪ To be ♪
♪ A part of you ♪
♪ When I see you holding ♪
♪ Someone in your arms ♪
♪ So tenderly ♪
♪ How I wish that someone ♪
♪ Someone, someway, somehow ♪
♪ Ooh, someday ♪
♪ It could be me ♪
♪ Won't you give just a glance ♪
♪ Please give me a glance ♪
♪ In my direction ♪
♪ Won't you give me a chance ♪
♪ Please give me one chance ♪
♪ For your affection ♪
♪ I know that you and I ♪
♪ Were made for the perfect romance ♪
♪ And I can prove it to you ♪
♪ If you give me a chance ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ That you and I ♪
♪ Were made for the perfect romance ♪
♪ And I can prove it to you ♪
♪ If you give me a chance ♪
♪ I was wrong to make you cry ♪
♪ I will love you 'til I die ♪
♪ Give me one more chance ♪
Tommy, I'm sorry I didn't
give you a chance to explain.
And I'm sorry I even could have thought
for a minute...
And now, everybody, let's really rock
with Big Al Sears and our big
band and Right Now, Right Now.
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock everybody ♪
♪ Rock, rock, rock, rock, everybody ♪
♪ Ya rockin' and ya rockin'
and ya rockin' around ♪