Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Spirituality is a particular term which
actually means: a dealing with intuition.
In the theistic tradition there is
a notion of clinging into a word.
A certain act is regarded as
displeasing to a divine principle...
pleasing for the divine... whatever.
In the tradition of non-theism,
however, it is very direct...
that the case histories are
not particularly important.
What is actually important
is Here and Now.
Now is definitely now.
We try to experience what is
available there... on the spot.
There is no point in thinking that a
past did exist that we could have now.
This is now.
This very moment.
Nothing mystical, just 'Now',
very simple, straightforward.
And from that Now-ness, however,
arises a sense of intelligence always
that you are constantly
interacting with reality one by one.
Spot by spot.
Constantly.
We actually experience
fantastic precision, always.
But we are threatened by the Now so
we jump to the past or the future.
Paying attention to the materials
that exist in our life...
such rich life that we lead
all these choices take
place all the time...
but none of them are
regarded as bad or good per se.
Everything we experience
are unconditional experiences.
They don't come along
with a label saying
'this is regarded as bad'
or 'this is good'.
But we experience them but we don't
actually pay heed to them properly.
We don't actually regard
that we are going somewhere.
We regard that
as a hassle.
Waiting to be dead.
That is a problem. That is not
trusting the Now-ness properly;
that what is actually experienced Now
possesses a lot of powerful things.
It is so powerful
that we can't face it.
Therefore,
we have to borrow from the past
and invite the future
all the time.
And maybe that's
why we seek religion.
Maybe that's why
we march in the street.
we complain to society.
Maybe that's why
we vote for the presidents.
It is quite ironical...
Very funny indeed.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
The more you begin to investigate...
What we think we understand,
where we came from,
what we think we're doing,
the more you begin to see
we've been lied to.
We've been lied to
by every institution.
What makes you think for one minute
that the religious institution
is the only one that's
never been touched?
The religious institutions of this
world are at the bottom of the dirt.
The religious institutions in this
world are put there by the same people
who gave you your government,
your corrupt education,
who set up your
international banking cartels.
Because our masters don't give
a damn about you or your family.
All they care about is what
they have always cared about
and that's controlling
the whole damn world.
We have been misled away from the true
and divine presence in the universe
that men have called God.
I don't know what God is
but I know what he isn't,
and unless and until you are
prepared to look at the whole truth,
and wherever it may go,
whoever it may lead to,
if you want to look the other way
or if you want to play favorites,
then somewhere along the line
you're going to find out
you're messing with
divine justice.
The more you educate yourself, the more
you understand where things come from
the more obvious things become and
you begin to see lies everywhere.
You have to know the truth and seek the
truth and the truth will set you free.
Because I gotta tell you the truth,
folks, I gotta tell you the truth.
When it comes to bullshit,
big-time, major league bullshit,
you have to stand in awe,
of the all-time champion of false
promises and exaggerated claims--
Religion.
Think about it.
Religion has actually
convinced people that
there's an invisible man
living in the sky
who watches everything you do,
every minute of every day.
And the invisible man
has a special list
of ten things he does
not want you to do.
And if you do any of these ten things,
he has a special place, full of fire
and smoke and burning
and torture and anguish,
where he will send you to live
and suffer
and burn and choke
and scream and cry
forever and ever
'til the end of time!
But He loves you.
He loves you, and he needs money!
He always needs money!
He's all-powerful, all-perfect,
all-knowing, and all-wise,
somehow
just can't handle money!
Religion takes in billions of dollars,
they pay no taxes,
and they always need
a little more.
Now, you talk about a good
bullshit story. Holy Shit!
This is the sun.
As far back as 10 thousand B.C.,
history is abundant
with carvings and writings
reflecting peoples respect
and adoration for this object.
And it is simple to understand why
as every morning the sun would rise,
bringing vision, warmth, and security,
saving man from the cold, blind,
predator-filled darkness of night.
Without it, the cultures understood
the crops would not grow,
and life on the planet
would not survive.
These realities made the sun the
most adored object of all time.
Likewise, they were also
very aware of the stars.
The tracking of the stars
allowed them to recognize
and anticipate events which
occurred over long periods of time,
such as eclipses and full moons.
They in turn
catalogued celestial groups
into what we know
today as constellations.
This is the
cross of the Zodiac,
one of the oldest conceptual
images in human history.
It reflects the sun as
it figuratively passes
through the 12 major constellations
over the course of a year.
It also reflects the
12 months of the year,
the 4 seasons,
and the solstices and equinoxes.
The term Zodiac
relates to the fact that
constellations were anthropomorphized,
or personified, as figures, or animals.
In other words, the early civilizations
did not just follow the sun and stars,
they personified them
with elaborate myths
involving their movements
and relationships.
The sun, with its life-giving
and life-saving qualities
was personified
as a representative
of the unseen creator,
or God.
"God's Sun," the light of the world,
the savior of human kind.
Likewise,
the 12 constellations
represented places of
travel for God's Sun
and were identified by names,
usually representing
elements of nature that happened
during that period of time.
For example, Aquarius, the water bearer,
who brings the Spring rains.
This is Horus.
He is the Sun God of Egypt
of around 3000 BC.
He is the sun,
anthropomorphized, and his life
is a series of allegorical myths
involving the sun's movement in the sky.
From the ancient hieroglyphics in Egypt,
we know much about this solar messiah.
For instance, Horus,
being the sun, or the light,
had an enemy known as Set,
and Set was the
personification of
the darkness or night.
And metaphorically speaking, every
morning Horus would win the battle
against Set;
while in the evening,
Set would conquer Horus and
send him into the underworld.
It is important to note
that "dark vs. light"
or "good vs. evil" is
one of the most ubiquitous
mythological dualities
ever known and is
still expressed on
many levels to this day.
Broadly speaking, the story
of Horus is as follows:
Horus was born on December
25th of the virgin Isis-Meri.
His birth was accompanied
by a star in the east,
and upon his birth,
he was adored by three kings.
At the age of 12, he was
a prodigal child teacher,
and at the age of 30
he was baptized by a
figure known as Anup and
thus began his ministry.
Horus had 12 disciples
he traveled about with,
performing miracles such as healing
the sick and walking on water.
Horus was known
by many gestural names such as
The Truth, The Light,
God's Anointed Son,
The Good Shepherd, The Lamb of God,
and many others.
After being betrayed by Typhon,
Horus was crucified,
buried for 3 days,
and thus, resurrected.
These attributes of Horus, whether
original or not, seem to permeate
in many cultures of the world, for
many other Gods are found to have
the same
general mythological structure.
Attis, of Phrygia,
born of the virgin Nana
on December 25th,
crucified, placed in a tomb
and after 3 days,
was resurrected.
Krishna, of India,
born of the virgin Devaki
with a star in the east
signaling his coming,
he performed miracles
with his disciples,
and upon his death
was resurrected.
Dionysus of Greece, born of a virgin on
December 25th, was a traveling teacher
who performed miracles such
as turning water into wine,
he was referred to as
the "King of Kings,"
"God's Only Begotten Son,"
"The Alpha and Omega,"
and many others,
and upon his death,
he was resurrected.
Mithra, of Persia, born of
a virgin on December 25th,
he had 12 disciples
and performed miracles,
and upon his death was buried for 3 days
and thus resurrected,
he was also referred to as
"The Truth," "The Light,"
and many others.
Interestingly, the sacred day
of worship of Mithra was Sunday.
The fact of the matter is
there are numerous saviors,
from different periods,
from all over the world, which subscribe
to these general characteristics.
The question remains:
Why these attributes, why the
virgin birth on December 25th,
why dead for three days and
the inevitable resurrection,
why 12 disciples or followers?
To find out, let's examine the
most recent of the solar messiahs.
Jesus Christ was born
of the virgin Mary on
December 25th in Bethlehem,
his birth was announced
by a star in the east,
which three kings or magi
followed to locate and
adore the new savior.
He was a child teacher at 12,
at the age of 30
he was baptized by
John the Baptist,
and thus began his ministry.
Jesus had 12 disciples
which he traveled about
with performing miracles
such as healing the sick,
walking on water, raising the dead,
he was also known
as the "King of Kings,"
the "Son of God,"
the "Light of the World,"
the "Alpha and Omega,"
the "Lamb of God,"
and many others.
After being betrayed by
his disciple Judas and
sold for 30 pieces of
silver, he was crucified,
placed in a tomb and after 3 days was
resurrected and ascended into Heaven.
First of all, the birth sequence
is completely astrological.
The star in the east is Sirius,
the brightest star
in the night sky,
which, on December 24,
aligns with the 3 brightest
stars in Orion's Belt.
These 3 bright stars are
called today what they
were called in ancient times:
The Three Kings.
And the Three Kings and the
brightest star, Sirius,
all point to the place of
the sunrise on December 25th.
This is why the Three Kings "follow"
the star in the east, in order
to locate the sunrise...
the birth of the sun.
The Virgin Mary is the
constellation Virgo,
also known as
Virgo the Virgin.
Virgo in Latin
means virgin.
Virgo is also referred
to as the House of Bread,
and the representation of Virgo is
a virgin holding a sheaf of wheat.
This House of Bread
and its symbol of wheat
represents August and September,
the time of harvest.
In turn, Bethlehem, in fact, literally
translates to "house of bread".
Bethlehem is thus a reference
to the constellation Virgo,
a place in the sky,
not on Earth.
There is another very
interesting phenomenon
that occurs around December 25th,
or the winter solstice.
From the summer solstice
to the winter solstice,
the days
become shorter and colder.
And from the perspective of
the northern hemisphere,
the sun appears to move south
and get smaller and more scarce.
The shortening of the
days and the expiration
of the crops when approaching
the winter solstice
symbolized the process
of death to the ancients.
It was the death of the Sun.
And by December 22nd, the Sun's
demise was fully realized,
for the Sun, having moved
south continually for 6 months,
makes it to it's lowest point
in the sky.
Here a curious thing
occurs:
The Sun stops moving south,
at least perceivably, for 3 days.
And during this 3 day pause,
the Sun resides
in the vicinity of the Southern Cross,
or Crux, constellation.
And after this time on
December 25th, the Sun
moves 1 degree,
this time north,
foreshadowing longer days,
warmth, and Spring.
And thus it was said:
the Sun died on the cross,
was dead for 3 days,
only to be resurrected or born again.
This is why Jesus and
numerous other Sun Gods
share the crucifixion, 3-day
death, and resurrection concept.
It is the Sun's transition
period before it shifts
its direction back into
the Northern Hemisphere,
bringing Spring,
and thus salvation.
However, they did not celebrate
the resurrection of the Sun
until the spring equinox,
or Easter.
This is because
at the spring equinox,
the Sun officially
overpowers the evil darkness,
as daytime thereafter
becomes longer in duration
than the night, and the revitalizing
conditions of spring emerge.
Now, probably the most obvious of all
the astrological symbolism around Jesus
regards the 12 disciples.
They are simply the
12 constellations of the Zodiac,
which Jesus, being the Sun,
travels about with.
In fact, the number 12 is
replete throughout the Bible.
Coming back
to the cross of the Zodiac,
the figurative life of the Sun,
this was not just an artistic expression
or tool to track the Sun's movements.
It was also a Pagan spiritual symbol,
the shorthand of which looked like this.
This is not
a symbol of Christianity.
It is a Pagan adaptation
of the cross of the Zodiac.
This is why Jesus in early occult art is
always shown with his head on the cross,
for Jesus is the Sun,
the "Sun of God",
the "Light of the World",
the "Risen Savior",
who will "come again,"
as it does every morning,
the "Glory of God" who defends
against the "works of darkness",
as he is "born again"
every morning,
and can be seen
"coming in the clouds,"
"up in Heaven," with his
"Crown of Thorns," or sun rays.
Now, of the many
astrological-astronomical metaphors
in the Bible,
one of the most important
has to do with the ages.
Throughout the scripture there are
numerous references to the "Age."
In order to understand this,
we need to be familiar
with the phenomenon
known as the
Precession of the Equinoxes.
The ancient Egyptians
along with cultures
long before them recognized
that approximately every
2150 years,
the sunrise on the morning
of the spring equinox would occur
at a different sign of the Zodiac.
This has to do with a
slow angular wobble that
the Earth maintains
as it rotates on it's axis.
It is called a precession because
the constellations go backwards,
rather than through
the normal yearly cycle.
The amount of time
that it takes for
the precession to go
through all 12 signs
is roughly 25,765 years.
This is also called
the "Great Year,"
and ancient societies
were very aware of this.
And they referred to each 2150
year period as an "age."
From 4300 B.C. to 2150 B.C.,
it was the Age of Taurus, the Bull.
From 2150 BC to 1 AD.,
it was the Age of Aries, the Ram
and from 1 AD. to 2150 AD.
it is the Age of Pisces,
the age we are still
in to this day.
And in and around 2150,
we will enter the new age.
The Age of Aquarius.
Now, the Bible reflects,
broadly speaking,
a symbolic movement
through 3 ages,
while foreshadowing a 4th.
In the Old Testament,
when Moses comes
down Mount Sinai with
the 10 Commandments,
he is very upset to see his people
worshiping a golden bull calf.
In fact,
he shattered the stone tablets
and instructed his people to kill each
other in order to purify themselves.
Most Biblical scholars
would attribute this anger
to the fact that the Israelites
were worshiping a false idol,
or something
to that effect.
The reality is
that the golden bull
is Taurus the Bull, and Moses represents
the new Age of Aries the Ram.
This is why Jews even today
still blow the Ram's horn.
Moses represents the new Age of Aries,
and upon the new age,
everyone must shed
the old age.
Other deities mark these
transitions as well, such as Mithra
a pre-Christian God who kills
the bull, in the same symbology.
Now Jesus is the figure who
ushers in the age following Aries,
the Age of Pisces,
or the Two Fish.
Fish symbolism is very
abundant in the New Testament,
as Jesus feeds 5000 people
with bread and "2 fish."
When he begins his ministry
walking along Galilee,
he befriends 2 fishermen,
who follow him.
And I think
we've all seen the
Jesus-fish on the
backs of people's cars.
Little do they know
what it actually means.
It is a Pagan astrological
symbolism for
the Sun's Kingdom
during the Age of Pisces.
Also, Jesus' assumed birth date is
essentially the start of this age.
At Luke 22:10 when Jesus
is asked by his disciples
where the last passover
would be, Jesus replies:
"Behold, when ye are
entered into the city, there
shall a man meet you
bearing a pitcher of water...
follow him into the house
where he entereth in."
This scripture is
by far one of the most
revealing of all the
astrological references.
The man bearing a pitcher
of water is Aquarius,
the water-bearer, who is always pictured
as a man pouring out a pitcher of water.
He represents
the age after Pisces,
and when the Sun (God's Sun)
leaves the Age of Pisces (Jesus),
it will go into the House of Aquarius,
as Aquarius follows Pisces in
the precession of the equinoxes.
All Jesus is saying is that
after the Age of Pisces
will come
the Age of Aquarius.
Now, we have all heard about the
end times and the end of the world.
The cartoonish depictions
in the Book of Revelation,
the main source of this idea
comes from Matthew 28:20,
where Jesus says: "I will be with
you even to the end of the world."
However,
in King James Version,
"world" is a mistranslation,
among many mistranslations.
The actual word being used is "aeon",
which means "age."
"I will be with you even
to the end of the age."
Which is true, as Jesus' Solar
Piscean personification will end when
the Sun enters
the Age of Aquarius.
The entire concept of end
times and the end of the world
is a misinterpreted
astrological allegory.
Let's tell that
to the approximately
100 million people in America who
believe the end of the world is coming.
Furthermore,
the character of Jesus,
being a literary
and astrological hybrid,
is most explicitly a plagiarization
of the Egyptian Sun-God Horus.
For example,
inscribed about 3500 years ago,
on the walls of the
Temple of Luxor in Egypt
are images of the enunciation,
the miracle conception,
the birth,
and the adoration of Horus.
The images begin with
Thaw announcing to the virgin Isis
that she will conceive
Horus,
then Nef the holy ghost
impregnating the virgin,
and then the virgin birth
and the adoration.
This is exactly the story of
Jesus' miracle conception.
In fact,
the literary similarities between
the Egyptian religion and the
Christian religion are staggering.
And the plagiarism is
continuous.
The story of Noah and Noah's Ark
is taken directly from tradition.
The concept of a Great Flood is
ubiquitous throughout the ancient world,
with over 200 different cited claims
in different periods and times.
However,
one need look no further for
a pre-Christian source
than the Epic of Gilgamesh
written in 2600 B.C.
This story talks of a Great Flood
commanded by God,
an Ark
with saved animals upon it,
and even the release
and return of a dove,
all held in common
with the biblical story,
among many other similarities.
And then there is the
plagiarized story of Moses.
Upon Moses' birth,
it is said that he was placed
in a reed basket and set adrift in
a river in order to avoid infanticide.
He was later rescued by a daughter of
royalty and raised by her as a Prince.
This baby in a basket story
was lifted directly
from the myth of Sargon of Akkad,
of around 2250 B.C.
Sargon was born,
placed in a reed basket,
in order to avoid infanticide,
and set adrift in a river.
He was in turn rescued and
raised by Akki, a royal mid-wife.
Furthermore,
Moses is known as the Law Giver,
the giver of the Ten Commandments,
the Mosaic Law.
However, the idea of a
Law being passed from God
to a prophet, up on a mountain,
is also a very old motif.
Moses is just a law giver in a long line
of law givers in mythological history.
In India,
Manou was the great law giver.
In Crete, Minos ascended Mount Dicta,
where Zeus gave him the sacred laws.
While in Egypt there was Mises,
who carried stone tablets
and upon them,
the laws of God were written.
Manou, Minos,
Mises, Moses.
And as far
as the Ten Commandments,
they are taken outright from Spell 125
of the Egyptian Book of the Dead.
What the
Book of the Dead phrased
"I have not stolen" became
"Thou shall not steal,"
"I have not killed" became
"Thou shall not kill,"
"I have not told lies" became
"Thou shall not bare false witness",
and so forth.
In fact,
the Egyptian religion is likely
the primary foundational basis for the
Judeo-Christian theology.
Baptism, afterlife,
final judgement, virgin birth,
death and resurrection,
crucifixion,
the ark of the covenant,
circumcision,
saviors, holy communion,
the great flood,
Easter, Christmas, Passover,
and many many more,
are all attributes of
Egyptian ideas,
long pre-dating
Christianity and Judaism.
Justin Martyr,
one of the first Christian
historians and defenders,
wrote:
"When we say that he,
Jesus Christ, our teacher,
was produced without sexual union,
was crucified
and died, and rose again,
and ascended into Heaven,
we propound nothing different
from what
you believe regarding those who
you esteem Sons of Jupiter."
In a different writing,
Justin Martyr said:
"He was born of a virgin,
accept this in common,
with what you believe
of Perseus."
It's obvious that Justin and other early
Christians knew how similar Christianity
was to the
Pagan religions.
However,
Justin had a solution.
As far as he was
concerned, the Devil did it.
The Devil had the foresight
to come before Christ,
and create these characteristics
in the Pagan world.
Fundamentalist Christianity,
fascinating.
These people actually believe
the World is 12,000 years old.
I actually asked one of these guys:
"OK, dinosaur fossils?"
He says: "Dinosaur fossils?
God put those here to test our faith!"
"I think God put you here
to test my faith, dude!"
The Bible is nothing more than an
astro-theological literary hybrid,
just like nearly all
religious myths before it.
In fact,
the aspect of transference,
of one character's attributes
to a new character,
can be found
within the book itself.
In the Old Testament,
there's the story of Joseph.
Joseph
was a prototype for Jesus.
Joseph was born of a miracle birth,
Jesus was born of a miracle birth.
Joseph was of 12 brothers,
Jesus had 12 disciples.
Joseph was sold for 20 pieces of silver,
Jesus was sold for 30 pieces of silver.
Brother "Judah" suggests
the sale of Joseph,
disciple "Judas" suggests
the sale of Jesus.
Joseph began his work at the age of 30,
Jesus began his work at the age of 30.
The parallels go
on and on.
Furthermore, is there any
non-Biblical historical evidence
of any person,
living with the name Jesus,
the Son of Mary,
who traveled about with 12 followers,
healing people
and the like?
There are numerous historians
who lived in
and around the Mediterranean
either during or soon
after the assumed life of Jesus.
How many of these historians
document this figure?
Not one.
However, to be fair,
that doesn't mean defenders
of the Historical Jesus
haven't claimed the contrary.
Four historians are typically
referenced to justify Jesus's existence.
Pliny the younger, Suetonius,
Tacitus are the first three.
Each one of their entries
consists of only a few
sentences at best and only refer
to the Christus or the Christ,
which in fact is not name but a title.
It means the Anointed One.
The fourth source is
Josephus
and this source has been proven to
be a forgery for hundreds of years.
Sadly,
it is still cited as truth.
You would think that a guy
who rose from the dead
and ascended into Heaven
for all eyes to see
and performed the wealth of miracles
acclaimed to him
would have made it into
the historical record.
It didn't because once
the evidence is weighed,
there are very high odds that the figure
known as Jesus, did not even exist.
We don't want to be unkind,
but we want to be factual.
We don't want to cause hurt feelings,
but we want to be academically correct,
in what we understand
and know to be true.
Christianity
just is not based on truth.
We find that Christianity
was in fact nothing more
than a Roman story,
developed politically.
The reality is, Jesus was the Solar
Deity of the Gnostic Christian sect,
and like all other Pagan Gods,
he was a mythical figure.
It was the political establishment
that sought
to historize the Jesus figure
for social control.
By 325 AD. in Rome, Emperor Constantine
conviened the Council of Nicea,
It was
during this meeting that
the politically motivated
Christian Doctrines were established
and thus began a long history of
Christian bloodshed and spiritual fraud.
And for the next
1600 years,
the Vatican maintained a political
stranglehold on all of Europe,
leading to such joyous periods
as the Dark Ages,
along with enlightening events such
as the Crusades, and the Inquisition.
Christianity, along with all
other theistic belief systems,
is the fraud of the age.
It serves to detach the species from the
natural world, and likewise, each other.
It supports blind
submission to authority.
It reduces human responsibility to the
effect that "God" controls everything,
and in turn awful crimes can be
justified in the name of Divine Pursuit.
And most importantly, it empowers those
who know the truth but use the myth
to manipulate and control societies.
The religious myth is the most
powerful device ever created,
and serves
as the psychological soil
upon which other myths
can flourish.
A myth is an idea that,
while widely believed, is false.
In a deeper sense,
in the religious sense,
a myth serves as an orienting
and mobilizing story for people.
The focus is not on the story's relation
to reality but on its function.
A story cannot function,
unless it is believed to be true
in the community
or the nation.
It is not a matter of debate
if some people have the bad taste
to raise the question of
the truth of the sacred story.
The keepers of the faith do not
enter into the debate with them.
They ignore them,
or denounce them as blasphemers.
It is wrong, blasphemous
and sinful for you
to suggest,
imply or help other people
to come to conclusion
that the U.S. Government
killed 3,000
of its own citizens.
As if a demolition team
set off,
when you do the demolition
of an old building.
It looks like one of those scenes
of an old building
being purposely dynamited
and blown up.
Anybody who ever watched
a building being demolished,
on purpose, knows that if
you're going to do this
you have to get the under-infrastructure
of the building and bring it down.
The way the structure
is collapsing...
This was the result of something
that was planned.
It's not accidental that the
first tower just happened to collapse
and then the second tower just happened
to collapse in exactly the same way.
How they accomplished this,
we don't know.
The building
collapsed to dust.
You don't find a desk,
you don't find a chair,
you don't find a telephone
or computer.
The biggest piece of a telephone I found
was half of the keypad,
and it was about this big.
What happened
to the concrete?
The concrete was pulverized.
From river to river,
this dust powder,
two or three inches thick,
The concrete was just uh...
pulverized!
Reminiscence of pictures
we've all seen too much in TV before,
a building is deliberately destroyed by
well placed dynamite to knock it down.
It's as if they had detonators,
yes, detonators,
planted to take down the building,
boom, boom, boom!
I heard a second explosion.
There was a heavy-duty explosion.
There was a secondary explosion
and then a subsequent collapse.
...explosion blow and then
it knocked everybody over.
To me it sounded like an explosion.
It sounded like gun-fire,
bang-bang-bang.
And then all of a sudden,
three big explosions.
...and we heard big explosion
coming down.
...and then the entire top
of the building just blew up.
We saw
some kind of explosion.
...by the force of the explosions...
- ...big explosion...
- It blew us back into the 8th floor...
...then we got to lobby,
there was a big explosion.
The lobby looked as though,
a bomb had exploded there.
...huge explosion,
now raining debris...
...there's been a huge explosion...
...huge explosion that
we all heard and felt.
We just witnessed some
kind of explosion...
...it was very loud... it blasted...
explosion...
...smoke and secondary
explosion in Tower 1...
...that is another bomb
going off...
He thinks that there
were actually devices
that were planted
in the building...
...planted in the building...
I don't think anybody
could have predicted
that they would try to use
an airplane as a missile,
a hijacked airplane
as a missile.
...nobody in our government at least,
and I don't think the prior government
could have envisioned
flying airplanes
into the buildings.
No specific threats involving,
really domestic operations
involving what happened obviously,
the cities, airlines and so on.
There were no warning
signs that I am aware of.
USAToday reports that in the two years
before the attacks on September 11th
NORAD conducted exercises using
hijacked airliners as weapons.
And one target was
the World Trade Center.
In confidential documents
from the Philippines
obtained by CNN,
the plan was clear:
He would board any American
commercial aircraft,
control its cockpit, and dive
it at the CIA headquarters.
Other buildings targeted
the Pentagon and the World Trade Center.
Security and counter-terrorism
was blinking red,
in the words of
George Tenet,
that the warnings of an
imminent attack were so severe,
that something dramatic
should have been done.
It was unparalleled.
Instead, our president went
on a month long vacation?
The head of Pakistani Intelligence
of the ISI, Mahmood Ahmed
requested Omar Sheikh
to wire $100,000
to Mohammed Atta,
who was the lead hijacker.
...hijacker Mohammed Atta received
wire transfers via Pakistan.
The man sending the money
to Atta is
believed to be
Ahmed Omar Saeed Sheikh.
Omar Sheikh admitted
he was supported by
the Pakistani Government's
Intelligence service; the ISI.
Although we are told that 4 or 5
of the alleged hijackers
were on each of the flights,
if so their names should have
been on the flight manifest.
But the flight manifest
that had been released
contained neither the names
of the alleged hijackers
nor any
Arab names whatsoever.
We know that the men who
were supposedly the hijackers
had their houses, cars, credit cards
paid for by the U.S. Government.
They were, in truth,
agents.
Evidence was also
apparently planted.
The passport of
one of the hijackers on
Flight 11 was allegedly
found in the rubble.
...it goes through the fireball,
through the side of the plane
and comes down
on the ground unscathed.
But something happened.
For 6 months they reported
they had this passport...
"Boy, we got it,
we got the proof"
and then the guy stood up
and was alive.
Several of these 19 men
are still alive.
Of course we're after Saddam Hussein,
I mean bin Laden, he's, he's, he's...
January 2001.
The Bush Administration orders
the FBI and intelligence agencies
to back off investigations
involving the bin Laden family,
including two of
Osama bin Laden's relatives
who were living, guess where?
In Falls Church, Virginia,
right next to CIA headquarters.
When he was already America's
"most wanted criminal"
he reportedly spent two weeks in
the American hospital in Dubai,
was treated by an American doctor
and visited by the local CIA agent,
We have not seen one piece of
evidence that links Osama bin Laden
directly to the planning stages
of September 11th.
This failure to provide proof
was later said to be unnecessary
because bin Laden in the video
allegedly found in Afghanistan,
admitted responsibility
for the attacks.
This confession is now
widely cited as proof.
But the man in this
video has darker skin,
fuller cheeks
and a broader nose
than the Osama bin Laden
of all other videos.
We again seem to have
the planted evidence.
In 1976, Osama's older brother,
Saleem bin Laden,
hired a man in Texas
by the name of Jim Bath
to handle all the investments in the
United States for the bin Laden family.
Jim Bath also happens to be a personal,
almost life-long friend
and former international guard pilot,
with George W. Bush.
The connections between the
Bushes and the bin Ladens
become much more
clearer when
George Herbert Walker Bush made
trips to Saudi Arabia in 1998 and 2000
to meet
with the bin Laden family
on behalf of the company
called the Carlyle Group.
How could anyone fly a 60 ton,
125 ft wide,
44 ft tall plane
through this obstacle course.
The aircraft,
before striking the Pentagon,
reportedly executed a
270 degree downward spiral
and yet Hani Hanjour
was known as a terrible pilot
who could not safely fly,
even a small plane.
No seats, no luggage, no bodies.
Nothing but bricks and limestone.
The official explanation is that
the intense heat
from the jet fuel
vaporized the entire plane.
Flight 77 had two Rolls Royce engines
made of steel and titanium alloy
and weighed 6 tons each.
It is scientifically impossible
that 12 tons of steel and titanium
was vaporized by jet fuel.
We're also told that the bodies
were able to be identified
either by the
fingerprints or by the DNA.
So what kind of fire can vaporize
aluminum and tempered steel
and yet leave
human bodies intact?
From my close-up inspection,
there's no evidence of a plane
having crashed anywhere
near the Pentagon
and as I say the only
pieces left that you can see
are small enough that you
can pick up in your hand.
Shortly after the strike,
government agents picked up
debris and carried it off.
The entire lawn was covered
with dirt and gravel
so that any remaining
forensic evidence
was literally covered up.
The videos from security cameras which
would show what really hit the Pentagon
were immediately confiscated
by agents of the FBI.
And the Department of Justice has to
this day, refused to release them.
If these videos would prove that
the Pentagon was really hit by a 757,
most of us would assume
the Government would release them.
It looks like there's nothing there
except for a hole in the ground.
Basically,
that's right.
The only thing you could see
from where we were, uh, was
a big gouge in the earth
and some broken trees.
You could see some people working,
walking around in the area,
but from where we can see
there wasn't much left.
Any large pieces of debris
at all?
No, there was nothing.
Nothing, that you can distinguish
that a plane had crashed there.
Pancake theory,
according to which the fires,
although not
melting the steel,
heated up sufficiently to cause the
floors weakened by the airplane strikes
to break loose from the steel columns,
and this started a chain reaction.
So, you would expect then from that
theory, which is the official theory,
to see a whole stack of floors
piled up on top of each other
and then a spindle of core columns
standing too.
The core of each of the Twin Towers
consisted of 47 massive steel columns.
If the floors had
broken loose from them,
these columns would have still been
sticking up in the air a thousand feet.
The plane did not cut
all those core columns.
We designed the buildings
to take the impact of the Boeing 707,
hitting the building
at any location.
The building probably could sustain
multiple impacts of jetliners.
...that the plane flew
straight into the building.
Straight through, right.
So you're saying
that the building
was actually designed to cope
with a hole like that
- and would still survive?
- Yes, it was.
If you would drop,
say a billiard ball
from the top of the World Trade Center,
110 floors up there
it would have taken 8 to 10 seconds
to hit the ground,
encountering no resistance
whatsoever.
The Twin Towers came down
in nearly free fall speed.
200,000 tons of steel shatters
and explodes outwards over 500 ft.
This means that floors shattered
at an average rate
of about
ten floors per second.
There is no scenario for a
pancake effect of buildings falling
that allows them to fall
at a rate of free fall.
And what can do that? What
can move mass out of the way?
Explosives.
47 huge steel columns going up
the core that are interconnected,
how do you get them to fail
simultaneously so the core disappeared.
It looks like
those core columns were cut.
The way we do this is by
cutting the beam at an angle.
I started looking
at the molten metal.
All three buildings,
both towers in the rubble,
in the basement areas,
and Building 7
there were
these pools of molten metal.
You get down below and
you see molten steel.
Molten steel
running down the channel rails.
Like you were in a foundry.
Like lava of a volcano.
The molten steel was found
'three, four and five weeks later
when the rubble
was being removed.'
He said that molten steel was also
found underneath World Trade Center 7.
So I'm looking through
the official reports,
what do they say about
the molten metal?
They say nothing.
Wait a minute.
This is important evidence.
Where did that come from?
Thermite is so hot
that it'll just cut through steel,
through the structural steel,
for example,
like a knife through butter.
The products are molten iron
and aluminum oxide
which goes off primarily
as a dust.
You know,
those enormous dust clouds
you can imagine, when you assemble
these chemicals on a large scale.
Molten metal pools under both towers
after they collapsed, and Building 7.
Now, Building 7 wasn't even
hit by a jet.
Part of the problem is that most people
simply don't know much about Building 7.
due to the extraordinary secrecy
surrounding its collapse.
This was a
47 story skyscraper.
This building fell at 17:25.
It was not hit by a plane.
This building had fires
on only 2 or 3 floors.
...and it was brought down by what
we know was a controlled demolition.
Demolitions look just like that,
kink in the middle,
and then that building just comes
straight down almost at free fall speed.
They first blow
one of the central columns
so the building falls in
on itself.
Building 7
had a classic crimp or wedge.
Its central column
was blown out first
so it didn't structurally damaged
buildings just a few feet away from it.
Our office
was on the B-1 level.
As I was talking to a supervisor
at 8.46
and all of a sudden,
we hear, boom!
An explosion so hard
that pushed us upwards.
And it came from the basement,
between the B-2 level and the B-3 level.
And when I went to verbalize,
we heard boom!
That impact
of the plane on the top.
As I'm walking by the main freight car
of the building in the corridor,
that's when I got blown.
I mean, the impact of the
explosion threw me to the floor
and that's when everything
started happening.
All of a sudden,
a big impact happened again
and all the ceiling tiles
were falling down,
the light fixtures
were falling...
You know, you gotta go clear across
the whole from 1 to 2 World Trade Center
and then all of a sudden,
it happened all over again.
Something else hit us to the floor...
right in the basement you felt it,
the walls were caving in on,
everything that was going on.
I mean, I know people that
got killed in the basement,
I know people that got
broken legs in the basement,
people got reconstructive surgery
because the walls hit them in the face.
According to
standard operating procedure,
if an FAA flight control
notices anything
that suggests a possible hijacking,
controllers are to
contact the superior.
If the problem cannot be
fixed within about a minute
the superior should ask NORAD
(North American Aerospace Command)
to send up or scramble jet fighters
to find out what is going on.
NORAD then issues
a scramble order to
the nearest air force base,
with fighters on alert.
And although interceptions usually
occur within 10 or so minutes,
in this case,
80 or so minutes had elapsed
before the fighters
were even airborne.
It's a mind-bending anomaly.
Not a single US Air Force interceptor
turns a wheel until it's too late.
There are no jets at all.
What if they were
so confused,
and had been so deliberately confused
that they couldn't respond?
The reason that they
didn't know where to go
was because a number of
conflicting and overlapping
war game exercises
were taking place
that involved the insertion
of false radar blips
on the radar screens in the
north-east air defense sector.
There was another exercise;
"Vigilant Warrior",
which was in fact,
according to a NORAD source,
a live-fly hijack drill
being conducted at the same time.
With only 8 available fighter aircrafts,
and that have to be dispatched in pairs,
they were dealing with as many as 22
possible hijacks on the day of 9/11
and they couldn't separate the war
game exercises from the actual hijacks.
Page 172:
"The US Government has
not been able to determine
the origin of the money
used for the 9/11 attacks.
Ultimately, the question is of
little practical significance."
The American authorities
have not managed
to trace
the source of the funding.
And then the most amazingly
disingenuous statement,
"Ultimately is it of
little consequence".
It is of
massive consequence!
Doesn't it matter
who paid for 9/11?
The collapse of Building 7
has been recognized
as especially
difficult to explain.
The 9/11 Commission Report
implicitly admitted
that it could not explain the
collapse of this building
by not even mentioning it.
Mr. President,
why are you and the Vice President
insisting on appearing together
before the 9/11 Commission?
Because the 9/11 Commission wants to ask
us questions, that's why we are meeting,
and I look forward to meeting with
them and answering their questions.
The question was:
Why are you appearing together,
rather than separately,
which was their request?
Because it's a good chance
for both of us
to answer questions
that the 9/11 Commission
is looking forward to asking us, and
I am looking forward to answering them.
Do you think they should be able to
stand up and speak their own words?
They should go under oath.
- They should be--
- Yeah. In public.
Don't you think that
the families deserve
to have a transcript
or to be able to see--
Adam, you asked me
this question yesterday,
I got the same answer.
Yeah.
The final report
was a unanimous report.
That means that if
there was a single commissioner
who had any objection
about anything,
that fact would be
dropped from the report.
We have found out that
he not only served on
the transition team
of the Bush Administration,
that he was a person
who wrote a draft memo for the
setup of the Bush Administration's
National Security Council,
that he was an individual who
wrote the preemptive war strategy
that was eventually
used for the war on Iraq,
that he's a close friend
of Condoleezza Rice's...
We want him to resign.
There is literally nothing
in the 9/11 report
that the Bush Administration
did not approve of.
We can understand therefore why that
commission under Zelikow leadership
would have ignored all the evidence
that would point to the truth
that 9/11
was a false flag operation
intended to authorize the doctrines
and funds needed
for a new level of
imperial mobilization.
Armed with knives. Armed with chemical,
biological and nuclear weapons.
Fanatics. Terrorists. September 11th.
September 11th. Killers.
September 11th. Terrorists.
Terrorists. Al Qaeda, Terrorists.
Nuclear weapons. Terror. 9/11.
Terror. Terror. Terror. Evil.
September 11th. September 11th.
The terrorists. War and danger.
September 11th. Terrorism.
Global terrorism. Terrorism. Terrorist.
Terrorist. Terrorist. Terrorist,
Terrorist. The terrorists.
Terrorists. Terrorists. Terrorism.
September 11th. Global terrorism.
Terrorism. Terrorism. Terrorists.
September 11th. World terrorism.
Terrorists. Terrorism.
September 11th. Global Terrorism.
September the 11th. Terrorist.
Terrorist. Terrorist. Terrorist,
Terrorist. Weapons of mass destruction.
September the 11th.
September the 11th. Terrorists. The evil
terrorists. Terrorists. Terrorists know!
Terrorism. The words are
hypnotically repeated:
Terrorism. Terrorists.
Terrorist threat.
And of course,
believe-to-be-linked-to-al-Qaeda.
But, it's the so-called
"War on Terrorism"
that's in our faces,
practically 24/7
as the inescapable focus
of our existence.
One day, our grandchildren will
look back on this time and ask:
"How was
the war on terror won?"
The entire US ruling class,
ruling elite
comes to see terrorism as the
preferred means, indeed the only means,
to provide social cohesion,
to provide an enemy image for
the society, to keep it together.
According to NeoCon Theory
from Carl Schmitt,
you have to have
an enemy image,
in order
to have a society.
A very dangerous thing because now
it means that the entire social order,
the political parties, intellectual life,
politics in general,
are all based
on a monstrous myth.
Look, what the CIA has
done in this country.
What they have done to us
is unbelievable.
Look at the terrorist acts
that have occurred.
The CIA behind most,
if not, all of them.
We had the Marine Barracks,
then embassy in Kenya,
We had Pan Am 103,
we had the USS Cole,
we had Oklahoma City, we had
the World Trade Center in 1993.
...that helped the terrorists
to blow up the WTC the first time.
They built the bomb,
they got the driver's license.
The informer
Emad A. Salem,
a 43-year-old former
Egyptian Army officer,
he was given the assignment
to put the bomb together
and he went to the supervisor,
that's the FBI supervisor,
and he said,
"We're gonna put a dummy bomb" right?
and the FBI supervisor says
"No, we're gonna put a real bomb."
The FBI actually carried out the attack
on the World Trade Center in 1993.
They actually hired Emad Salem
and paid him 1 million dollars
and gave him real explosives,
a detonator and told him to build a bomb
and to give it to the foolish people
that he was controlling
to allow them to attack
the World Trade Center complex.
Unfortunately for them,
there were only six people killed,
not enough
to pass the legislation.
So, what happened
is two years later,
April 19, 1995 down comes
Oklahoma City, the Murrah Building,
168 people killed... one year later,
the anti-terror legislation,
which takes away
many of our constitutional rights
and civil liberties,
is passed.
It was at half past 9
this morning.
We were actually running an exercise
for a company
of over a thousand people
in London
based on simultaneous bombs
going off precisely
at the railway stations
where it happened this morning,
so I still have the hairs on the back
of my neck standing up right!
To get this quite straight,
you were running an exercise
to see how you would
cope with this
and it happened
while you were running the exercise?
Precisely.
We're supposed to believe it
was some kind of coincidence.
There was also an anti-terrorist
drill going on on 7/7.
And again,
just like on 9/11,
they were talking about attacks on the
same targets, the same tube stations
at the exactly the same time
as the actual attack happened
providing some
kind of cover for what
must be operations orchestrated
in some way by the State.
I am absolutely appalled at how much
people in this country do not think.
We are given to understand that an
Arabic guy out there up in the mountains
financed the most elaborate
attack on this country.
Do you think some people in a cave
were able to have NORAD stand down?
Do you think that people in the cave
were able to have all of this happen?
And when I think about how many
Americans were killed in New York City
and believing as I do that
this thing was a set up job,
this is a textbook operation
that Nazis used
and they've used it
over and over again.
America has been suckered in
one more time.
I don't have to tell you things are bad.
Everybody knows things are bad.
The dollar buys a nickel's worth.
Banks are going bust,
shopkeepers keep a gun
under the counter.
Punks are running wild
in the streets.
There's nobody anywhere who
seems to know what to do,
and there's no end to it.
We know the air is unfit to breathe
and our food is unfit to eat.
We sit watching our TVs
while some local newscaster tells us
that today we had
15 homicides and 63 violent crimes
as if that's the way
it's supposed to be!
We know things are bad.
Worse than bad. They're crazy.
It's like everything everywhere
is going crazy,
so we don't go out anymore.
We sit in the house and slowly the world
we're living in is getting smaller.
And all we say is, "Please, at least
leave us alone in our living rooms.
Let me have my toaster and my TV,
my steel-belted radials
and I won't say anything.
Just leave us alone."
Well I'm not gonna leave you alone.
I want you to get mad!
I don't want you to protest,
I don't want you to riot.
I don't want you to
write to your congressman
because I wouldn't know
what to tell you to write.
I don't know what to do about
the depression and the inflation
and the Russians and
the crime in the street,
All I know is that first
you've got to get mad!
You've got to say,
"I'm a human being, goddamn it!
My life has value!
Oh God!
"When hostilities
commenced in Europe in 1939
it was realized that the American people
had no intention of entering the war
but they believed that
this country could be enticed
into the war,
in very much the same way,
that it was enticed
into the last one
They planned, first, to prepare
the United States for foreign war,
under the guise
of American defense
Second, to involve us in the war,
step by step without our realization.
Third,
to create a series of incidences,
which would force us
into the actual conflict.
These plans were, of course,
to be covered and assisted
by the full power
of their propaganda,
Our theaters soon became
filled with plays,
portraying
the glory of war.
News reels lost all
semblance of objectivity.
and they have used the war to justify
the restriction of congressional power
and the assumption of
dictatorial procedures,
on the part of
the President and his appointees.
A fear campaign was inaugurated.
We cannot allow the natural passions
and prejudices,
of other peoples,
to lead our country to destruction"
1775, the
American Revolutionary War began,
as the American colonies
sought to detach from England,
and it's oppressive monarchy.
Although many reasons are
cited for the revolution,
one in particular sticks
out as the prime cause:
that King George III of England outlawed
the interest free independent currency
the colonies were producing
and using for themselves,
in turn forcing them
to borrow money from
the Central Bank of England,
at interest,
immediately putting
the colonies into debt.
And as Benjamin Franklin
later wrote:
The refusal of King George III
to allow the colonies
to operate
an honest money system,
which freed the ordinary man from
the clutches of the money manipulators
was probably
the prime cause of the revolution.
In 1783, America won its independence
from England.
However, its battle against the
central bank concept and the corrupt,
greed-filled men associated with it,
had just begun.
So what is a Central Bank?
A Central Bank
is an institution
that produces the currency
of an entire nation.
Based on historical precedent,
two specific powers
are inherent in
central banking practice.
The control of interest rates,
and the
control of the money supply,
or inflation.
The central bank does not simply supply
a government's economy with money,
it loans it to them
at interest.
Then, through the use of increasing
and decreasing the supply of money,
the central bank regulates the
value of the currency being issued.
It is critical to understand that
the entire structure of this system
can only produce one thing
in the long run:
Debt.
It doesn't take a lot of ingenuity
to figure this scam out.
For every single dollar produced by the
central bank is loaned at interest.
That means every single dollar
produced is actually the dollar,
plus a certain percent of debt
based on that dollar.
And since a central bank
has a monopoly
over the production of the currency
for the entire country,
and they loan each dollar out
with immediate debt attached to it,
where does the money to
pay for the debt come from?
It can only come from
the central bank again.
Which means the central bank
has to perpetually increase
its money supply to temporarily cover
the outstanding debt created,
which in turn, since that new money
is loaned out at interest as well,
creates even more debt!
The end result of this system
without fail is slavery.
For it is impossible for the government
and thus the public,
to ever come out of the
self-generating debt.
The founding fathers of this country
were well aware of this.
By the early 20th century,
the US had already implemented,
and removed a few
central banking systems,
which were swindled into place
by ruthless banking interests.
At this time, the dominant families
in the banking and business world were:
the Rockefellers, the Morgans,
the Warburgs, the Rothschilds.
And in the early 1900's,
they sought to push once again,
legislation to create
another central bank,
However,
they knew the government
and public were weary
of such an institution.
So they needed to create
an incident to affect public opinion.
So, J.P. Morgan, publicly considered
a financial luminary at the time,
exploited his mass influence
by publishing rumors
that a prominent bank in New York
was insolvent, or bankrupt.
Morgan knew this would
cause mass hysteria
which would affect other banks
as well, and it did.
The public,
in fear of losing their deposits,
immediately began
mass withdrawals.
Consequently, the banks were
forced to call in their loans,
causing the recipients
to sell their property,
and thus a spiral of bankruptcies,
repossessions, and turmoil emerged.
Putting the pieces together
a few years later,
Fredrik Allen of
LIFE Magazine wrote:
"The Morgan interests took advantage
to precipitate the panic of 1907
guiding it shrewdly,
as it progressed."
Unaware of the fraud,
the Panic of 1907 led to
a Congressional investigation,
headed by Senator Nelson Aldrich,
who had intimate ties
to the banking cartels,
and later became part of the
Rockefeller family through marriage.
The Commission led by Aldrich
recommended
a Central Bank
should be implemented,
so a panic like 1907
"could never happen again".
This was the spark the international
bankers needed to initiate their plan.
In 1910, a secret meeting was
held at a J.P. Morgan estate
on Jekyll Island off
the coast of Georgia.
It was there that the
central banking bill
called the Federal Reserve Act
was written.
This legislation was written by bankers,
not law-makers.
This meeting
was so secretive,
so concealed from government
and public knowledge,
that the 10 or so figures
who attended,
disguised their names
when in route to the island.
After this bill was constructed,
it was then handed over
to their political front-man,
Senator Nelson Aldrich,
to push through Congress.
And in 1913, with heavy political
sponsorship by the bankers,
Woodrow Wilson
became President,
having already agreed
to sign the Federal Reserve Act
in exchange
for campaign support.
And 2 days before Christmas,
when most of Congress
was at home with their families,
the Federal Reserve Act was voted in,
and Wilson in turn made it law.
Later, Woodrow Wilson wrote,
in regret:
Congressman Louis McFadden
also expressed
the truth
after the passage of the bill:
"A world banking system
was being set up here...
a superstate controlled
by international bankers,
acting together to enslave the world
for their own pleasure.
The Fed has usurped
the government."
Now, the public was told that
the Federal Reserve System
was an economic stabilizer.
And inflation and economic crisis
were a thing of the past.
Well, as history has shown,
nothing is further from the truth.
The fact is the international bankers
now had
a streamlined machine
to expand their personal ambitions.
For example,
from 1914 to 1919,
the Fed increased the
money supply by nearly 100%.
Resulting in extensive loans
to small banks and the public.
Then in 1920, the Fed called in
massive percentages
of the outstanding
money supply,
thus resulting in the supporting banks
having to call in huge numbers of loans,
and just like in 1907: bank runs,
bankruptcy, and collapse occurred.
Over 5400 competitive banks outside of
the Federal Reserve System collapsed.
Further consolidating the monopoly to
a small group of international bankers.
Privy to this crime, Congressman
Lindberg stepped up, and said in 1921:
"Under the Federal Reserve Act,
panics are scientifically created.
The present panic is the first
scientifically created one,
worked out as we figure
a mathematical equation."
However, the panic of
1920 was just a warm-up.
From 1921 to 1929, the Fed again
increased the money supply,
resulting once again in extensive
loans to the public and banks.
There was also
a fairly new type of loan
called a margin loan
in the stock market.
Very simply,
a margin loan allowed an investor
to put down
only 10% of a stocks price,
with the other 90%
being loaned through the broker.
In other words, a person could own $1000
worth of stock with only $100 down.
This method was very popular
in the roaring 1920's,
as everyone seemed to be
making money in the market.
However,
there was a catch to this loan.
It could be called in at any time,
and had to be paid within 24 hours.
This is termed a margin call,
and the typical result
of a margin call is
the selling of the stock
purchased with the loan.
So, a few months
before October of 1929,
J.D. Rockefeller,
Bernard Baruck,
and other insiders
quietly exited the market,
and on October 24th, 1929,
the New York financiers who
furnished the margin loans
started calling them in, in mass.
This sparked an instantaneous
massive sell-off in the market,
for everyone had to
cover their margin loans.
It then triggered mass bank runs
for the same reason,
in turn collapsing over
16,000 banks,
enabling the conspiring
international bankers
to not only buy up rival banks
at a discount,
but to also buy up whole corporations
at pennies on the dollar.
It was the greatest robbery
in American history.
But that didn't stop there.
Rather than expand the money supply
to recover from this economic collapse,
the Fed actually
contracted it,
fueling one of the largest
depressions in history.
Once again outraged,
Congressman Louis McFadden,
a long-time opponent
of the banking cartels,
began bringing impeachment proceedings
against the Federal Reserve Board,
saying of
the crash and depression:
"It was a carefully
contrived occurrence.
International bankers sought to
bring about a condition of despair,
so that they might emerge
the rulers of us all."
Not surprisingly, and after 2
previous assassination attempts,
McFadden was
poisoned at a banquet
before he could push
for the impeachment.
Now, having reduced
the society to squalor,
the Federal Reserve bankers decided that
the Gold Standard should be removed.
In order to do this,
they needed to acquire
the remaining gold in the system.
So, under the pretense
of helping to end
the Depression came
the 1933 Gold Seizure.
Under threat of imprisonment
for 10 years, everyone in America
was required to turn in all
gold bullion to the Treasury,
essentially robbing the public of
what little wealth they had left.
At the end of 1933,
the gold standard was abolished.
If you look at a dollar bill
from before 1933,
it says
it is redeemable in gold.
If you look
at a dollar bill today,
it says it is legal tender, which means
it is backed by absolutely nothing.
It is worthless paper.
The only thing that
gives our money value
is how much of it
is in circulation.
Therefore the power
to regulate the money supply
is also the power
to regulate its value,
which is also the power to bring entire
economies and societies to its knees.
It's important
to clearly understand:
The Federal Reserve
is a private corporation.
It is about as "Federal"
as "Federal Express."
It makes its own policies,
and is under
virtually no regulation
by the US government.
It is a private bank
that loans all the currency
at interest
to the government,
completely consistent
with the fraudulent
central banking model that the
country sought to escape from
when it declared independence in
the American Revolutionary War.
Now, going back to 1913,
the Federal Reserve Act was not
the only unconstitutional bill
pushed through Congress.
They also pushed
the federal income tax.
It's worthwhile
to point out that
the American public's ignorance
towards the federal income tax
is a testament to how
dumbed-down and oblivious
the American population
really is.
First of all, the federal income
tax is completely unconstitutional,
as it is a direct,
unapportioned tax.
All direct taxes have to be apportioned
to be legal based on the Constitution.
Secondly, the required
number of states in order to
ratify the amendment to allow
the income tax was never met,
and this has even been cited in
modern court cases.
Third, at the present day,
roughly 25%
of the average worker's income
is taken via this tax.
and guess where that money goes.
It goes to pay the interest on
the currency being produced
by the fraudulent
Federal Reserve Bank,
a system that does not
have to exist, at all.
The money you make working
almost three months
out of the year
goes almost literally
into the pockets of the
international bankers,
who own the private
Federal Reserve Bank,
And fourth, even with
the fraudulent government
claim as to the legality
of the income tax,
there is literally no statute,
no law in existence,
that requires you
to pay this tax.
Period.
I really expected that
of course there's a law,
that you can point to in the law book
that requires you to file a tax return.
Of course there is.
I was at that point
where I couldn't find
the statute that clearly
made a person liable,
at least not me,
and most people I know,
and I had no choice in
my mind except to resign.
Based on the research
that I did throughout
the year 2000
and that I'm still doing,
I have not found that law.
I've asked Congress,
a lot of people,
we've asked the
IRS Commissioner's helpers,
they can't answer,
because if they answer,
the American people are gonna know
that this whole thing is a fraud.
I haven't filed a federal income
tax return since I left.
I have not filed a
tax return since 1999.
The income tax is nothing less than
the enslavement of the entire country.
Now, the control of the economy
and the perpetual robbery of wealth
is only one side of the Rubik's Cube
the bankers hold in their hands.
The next tool
for profit and control is war.
Since the inception of the
Federal Reserve in 1913,
a number of large and
small wars have commenced.
The 3 most pronounced were
World War I, World War II, and Vietnam.
World War I.
In 1914, European wars broke out
centered around England and Germany.
The American public wanted
nothing to do with the war,
in turn President Wilson
publicly declared neutrality.
However, under the surface,
the US administration was looking for
any excuse they could find to enter it.
In a noted observation by
Secretary of State William Jennings:
"The large banking interests were
deeply interested in the World War,
because of the wide opportunities
for large profits."
It's important to understand
that the most lucrative thing
that can happen for
international bankers, is war.
For it forces the county
to borrow even more money
from the Federal Reserve Bank,
at interest.
Woodrow Wilson's top adviser
and mentor was Colonel Edward House,
a man with
intimate connections with
the international bankers
who wanted in the war.
In a documented conversation between
Colonel House, Wilson's Advisor,
and Sir Edward Grey,
The Foreign Secretary of England,
regarding how to get America
into the war.
Grey inquired:
"What will Americans do if Germans
sink an Ocean Liner
with American passengers
on board?"
House responded:
"I believe that a flame of indignation
would sweep the United States
and that by itself would be
sufficient to carry us into war."
So, on May 7th 1915 on essentially
the suggestion of Sir Edward Grey,
a ship called the Lusitania
was deliberately sent
into German controlled waters
where German
military vessels were know to be.
And, as expected,
German U-boats torpedoed the ship,
exploding stored ammunition,
killing 1200 people.
To further understand the
deliberate nature of this setup,
the German Embassy actually put
advertisements in the New York Times,
telling people that if
they boarded the Lusitania,
they did so
at their own risk,
as such a ship sailing
from America to England
through the war zone,
would be liable to destruction.
In turn and as anticipated,
the sinking of the Lusitania
caused a wave of anger
among the American population
and America entered the
war a short time after.
The 1st World War caused
323,000 American deaths.
J.D. Rockefeller made
200 million dollars off of it.
Not to mention the war cost about
30 billion dollars for America,
most of which was borrow from the
Federal Reserve Bank at interest,
furthering the profits of
the international bankers.
World War 2.
On December 7th 1941, Japan attacked
the American fleet at Pearl Harbor,
triggering our entry
into that war.
President Franklin D. Roosevelt
declared that
the attack was a
"day that will live in infamy".
A day of infamy indeed,
but not because of the alleged
surprise attack on Pearl Harbor.
After 60 years of surfacing information,
it is clear that not only
was the attack on Pearl Harbor
known weeks in advance,
it was outright wanted
and provoked.
Roosevelt, whose family had been
New York bankers since the 18th century,
whose uncle Fredrik was on the
original Federal Reserve Board,
was very sympathetic to the
interests of the international bankers
and the interest
was to enter the war.
And as we have seen,
nothing is more profitable
for international bankers,
than war.
In a journal entry,
by Roosevelt's Secretary of War
Henry Stimson,
dated November 25th, 1941,
he documented a conversation
he had with Roosevelt:
"The question was how should we maneuver
them into firing the first shot.
It was desirable to make sure the
Japanese be the ones to do this
so that there should remain no doubt
as to who were the aggressors."
In the months leading up to
the attack on Pearl Harbor,
Roosevelt did everything
in his power to anger the Japanese,
showing a posture
of aggression.
He halted all of Japans' imports
of American Petroleum.
He froze all the Japanese assets
in the United States.
He made public loans
to Nationalist China
and supplied military aid
to the British,
both enemies
to Japan in the war...
Which, by the way, is completely in
violation of international war rules.
And, on December 4th,
3 days before the attack,
Australian Intelligence
told Roosevelt about
a Japanese task force
moving towards Pearl Harbor.
Roosevelt ignored it.
So, as hoped and allowed,
on December 7th 1941,
Japan attacked Pearl Harbor,
killing 2400 soldiers.
Before Pearl Harbor,
83% of the American public
wanted nothing
to do with the war.
After Pearl Harbor, 1 million men
volunteered for the war.
It is important to note,
Nazi Germany's war effort
was largely supported
by two organizations,
one of which
was called I.G. Farben.
I.G. Farben produced 84% of Germany's
explosives and even the Zyklon B
used in the concentration camps
to kill millions.
One of the unspoken partners
of I.G. Farben was
J.D. Rockefeller's
Standard Oil Company in America,
In fact, the German Air Force
could not operate without
a special additive patterned
by Rockefeller's Standard Oil.
The drastic bombing of London
by Nazi Germany, for example,
was made possible by a 20
million dollar sale of fuel
to I.G. Farben by the
Rockefeller Standard Oil Company.
This is just one small point
about how
American business funded
both sides of World War 2.
One other treasonous organization
worth mentioning
is the Union Banking Corporation
of New York City.
Not only did it finance numerous
aspects of Hitler's rise to power,
along with actual
materials during the war,
it was also a Nazi
money laundering bank,
which was eventually exposed
for having
millions of dollars
of Nazi Money in its vaults.
The Union Banking Corporation
of New York was eventually
seized for violation of the
Trading with the Enemy Act.
Guess who the director and
vice-president of the Union Bank was?
Prescott Bush,
our current president's grandfather,
and of course,
our former President's father.
Keep that in mind,
when considering
the moral and political
dispositions of the Bush family.
Vietnam.
The United States official declaration
of war on North Vietnam in 1964,
came after an alleged incident involving
two US destroyers being attacked
by North Vietnamese
PT boats in the Gulf of Tonkin.
This was known as the
Gulf of Tonkin Incident.
This single situation
was the catalystic pretext
for massive troop deployment
and full fledged warfare.
One problem however.
The attack on the US destroyers
by Vietnamese PT boats...
never happened.
It was a completely staged event
to have an excuse to enter the war.
Former Secretary of Defense,
Robert McNamara, stated years later
that the Gulf of Tonkin incident
was a "mistake",
while many other insiders
and officers have come forward
relaying that it was a contrived farce,
a complete lie.
Once in the war,
it was business as usual.
In October 1966,
President Lyndon Johnson
lifted trading restrictions
on the Soviet Block,
knowing full well that the Soviets
were providing
upwards of 80% of
North Vietnam's war supplies.
Consequently, Rockefeller interests
financed factories in the Soviet Union,
which the Soviets
used to manufacture
military equipment and
send to North Vietnam.
However, the funding
of both sides of
this conflict was only
one side of the coin.
In 1985, Vietnam's Rules of Engagement
were declassified.
This detailed what American troops were
and were not allow to do in the war.
It included absurdities like:
North Vietnamese anti-aircraft
missile systems could not be bombed
until they were known
to be fully operational.
No enemy could be pursued once they
crossed the border of Laos or Cambodia.
And most revealing of all,
the most critical,
strategic targets were
not allowed to be attacked,
unless initiated by
high military officials.
Apart from
these imposed limitations,
North Vietnam was informed
of these restrictions
and therefore could create
entire strategies
around the limitations
of the American Forces.
This is why the war went on so long
and the bottom line is this:
The Vietnam War
was never meant to be won...
Just sustained.
This war for profit resulted in
58,000 American deaths
and 3 million
dead Vietnamese.
So, where are we now.
September 11th was the jumpstart
for what is now
an accelerating agenda
by the ruthless elite.
It was
a staged war pretext,
no different than the
sinking of the Lusitania,
the provoking of Pearl Harbor
and the Gulf of Tonkin lie.
In fact if 9/11 wasn't
a planned war pretext,
it would be an exception
to the rule.
It has been used to launch
two unprovoked illegal wars.
One against Iraq and
one against Afghanistan.
However, 9/11 was the pretext
for another war as well.
The war against you.
The Patriot Act,
Homeland Security,
the Military Tribunals Act
and other legislations,
are all completely and entirely designed
to destroy your civil liberties
and limit your ability to fight back
against what is coming.
Currently
in the United States,
unannounced to most
brainwashed Americans,
your home can be searched
without a warrant,
without you being home,
you can, in turn, be arrested
with no charges revealed to you,
detain indefinitely with no access
to a lawyer and legally tortured.
All under the suspicion
that you might be a "terrorist".
If you need a painted picture of
what is happening in the country,
let's recognize
how history repeats itself.
In February 1933,
Hitler staged a false flag attack,
burning down his own
German parliament building,
the Reichstag,
and blamed it on communist terrorists.
Within the next few weeks,
he passed the Enabling Act,
which completely eradicated
the German Constitution
destroying people's liberties.
He then let
a series of preemptive wars
all justified
to the German people as
necessary to maintaining
"homeland security".
Our enemy is a
radical network of terrorists
and every government
that supports them.
It's time to wake up.
The people in power
go out of their way
to make sure you are perpetually
mislead and manipulated.
The majorities perception
of reality,
especially in the political arena
is not their own.
It is shrewdly imposed upon them,
without them even knowing it.
For example, the public
at large actually believes
the invasion of Iraq
is going badly,
as sectarian violence
doesn't seem to stop.
What the public fails to see,
is that the destabilization
of Iraq is exactly
what the people
behind the government want.
This war is to be sustained,
so the region can be divided up,
domination
of the oil maintained,
continual profits reaped
for the defense contractors
and most importantly,
permanent military bases established
to be used as a launching pad
against other oil bearing,
non-conforming countries,
such as Iran and Syria,
For further implication,
that the civil war and destabilization
is purely intentional--
In 2005, 2 elite British SAS officers
were arrested by Iraq police
after being caught driving around
in their car shooting at civilians,
while dressed up as Arabs.
After being arrested and
taken to a jail in Basra,
the British army immediately
requested the release of these men.
When the Basra government refused,
British tanks came in
and physically broke out the
men from the Basra prison.
If you wish to destroy an area,
how do you do it?
Well there are two ways:
You can go in there and bomb it, and so
forth, but that is not very efficient.
What you do is try to get the people
in that area to kill each other
and to destroy there own territory,
their own farms.
And that's what
has been done in that area.
The way in which you destroy an
opponent is get him to destroy himself,
by dividing his ranks
against one another.
Then you feed both sides,
you have agents feeding both sides,
inflaming both sides.
And they kill each other off.
And it's time that some of us
woke up to this reality.
To understand that people who try to
maintain empires and create empires,
do it by manipulating the people
they are trying to conquer.
You might to ask yourself
why the entire culture
is utterly saturated with
mass media entertainment from all sides,
while the educational system in America
continues it stupefying downward slide
since the US government
decided to take over
and subsidize
the public school system.
What your government pays for,
it gets.
When we understand that,
then we look at
government financed institutions
of education
and see the kind of students
and the kind of education that is
being turned out by these
government financed schools,
logic will tell you that if what is
being turned out in those schools
was not in accord with what the state
and the federal government wanted,
then it would change it.
The bottom line is that the government
is getting what they have ordered.
They do not want
your children to be educated.
They do not want you
to think too much.
That is why our country
and our world has become
so proliferated
with entertainments,
mass media, television shows,
amusement parks, drugs, alcohol
and every kind
of entertainment,
to keep the human mind
entertained.
So that you don't get
in the way of
important people by
doing too much thinking.
You had better wake up
and understand
that there are people who are guiding
your life and you don't even know it."
We are
in a lot of trouble!
Because you people and
62 million other Americans
are listening to me right now.
Because less than 3 percent
of you people read books.
Because less 15 percent
of you read newspapers.
Because the only truth you know
is what you get over this tube.
Right now there is a whole,
an entire generation
that never knew anything
that didn't come out
of this tube.
This tube is the gospel,
the ultimate revelation.
This tube can make or break
presidents, popes, prime ministers...
This tube is the most
awesome goddamn force
in the whole godless world
and woe is us,
if it ever falls in the
hands of the wrong people.
And when the largest company
in the world controls
the most awesome goddamn propaganda
force in the whole godless world,
who knows what shit will be
peddled for truth on this network!
So you listen to me...
Listen to me:
Television
is not the truth.
Television is a
goddamned amusement park,
television is a circus,
a carnival,
a traveling troop of acrobats,
story tellers,
dancers,
singers, jugglers,
sideshow freaks,
lion tamers and football players.
We are in the
boredom killing business!
But you people sit there,
day after day, night after night,
all ages, colors, creeds...
We are all you know.
You're beginning to believe
the illusions we are spinning here,
you are beginning to think
the tube is reality
and that your own lives
are unreal.
You do
whatever the tube tells you.
You dress like the tube,
you eat like the tube,
you raise your children like the tube,
you even think like the tube...
This is mass madness,
you maniacs.
In God's name,
you people are the real thing.
We are the illusion!
The last thing the men
behind the curtain want
is a conscious informed public,
capable of critical thinking.
Which is why a continually fraudulent
zeitgeist is output via religion,
the mass media,
and the educational system.
They seek to keep you in
a distracted, naive bubble.
And they are doing a
damn good job of it.
In 2005, an arrangement between Canada,
Mexico and the United States was made.
This arrangement,
unannounced to the public,
unregulated by Congress,
merges the United States,
Canada and Mexico
into one entity,
erasing all borders.
It's called
the North American Union.
You might want to ask yourself
why you have never heard of this.
In fact, there is only one mainstream
reporter who has actually heard of,
and has had the courage
to cover this issue.
The Bush Administration's
Open Borders Policy
and its decision to ignore
the enforcement of this country's
immigration laws
is part
of a broader agenda.
President Bush
signed a formal agreement
that will end the United States,
as we know it.
And he took the step without approval
from either the US Congress,
or the people
of the United States.
It's a deal that few
have even heard of.
It's been done again,
by very few people, at the very top,
on behalf
of the investment class.
But the working class
of people,
political officials across our country
from communities and cities,
they don't know anything
about this.
This isn't some trade agreement.
It is a total removal of
sovereignty from these countries
which will also result in a completely
new currency called the Amero.
Apart from that, I think the one thing
that people who are
dollar based need to focus on
is the Amero,
that's the one thing that
nobody is talking about.
I think it's going
to have a big impact on
everybody's life in
Canada, the US and Mexico.
The Amero is the proposed new currency
for the North American Community,
which is being developed right now
between Canada the US and Mexico
to make a borderless community,
much like the EU,
and the Dollar, the Canadian Dollar
and the Mexican Peso
will be replaced
by the Amero.
By default of this agreement,
the American Constitution
will eventually be obsolete.
You would think that
a situation like this
would be on the cover
of every major newspaper.
That is until you realize that
the people behind this movement
are the same people who are
behind the main stream media
and you are not told what
you are not supposed to know.
The North American Union is the
same concept as the European Union,
the African Union and
the soon-to-be Asian Union
and the same people
are behind all of them.
And when the time is right,
the North American Union,
the European Union, the African Union
and the Asian Union
will be merged together,
forming the final stages of a plan
these men have been working on
for over 60 years.
A one world government.
One bank, one army,
one center of power.
And if we have learned
anything from history.
It is that power corrupts and
absolute power corrupts absolutely.
This is Aaron Russo,
a filmmaker and former politician.
To his left is
Nicholas Rockefeller
of the infamous Rockefeller
Banking and Business Dynasty.
After maintaining a close
friendship with Nicholas Rockefeller,
Aaron eventually
ended the relationship,
appalled by what he had learn about
the Rockefellers and their ambitions.
I got a call one day from an attorney
I knew and she said:
"Would you like to meet
one of the Rockefellers?"
And I said:
"Sure I would love to."
And we became friends and he began
to divulge a lot of things to me,
so he said to me,
one night, he said:
"There's going to be
an event, Aaron,
and out of that event,
we are going to go into Afghanistan,
so we can run pipelines
from the Caspian Sea,
we are going to go into Iraq
to take the oil
and establish a base
in the Middle East
and we are gong to go into
Venezuela and get rid of Chavez."
The first 2 they have accomplished,
Chavez they didn't accomplish.
And he said: "You are going to see
guys going into caves looking for...
looking for people they
are never going to find."
He was laughing about the fact
that you have this war on Terror,
and there is no real enemy.
He was talking about how by having
this war on terror you can never win it,
because it is
an eternal war,
and so you can always keep
taking peoples liberties away.
And I said: "How are you going to
convince people that this war is real?"
And he said: "By the media, the media
can convince everybody that it's real."
You just keep talking about things and
saying them over and over and over again
and eventually,
people believe it.
You know, they create the Federal
Reserve in 1913 through lies.
They create 9/11,
which was another lie.
Through 9/11, then you are fighting a war on
terror and all the sudden you go into Iraq,
which was another lie,
and now,
they are going to do Iran.
It's all one thing
leading to another,
leading to another...
I would say to him:
"What are you doing this for?
What's the point of this thing?
You have all the money in the world
you would ever want,
you have all the power,
you're hurting people.
It's not a good thing."
And he would say:
"What do you care about the people for?
Take care of yourself and
take care of your family".
And then I said:
"So what are the ultimate goals here?"
He said:
"The ultimate goal is to get
everyone in this world
chipped with an RFID chip.
And have all money be on those chips
and have everything on those chips,
and if anyone wants to protest
what we do or violate what we want,
we can just
turn off their chip."
That's right--
micro chipped.
In 2005, Congress,
under the pretense of immigration
control and the
so-called war on terrorism,
passed the Real ID act,
under which it is projected by May 2008,
you will be required to carry
around a Federal Identification card
which includes on it
a scannable barcode
with your personal information.
However this barcode is
only an intermediary step,
before the card is equipped with
a VeriChip RFID Tracking Module,
which will use radio frequencies to
track your every move on the planet,
If this sounds foreign to you,
please note
that the RFID tracking chip is already
in all new American passports.
And the final step
is the implanted chip,
which many people have
already been manipulated
into accepting
under different pretenses.
We have a Florida family who are
really pioneers in a brave new world.
They have volunteered
to be the first ever,
to have microchip
identification devices
implanted into their bodies.
After 9/11, I was really concerned
with the security of my family.
I wouldn't mind having something
planted permanently in my arm,
that would identify me.
In the end, everybody will be
locked into a monitored control grid,
where every single action
you perform is documented,
and if you get out of line,
they can just turn off your chip,
for at that point in time,
every single aspect of society
will revolve around
interactions with the chips.
This is the picture
that is painted for the future
if you open your eyes
to see it.
A centralized one world economy,
where everyone's moves
and everyone transactions
are tracked and monitored.
All rights removed.
The incredible aspect of all:
These totalitarian elements
will not be forced upon the people,
the people will demand them.
For the social manipulation of society,
through the generation of fear
and division has completely
detached humans
from their sense
of power and reality.
A process, which has been going on
for centuries if not millennia...
Religion.
Patriotism.
Race.
Wealth.
Class.
And every other form
of arbitrary,
separatist identification
and thus conceit,
has served to create a
controlled population,
utterly malleable
in the hands of the few.
Divide and Conquer
is the motto,
and as long as people continue
to see themselves
as separate from everything else,
they lend themselves to
being completely enslaved.
The men behind the curtain know this.
And they also know,
that if people ever realize the
truth of their relationship to nature,
and the truth
of their personal power...
The entire manufactured
Zeitgeist they prey upon,
will collapse
like a house of cards.
The whole system that we live in,
drills into us that we are powerless,
that we are weak, that society is evil,
that it's crime ridden and so forth.
It is all a big fat lie!
We are powerful,
beautiful, extraordinary.
There is no reason
why we cannot understand
who we truly are;
where we are going.
There is no reason why the average
individual cannot be fully empowered.
We are
incredibly powerful beings.
I think
I spent 30 years of my life,
the first 30,
trying to become something.
I wanted to become
good at things,
I wanted to become good
at tennis and school and grades.
And everything I kinda
viewed in that perspective,
I'm not okay the way I am,
but if I got good at things...
I realized that
I had the game wrong.
Because the game was to
find out what I already was.
Now, in our culture we have been trained
for individual differences to stand out.
So you look at each person
and the immediate hit is.
Brighter, dumber, older,
younger, richer, poorer...
And we make all these
dimensional distinctions,
put them in categories
and treat them that way.
And get so we only see others
as separate from ourselves
in the ways
in which they are separate.
And one of the dramatic
characteristics of experience
is being with another person
and suddenly seeing
the ways in which they are like you,
not different from you.
And experiencing the fact
that which is essence in you,
which is essence in me,
is indeed, One.
The understanding that there
is no other. It is all One.
I wasn't born Richard Albert,
I was just born as a human being
and then I learned
this whole business of who I am,
and whether I'm good or bad,
or achieving or not...
All that's learned
along the way.
The old appeals to racial,
sexual and religious shovanism,
to rabid nationalistic fervor,
are beginning
not to work.
A new consciousness is developing which
sees the earth as a single organism,
and recognizes, that an organism
at war with itself is doomed.
Bill Hicks
used to finish his shows
with this:
Life's like a ride
in an amusement park,
and when you go on it,
you think it's real
because that's how powerful
our minds are.
The ride goes up and down
and round and round,
it has thrills and chills
and it's very brightly colored.
And it's very loud and
it's fun for a while.
Some have been on the ride for a
long time and they begin to question:
Is this real?
Or is this just a ride?
And other people have remembered and
they come back to us and they say:
'Hey, don't worry,
don't be afraid ever.
Cause this is just a ride.'
And we kill those people.
Shut him up, I have got a lot
invested in this ride, shut him up!
Look at my frowns of worry...
Look at my big bank account
and my family...
This has to be real...
It's just a ride.
But we always kill those good guys
who try and tell us that,
you ever notice that?
And we let the demons
run a muck...
But it doesn't matter,
because it is just a ride
and we can change it
anytime we want.
It is only a choice.
No effort, no work, no job,
no savings of money.
Just a choice right now.
Between fear,
and love.
Ripped by: Rogard
Final Edits by: VeRdiKT
Exclusively for SubScene.com
and dedicated to all Zeitgeist fans!
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org